previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Wizard?
Could you help me get my spellbook back? You hold him down? All like rubbed dirt in his face or something?
What if you had a competition and the winner wins the rights to own the book?
Oh we could be judges. So five minute time limit. Whoever can do it in five minutes, chop style.
Alright, one axe and one bag of holding, coming up.
How long do you think they've been battling?
I think a while.
I think our mix was young when they started.
But hey, you got that sweet bag there and I got this axe that we've been looking for for like millenniums pretty much
Oh, that's good. Maybe they'll make you king because of it
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. We're a D&D 5th edition actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Ross More
And with me today is Tom Laird. That's me. I play Flint fire beard
And that's it. That's all that's with me today
Flint episode just a solo Flint episode Flint finds himself. No one else. Amy is just here for moral support
I play some NPCs
Also with me Amy More, it's true
Regardless of what Russ says I'm never allowed to skip a podcast like Carla does
Carla you get special treatment
I think you might be the favorite and I play the amistacia a druid elf an elf druid
I mean, it's it's fine. Either way. I think it's druid. Yeah a druidic elf a druidic
Elven druid of the moon circle
Correct
Yeah, welcome welcome everybody. It's a flint and Thea episode today get buckled in
Strap in and strap on I will I will give I mean we've already done two of these episodes
If this is your first episode and you don't want season one spoiled now's the time to stop
Clever and there's a reason Carla's not here wink
Yeah, all right where we
Some time has passed
No, we have to do on dedication, oh right, I was trying to come up with a where we also but there was nothing there
I thought it was more where we were last time sort of thing. Yeah, he hasn't fucked it yet
So this episode is gonna go over right I have red wine people have red wine
Whoo goes right to your head where we don't always have red wine
But sometimes we do is over on Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
Where if you haven't stopped by there recently, we have some pretty cool news deeper
We have some pretty cool stuff that you can go check out like some deeper props. That's exactly correct that out now
You're just deep
Everyone knows me from a hip deeper props
But what is always consistent over there is you get an episode dedicated to you when you're a patron and today's episode is
dedicated to
Coop mer
Hey, thanks, Coop. Thank you very much. Thank you
Carla thanks you to probably I mean find out maybe never know. Yeah
It just means that it's more concentrated the thank you because it's between three people instead of four, right?
It's not this diluted. Thank you
This is concentrated the real stuff with just wait there's ever just an episode of two people
Oh, man, it'll happen that thank you is gonna blow you out of your seat
wait, I believe there's been talk of Russ just doing a
hillup and
Yeah, no fuck it let's play D&D
He fucked it
We
find ourselves
back in the well of dragons
The you are
knelt over
Nulara's body
Flint is standing stunned off a distance away
We see a
Couple quick flashes couple
Jumps of image from
Thea's face to flint looking away to the dagger on Nulara's belt
Thea grabs the dagger quickly and stabs it into the charred body of Nulara
Suddenly everywhere around you Thea is black
Wait
Your voice echoes off into the unknown beyond what you can see
Donnie
You begin to hear footsteps
Like someone walking in just a thin
puddle
Just like they're walking in water
You
Look around and you see coming towards you a very shadowy silhouette come into focus a
Couple more flashes and the the
person who you can tell
Kind of jumps in distance towards you quickly
Directly
Directly before your face you see Nulara. She's drenched wet
Eyes are sunken her compLexion is sallow and she grabs you and says
And you wake
Ah
What's uh, what's the problem I
Had that dream again
Again fuck. What is this the tenth time?
Feels like it
Maybe maybe there's something we can do to help her. Maybe this is prophetic
Or I mean maybe
Maybe we can do something to stop having this dream come up for you
Well, okay, yeah sure
but what what if it is prophetic and I stopped the dreams and and Nulara's soul is trapped somewhere or and
And we have a chance to help her but we don't
Well shit, you had to put it that way didn't you? Yeah, I did. Yeah, I mean, let's uh
Let's figure this out if there's a chance that we can help her out with whatever I mean we over
Yeah, we do and stop hogging all the blankets
Sorry, sorry, yeah dwarfs we get cold
Run chilly
You get up and start your day I assume you head back on the road
Last we saw you you were traveling towards water deep
That's still the plan
Sure. Yes
You hop back on the road and to this point you have passed many small towns all of which have been
Evacuated or just left
Because of the battle with the cult of the dragon
And you come upon one a large sign
Notes the town name of Fairhaven
And as you come in you notice that people have begun to return to this town
You see caravans coming up the road as you are coming up to it and
It looks like people are are
moving back in
Moving back in
It's a good sign
What do you think
What do you think happened here just more cult shenanigans
Probably people are trying to put back the pieces of their broken lives after everything that's happened
I think it's a good sign everything's returning to normal I guess
Should we see if they need a hand or anything or what's the plan here? Yeah
Side all up to a friendly looking caravan
You see a
Caravan filled with what looks like a couple families
And they're offloading some things into a house near the edge of this town
Can we can we help you out at all is there anything you need oh
Yes, I'm sorry, sorry were you were you with the caravan before
You're coming from the other direction. No, we're just we're just passing through on our way back to Waterdeep. Oh
of course
A lot of people coming coming back out this way
But but yes, of course
We've got to get some heavier boxes that you could that would be great if you could help you're speaking to a
human woman
Spout five feet dirty blonde hair kind of looks like she's in a
Bit of a tattered a tattered dress but
Appears that she's been putting herself together for this moment
Sorry, um, hi, I'm I'm Thea
Yes. Yes. Pleasure to meet you. Um, my name's Morgana. Nice to meet you. I'm Merlin
Flint Flint over here there Morgana
pleasure pleasure
This is my family is
She points out to a couple kids, that's
Gohman and Fowler in
My husband he's off helping some other other
Other families get their stuff moved in. How long have you been away from your home?
it's
Seems like a while now we went to Waterdeep once the cult started hitting smaller towns
so
It's been a couple months. It feels like
That you're happy to be back
Definitely. It's it's certainly a nice change
How about you two
Wait, don't I know you from somewhere?
No, probably not I mean we've been around
Like a deception check
14 for
Well, I'm definitely not the flint fire beard from the song and then that's just decimator of dragons
That's not a percent. Not I mean that guy's a dwarf I hear
I'm clearly
Halfling
Clearly
No, really, I think I think
Hmm
you just look very familiar and
Like I've seen you on some big big poster somewhere
Big sign big banner. I've just I've been told I have one of those beards, you know
That's it. That's the beard
Wait, she comes in a little closer
Are you
This decimators of dragons
What's uh, what's left of us? Yep
I
Can tell you're you're trying to keep a low profile
Unsuccessfully sir, if you don't mind me saying you're wearing exactly the same outfit as I'll not think better
I mean, it's the beard. It's kind of a hard thing to hide. I gotta be honest. That's fair. That's fair
I'll I'll I won't I won't make a big deal out of it
But thank you
For everything that you you've done
I
Say any time but I really hope we don't have to do that. Yeah, I'd prefer if we didn't have to again that's for sure
It's fair. I pick up a crate and I go kitchen
Yes, please yeah, it's books but I'm sure we'll find we'll find a where it goes
You can read in any room the box marked kitchen books. They could be cookbooks could be
You go about helping
Morgana unload her boxes and you get you get everything all packed up and inside
Well, I guess I guess we best be off
Are you where are you headed
Back to water deep
Well, I'm just just be beware will not weary but careful
The roads are pretty packed with people moving back out
as you probably know the city was pretty
overloaded and now they're trying to get everybody relocated back to
If they have a town left back to their towns if not then to a neighboring
neighboring city or town
Well, maybe we'll take the backwards
That's a good idea
Of course
Okay. Well, it's pleasure. Thank you very much for for everything. Good luck Morgana. Thank you
Get back on our little
Wagon with tiny and
You make your way through this town and you see a
Look that
you haven't seen on
just
the
Common folk for lack of a better term but in quite a while
People of any village across Faerun you haven't seen a look of hope and
Happiness
It's nice isn't this nice it's nice I kNulara would have liked this
Who do you think we can talk to about this
Dream and the possible
Implications of it. Well, if we need any like real good gypsies or witches in the woods
I mean, I mean we have a bit of a track record with witches in the woods if you do recall
They always have some good insights to that kind of stuff
But maybe it'd be safest to keep that information and discuss it with someone once we get to water deep
Can't remember who's there. I'm suffering from PTSD
Maybe like do you think that arcane brotherhood knows anyone who delves in that kind of stuff?
maybe
can't hurt to ask
As you exit the town make a perception check
Well
19 oh I did even better. No, I got the same 19
You get to the edge of town and back into moving into some forested area and you think you hear
Cries of help from behind you in the town
Do you hear that?
And it's always it's always something isn't it? I was just joking, but it's it's a fucking witch. I'm just leaving
Well, I mean usually they don't cry out for help
Oh shit unless it's someone crying out for help because of a witch. Oh god. Okay. Well, let's go
So we turn around and come back into the
You quickly make your way towards where you hear the screaming and it's coming from the center of town
This is woken Donnie
He wakes up and hey what what's going on out there?
and as you get in round the corner to the town square you see the ground starting to heave up and
Coming up from it are monstrous centipedes
Tremors where's Kavin Bacon they begin pouring out of the ground in front of you
And roll for initiative. Yeah, we do
And that's a four
five
Plus two that is a 17 for old flint
Just like old times
Sorry, you got a four. No, I got five. Yeah, how dare you Russ? I have a plus two to my initiative
Lit you're up first. So you have in front of you
Rough estimate you've got between 10 and 15 centimeters coming up and out of the ground you see that they're
Surrounding some people on a far side of this square that you're in and there are people running in every direction around you
Yeah flint pulls the sword out from behind his back and says things are about to get moist
Cueing up his moist tongue longsword to do extra damage, and he
attacks the the
centipede closest to him
Already with a 21
Now the 21 is now the new one okay perfect
It's opposite day. I should have gone first. It's russ is sassy today
Sassa pants all right. Oh, I need to d6 this as well because I've activated the sword
Okay, we got
Slashing damage and then four cold damage so 19 damage in total
Holy fuck you leap down off of the wagon into this this fray of
Rithing and
Wriggling
centipedes
But you launch yourself down into them, and you cleave through one entirely and into another one
Perfect time for the second of three attacks via claps and is like
Come on. Oh, that's not very good. That's a 12
A
12 will not do it one sack one sack
Blances off its natural armor. Let's have to go back over flints skills in shit here
I know it's a one or two on a damage roll not an attack roll all right and
one more attack
And that is a 23 that will
Okay, that is
Plus eight cold damage so 17 in total
The second one that you hit kind of turns to you and looks with its beady eyes as you strike into its face and
It explodes back and out towards some running people. They're covered in centipede goop
Sorry about that
That's it for fun screams all right some centipedes across the square, and they are
Corraling and cornering some towns folks, and they go to attack them
Holy shit, there's bystanders now the stakes have been raised
Stakes have been raised. I mean you guys can cleave through fucking anything, so I got to give you something to work for here
You see one of them jump up and bite at one of these one of these towns people
And they sustain some damage and make us
And
the one that bites
Let's out a yell and falls to the ground as the centipede crawls over top of them
Thea your turn
How far am I from the centipedes that are crawling the people?
Probably
50 feet I'm gonna cast eldritch blast at the one
that one that's like furthest away from
the people still in the group, but
So that is
Instantaneous an attack roll per each okay
and I
Get four beams. I'm at 17th level for beat 16th 16th level
Oh 16 okay fine three beams
I'm gonna roll all three
Said beans and not beams. I'm gonna throw some beans
Well here's a nat 20
Here's a 19
Here's an 11, but my attack bonus is a plus 7 so that's an 18
All right, roll me some damage. Okay, it's going to be
Oh
Roll your double one for my double. So the double is 2d 10
Force damage
That's a six and that's a seven
Which
13 for the where are you aiming each of these three all at one or at three different ones?
I think it's gonna be three different ones. Okay, so the first one goes to
The one that maybe bit the person sure well no isn't that crawling on top of the person right now
I don't want to do that
What if it hits the person maybe you're like a fucking sniper with these with these beams level level 16
Yeah, okay, I'm gonna explode it on top of that guy, and he's gonna be fucking grateful
And he is and you do it rains down this first bolt hits into that
It's almost like goes up its butt
It's almost like goes up its butt and like spreads like
Nice there's Santa Pete's I gotta do something right might as well be but stuff behind as well
Wouldn't be enough dimensions if it wasn't
My zombie butt stuff what I always say
It's middle time can't touch this
It's bill time welcome to the middle of the episode this is where we talk about things and stuff and how much we love you
Wow, I do two songs right off the bat
Should we do an interlude where it's all song
I mean like that episode of Buffy. Yeah, we're gonna have to maybe a bit of a high water mark
We'd have to hold on. Yeah, we have to try a little harder. Why would this just be interludes are for everyone
Oh interludes are for this is where we try and get them to become patrons
Then I will not sing because I don't know if Joss Whedon will come after me
You might you might become a patron, maybe you'll get some
Joss turn it off right now
Yeah, Joss, I know you're a big fan, but yeah, this one's not today you right now
I'm mad at you today. Joss. I'm mad at you for what you did to Cordelia. It's all right. He's
Spoilers
Ten years ago
And also it's not like you said what happened
But something now knows it happens patron.com. This is the
Joss cast
Just just Joss and around
Cuz you never know right you never know maybe we'll want another podcast we don't have an entirely possible
What are we talking about
Looking to see if it's not a chance and around
Going to go down right now watch all the
There's too many things honestly, that's that's good content. That means I would never run out. Okay Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
That's where we would like you to go visit. Why these because when you're a patron at a specific tier
We can play a game with you
Yes
But that tier called game time
We if you get a whole bunch of other stuff like everything else that's available over there
Which is a whole bunch of bonus content very exclusive very cool
But at this tier at game time we get to play sit down and play a game with you
We prep it we do all the work
We just tell you what kind of character you got to make and then you can come hang out with us, right?
It's so fun. Dom jins game time
excellent
I'm currently the the person in charge of DMing this month's game time
Shenanigans, I have one
Sentence written on a piece of paper. You guys don't get to see what it actually said
But it is the basis off everything. I'm working towards
Intriguing
Interesting let's start guessing let's start guessing is it an animal
No sentence for us high heels pantyhose and other question mark
Write this down sounds more like a shopping list, but alright
Anyways, you're gonna figure out what that sentence is if you come join us Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast if the game time
Is a little bit out of your reach though. We totally understand. We have a plethora of bonus content including a good word
Thank you
Including our new show, which is starting January 2020, which is being released exclusively to patrons
Called facing fate
Where we do indeed face fate we do and it's quite frightening and it is not D&D. It is
Something other stuff. It is. Yeah, our first season is called Luna Corp and it's got you know, it's got some sci-fi
It's got some thrills. It's got some scares. It's got some clip-clopping
and hip-hopping
I don't think it has either of those things. It has both of those things actually
Well, maybe not the hip-hopping but it does have clip-clopping because you know
There's the one character who walks kind of funny and we draw attention to it every time she comes in
So it's still got that good old Dumbgeons and Dragons humor but a little edgier
It's just a little different that's all different and we enjoy it and that's available over Patreon.com slash dumb dragon
We'd love you to come see what we have to offer
Just gave a lot I just gave a lot
Which you can also have access to yeah, if you're a patron, I think there's a common theme here you should come patronize us
I think it is
We are way too up on our high horse right now and I we need a little bit of real talk
I think this is I think we've gone a little far off the tracks here
But this is exactly what we need Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and in the meantime
Go listen to that promo that's coming up next and then the episode. Oh, yeah, don't just stop at the promo
No, cuz yeah finish the episode to Flint and Thea they're up to some wild and crazy stuff. Okay. Bye
Welcome to facing fate an anthological audio fiction actual play podcast
What does that mean outside of being amazing alliteration?
Well, it means when you subscribe to facing fate you will find two 10 episode seasons every year
Starting January 2020 in the facing fate feed each season will take you through a different setting
Different genre and different characters going through thrilling exhilarating and maybe hilarious collaborative stories
I'm your game master rust more and along with my friends. Amy more Carla max dead and Tom Laird
We will bring you along on a shared journey together
Season one of facing fate titled lunacorp begins January 2020
Lunacorp is a sci-fi thriller placing you among the crew of a near future moon base mining for an alternate energy source
But the decisions and hasty thinking of mankind in this time place the crew and the world in danger
Subscribe to facing fate in your favorite podcast app to hear sneak peeks world archives and more leading up to January 2020
Or visit facing fate.com to find our social feeds and more about us
Patrons of dumb dragons productions have early access to weekly releases of season one now
Join the crew of lunacorp main base at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
Facing fate a dumb dragons production
That is for
Yep, that is a four for the next one second beam strikes into one of them and like loses a bunch of its legs
Turns and looks towards your direction and begins crawling that way
And the next one off only one
It's another one it barely notices they thought it just kind of stumbled over a rock
Keeps going towards some more towns people. It's more centipedes turns ones that are near you and they come to bite you me
More me. Well, I mean both of you. I mean both of you. All right, there's a bunch of them. So
Folks
That's right two of them are going to attack at flint that is double 19s
Plus fours that's crap. That's double 23. Oh, yeah, that'll hit. Oh, yeah, and
That's a natural 20 and a 15 for Thea a 19 for Thea
Yeah, yeah. All right. Let's roll some damage
Flint you're gonna take
Six nine piercing damage and you must succeed on a Constitution saving throw. Is this
Non-magic damage Russ. This is non-magic. This is centipedal damage and you said nine, correct? Nine
All right. I will take six
Because of my heavy armor mastery. Yeah, and then you said a Constitution saving throw you betcha
that is a
You are fine. Yeah
Gotta love them plus four bonuses
Thea you will take ten piercing damage and also must succeed on a Constitution saving throw
Nine you failed but it's poison so you're fine. Oh, yeah
Hey
Back to flint
Some of these centipedes have started that are on the outer edges have started to go into the town
Is there still some that are around like townsfolk?
Yes on the other side of the
Square how far away from me are they?
Approximately 40 feet. All right, I will
Walk like I don't know
10 or
15 feet or so. How far do we have with the jumpy diamonds Ross was it 30 feet?
30 feet with the jumpy diamonds. Now if you walk I
Will invoke two opportunity attacks against you
To that just bitch you okay, you know what let's attack these two first and then maybe I'll go for a little walk
In a jumpy diamond
All right, first one coming at you that is a 27
Just you know, you know
All right, uh
Seven plus nine is 16 damage
That one that was getting all sassy and was like opportunity attack. Yeah, you just split hit skull perfect
Have a scholar. It's exoskeleton
Exoskeleton, let's go for the other one that would have been opportunistic against me. So I'm assuming there's two there were two
Oh, that's a nat 20. I
Mean you can roll it. I mean I gotta roll it just for the sake of I rolled in at 20 and you got to
Roll it
So that is 8 plus 715
Followed by another 5. So that's 20 plus another 16. So that is 36 damage
You know what you strike into this one and you hit it so hard
It blinks out of existence
No, not even that you hit it so hard and with such accuracy that its body splits in twain and
Shoots off and does more damage to two that are farther away. Just like their legs like pierce into
These other two centipedes and you've taken out four centipedes with this
Just like I planned it
And now I'm gonna toss the little jumpy diamond up in the air looking over towards where these town people are
Where there's other centipedes attacking them and I'm going to arrive right over there
And I'm gonna do a little more hackin and or a slashing
All right
Been wanting to use the jumpy diamond forever. I know now is the goddamn time
That is a 26
So that is 11 plus 6 so 17 damage there
you get one right you kind of appear and
Move to get this one right as it's about to jump at some towns people
and
Pin it to the ground with your sword
excellent
That is all for Flint's turn
Well, that's it just take out half the centipede well I could action surge if you want me to try forth, but no no
No, that's fine
I
Don't know you got a mr. Twelve turns
It would have been the centipedes turns but now it's Amy's turn they got got so it's
Thea's turn there are two centipedes around you and you see some
Maybe three or four more going into the city or into the town Amy. I made it your turn quicker
Are you happy? He's so happy
Okay, so three or four more going back toward the town, yeah, but two are on you but two are on me, okay
Well, I guess I am going to have to
Do something about that I'm gonna do eldritch blast again
Against the two in front of me and one that's heading toward the city. All right
Well, then that one's only a 13
18 and 17
All of those will hit
All right, so for the ones that are on me one gets two damage. Yes
Force damage another one gets four damage. All right
And the next one is a one watch out. I'm a level 16 bitches. Calm yourselves down
So your elders blast goes out and like
Like vaporizes into the face of these centipedes who now their eyes shrivel up
But they're just kind of riling around on the ground in front of you
One goes off and fires into the back end of one and just kind of skitters it further into the town quickly
Whoops
Sorry, I'm you know that dream really got me
Not at my best right now the centipedes that are they're just kind of spinning
They're going to try to attack you but at disadvantage
That's gonna be a 16 for the first time me. Yeah, they should always attack me with disadvantage
I have my cloak of displacement on it got shredded. It got shredded by Tiamat. I don't remember that
Fucking it's got duct tape on it
It's got to be re-enchanted as shit. You haven't stopped down to do that
So you get hit by one because the other one rolled an eight
That's gonna be six piercing damage and poison but whatever
Back to Flint so there are no more around you
You too have seen some go in the direction of the city. You look back at Thea. She has
Two that are just kind of spinning and trying to bite her but appear to have something
You know optically wrong with them
And there is the one townsperson who is knocked down to the ground and it appears to be unconscious
All right, I guess I'll make my way over to Thea's crazy spinning centipedes of death
Okay
How far away are they from me?
They you were 40 feet to get
Across to the townspeople. So
So somewhere in that neighborhood somewhere in that neighborhood. Okay, I'll make my way towards her
But I can't get that far on one set of movement
Oh, I guess I could dash
That uses up one of my actions correctly. Yes. Okay, I will dash over there and I will attack
The first of the two spinning centipedes possibly with disadvantage because they're spinning and therefore are probably harder to hit I
Mean they can't see which would put them at a disadvantage
So you would probably get advantage because they don't know it's coming because they can't dodge or anything
I'm well first one wasn't had twice
All right out of curiosity, I'm gonna roll the second one. All right, it was the 13
See if that dice is broken too many gnats
like he does I
Mean I feel like I could save these for our other game and they would be more useful there than they are right here
But you don't know what kind of use these these sense of feeds are well, that's true
Okay, so 13 plus 4 is 17 plus 10 is 27 damage
It's spinning very quickly
But you kind of give one of these like you're watching it like your head's going around in circles and then you just
You get it just like tracking it. Yeah. All right, and I guess second one that is a
15 on the attack roll Russ
That will also hit. Oh, I was pleasantly surprised about that
Ten and five fifteen
This last centipede that you can see is also now dispatched centipede guts
strewn across
below your feet
You look around and survey the situation. There's a giant
Not a giant but a large hole where these centipedes came up
You hear some distant calls distant screaming
Sounds like maybe they've moved into other parts of the city as you had watched them go and there is a townsperson
Unconscious
You're not in direct combat anymore so you can do whatever you can I pick up this townsperson and like firemen carry them back
into town
Yeah, yeah, I mean technically you're in town but I can take them somewhere to and to perhaps a another group
Sorry, I thought you said the centipede was like heading into town. Oh, sorry. No, I had you place like in town square
Oh, okay. Perfect. Yeah, so you're in town. So like further in town. They're heading. Yeah. Yeah, sorry. They're going out into like
Hit the mic they're going out into like the surrounding
Suburbs, okay, you know as far as small town. Well that case
I guess we can maybe just leave this person here if it doesn't look like there's any immediate danger
Yeah, I think main
Objective is stop other ones from doing more damage. Yeah. Oh, can we can I like put this person on the cart?
Sure, you can I just get them off the ground that might be at least some form of
protection if there's more centipedes to show up
Donnie and kind of leans back in the back of the wagon. It's like yeah, you guys looked like you had it down
I'll watch this this MOOC
Yeah, thanks. Thanks for all your help Donnie
You walk away and you hear him. He's like hey, hey buddy
You got you got bit by a centipede now. You're gonna wake up to a dragon face when you wake up
That's gonna be real exciting. Oh
Boy, this was a good idea
Because these people are not at all, you know
Traumatized by the recent events. No, they haven't had any trouble with dragons
It's gonna be fine. It's gonna be fine. All right, I guess take off after these other centipedes
All right, you know the approximate direction, but as you follow
you
need to roll a
survival check or
Or nature nature or survival. I
Will choose nature because I have a much better bonus in that one. Oh, I critically failed so it does not matter
Are you going to attempt to do anything we're not in combat so you guys are together
Fuck me
It's going to be
Well survivals plus four so how about an eight solid
You begin walking and you kind of lose the path after a little while
Okay, I'm not gonna lie I don't know where we are yeah, I've I've totally lost track of everything
Should we retrace our steps
Yeah, I guess
Now you begin retracing your steps and you make it about halfway back to the town square when you hear a another scream
off into your right
Shall we run to the scream?
Like you're already behind me see he's taken off
Run we shall
You make it there and you see a woman running out of a house
And she passes you like running full-tilt doesn't stop to say anything. I think we're going the right way. I think so
Let's get into that house over there
You make it into the house and it's dark and shadowy make a perception check
14 to 13 flint you see
Kind of the tail end of what you
Think is centipede go down some stairs and just barrel on down those stairs
Following quickly behind
What are you doing? I've seen him murder like a hundred centipedes in like the last five minutes
Okay, so I yell after him. I'm gonna make sure everyone's safe, and I go and I go upstairs to
Go to like investigate the rooms
Okay, so
The rooms
Okay
You make it down to the basement and you roll a perception check
Gladly good, sir
That is a 15
you get down to the bottom of the stairs and
There are some some boxes kind of stacked up and you hear off and to the left
The sound of a scent centipedes
Feet am I is there stuff in the way am I able to see?
It's kind of tucked away behind some of the boxes. All right, so I guess I'll
Rip these boxes out of the way and get my sword ready in one fell swoop you do so
Make a dexterity saving throw
That is a 14 to centipedes jump out at you
You nimbly throw your dice across the room perfect mission accomplished
Nimbly dodge out of the way as you see their fangs fly towards your face. You're up first
Okay
It's a 26. Oh my god. Yeah
That is
22 damage that time
It's almost like you kind of backhand your sword as you catch it and splits it runs all the way down those one of them
Second one 22
18 damages on that one
Also dead also dead it didn't even turn around
And you had you had killed it cut its head clean off as
You stabbed this last one. You kind of take a quick look around the room and you see that there is a
a hole in the dirt
Off to where they were behind the boxes
Does this look like a hole they were like trying to escape into
Perhaps one could presume. All right, I guess I'll
Inspect a gate this hole
Roll an inspection
He's the best investigator, that's right
That is an 18
It definitely looks like they were moving towards that direction you look down it it's
You can't really see where it terminates, but you
Get the sense and almost you feel kind of a draft coming back through it
Leading you to believe that this hole leads elsewhere in the town
Although not big enough for me to like climb in to I'm assuming
No, not really not human size. Hey. No. All right. Is there any like
Bookshelves or heavy things like maybe a filing cabinet because they had those things back then right? Definitely
Maybe it's full of old tax returns and weighs a lot and I can like dump it in front of the hole
So it can't be moved. I mean there are some pretty heavy boxes. Perfect. Let's do heavy boxes. Okay
You do so back to Thea. What are you doing?
I'm running up the stairs to go see if there's anyone upstairs who needs assistance. I want to get people out of here
I'm on safety patrol because you know
My fighting is a little iffy right now rubble on the double
Video very nicely done. Yeah, it was good, right?
You quickly run up and clear all the rooms. There's nobody up there
You hear Flint's footsteps coming back up the stairs after a very short amount of time
I slide down the banister and meet him at the bottom
How'd it go? I?
Mean seem pretty good
I dispatched the two that I found and but there's like a tunnel of sorts down in that basement
It obviously leads somewhere
Man, they're gonna want to get that checked out like probably get an exterminator up in here
Yeah, maybe I have a problem. Yeah centipedes are us or something. I know I think that's where you go to buy giant centipede
Oh, right. Okay. Yeah, then probably not that store. No
I don't I don't feel like chasing that lady down to tell her that her house is clear
Just leave like a little note on the door
Yeah, I mean I take take out a scroll
And I and I write in bit like the penmanship is amazing, but I write
Killed to this was after talking to Flint killed two centipedes
corpses left in basement
sorry for the mess
might want to get that hole taken care of and I
put it on her door as
You pin it to the door close the door behind you ever so gently
And head back out into the streets you begin to feel a rumble like a
Tremored earthquake rumble course through the town
Well, I can't that can't be good
Glass begins to shatter in windows and people that were still around it begin to run out and into the forest as
you see a
Giant
Centipede I said the last ones were monstrous, but these this one is huge
It erupts up and out dirt and debris flies everywhere. It easily stands about 30 feet above you
So we're talking like a dune level sandworm
With its hundreds of legs it screams and looks down towards you
All music in today's episode is by Kavin McLeod of incompetent film music dot IO a huge
Thank you to our supporting producers Gabriel Lynch Ryan Cushman Joshua Dixon Devin Michaels cat water flame and Jacob Madden
Find out more at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
Rose
Sorry, oh my god, I thought Paisley was the disgusting one in that room
It's me. I had tacos. Well, I mean
I
Actually think I've been incorrectly rolling my damage as in not giving myself enough because it says on my sheet
1d 10 plus 10 for the damage on this moist on long sword and I've been rolling 2d 10s
So whenever I mean pretty close, but yeah, you should be doing 1d 10 plus 10. Yeah
Yeah, my bad. Anyways, oh my god good Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production