previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Oh, okay, yeah, thank you. Who are you? Welcome. I am Yenbul. I believe my friend Leosin said to look for me.
We're hunting down that amulet of wonder. Any, any leads?
It's not the best news I could give you because it is with
Shangalar. Oh, that is real crappy. The Lich, whose undead army has overtaken the city and- Well, this means two birds one stone.
Well, that's true. We help your city and we get the amulet back.
I have a friend or a man I know, Mannix Fallenleaf. He knows where there's a portal
leading to this flying fortress. I can get you to
the next city. It must move quickly though. And you exit
further from where a massive wall has been erected and
you see just swarms of undead crashing into and climbing up over.
Mannix leads you through
the streets of this town that he referred to as Keltar. And inside there are runes on
the wall. The runes begin to glow as he runs his hand along them.
He says, when you are ready, we shall step through. You look up and beyond the clouds as they begin to part you see a
massive
pyramid floating high in the sky above the mountains. Is this like the one that you crashed?
Hers was more of a castle.
Much smaller.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We're a D&D 5th edition actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Russ More. And with me today is Amy More.
Yeah, I'm here. I'm here for you listeners.
Not for you, Russ. For you listeners. Yeah, no one's here. And I play Thea Amistacio.
And Tom Laird. Yeah, I'm here and I'm here for all of you, but not Russ. And I play FlintFirebeard.
And Carla Maxed. I am also here for everyone in the whole world except
No, just for everybody even Russ. Thank you. And I play
Yen Bull Nury. Yes, Yen Bull. Welcome Yen Bull.
New character. Very exciting. First time getting to introduce her in the intro. That's exciting.
It's very good. You guys didn't even know her last name. No idea.
Thea doesn't ask about last names.
Why would you? What are you gonna ID me?
Where we are concerned about last names is over on Patreon.
That's weird. That is weird. And also your social insurance number, please.
Yeah, credit card number and the little one on the back, the little three-digit.
Spirey date too.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast. We don't ask for any of that stuff, but what we do ask for is that you come join us.
Because we've got a ton of great stuff including a great community that gathers on
Discord and we talk and they play games together and it's awesome and
we've got bonus content more of what you love with great shows.
Some run by Tom. What? Some bonus episodes run by Amy and Carla. Yarp.
So many things happen over there.
Sorry, I'm not sure where Yarp came from. I mean, I think Sean of The Dead.
Thea from Within Me is where it came from. Oh, Hot Fuzz, of course. Hot Fuzz, yes.
I saw that once. Oh my god, you should watch it again. It's amazing. Did that stick with me?
They're all so good. Must've.
But what you also get over there is you get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron.
And you're right. What?
Such a big fan. Thank you for listening. Jessica
Babyok.
Thanks, Jessica.
Such a big fan. Thanks for listening. Thanks so much for listening. Thank you for being here. Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Patreon.com. Nailed it. Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast. Go check it out.
Only one that rust slips over. No.
It's gonna be a good episode everybody. Fuck it. Let's play D&D.
We see or hear rather a figure quickly scurrying down a stone hallway.
We see the point of view from this creature and we know it's a creature because it's very low to the ground.
We hear heavy footsteps
stomping behind further down the hall. The point of view looks behind and doesn't see anything and quickly flies up
into this dimly torch lit hallway. Stone all around. Cobwebs all around.
And we see a small alcove off to the side.
This creature zips in to this alcove and it goes deep into the wall.
It's heavy breathing that kind of echoes soft and light but it echoes
loud in the ears of this creature.
Those footsteps that we heard previously
walk past this spot. Loud and there's grumbling.
And we pan out and we see Donnie
curled up inside of this labyrinth. This tunnel. This maze that he is in.
And we flash back to Flint,
Thea, Yen Bull, and Mannix at the base of the mountain
overlooking the fortress before them.
Thea immediately sinks to the ground and like starts touching all the foliage and stuff and just kind of
really getting her nature on.
She didn't quite realize how much she missed
the nature of this creature.
It's a real deserty country too, so this is the only place you're going to get that lushness.
Yen Bull is going to
not like disappear into the forest or anything, but she's going to start looking
for some kind of
some kind of
Not like disappear into the forest or anything, but she's going to start looking for
signs to see if those friends that she mentioned might be anywhere near her.
Okay.
What kind of signs is she looking for? You know, do this, don't do that. Friends this way.
Can't you read the sign, Amy?
Uh
So because they are there's like various groups of these sort of wandering warrior groups, they
leave signs in the trees for one another like
specific ways of breaking branches like things that no one else would notice unless you knew to look for them.
Like the hobo signs of the woods.
Okay, cool.
So I'm looking you're looking for that. Okay, roll me
a d20.
Odds you find it
evens you don't.
It's a 19.
Okay, so you find something. What do you find?
In a specific tree
a specific type of tree that is sort of rare only found
um
in the marching mountains right near the crook of kind of where uh
branch meets the tree trunk
there is a little uh
slice and some like a knife marks there
um, just indicating that that they have been there.
Um, I can tell how old they are based on like
how dried out and like
the old they are. Okay, basically. Um
Russ hates everything that's happening right now. Uh, they are
a day old.
A day old.
Okay
that is
probably
too far
if well, I guess I should ask my friends.
What is our plan for
attack? Are we going to I have friends who are
are
great fighters.
I do not know if they would help us. They are
at least one day away.
Well, not on any kind of specific timeline. Um, it kind of sounds like calum port
has
fallen. If we stop Shangalar, the undead army will disperse.
I want to find my friends, but I want
I want to save calum port. It is
the greatest most ancient city in the world and it cannot
fall in such a
disgusting way. Our best chance of defeating him
would probably be with the help of your friends.
Mannix, what do you know of Shangalar? Is he
surrounded by
many many others or or
by himself?
Mannix looks up at the floating fortress in the sky
and says
there are many levels
to this fortress
and
Shangalar does not travel alone.
I fear we will need to fight through many in order to get to him.
So all the friends we can get are a good thing.
Be it a day away or not, I think we stand the best chance.
Well, then
let us go this way.
I pick up the daisy chain that I had been making and I set it on Flynn's head and I follow Yen Bull.
The group gathers their things and begins heading off following the tracks that Yen Bull has found.
How much do you know
about
the history
of Calum Shan?
Oh my goodness.
Um, I think we only just really figured out that Calum Shan was over here in a place that we needed to go
two days ago.
Well, I mean, Leosen told us a little bit about some
genies
that battled.
Yes, many
long ago many battles with genies.
More recently
there was a a glorious revolution and there were
uh many slaves who escaped and overthrew their oppressors and and my friends the Janissar,
many of them
are the children of those escaped slaves and they
they now
live in isolation and
fight and train
in case another
need arises.
And on one of my adventures I
came to this place and spent time with them.
And you think they might be willing to help us?
They do not stand for evil.
So I I think they will want to help.
All right.
They can be elusive though many many people here never have even
seen a Janissar.
Count me in with those people.
You travel through the forest of Myrrh.
M-I-R.
Um following Yen Bull who is following
more of these signs. Yen Bull make a survival check.
Okie dokie.
Well, that was a one.
Plus?
Three.
Nice.
Yes.
Um
I'm distracted by my new friends.
You travel for
going off your confidence of the the marks.
Um, I assume that you would have followed them for a good while.
Um, you travel for about four or five hours into the forest.
Uh when you
the path you are following
you you lose it's not that it disappears, but you you lose your your tracking of it.
Yen Bull why have we stopped?
The marks in the trees they are gone. They are not I cannot find anymore. I'm I'm not sure
which way they have gone.
Oh
should we go back
the way we came?
I am going to cast locate creature.
Okay, what are you trying to locate?
I am trying to locate
um this group of
people whose name I already forgot
from my own thing that I made happen. Janissar. Thank you Janissar. Um
the spell can locate a specific creature known to you or the nearest creature of a specific kind
so long as you have seen such a creature up close.
Okay, so what type of creature is this? I guess it depends how generous you want to be. It does say human.
I mean I can't find a human. Okay, um, but if
I can also maybe they are like
give off some specific vibes.
Yeah, one of them doesn't shower very often.
Okay, well as long as you can find rather than just like a monster creature. Yeah, no, no, sorry, uh
a creature of a specific kind such as a human or a unicorn so long as I have
such as a human or a unicorn. You know, either or. Or both. The two standard types of creatures. Sure, that you want to track down
those would be the only kinds of creatures I would want to track down. Cool. Okay.
Um, so what do you got to what do you got to do for that?
So I pull out a little bit of fur from a blood hound and close my eyes
and just think real hard.
A roll? No, just does it. I don't think so. One action.
All right. Components, concentration.
No, I think it just
happens.
Um, uh, you'll sense the direction of the creature's location.
Um, if the creature is moving, you know the direction of its movement.
Can't locate a creature of running water at least 10 feet wide blocks of path between us.
You didn't have to give him all the information. He'll be like, oh they went over a river.
I mean, it's a very big river. They're on a fjord.
Uh, yeah, there's no no river on this side that you're on here. Um, that's fine.
You definitely get a sense. Your your bloodhound dog hairs tingle.
And uh,
maybe you tell me what you do now that you you sense a direction or location of
this person.
Come come this way. I have found them
or at least an indication of which direction they are heading in. Let's let's go this way quickly.
Okay, handy trick.
Um, with this new
ability, um, I'm gonna say that you track within
You feel like you're getting very close. So it's been the better part of a day
whether you stopped for
Do I start seeing, um
Like sign of them again. Yeah. Yeah. Yes, you definitely once you once you cast the locate locate creature
Um, you got back on path. You see the the markings start to appear back up and the further you go the fresher they get
um, so you feel like you're within
about
And you know an hour or less of catching up to them
Um
The genus are as I said very
secretive so
We are getting close when we get
very close we should
Perhaps
I should
Just approach to explain
Who we are and I think they are great warriors as I said
They will probably know we are we are coming or they will know when we are near them
Um
Sounds reasonable
Yeah, I mean you've been here before you've met them before you take lead on this
As you've been traveling for a day, um
Yimbul and
How are Mannix's little legs doing does he need me to carry him on my shoulders?
Mannix still kind of seems like he's gliding. Right, right, right. He's got heelys on. Exactly
Are they light up heelys maybe they're below a rope you can't quite tell there's just there is an odd like
um
Under lit carriage thing happening. Yeah
so maybe
Um, but so he's got an odd undercarriage making a note dn flint make a constitution saving throw
Uh, this is like new heat that you're traveling in this. Oh nat 20. Oh, you're so robust
a six
Great constitution saving throw plus four
Ten
Okay
I'm hot and sweaty you are hot and sweaty and you suffer a level of exhaustion
The three of you Mannix and everybody and flint and thea
Thea you you rp the way you get rp with now that you're getting levels of exhaustion and stuff. Okay
Um yimbul you're going off to track down your friends
completely
Um, I guess yeah once we're pretty close
um
I think that would make sense. They are
You get to a point where you think that it's time to separate
And based off of your tracking, how many people do you expect to find here?
I'm not sure that I know because any group even if it was just like two of them
They would have been making those markings because that is how they
kind of
Find each other
Uh, okay, you head off. Um, the three of you stay behind. Um, as you see yimbul disappear through the trees
Uh, what do you three do to pass the time until she comes back?
Um, I sit down
And I lean against a tree
And I grab some fronds
From nearby
Bushy thingy and I start to fan myself
Is anybody else hot?
It's so hot
Uh, I head over and use the fan that thea gifted me
and add to the fanning
I mean, it's really hot here. You're so sweet. It's so hot. Well, how are you not hot?
No, I'm hot
but for some reason this armor seems like
Weirdly cool. You're wearing like four times more clothing than I am. Maybe it's the headband. I don't know what's going on, but maybe
Maybe
Yimbul you're tracking your your friends
um
Are you moving stealthily? Are you moving with intent to allow them?
You know if they were to hear you to know that you're coming. How are you? How are you traveling?
Are you singing some sort of ditty?
Not singing a ditty. Um
I don't think i'm being like trying to be stealthy or anything. Um, I think they are
Um
I don't think they're like afraid of people generally. Um
they just
Choose to remain isolated unless they are coming to fight for the good guys. So
um, I am assuming that once I go see them
I can like talk to them and even though I probably won't know the two that I am going to see
Or the however many that i'm going to see. Um, I can explain
That I spend time with them and blah blah. Okay, perfect. Uh, you head off and into the trees and after um,
About 10 or 15 minutes
um
Get to a point where you no longer see any
Of the markings not that you've lost them, but that they're just not there anymore
Hello
I feel like
You might be nearby
My name is yen bull. I spent time
With some of you
Two or three years ago
You you hear from behind you a branch crack
You turn and you see a a female genus our warrior
bearing the symbol
uh of tear
On a on an amulet around her neck
She has a bow loaded and aimed towards you
And says why are you following us?
This episode of Dumbgeons and Dragons is brought to you by hey, it's jelly entertainment
You can purchase their new novel the veiled monarch on amazon kindle and coming soon to audible.com
Or visit hey, it's jelly.com to get your copy today
Humans always tell me they think it's easier to be non-human
They don't know what it's like to be one of us how difficult it is to keep your head above water
You wouldn't happen to know anything about that would you falconer looked back over his shoulder not a clue
I believe you have a mole
Me
Vince flew at falconer grabbing his shirt collar. Yes. I'm angry. I love them
You love them too. Constance was like a sister to you. You call robert your nephew
Leo and I both struggled against falconer and brian our minds and emotions were in such a state that we didn't know what we were
Doing all we could think of was getting back inside that room and killing jacob stewart
dead brian, please
Get the veiled monarch on amazon kindle and coming soon to audible.com
Or visit hey, it's jelly.com to get your copy
And we're back in the middle again
Dun dun dun dun dun dun
See how i've let russ take this back again because he so desperately needed something like this in his life. I just
Thanks everybody. He really seemed like he was throwing off last time
I mean, I didn't say a single thing till the end. So really yeah, I was thrown off
sorry
Now is a crazy time and place that said
Uh where you might find yourself with a little bit of extra time
Some people have said
Um, we have another show if you haven't gone and listened to it yet
We thoroughly enjoy it everybody who has talked to us that has listened to us thoroughly enjoyed it
And that show is called facing fate
The whole first season's out so it's fully bingeable
You can listen to the whole thing. It is a little spooky warning. I didn't enjoy it too scary
Says the woman who was in it
Yeah, but it's very good. Yeah, it's excellent
Yeah, russ, uh, you know, we do a lot of patting ourselves on the back every now and then but you know
got a hats off to russ on this one because
Oh boy is it good. He took our shenanigans and turned it
into
Into something serious and kind of spooky right? Yeah, I don't know how I did it, but I did it
Um, so yeah first season of facing fate what facing fate is is our new show
But it's still an actual play we play different game systems. The first one is fake core
and we play a
Real world quote unquote, uh futuristic sci-fi on the moon
thriller genre
Uh that uh, we had a lot of fun playing scared carla
To the point of probably no sleep some nights. I had nightmares some nights when it left on like big cliffhangers and stuff
Sure, there was some good ones. Yeah
And we tell you this go listen to season one because we've got season two
Coming out in it starts in september, which seems like a long way away
But it's not going to be because for patrons over at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
They're going to be starting to hear those episodes that won't be publicly released until september
This month we're going to get our first like teaser episode
And then next month is going to be episode one and we're going to start to roll them out because we've started recording them
And we're super excited about season two. It's so different. It's so different. It's going to be real fun
We are playing the game urban shadows by magpie games for that season and it's uh based in like a 90s toronto
Setting which is a city in canada for those who don't know with with monsters who live in the real world kind of like a
I don't want to say a buffy the vampire feel but kind of like that
But where everyone's in but we're where everyone and no one at the same time are in on it's like a crime political
Thriller drama thing figure it out
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where we have goals that we want to reach as well
So when you join us, we're now we're just trying to
Build our community that we've got so our next goal is 45 patrons, which we're currently at 43
So that's a quick one if a couple people hop on
Then we've got that goal made goal reached and we will play a character swap episode
For our patrons come join us. We'd love to have you
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast come join our family
It's so nice over there
But now we'll get you back to this episode
Hopefully you're enjoying uh all the things that are happening over there all the crazy planning
That's happening forest walks. Uh, we'll talk to you all next week. Thanks everybody
Why are you following us
I come
seeking assistance from you
I spent time with
Jasim and some of the others
several years ago, and I know you are
very mighty warriors and you will
Perhaps help my friends and I
A male voice comes out from behind you and says
What is it you require
Shangalar has sent an undead army that has taken over calum port and the city is falling in it is
Is we need help to defeat him you wish to defeat shangalar you have an army yourself
They'll know I have just myself and three others
You wish to take on a lich
Which
That can control an undead army and take down the largest oldest city in the world
With you
And three others
Though I did not say
It would work, but we will try
also
two of them are are mighty warriors that have
Saved Faerun time and again, and now they are here and they will they will help us
Uh make a persuasion check
She like accidentally dropped our business card
Uh 13
You see the two
Uh, you kind of step back and you can see the two now they've moved in front of you
And they're looking to each other
That is a tall order to ask the man says
Yes, you are right the woman steps forward and says we
We wish
We had more to give you but going up against shangalar with six people would be suicide
Perhaps you could
Speak to more janice are and and and bring them we will we will start and you will come
Help us
The nearest settlement is
A day away
You are going at this with or without us yes, yes, I must
Defend my city
It's very noble stupid but noble
and
We will hurry
And hope that
You make it until we get back
Thank you
If you see just seem tell him yen bull is fighting
Um
Okay
Totally
You bet will do got it
Yen bull yen bull is fighting
Let me write that one down, I don't know if i'm gonna remember
Of course. Yes. We will tell jaseem that you are fighting the good fight
Right before they turn the woman speaks up and says I am zana
And this is massoud
We will do what we can to bring you aid
if
the janice our council
declines
You will not see us
I understand zana massoud. Thank you
They bow their heads
Yes
And they begin walking off in the direction where you were tracking them. Well, I want to zip back to my friends pretty quick
Where do we where do we come in with flint thea and um
Mannix my arms are real tired from i've i've lost the gossamer cape
I have like stripped down to like covering important bits, but i'm like gross sweaty
It's only been about an hour. Oh god, it feels like forever
How long have we been in this jungle when yen bull runs back up?
Well, uh, how did uh, how'd it go well they
I found two they will
Go to their gathering and ask more to come help, but they could not come now
So perhaps soon we will have reinforcements but for now
It might just be us
Did you say did you say really convincing things like
when he's done with
Callum port, he's probably coming here next, you know stuff like that the real light of fire
I think this guy's not gonna stop at like, you know, just one city
You are you are probably right he will overtake all of callum shan
You seem and did you tell them that did do they seem like they really want to help
Well, I don't i am not so good with words as you thea
Oh, okay. Now do we think that maybe it might be colder up on the giant floating pyramid. Oh
You are finding it too hot
It is very hot
Yeah, i've been fanning her like non-stop here. Your muscles look super great though flint flint make a constitution saving throw
Because of the muscles 18 before bonus
I was hoping that you'd get exhaustion just based on
I am so sorry. We traveled all this way and perhaps not even
found help but
I have a solution for how we can get back
To the base of the mountains near the pyramid
Without you getting more tired
Lay it on me sister. What do you got?
So I take off my backpack and there's like what looks like a bedroll rolled up on it and I unroll it
Just go to sleep
Okay, you guys gonna carry me and it is, uh
a beautiful like intricately woven carpet
And
I roll it out and it's it's quite big it ends up being you know, like
Four by six feet and uh, I say
It's here
And it floats up into the air
That is a hell of a trick this is so cool
Is this way you can save energy before we have to fight
Right
And great idea yanbo, thank you
um
This is a dia gets on and just lays down. This is a
Rude question, but how much do you weigh?
Y'all are fine. It's gonna be carry the four
Like a hundred
Like a hundred eleven pounds with all my stuff
It's just tiny I so tiny I way fish way fish. Yes, that's why I get fucking beat up all the goddamn time
This will be no problem
and I get up
on there with you and then
It like lowers a little bit so that Mannix can get up and flint can get up on there, too
But we can all ride on the magic carpet
I'm so excited. I mean
Mannix looks to you and says did you
Steal
One of these no, I would or are you paying out the ass for I did not it is not a rental
I did not rent it
On one of my journeys. I met a man in the desert and we had uh
How do you say a uh, uh bit uh
He oh you were gambling a little bit of gambling. Yes, and i've won it
Wow
I mean, that's awesome. Was it a dice game by any chance?
It was not it is a complicated game with many moving pieces
And there is dice and then words and you have to solve a puzzle to be honest. I didn't even really know how to play
Well, there's nothing at all sinister about
Winning a magical item from someone you don't know in a way that you don't really feel like you earned
Shall we
uh
Uh, do you fly through the trees or do you fly above the trees?
It doesn't say how high it can fly. I guess it depends. It's a magic carpet. It can fly
Um, then I guess wherever you want it, I guess above the trees
But maybe in like the top of the canopy so that we're not getting like thwacked by leaves
But um, we're not just like
Shake it off. What's up?
Sure coming for you
So now we should be probably twice as fast probably should have pulled this out earlier because now we go, uh
60 feet instead of 30 is our movement
Yeah, that's fine. So you make it back in half the time
No incident, I mean you see various different animals
But nothing that really makes a move to try and track you down as prey. What kind of animals? There's some uh monkeys
some
Jaguar-esque creatures
Smaller creatures that you see kind of scurrying around can't really get a good eye on because you're now flying up
Um, and you make it back to the location of which you started
It's like the base of the mountain. Yeah, yeah base of the mountain. You see the fortress up
Floating amidst the cloud now. We at least know how we're gonna
Get to the fortress
Manic says I don't think that guacamole could have carried us all up there at the same time
um, you
Magic carpet up
When russ closes the door, amy opens a carpet. I believe that's the saying
Carla opened the carpet. I don't know if I like that
Dear oh my
So, okay fair. So you're flying up with the intent. You were just in mexico, Carla
You're flying up with the intent to begin battle
One of you has a level of exhaustion. No, we're not flying. Wait. I don't think we said we were flying up there
I said we she said we had the means to fly up. No, I said now
We have a way to fly up there because I don't think guacamole could have flown us all up at the same time
Listen to the words that are coming out of my mouth. I don't think I thought we camped at the base of the mountain
Yeah, all right. I'm exhausted man. All right, you may camp at the base of the mountain
It's only in our other game that amy just shoots a guard without any play. Yes
No, I fia is much more like precious right now. Fair enough. Okay
Uh, you make camp at the base of the mountain kind of in in the in the forest line, and i'm no longer exhausted
um
uh
If you take a long rest, which is eight hours
Okay, but what she's an elf I was just gonna say what if I meditate for four? All right
Well, okay, I mean everybody else still has to sleep too. So if you're going full long rest
For everybody else sure if you're not
Everybody else gets exhausted
Let's
We're bringing exhaustion into this game. Okay. Why are we getting exhausted?
Oh because we've just been up because you if you don't sleep for yeah, I say we all have a nap
All right, uh you take
Proper rotation of keeping an eye on things. Yeah dibs first on sleeping first. Okay
Yeah, you make it through the night
With all this great planning
If you don't say you take a rotation I throw shit at you, of course we take rotation
What are we noobs? Yeah, you wake up the next morning all rested and refreshed
Manic says
So what is your plan?
Yes
What is our plan?
Oh my yes. Oh, what is our plan?
Yes, it's basically the we have a plan the not it
Okay, here it is. I'm just who's on first. I'm just gonna throw it out there
We
Go up
Okay, i'm with you so far and we present ourselves as um big fans
Of what mr. Lich is up to
Okay, I feel like this might not be but you know, i'm willing to hear it out big fans
You know
love is work
Uh seen some of it firsthand
Wondering if he needs, you know
some advisors or you know some like
some
Peeps to
Just tell him how great he is
Okay, i'm gonna throw another plan out there. Yes, please and you tell me if it's as ridiculous as yours
We're playing this game
Yeah, so we show up and we claim that we're
Follow up people from the amulet store and we realize that we sold him the wrong amulet
And we need to switch it out for the real amulet
Yours is more ridiculous in mind. I think
I don't feel like it is
Okay, manic speaks up and says funny people
You are walking into the iron fortress of shangalar
with multiple layers
Of battle
with undead
Okay, so here's what we do we fly to the top layer
There is no entrance
except by portal
Can you make one of those?
I know where one is which is why we are here
Yeah, but can you make it anywhere?
No
Oh, okay. There goes that one
Look I just wanted to say that I was joking with my plan before in case anyone thought it was serious
It's hard to tell sometimes with you funny people from another place
Fair maybe we try the sneaky route we sneaky sneak in
We quietly kill whoever we have to quietly kill
I mean, it's really easy to dispose of a body if you can like, you know throw it off of a
Like hovering yeah
I mean just throw it right off a flying pyramid, but we quietly make our way up to the top and um, you know
This so far is the best plan
I
Have never I mean it's not saying much, but you're right. I have never saved the world before
Okay, we usually do so very accidentally so I
I trust decimators of dragons to know the right thing to do
I feel we are unprepared
But they don't know how to get more prepared so that's kind of how we start all of our adventures very unprepared
You know
Okay, there's gonna be a five-headed dragon. Are we ready for this? No. Okay
Let's do this
Okay, so we portal on up there
Sneak around
Kill whoever needs killing
And then kill the lich. This is easy only four things
That's four step plan
Super concise plan
And and somewhere in there finding the amulet. Yes
Well, I assume he has it on his person
That would be easier than if he had it somewhere else
In his safe deposit box, it's the bank
Back in who's a funny person now
We're rubbing off on her I don't know whether or not to be happy or sad
All right. So I I think that is our best plan. Maybe we should
We don't we don't know you two very well in terms of
What you bring to a battle? I know what I can trust flint to do which is smash everything
um
but what
What would you say your strengths are?
I am
Not so strong
But I beg to differ but I
Am
Pretty good with the magic
And
I am good for
healing
When you are hurt
Very helpful awesome. Um
You sir mannex, how about you
I I know you do that hover thing. That's pretty cool. Thank you. Thank you
I
Well, how do you sum up being able to?
To
Destroy or bring back life
Walk between the ethereal
Thea gives flint a look
Skip between planes
Okay, and how is that applicable to what we can do but you can smash I can
Well, I'm not gonna don't worry what do you don't worry i've got i've got it covered
Look funny people
I've been dealing with this shit a long time. Oh, I broke them
I like that. He's just getting like all bets are off now
All i'm wondering is in the heat of battle walking between the ethereal and the material planes
Is great. Um
But is there anything specifically maybe that you can give us that would give us an edge or an advantage upon
entering sneaking
Coming face to face with a lich
Also, what's the best course of action when we are face to face with a lich don't be face to face with a lich
Oh, well, that's unhelpful. I feel like we're going to end up there
Yeah, if we don't end up face to face with a lich we've died somewhere between level like bottom and
Is the concern?
Don't worry. I can bring you back
And I can heal you before you go and have to be brought back
Okay, Mannix walks over to you thea
Ushers you to bend down
You want me to bend the knee no, i'm just kidding I crouched down don't be weird about it
Um he
Thanks carolyn
He puts his hand up
says
may I
I don't know. It depends where your hand is up near your face. Okay. Yes, you may put his hand up near your face
You just hand up my skirt my what puts his hand up near your face, okay?
It says you have some darkness in you
And places his hand on your cheek and temple
Closes his eyes
And yen bull and flint you see thea's eyes roll back in her head
Did he did he just kill her what happened here
Thea you are now in a dark place
Mannix is standing beside you
Wait dark like there's no light or like dark mineral dark place right dark like there's no light, but you feel like dread
pour down on top of you
You take a few steps and you hear splash splash splash
Where are we
You tell me how am I supposed to know
In a quick flash you see Nulara before you oh no, you're not real. You're not real. You're not real
Mannix snaps and you're back
I like push his hand away from my face
I will help you fix that after we stop this
And I just nod obviously really shaken and move myself away from Mannix
You
The intro song nowhere land is by Kavin mcleod of incompetech.filmmusic.io
All other music and sound effects can be found at epidemicsound.com
A huge thank you to our supporting producers christian brown creighton's raven devin michaels gabriel lynch jacob madden
joshua dixon cat water flame
and stevie
To find out more how you can support dumbs and the dragons visit Patreon.com
Slash dumb dragon cast
Thank you for listening. Have a great week
We'll talk soon
Before they turn the woman speaks up and says I am zana
And this is massoud
And we notice that you ask for our help but not for our names
Can we at least like sing the end of it
On a magic carpet ride
And then no more you'll be killed by liches
Because liches give stitches to you
Tom just pulled up scissors was like
Don't pull on me and then put them down. I was like
That's right
It's very confusing the adventure going on crafting projects going on over there. What are you cutting?
Well, he's not trying to find his way out of this mess I have forced us into
Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production