previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We've been robbed! We gotta get you out of here quick. I know a guy who can maybe give us a hand and then you hear the sound of soft footpaths land behind you.
You see a very lanky tabaxi. Welcome, seekers.
They were the ones who went all blasty face on those cult members.
They do not post the pictures up this high.
Yeah, it's not a good story. Glim here lit up a dude, but in all fairness, he wouldn't stop touching the donkey.
Glim, I'm not entirely sure on that one.
Well, remember you were hiding under the blankets.
For good reasons, in which we will talk about at a later time, not now in front of new friends.
No, we're not being very clear. What we are in need of is getting the heck out of here.
I can help you with that, yes. I am a disciple of the way of the rooftop.
You realize carrying all of this stuff is going to make it much more difficult.
Yeah, it's kind of part of the deal though.
A woman sent us through a portal and now we gotta get back to Proska so that we can give her this stuff so that we have fulfilled the promise that we made to her and so that nothing bad will happen to me.
Glim, like, start to rock yourself back and forth.
Silence.
Oh, like, she can't, oh, we can't hear anything. Okay, I'm mouthing this like an idiot then.
You tuck and roll just enough. You feel them connect with each other, but you don't feel like that smash that you would expect from these clay jugs.
And you see helmed guards and turns its body and begins marching down, pulling its long sword.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We're a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Russ More and with me today is Amy More.
There's a hesitation there. Who's it gonna be? It was me. I am Amy More and I play Sullivan Sleight, a light but halfling rogue.
And Carla Maxted.
That is me. I play Norixius Akra, better known as Glim, a dragonborn pAlydin.
And Tom Laird.
And I play Moot. He's a half-orc, wild magic sorcerer.
And joining us again this week, he spent all his key points. What will we do now? It's Keith Amann.
I am playing Floor is Lava, a tabaxi way of the rooftops monk.
Thank you so much for joining us again, Keith. We look forward to finding out what happens next here.
In this pickle that, I mean, you didn't get anybody into. You've, you've done really well.
He kept us out of so many pickles the whole last episode.
It was jar after jar of pickle.
I had to twist the world to get out of the pickles, which is what I had to do here.
The work you have to do.
Right?
Nobody thanks you for it.
Where you find all the other work that I do is over on Patreon. Patreon.com slash dumb dragoncast.
Actually, everybody else does more work than I do over there, I think.
Tom does a lot of that work.
Tom does. Tom does a lot more work over there.
Amy and I just freeloaders.
Oh, God. Yeah.
But what happens when you are a patron is you get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron, Megan Balding.
Thanks, Megan.
Thank you, Megan.
Thank you so much.
You're awesome.
You can find out more at Patreon.com slash dumb dragoncast. And now fuck it. Let's play D&D.
Moot and Floor is Lava. You see your two friends fall down to the ground.
You don't hear them.
It's silent.
But you hear footsteps further down outside of this range and you peek your head out the window and you see two helmed guards who have caught sight of Sully and Glim and are now walking down the street towards the two of you who have picked yourselves up and you're brushing yourselves off.
What do you do?
First of all, are they human?
Do they appear to be human?
They appear to be human.
They are in full plate male. They appear to be humanoid, but you can't see whether they are human or not.
So we don't know whether they have dark vision.
You do not know.
And are they just walking, as you said?
One was pulling his sword.
But they're not like running.
Nope, they are.
Because they didn't hear anything.
Calmly bad guy walking.
Oh, psycho serial killer walking.
Yeah, cool, cool, cool.
I get it.
What do we see around us?
Like, is there anywhere we can like...
Like a ladder? Like an escape?
A ladder or like something we can hide behind.
That would have...
I mean, a ladder would have helped last time.
Yeah.
There could be a ladder on a different building.
You see a door to get into what looks like a tailor's...
Is there a door?
Okay.
...across, which is where Moot and Floor's Lava are.
There's the door to get into the building that you just fell down.
And then there are alleyways a little further down on either side of this building.
I think we said about 25 feet.
I look at Moot and make a kind of a coiling rope gesture
and give him a questioning expression.
Is there what looks to be like a sturdy bolt of fabric that we're next to
that maybe we could like unroll and hang down over the edge
and they could like shimmy up?
Yeah, you're in a store room for like this tailor.
So there are spools of fabric and all over the place.
And what about in the alley?
Like is there trash cans?
Is it a clean alley or is there like trash cans and stuff?
It's a pretty clean alley.
The alleyways that you have been jumping over, there have been trash cans.
No big like dumpsters.
Not in the time of dumpsters right now.
But also side doors to most buildings from what you have seen jumping over buildings.
Can we just calmly walk to the door across from us and just turn the handle?
Yes.
That's what I was going to say.
Let's just try and go in the door.
He's going to serial killer walk.
I'm going to be so nonchAlydint and be like, uh.
It's locked.
I pick it.
I get out my thieves tools.
Roll for initiative then.
Oh, what?
Well, that's going to take longer.
He's walking down a street.
Slowly.
I'm so fast.
All right.
Everybody roll for initiative.
14.
Oh, sure.
Now she rolls a 14.
15.
I've got a 21.
Six for mood.
He's really working on that cloth plan.
He's like, he's busy.
He's braiding right now.
He's got like he's making a tensile of the fabrics.
Like, oh, can't use rayon.
That's just going to tear.
It's going to tear immediately.
Yeah.
You can't use natural cotton.
It's going to pill.
It's just not going to look good after a while.
OK.
So the scene, there's two helms walking towards you.
They are approximately 45 feet away from you, Sully and Glim.
Floorslava, you are up first.
I'm going to hide at the window, looking out, just observing what they're doing.
I guess I will need to take the hide action.
So that's what I'll do.
OK.
And that is a 22 stealth.
Yeah, you are absolutely hidden.
You can see perfectly everything.
You see two helms walking towards them.
You see Sully moving over to the door, giving it a spin, but still at the door
and then fumbling in his pockets for something.
Who says I fumble?
Going into his pockets gracefully.
Thank you.
Gracefully.
Is that all you would like to do?
Hang on.
Let me see about a bonus action.
Nope, I'm out of key.
So that's that.
Let me just check here real quick.
No.
Big ol' nope.
You're on your own, you guys.
All right, Glim, you're up.
It's just the two, right?
Just two.
So when you saw them as you were kind of brushing yourself off,
you saw a total of four, but only two have turned.
OK.
And they've continued to walk towards us.
How close are they now?
They haven't had a turn yet, so they're still 45 feet.
I'm just going to ready in action.
I'm not going to run for them.
I'm hoping my friend's still going to pick this lock behind us.
So I'm just going to ready in action an attack with my war pick.
OK.
Or when they get closer to me.
Within range.
I'm not going to run away from my friends to go murder some people.
Yeah, you only do that once in a city, right?
He touched my donkey.
How many times do we need to go over this?
Fair enough.
You do see.
So one has pulled his long sword.
The other one has a spear on his back.
And Sully, it's your turn.
I'm going to try to pick this lock like a boss.
Watch me go.
Do it.
16.
Wasn't quite as boss-like as I was.
How much would you say that sound is required for your lock picking?
Oh, no, it's a feel thing.
Totally.
It's just in my heart.
Like you can feel when you catch it on something.
Yeah.
It usually is, right?
Sure.
It's like those two little tools that you like monkey around.
It's not like safe cracking.
Yeah.
Sure.
Absolutely.
I'll give you that.
Yeah.
Your tools move in and you feel it catch and you give the knob a turn and you are able to open it.
I tap Glim, who's probably not looking at me.
She's probably ready.
I'm like, ooh, and I waver inside and I make little I did it dances.
Yeah.
We'll say that you're able to pull and that's kind of your action there.
You get inside the door, shut it behind you and the footsteps stop.
Range on that, sorry, was 20, 25 or 30 feet.
20 foot radius.
Oh, no, they're silent.
You hear the footsteps stop.
Yeah, that's not at all suspicious.
This is fine.
It's totally fine.
And then you see silhouetted outside the window of this door.
There are curtains drawn, the two imposing figures.
You feel the knob turn in your hand.
I do that thing that if any of you have siblings, you know you've done on the other side of the bathroom door.
And I for sure hold that.
And is there a deadbolt or anything?
Maybe like a little sliding chain lock.
A little.
I mean, did I did I go inside?
I said I said that Sully pulled you in as an action.
OK, I mean, then I'm going to help.
Obviously hold the door.
No, I like I like Sully holding the door against two armed guards.
Just going to watch the halfling do it.
I'm just standing there.
It's really about hand strength, which just it doesn't matter how big you are.
You've got a lot of dexterity.
So you probably do a lot of like, you know, this like.
Right, totally.
Yeah, with the squeezy thing.
We said door opens in.
So you're holding you're holding it.
So opposing strength check.
What did you get?
What do I have to beat?
18.
Oh, my God.
12.
Those jugs are really taking it out of me.
It's only an 11.
So you put up a good a good solid push.
But the door is like, you know, in cartoons, when you're being pushed by something, you're sliding backwards.
That's what we see is the door slides open silently.
And now it's a silent murder.
There nobody's going to hear a scream.
Keith, you done us dirty.
To which the second helm steps in behind, pointing his spear down at you.
You can't tell if he's trying to say anything, but he's going to make a stabbing motion towards Glim with his spear.
That's going to be a 20, not natural.
What happens with my ready to action?
I lost that when I went inside the door.
Oh, yeah, I pulled her in, but I assume maybe hopefully she's good.
Good to keep in track of things.
Yeah.
So he lowers his spear to you and he's within range.
OK.
So that is 21 to attack.
That will hit.
And that is 10 damage.
Did she kill him?
No.
He's made of tissue paper.
Oh, my God. It's actually tin foil.
Oh, that'd be fun.
You stab in like with your war pick and it crunches the plate armor and like this.
This energy like dust kind of poofs out around where you stab it, not blood.
Energy dust.
I scream. No one can hear me.
Don't breathe it in.
And I hold my shirt up.
And you stab in and they are going to, which I said they rolled a 20.
They are going to stab down at you with their spear.
And that's going to be four piercing damage.
Oh, my God. Does I have her hit points?
I hate getting into battles, baby characters.
As level two.
It's like we're just going to die.
You're up.
So you see your two friends duck in and then the door.
You assume that the door has opened because the guards have kind of pressed their way more or less out of sight.
There's still one standing out in the street, but you only see kind of the back.
Looking over, you kind of only see like the back leg of the second helm.
You going to come save us?
Save us.
Yeah, I guess.
You guess.
I don't know.
I'm up here in this cloth warehouse.
I'm pretty safe.
No, I'm just trying to I'm trying to parse what I want to do here.
Yeah, I guess I'll I'll kind of I guess I can run in behind because everything's silent.
So they won't know I'm coming from behind them, I suppose.
You're going to run out of the because you're on the second floor of this building.
You wouldn't be able to take some sort of stair or ladder or whatever connects the second floor to the bottom floor.
Okay.
Actually, they're completely separate unit.
Whoa, bold choice to crane everything out through the window.
Actually, the upper tenants, they have flying capabilities.
So yeah, so I will I'll head downstairs and from behind these two guys as they're like I'm picturing them kind of in the doorway.
But facing like away from where I'm coming from anyway.
Yes. Yeah, yeah.
They're both looking into the door towards Glim and Sully.
Okay, so I'm going to kind of go right up beside them almost.
And I'm going to cast Burning Hands, which is a level one spell, Russ.
So I'm going to have to roll on that wild magic surge table after this.
Yeah, you are.
But Thin Sheets of Flame will shoot forth from my outstretched fingertips and each creature in a 15 foot cone.
So I'm going to angle it so that my friends are not included in this cone.
I believe maybe we saw you come.
I backed up.
I'm fire resistant.
Light me up.
I just kind of took a couple steps backwards as I saw you with flaming hands coming towards them.
I do nothing.
I'm resistant.
I don't care.
Perfect.
Is that an auto hit?
Deck save.
I'm going to give disadvantage on and you'd be able to get both of them within that.
First one.
Oh, disadvantage for both of them.
So four and a nine.
Neither one saves.
So they're going to take 3d6 fire damage.
Here we go.
Yeah.
Come on, 18.
Five and six is 11 and two is 13.
And I suppose I need to roll some percentile dice for you.
Oh, my gosh.
Yeah.
So you're you're.
Yes.
Roll the percentile dice.
Like how scared he is.
He's like, oh, no.
That is a 40 and a zero.
So 50.
No.
40 and a zero.
Yeah.
So 40 and a 10.
Oh, yeah.
40 and a 10.
I don't know how the percentile dice work.
Wait.
40 and a zero would be 40.
That's what I thought.
Yeah.
Because you can't.
40 and a zero on the 10 was like the 10, though.
Isn't it?
Then you'd never be able to roll double zero.
Yeah.
That's true.
How do you roll 100 then?
You don't.
It's double zero to 99.
Yeah.
Well, there you go.
We're learning so much.
I always learn anytime we have someone on the.
I know.
It's always very educational for us.
Also, this is like the third time I've had to do this.
It's true.
Although this is a man who has literally written the two books.
So I mean, we have much to learn.
We differ.
So you release burning hands.
And what you see with the Helms is like their plate armor gets red hot.
And you see from within like this crumbling material come out of the one that looks
like it was.
You see Glim's Warpick stuck into this one.
And then it crumbles and falls.
And the other one falls to one knee as it takes this heat damage.
And with your Wild Magic Surge, you feel this warmth of energy kind of come over
you as you regain 2D10 hit points.
Oh, well, all right.
That's pleasant.
Which is, in theory, more hit points than I even have to work with.
I was going to say, are you even down any hit points?
You just feel really good about yourself.
All right.
Back to Flora's Lava.
The one that's still intact is the one outside or the one inside?
No, it would be the one inside.
The one who pushed it.
So I would not be able to see it then.
Yeah, you'd see like because it fell to one knee.
You'd be able to see like its foot and leg sticking out if you were to look over.
OK.
Well, I can hit that.
I am presumably unseen.
So I'm going to make a sling attack against it.
All right.
Sling to the foot's the new arrow to the knee.
And that is a that is a 23 to hit.
23 is going to hit.
Absolutely roll damage.
That is five damage.
Glim, Moot, and Sully, you see this.
You're slinging like rocks, I assume.
Or like little little sling bullets.
You see this bullet zip through the air and hit this foot.
And then its leg explodes and it's like this crumbling dust that falls out and the armor falls to the ground.
And I am amazed.
I hit one of these with my war pick.
Kind of hurt it.
This guy sling takes it out.
Amazing.
Glim is so impressed with Flora's Lava.
I go down and I I look at like what is the powder?
Does it seem?
Is there a residue?
Is it sand?
It looks like like earth clay, like dried like their golems.
I don't think these are real people.
You're still silent.
Talking is about the only good thing Sullivan's Sling does.
You're out of combat.
What do you what do you for do?
I think we need to go upstairs because we know Flora's Lava isn't going to come down to ground level and we want to like get going.
Make the little like walking with my fingers pointing up.
Yeah.
Moot leads you back up the way that he came.
And now you're all in the same room again.
OK.
I close the windows.
If there are shades I pull them.
I drop the silent spell and I say I assume you have left no trace of our movements downstairs.
You close the door lock it again.
Yeah.
Just just give me just give me one second.
I just I forgot something definitely incriminating down there.
Sullivan Slate sneaks downstairs closes the door.
Roll stealth.
What do you do with the armor?
I there was just a little foot outside the door.
I bend it.
There was also another helm outside the door.
No that happened inside the door.
No.
How what?
Well I I rolled a 22.
So at least I'm stealthily trying to pull these.
They're not filled with anything but dirt anymore.
So I'm going to try to pull them in quietly.
Yeah.
OK.
Twenty two.
You can absolutely get them back inside.
It takes you a little while.
Like I assume that the three upstairs are just kind of kicking around like looking down the street like oh god.
Why did we let him leave alone.
It takes you a while but you are able to clean up most of the mess that was made downstairs and then you come back up.
Probably a little winded because there's a lot of armor pieces.
I must rest here for a while before I can take you any further on.
Yeah me too.
That was like really hard.
You guys carried some jugs the whole time so I thought I had to do my part you know.
OK so we're taking a short rest.
Yes.
OK.
If anybody would like to regain hit points you can roll hit dice.
I think Glenn was the only one who was hit.
Yeah.
You get all of your key points back Keith or.
And I can because I'm brass I can get all all my hit points back.
I mean I'd only lost four but four is a lot when you're a level two.
That's right.
It is a lot.
Perfect.
Everybody is rested.
As you're as you're waiting you hear more footsteps of helms patrolling the streets.
You hear far off in the distance the sound of shoes voice.
It's got to be around this corner here sometime.
They can only have gone so far the city isn't.
That's pretty big.
But I mean you know they won't get past the guards at the gate for sure.
And you see more of those sentry gargoyles zipping through the air.
As your short rest concludes.
OK.
I will go to the window and wait for a gap in the in the sentry gargoyle activity.
And then when when there seems to be a break open the window quietly and scamper up to the roof and not casting pass without trace or anything at this moment.
Not yet.
I'm just trying to move quietly myself.
Do you articulate anything to your friends or you're just going up by your lonesome.
I will say wait here for a moment while I make sure everything is safe.
Give me an acrobatics check please.
That's a 16.
Yeah.
You climb out the window once you're you're fairly certain that the sentries have have cleared the area and you can make it up to the top in a pretty well hidden area.
Are you looking for anything in particular or just to just to make sure it's clear.
I'm just trying to stay hidden myself and I'm scanning the sky to see can I see any sentry gargoyles.
What are they doing.
You get up there and you do see them.
They are at this moment they've fallen into a formation where they're circling streets now.
Like you see two or three of them in tandem moving around streets and then moving down one group to the east.
The east is heading away from your area and then you catch just kind of a glint of another group that's coming from off to the west.
OK.
So we need to stay ahead of them basically.
Yeah.
I will climb back down report that to the group and say it is time we must go.
Now have we made it halfway to our destination.
Less than halfway.
I'd say you're halfway maybe a little bit more.
OK.
Absolutely.
That's some pretty good pretty good ground in that first one with the pass without trace there.
So yeah you're a little more than halfway of where you need to be.
We will do that one more time.
Another pass without trace.
And does anyone here have a rope.
Yeah.
OK.
Give it to me.
Both of our ropes are.
I only need one.
OK.
All right.
I will climb up to the roof lower it down so that so that they can climb up it.
Everybody's able to climb up.
No real danger based on floors lavas scouting ahead.
So you can all make it back up to the rooftop and proceed along as you desire.
And return the rope.
OK.
I will lead them toward the northern edge of the city then.
All right.
Everybody give me a stealth check.
Given given that the city is on high alert I am not going to lead them to the north gate.
I'm going to lead them to any place that is close enough to the north wall that they might be able to get over it without going through the gate.
OK.
Now I don't know if this is like a castle wall where they have people patrolling the battlements or anything like that.
But but we're going to try to circumvent the gate if we can.
Sure.
Yeah.
There are two main entrances.
But definitely you know I would say you that you know of an area off of that that you would maybe needs a little repair.
Yeah.
That you would you would use to get in and out if you so desired.
Well plus those walls are primarily built to keep people out.
Exactly.
Not to keep people from going out.
So that's what we're going to do.
And I did not make my stealth roll yet.
Let me do that.
That is a glorious with pass without trace 19.
Good thing for pass without a trace.
I know.
Yeah.
Thirty six.
Fuck.
Sixteen.
Which normally would be just a fine roll but somehow feels.
Twenty two for me Russ.
Listen this is all I have.
This is it.
OK.
The four of you begin hopping from rooftop to rooftop again following in this from what the three of you can tell like this haphazard pattern like it doesn't look like.
You can see now that you can see the gate or the wall of the city and you frequently turn away from it as you are being led into more of a spiral pattern in order to hop from the best rooftop to the next one.
That is the easiest.
You make it most of the way you you notice that you're you're gaining on the wall and you see the three of you see the gate that you came into the city on.
But it doesn't look like you are going in that direction.
We're here in the middle.
We sing all the time Keith.
It's just what we do.
Always an intro song.
Keith gets it.
Now can you can you spit us some hot rhymes.
Oh yeah.
Sometimes we try and do that and it is not good.
I know my limits.
It's good to know your limits.
That's the correct answer.
And we just keep trying to push through.
But this is the point where we come talk to you Keith because you have two books.
One is new that we want to tell everybody about where they can get it.
It's called Live to Tell the Tale.
New out.
Give us a little bit of why did you write this book and who is it for.
This book is for players mostly beginning and intermediate players.
Although advanced ones might be able to pick up a thing or two by going back to the fundamentals.
But mainly it is for players who want to increase the chances that their beloved immersive role play characters will survive what their DMs are throwing at them especially if those DMs have read my other book.
The Monsters Know What They're Doing Combat Tactics for DMs.
This is not a book about min-maxing.
It is a book about determining the best strategies for the character you have created however you've chosen to create that character.
So if you are an immersive role player or you just like doing wacky things with your characters there whatever you have whatever choices you have made in creating that character.
There is a way to optimize that character's chances of being effective in combat and surviving combat encounters.
And living to play out the terrific story arcs that you and your DM have planned for your characters.
I love it because both Tom and I have The Monsters Know What They're Doing.
And you know it it it's not that it makes it harder but it's good that everybody is kind of on the same playing field with having both of these together now.
I've started reading through it initially here and there's lots of great useful stuff that I'm sure Amy and Carla are going to go just.
Well someone who has lost one of their beloved characters.
I'm going to give this a cover to cover.
Someone who's seen a friend lose a beloved character.
I'm also going to avoid that.
Not do that again.
Although you know I did my best but still I'd like to not lose more.
I'm the one that loses all the characters.
I was reading Keith's older book earlier today because I'm DMing a session tomorrow that we're playing in.
And every time I DM I read about the monsters that I've picked to use in my adventure.
Every single time I learn something new and it's just awesome.
It's such a good resource.
I 10 out of 10 cannot recommend it enough.
Keith it's an awesome book.
Thank you.
And we've talked about the book.
Where can people find it?
Both The Monsters Know What They're Doing and Live to Tell the Tale are published by Saga Press which is a trade book publisher which means you can buy it at your local independent bookstore.
You can buy it from bookshop.org, from Barnes and Noble, Amazon, anywhere else you buy trade books.
But you know this pandemic has really hit local bookstores hard.
So if you've got one in your area do them a solid.
Do so.
We'll link all of Keith's information down in the description.
Thank you Keith again for joining us for these two episodes.
Tons of fun.
If this is the first episode the second episode is going to be more wild for you.
If this is the second episode thank you so much for joining us again Keith and we look forward to when we're able to sit down and play again in the future.
Thanks again for inviting me.
Thank you so much.
It was a real treat.
Alright we'll get you back to the episode now.
Have a great week.
We'll talk to you soon.
Hey how are we going out the gate?
It's like right over there.
The city is on high alert.
We are trying to avoid the gate, not go through it.
I am taking you to another point on the wall.
That sounds sound.
Yeah.
Good idea.
That's what I would have done if I was in charge of the sneak mission.
Trusting Flora's Lava now you pause when you need to pause.
You sense when the sentries are coming and you make your way to the closest building to the wall.
Now as far as making it to the wall it is a double wide street going around the perimeter.
Does the owner of the rope also happen to own a grappling hook?
I don't think that I do.
This character doesn't I don't think.
How about you Sully?
You're kind of sneaky.
Seems like something you'd be more likely to have.
You'd think I'd have a grappling hook.
I used to have a thousand ball bearings if anyone needed to know.
I do have a fairy tale book.
People just don't buy grappling hooks in 5E the way they used to.
I guess I just don't scale buildings or walls.
Long for the good old days.
Grappling hooks.
I got nothing.
So by a double wide street we're talking like 10 feet, 20 feet?
Probably closer to 20 feet.
Okay.
Is there a plan for where you want this rope to go?
Because I might have a little trick up my sleeve.
Tell us about this trick.
Well Flor I see this nifty cloak I'm wearing.
I have the ability to turn into a bat.
I totally forgot.
So if there's somewhere we need that rope to go I can maybe take it up there unbat myself and tie it up.
We need to find a way to make the rope taut between this building and the wall.
Can you do that?
Is there any place on the wall that he might be able to tie it off?
There would definitely be at the very least a flag pole.
But yeah there's ramparts or whatever they call it.
The up and downy parts.
The pointy parts up at the top.
That is to leg might or is to leg tight?
Exactly.
Yes there would be a spot.
If he were able to get it up top there, there would be a point where you could tie it off.
Now as a bat can he actually carry the weight of a rope?
That was going to be my other question.
What kind of bat are you?
Because some fruit bats are pretty big.
Like volleyball sized.
It just says I'm a bat.
What sports ball size would you say you are?
We talk in golf.
We do not need the bat to carry the rope.
He flies across as a bat then we throw the rope to him.
That's true because a bat has minus four strings.
But yeah he could just fly over and then we could check it.
Or we could like shoot an arrow at him.
He can catch it out of the air.
How are you feeling Lucky?
I feel great about that idea.
If only he was a monk.
Yeah I guess I can turn into a bat and head over there if that's the game plan for everyone.
This is going to blow my fucking mind.
Do it.
I can't wait to see it.
Are you naked when you're a bat?
We haven't seen you do it. Please do it.
Are you wearing clothes when you're a bat?
You know what? I'll find out soon enough.
Yeah I guess we're going to find out.
I've never done it before.
And maybe it won't even work.
Someone just told me that it will turn me into a bat.
Oh that's awesome.
Did this person seem honest?
Yeah she was a magic shopkeeper so I hope so.
You fixed a roof.
I sure did.
So I'm going to use this cloak and turn myself into a bat.
Okay so because we've never used this before I'm going to say that yes Bombera was honest in that it does do that.
He bought it with real money.
He bought it with real money and sweat labor.
So that's absolutely fine.
Does it not turn him back at the end?
I think that's the important question.
It's a 50% chance of staying bat for a long time.
Oh perfect.
I mean he's been sheep or goat for a long time.
I feel like that isn't in the D&D Beyond write up on this item but who knows.
Homebrew man.
That's how you explain everything.
Okay so because we've never done this before now explain how it works for moot.
Is it like Dracula poof?
Or is it like wild shape amorph into?
Well I use the action to cast polymorph on myself so I think it's just like it happens and I'm a bat.
Okay.
Can there be a poof though?
Like make it a little flashy.
Can you just yell Shazam.
Make sexy it up a little.
I'll give it the old razzle dazzle for you.
You're Richard Gearing it in Chicago.
I go bat now.
And as you poof I turn to Glam and I go.
Did he just say I go bat now?
I think that is what he said.
Maybe we can workshop it.
And as a bat I fly over to where we need me to be.
Now as a bat do you remember that you are moot?
I retain my intelligence wisdom in Christmas so I'm assuming that yes I do.
And he just flies the fuck off.
He's just gone.
Goodbye forever.
There's significantly less mosquitoes around though so I mean.
It's a win.
Okay yeah you fly over and as you fly up to the top you get a better view of what's up top here.
It is a walkway and from your location you see probably down about 60 feet.
There are torches lit along the outside.
You see 60 feet either way.
You see two large gargoyles seemingly motionless.
I avoid these gargoyles as best I can because of the little ones that we saw earlier.
So do you turn back there?
I guess.
Where am I going to be tying this rope to?
Because that's where I need to be.
Yeah all along there are points like larger columns that kind of stick up that you'd be able to get the rope around.
So you just have to pick your spot.
Probably the one directly across from where we are would be.
Yeah I mean one that seems like a pretty straight shot would be a good idea.
Okay unless you say otherwise you poof back into moot.
Do you say I'm moot now?
I don't think bats can talk.
It's more of a squeak.
Yes bats sound like flipper.
Perfect.
And you poof back and make a stealth check.
Make a bat poof check.
You've still got pass without trace going?
Yes.
We'll say it's just kind of on the.
Calculate the vector.
I've got to calculate A squared plus B squared.
We'll say it's just on the edge so you can still take your plus 10.
Fun fact about my cloak it gives me advantage on stealth checks as well.
Well you should know that.
Yep it always helps to know these things.
That's a 27.
Okay you turn back into moot and kind of crouch down.
The two gargoyles remain motionless as you do what you're going to do next.
Okay so how are we going to get the rope to him?
Is someone going to throw it?
Should we attach it to an arrow and like not actually shoot it at him but have it be like somewhere he can reach?
Like what's the play here?
I think throwing it is best.
It's only 20 feet right?
Yeah.
I'm just imagining what Amy would look like throwing a loop of rope 20 feet.
Graceful.
Doesn't go well.
I feel like we would tie a knot in the end so that there's like some bulk to it and then throw that rather than just like loose rope.
Well hold the loose end and throw the coil.
Okay I think you need to be really strong to do that.
Yeah what is this? Strength is what we'd be doing?
Flores lava is very long but not very wide around.
Much more dextrous than strong.
Yeah if it's strength then it's me I assume.
I'll hold your backpack Glim.
Yeah and then you fall over when I hand it to you.
Crushed me.
The jugs!
No!
They break.
We worked so hard.
It's over nothing.
That is 19.
This rope flies through the air towards you.
Make a dexterity check to grab it.
18.
And you snatch it out of the air and pull it down and you're able to get it tied off.
The three of you are able to find a spot to tie it when it is safe to do so.
And let's, for everybody going across, let's make a dex.
Sorry what are our height differentials here like between the building and the wall?
Are they the same or is one going up or one going down?
The wall is going up from the building so probably about 10 or 15 feet.
Oh god.
I was hoping it could be like I throw a piece of fabric I got from that tailor shop and I like woo wee.
No zip lining here.
I wanted the zip line down.
This feels like I'm tired just thinking about it.
Oh god.
Alright acrobatics or athletics and who's going first?
I have most of, well I guess I don't have most of the stuff.
That's not fair.
I have most of the big heavy, you know what?
I don't want to go first.
Let's see how good this rope strength is.
Let's send a small person.
That was a roller coaster ride.
I'll go first.
No it's okay.
I was like yeah no.
Oh thank god.
Sorry it's acrobatics?
24.
Or athletics.
Alright.
Sully you are able to get across.
Do you want to describe what you do?
Yeah I realize that it's not as difficult as I thought it would be based on my size
and I'm like doing like hand over hand and then I'm like swinging and I caught my feet
and then I've swung my body under word and I caught it with my hand
and I'm making a little bit of a show of it.
But not too much of a show of it.
Make a stealth check.
The description always gets you.
Well that was almost a 1 you guys but it wasn't.
It was a 7.
And a 7 is 14 plus 10.
Plus 10 stealth.
24.
Okay it's graceful and silent as the night.
That's right.
You get up to where Moot is.
You land softly down.
Both of you look towards the gargoyles again who still remain motionless.
I say you got room for one more under that cloak.
I mean I don't think I can use it again until tomorrow.
But sure.
I snuggle in.
That's cool.
That's sweet.
I guess I'm gonna go then.
Just so we know Floor are you going across with them or is this where you're parting ways?
No.
This is where I leave you.
Oh well Floor thank you.
Thank you so much.
I want to learn more about your way of the rooftop.
The rooftop you called it seems like a great path to follow.
I myself follow Baja Met.
If I had more time I would tell you all about him.
He's a really cool guy but I think I probably better go.
Wow took some self control.
I know I didn't start being evangelical until we said goodbye.
It's never happened before.
That is a 19.
I think I am not graceful.
I'm like workman like but I'm just trucking along.
There's a little more give to the rope as you're going across.
Sully and Moot and Floor's Lava you hear like the rope pull tight along the chimney that you might have.
Like some ship creaking.
Not the jugs.
Don't want to fall again.
The jugs.
And then as you get about halfway across there Floor's Lava you hear that same wings and whistle coming from behind.
As Glim is about halfway.
I hide.
It's the right thing to do.
Self preservation.
Moot and Sully you see Floor's Lava quickly duck behind the chimney that the rope is tied to.
One of these gargoyle sentries comes up to the street before where Glim is and stops and hovers there.
Glim doesn't see this.
No I'm just.
She's trucking along.
She's about three quarters of the way there now.
Trucking along.
Like the mime action that's happening over there.
Do the two of you do anything?
Can I ready an action?
What do you want?
What is your goal?
You were so close saying you can do whatever you want.
Then you knew that was a mistake.
Well I said I hide.
I actually meant that as an action unless I'm already considered hidden.
Yeah.
I'm going to ready an action.
Is it looking at us?
Yes I should take the action.
You need to be specific.
Sorry.
Yes you are hidden and yes you can take an action if you would like.
Okay.
I'm going to ready my sling.
If the sentry gargoyle seems to have noticed us and starts coming this way then I will attack.
Okay.
Not knowing that he's doing that Sully and Moot do you do anything?
Yeah I ready my short bow.
And I'm just like all sneaky just up over the edge.
Yeah that was my main question is has this thing seen us?
Like do we get the idea that it's aware of us?
It's facing your direction and is like flapping its wings.
It's stopped and is hovering and watching.
But it hasn't like made any like shrieking noises or anything like that too.
If it goes for Glimel.
You watch it and Glim you get just about to the wall and the three of you see this thing like enter a dive.
Going straight towards Glim which will trigger everybody's attack.
Starting with Flora's lava.
That's a 20.
A non natural.
Got all excited.
Yes that will hit.
Roll damage.
That is 8 damage.
Moot and Sully you see this thing enter a dive and as you're pulling your bow back.
You see one of these bullets shoot out and into and it explodes and dusts everywhere.
Like that baseball picture that one time that blew up that bird.
Oh yeah Randy Johnson.
I didn't know that that happened.
It was wild.
All of a sudden there's just feathers and you're like what just happened?
That's exactly what you see this gargoyle explodes.
Wait does it explode with the same dust or does it explode with like it's a gargoyle it was made out of rock.
It's a gargoyle it's made out of rock.
So yeah it explodes and then pebbles fall to the ground as Glim makes it back up and on top of the wall there.
From across the way you see Sully give you a thumbs up over the edge of the walkway.
How tall is the wall?
30 feet.
Great.
Well I guess I can't see floor anymore but I'm going to mime like untying the rope and then we can pull it across and then drop it down.
And that is exactly what I'm going to do.
Perfect.
Then we can pull it across and drop it down.
The ropes 50 feet long should be able to just rappel down that wall.
You feel the rope go loose and it swings down and you pull it up you tie it off.
The three of you make a stealth check.
We said you were still within just kind of perimeter.
Oh nanny 20.
Thank God.
Two.
Hold on.
21.
Two and nine.
19.
Okay you tie off to the other side and one two three you go over and scale down.
You leave the rope there.
But you come down and land into some brush and you see off towards the main road that cuts across the city you see helmed guards patrolling.
But you are able to make your way through the brush and you look back up to the wall and the location where you came down.
You see one of these large gargoyles come out of the night and land and crunch down on top of the pillar where you climb down and it's scanning the grass below.
But it doesn't appear to see you as you disappear into the night on your way back to Prosker.
And from the city of Cerlun you just hear faintly on the wind the sound of a pan flute playing a melody from a faraway land.
The song Long Road Ahead is by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
All other music and sound effects can be found at epidemicsound.com or boomlibrary.com.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers Christian Brown, Darylith, Devin Michaels, Gabriel Lynch, Jacob Madden, Jessica Babyok, Kat Waterflame, Mark Heartless and Stevie.
To find out more about how you can support Dumbgeons and Dragons visit us at Patreon.com slash dumdragoncast.
Where you can have exclusive access to 50 plus hours of bonus audio content, create in-game NPCs and items as well as play games with the cast.
Patreon.com slash dumdragoncast.
Have a great week and we'll talk soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.