previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
turn and begin to see this huge glowing aura coming directly from Boppa, who begins levitating
from his bed.
Well, I mean, that's new.
That's gotta be a good sign.
Yes, that must be good.
We should go.
We should go get that dragon lady.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Amy didn't like that.
I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More.
He, him also with me today is Amy More.
Duh.
It is me, Amy More, and I go by she, her, and I am playing a slew of characters
today.
I've got Sullivan Sleight, he, him.
I've got Thea, Mastasia, she, her, and a fun little bonus character I didn't know
I was going to be playing.
Nighthunter, she, her.
Let's do it.
And Karla Max did.
She, her, all of these gals also go by she, her.
We've got Yen Poldnuri.
We've got Anelia Strong, and we've got an Euryxia's Akra, better known as Glim.
And Tom Laird.
Yeah, that's me, he, him, and all of the characters I am playing also go by
he, him.
There's Lint, there's Telgir, there's Moot, there's probably one or two more.
Who knows?
They're all here.
Are you a janitor at some point?
Like cleaning up inside that first aid tent?
I mean, why not, right?
That's right.
Well, as far as we know, the janitor's still locked away, right?
So he's still locked in that cell because he bamboozled Yen Poldnuri.
He does not bamboozled, that's true.
Yeah, lots of things happening.
But you know where we don't bamboozle people?
No, yeah.
Where's that, Amy?
Over on Patreon.
Oh, yeah, we never bamboozle you.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon.
We're straight up with what we give you over there, which is a whole bunch of sweet bonus
content.
It's pretty serious.
Like the many, many episodes we have where you can find out all about Opal, who
apparently became king, Night Hunter, and Elia.
You know, sometimes you just have to write your own history, Tom.
And when you see your DM not not curbing into that, you just got to just take the
bull by the horns and make him king in your own timeline.
I mean, was I supposed to be making you king?
Anybody else wonder if, like, he's definitely, like, put a spell on everyone in that town
to make him think he's king?
I don't remember in his character backstory that his parents were the rulers of this area.
No, I don't remember that.
This is a different timeline, you know?
It's been a long time since we talked about that.
Who knows what's changed in a backstory, right?
I mean, characters evolve, their histories evolve.
Do their paths evolve?
I don't think that's right.
The history books?
Maybe while he was a king, his dad became the king.
And then when his dad passed, now he's the king, so it wasn't...
Sure.
I can see that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now, are we talking like a violent coup or is it just like order of success?
I really don't see...
We're getting too deep into the Opal backstory here, but I don't see Opal throwing a
violent coup.
No.
Like sending...
No, I meant Opal's dad.
Oh, sure.
In order to actually...
Because normally it is a pass down through family type of thing.
I guess we don't know Tabaxi culture.
But what happens...
Or how old Tabaxi's lived to, because maybe his dad had to wait that long for
grandpa to kick it and finally him for to become the king.
He lost seven of his nine lives by then.
Yeah, he had to wait for him to become the king there.
That's right.
To make this story short, when you are a patron at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
you get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Lindsay Bowen.
Lindsay, I tried to throw to you so many times.
It's true.
Someone said royalty and I was like, you know who else is royalty?
And then everyone talked over me.
Lindsay, you're royalty.
That's right.
You are.
Agreed.
Lindsay, you're royalty.
Thanks, Lindsay.
Is actually also playing with us in the games that are running in the other episodes.
So thanks, Lindsay, for being here with us and hanging out on Patreon.com slash dumb
dragon cast.
Come join us over there.
Okay, bye.
No, not bye.
This is the beginning of the episode.
What are you doing?
Don't say goodbye.
Russ has this manic opal knot of stress inside of him.
He should not be elected to DM when he's playing that character.
He is turning into player Russ, which is very chaotic and dangerous for DM Russ.
Get it together right now.
We'll talk about this in the downtime, but this is an anchor point where maybe a little
chaos is needed.
Fuck it, let's play.
Fuck it.
Let's play.
Scared.
I'm Batman.
This is unsettling.
Not Batman.
You're Batman.
Okay, I'm Batman.
A well adorned temple is before us, built with steel and stone structures, gold ribboned
through everything as Flint and Bort push open large doors that echo through this sparse
chamber and take a few footsteps inside.
Up at the altar, Flint, you immediately notice the cleric who ran service for you when
you were growing up.
Father Murren.
Yeah.
Got a little situation here.
He sits up from a pew where he's having a nap.
All right, that's what we're doing.
Huh?
Oh, hey, hey, Flint.
Oh, sorry to wake you.
No, that's okay.
I was sleeping, sitting up.
You know how us and the god business got to do it.
We got to just sleep when we can.
Take it when you can get it.
Right.
It's tough to tell if it's day or night down here under the ground, too.
So what can I do for you?
It's a golden hour, so you're right in between.
Who's your friend?
Well, this here is, well, his name's Bort.
Hi.
Turns out he's, we're sharing a body.
Well, it doesn't look like you're, I see both of you.
It doesn't look like you're sharing a body.
Okay.
How to say this?
Yeah.
Without sounding like you don't, maybe, maybe how we say without sounding like there's
a couple.
You're a man of faith and belief that souls and spirits.
Yes.
So what if there were two spirits or souls that were trying to inhabit the same vessel?
Well, that would be very problematic for one or both of them.
How would somebody go about and separate the two of them?
Well, there's rituals that could be performed to transfer one soul into another vessel,
be it a recently deceased vessel or an actual container of sorts.
But again, this doesn't look like an issue that is bound by you.
It's like, I have a friend who is dealing with this kind of thing that we need to
talk about, Flint.
Yeah.
Yeah, I've got a friend that's dealing with this thing.
Okay.
Well, it's, you require someone of divine power.
Oh, that's why I came to you with this question.
Of course.
It's not something I've ever done or witnessed, but it is something that I have read where
the two souls themselves, depending on how long they've been for, can be salvaged.
But if it's been a while, they tend to merge.
We'll just estimate and say like 11, 12 years.
That seems like longer than anything I have ever read.
Okay.
So like seven years?
Is that more along the speed?
It is believed that after a point, it's tough to say because souls are, there's
There's no precise way to determine how a soul merges with another one.
But after a set point, those two souls begin to merge and their worlds become one.
Okay.
So let's say that they have done this merge and the worlds have become one.
Is there any way to separate them then or is it like too late for that?
Well, with the right person, with the right reason, and a ritual that is performed to
perfection, it could be possible to separate them.
your eye as you're talking to Father Murren, you see a lush, rich forest come into view.
You turn to look at it, it's like there's this tear in the wall.
A bird flies out past you, Bort sees it and looks as it moves past, and as you
follow this bird and it lands on a sculpture on the other side of the room, you look back
and the forest is gone.
Is the bird still there?
Yes.
Does Father Murren also see the bird?
No.
Okay, so for the ritual, we need another, or my friend would need a secondary vessel
for the souls to be split into.
Yes.
Well, yes, somewhere for the soul to go unless the soul wishes to pass to their
great beyond.
And kind of give like a little look and a slight turn of the head towards Bort, like
maybe this is something you're into?
Bort shoots eyes and like just like, it's just like a hard line across the neck to
say nope.
Okay, what kind of, this might be a dumb question, but what kind of vessel?
Where does one just find an empty vessel?
When a person dies through natural causes, that could be a way.
I'm not saying it's the only way, but this is where it gets gray.
How do you pick a vessel?
I think you and your background, you know how you can find a vessel.
Okay, now this might be a little bit beyond your know-how.
Is there a, I don't want to say specialty cleric because I don't think that's the
right term, but is there a specialty cleric who deals in this kind of thing?
There are tomes on it and many, myself included, have read on it.
I mean, gods have the power to do a lot of things, but who has access to a god, right?
It's a great question.
Certainly not me.
Then you would need someone who is close, who has been studying and exploring their
divine following for quite some time.
Their closeness to their god is or could bridge that gap.
Okay, so Hail Mary pass for a god himself or herself or just someone who's like real
tight with one of them.
Yes, I mean, if this is something you're interested in, Flint, I mean, you fell asleep
so many times in service that I didn't, these are questions that are somewhat out
of the blue for me, but I mean, was this covered in the services?
Because I feel like this would have kept my interest pretty good.
No, to be, no, and not not directly, and maybe that's that's my bad.
I will review my sermons and see if we can't liven them up.
But with that, if this is something you're interested in, I could I could show you
the tomes and see if there's anything that you can glean from them yourself
and help your friend.
I mean, I'd love to have a look.
He beckons you and you follow him down a spiral staircase.
He's walking a few paces faster than you.
Can I just push board down the stairs?
Try no, that's your your character.
You can do what you want to do, Tom.
I won't stop you.
I brought my own character and you do what I wanted.
The camera pans down.
You see Flint's leg kick out.
Whoops.
You follow down these stairs and Father Mern is getting is moving faster and
faster and quickly moving down these stairs.
And as you are moving and following him and trying to keep up with him, the
the steps, like the echo that was happening softens and you begin to hear
the sound of wildlife and trees and breeze blowing through.
And you get to the bottom of these stairs and it opens into this lush green
forest, board steps down behind you.
And he turns and looks at you and says, are you seeing what I'm seeing?
Man, we're this close to getting some answers and I don't know what to do now.
We cut back to the medical tent and standing outside of the tent as we pan
into view are Opal and Sully, who are just kind of kicking the dirt outside.
What are you out here for?
Well, I mean, I'm in charge of this whole place, but they don't let me near
things of great importance.
So you're the king, but you're not allowed to do anything important?
Not when it comes down to, I'm not really the most helpful when it comes
to dead bodies and blood just kind of makes me feel weak in the knees.
Oh, they don't keep dead bodies in there?
No, it's like the, it's like the first aid tent.
It's like people trying to get better.
Oh, oh, that's why they didn't let you in there.
Okay.
We move inside and Bahamut is levitating in the center of the room, this
brilliant illuminating aura coming off of him and everybody is in this room.
Except for Sully and Opal, we've already established they're out.
Everybody else is in this room.
I feel like Flamingons is definitely crisscross applesauce on top of Grantz's bed.
Hey, hey, hey, how long has he been doing this?
And Moot is just pinching Glim with his crab claw on the arm.
No, keep doing it.
Glim, are you seeing this?
I keep pinching because I feel like I'm going to wake up.
I can't believe I thought he was gone and then I thought maybe he would
just be unconscious forever and now he's glowing and floating.
And like, I don't know if you remember, because I don't really talk about
him so much anymore, but that is like totally on brand for him
because it's so awesome.
I mean, it's pretty amazing.
I am just going to keep pinching you though.
Yeah, please do because it's reassuring that I'm not
waking up as you pinch me.
Elia, so who is Shiny Guy?
I'm not really sure, but I mean, it is pretty amazing.
It's very impressive.
I mean, I can't deny the spectacle of it.
I'm not sure.
Opal, just be so mad he's not here.
He's going to be so mad.
He's missing all of this.
Turn around and Opal's head is peeking through just big eyes.
I make that tssst.
Ah!
No, he makes a cat.
It's getting out of there.
You know the one.
Yeah, no, it's nothing in there you want to see.
It's totally fine.
I'm just going to sit here.
Like, I can see the shiny light coming out from underneath the...
I know, right?
Listen, I'm only out here babysitting you, so it's fine.
I'll get filled in later.
You're babysitting me?
We flash back to Inside the Dead.
A moment goes by and it's like stunned silence.
Everyone who is slightly injured, not unconscious, begins to stir in their
beds, like they are being healed.
They unwrap bandages and cuts go away.
Bruises and broken bones seem to heal themselves.
Yenbl, are you seeing this?
I...
It's unbelievable.
Look at this, this man over here.
He had a huge cut on his head and now it's disappearing.
And the corporeal form of Bahamut begins to float down and right itself
at the side of his bed.
He's seated there, the aura beginning to fade.
He opens his eyes slowly and he looks around at everybody and stops on Glim,
who's...
Doing Zumba?
Still getting pinched.
All right.
Glim, oh my God, oh my God, oh my God, oh my God, Glim, oh my God, oh my God.
Are you okay?
What can we do for you?
You're here.
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
I'm fine.
It's nice of you all to break me out of there, hey?
Well, it wasn't easy.
The world's kind of, I mean, things are pretty bad.
Yeah.
Sorry, is anybody allowed to talk to the God or is it just her or I
don't know how to do this.
Yeah, no, it's chill in here.
Oh my God, I was whispering that to Yenbl.
Your hearing's amazing.
Hello, hello, God, it is, it is nice to have you with us.
Yes, just do a once around here, Bahamut, got all your names all ready.
Oh, wow.
That's convenient.
It's nice that you're all here.
You were in different organizations, I guess, when I last saw you, but that's
all right, we'll sort it out later.
What, what are we, where, where are we at?
I mean, like literally or existentially or.
In the, in the, in the stream of, in the stream of life.
Oh, um, I mean, there's not a lot of life left in the world, just a
lot of orcas followers.
Right.
A lot of death.
Yeah.
A lot of zombie things happening.
We got anything to drink?
Oh, let me get you a glass of water.
Of course.
Oh, no, no, no.
Oh, something to drink.
Something to drink.
Of course.
All right.
She comes back with a Fanta.
Welcome to the middle.
The middle, the middle.
It's where we talk about things.
Stuff and things and stuff and stuff.
And it's Christmas time.
You Fox.
Hey, I mean, I mean, I think maybe just the repeat song would
be maybe better preferable at this point.
I mean, is this just a cute pet name for our listeners now?
What's up?
Fuckers.
I think I'm comfortable.
I just started sweating all flesh.
She's like, take it back.
I love you guys.
I don't I don't like it.
I mean, it is kind of funny, though.
It is a little bit funny.
Especially while I'm over here being like, what's up, fuckers?
Yes.
Carla's left the room.
She's like, I can't do this anymore.
Not the podcast.
I mean, I think about it.
And if Amy said that to me, then I would like it.
So I think it's probably fine.
We apologize if we've offended you.
Oh, no, I don't.
No, you know, you know, you know what you got into in here.
The obligatory.
And if that's what got you.
Yeah, this is your first time listening.
And then if that's the case, you've got to go way back.
Go way back.
And you know that it's all in love.
This middle is all about just saying how next week
we're doing a sweet crossover with our good friends from Dum Dums and Dragons,
which we've played by now.
And it was just a riotous good time.
So funny and fun and awesome and like that thing happened.
Yeah, I got a little confusing with the with the multi Tom.
Well, there was actually a confusing bit about the other guy named Tom,
because I looked in my calendar on Saturday morning
and there was a thing that was like seven a.m.
Russ and Tom discuss crossover.
And I was like, what in the fuck is this?
It's like eight thirty.
I'm like, well, I missed it.
Oh, no, I was like, I don't know when this got added to the calendar,
but I missed it.
And he's like, no other Tom.
I'm like, OK, perfect.
Don't worry.
And then he was like, other Tom.
Hold on a minute.
Who is this person?
If there's another time I could show up to my meetings, that would be great.
That would be ideal.
So that's coming up next week.
And it's going to be great.
We hope you listen to it.
It's another two parter one episode on their feed, one episode on our feed.
We would love for you to check them both out.
Hoo boy.
Lots of good jingle bells happening in this one.
Let me just tell you.
Jingles and jangles.
Yeah.
Amy's just been staring at Russ the whole time
since he said, oh, boy.
But like in Russ's voice, not in Grant's voice.
And it's like, are they merging?
And then he said, like, there's lots of jingle,
but like he's using it as like a noun and an adjective at the same time.
And I'm like, jingle bells.
I don't see what the problem is here.
No problem.
Look forward to that.
Go subscribe to Dum Dums and Dragons as well to make sure you get,
you know, that feed.
So that's coming out next week.
And then we're off for a whole week, everybody.
Bizard.
One week.
And then we're back at it.
It's the week we take to rest our voices.
We don't speak for an entire week.
Just save it all up.
We're going to a silent yoga retreat.
That's right.
I'm going to a yogurt retreat, so.
Oh, did I misread the invitation?
Yeah.
It's just all Denon all the time.
Not a sponsor.
Not a sponsor, but Denon, if you're listening.
Will there be Gogurt?
Yeah, we hope so.
I don't know where to go from Gogurt.
Me neither.
Yogurt.
No one ever does.
All right.
Thanks, everybody.
Have a great Christmas, holidays and New Year's.
And we hope to see you again on our next episode.
OK, bye.
Love you. Bye.
So I got to lead this thing, I guess.
Well, I mean,
no one else knows what to do or even where to start.
Yes, if you could offer.
Guidance or.
Inside, they're all very willing to do the work,
but you have to maybe point us in the direction.
We can even start small, like how do we wake these two up?
They haven't started glowing and hovering like you did.
Well, they probably won't.
I don't think they're gods.
This one might think he is nailed it.
Well, we all know who he's pointing to.
Oh, yeah.
Well, let's see here.
He walks over, gets stands up slowly, walks over between the two,
holding his Fanta in one hand.
Not a sponsor, but they could be stands between the two of them
and holds his hand out over Flint.
This light comes from his hand.
Shines down on Flint, but nothing, nothing happens.
This one's not quite ready yet.
Ready, meaning like, like it will happen.
Five more minutes in the oven.
Well, he's he's a key player, so it's going to have to happen.
We're going to have to figure that out.
He holds his hand out over Grancis, same glowing light.
And as Grancis begins to stir.
Of course, this this one, this one, he was ready.
He was just.
He's seen some things.
He's actually been awake this whole time.
He's been just been enjoying the sponge baths.
I don't.
Grancis begins to stir and he opens his eyes.
Slowly begins to prop himself up.
Oh, oh, oh, goodness.
Oh, well, it's you've done some nice things with the with the sewer there, Leosan.
Thea, Thea.
Hey, hey, hey, whoa, hey.
Whoa, oh, boy, come on over here.
Hey, hey, you're pretty cool.
Bonama just nods his head and backs off to give Thea space to take
a couple of steps forward.
Oh, yeah, she goes to his bedside.
Hey, hey, so.
When were you going to come and get me?
Oh, you know what?
Lots of irons in the fire and you were one of them, my friend.
Oh, wow.
Look, Flint's still over there.
God couldn't even wake him up.
We've had our hands full.
I tried to I was like in a ghostly plane at one point and I saw you and I was like,
Hey, Thea, Flint, but you didn't do anything.
Well, new law.
Where's new law?
Well.
Oh, lots changed.
We cut out to a scene in the center of town and Glim particularly is following
very close to Bahamut.
Who else do we think would want to be?
I know everybody would want to be, but if we were to pick three particular
people, who do you think would want to be talking to Bahamut first?
Opal.
All right, sir.
And I get to talk to the God.
You're technically my God.
You're on my property.
Squatter's rights.
Possession is nine times the law.
I mean, I think Mute would go with Glim for sure.
They've been hearing about this guy for a long time.
Yeah, see what all the hubbub's about.
Yeah, Mute, Glim, and Sully.
You're at like a campfire that's just at the center of town.
There's lots of people milling about.
You three have Bahamut's attention at the moment.
It's good to see you've been hanging on to that book there.
Some people might have given that up a while ago.
Well, I mean.
Oh, well, she never wavered.
Not one minute.
Yeah, she's all like, I'm not going to give him up
and I'm not going to let him down.
Yeah, not going to run around and desert him.
Not a chance. Yeah.
I mean, I wish that was true.
Glim. He knows he's Bahamut.
I can't. He knows the truth.
I held on longer than reason dictated.
And then my friend got hurt.
And I realized that was it.
She held on so long, sir.
You did. I lost my eye.
You did.
So he's like, I want to be a part of the conversation.
Look, I'm I'm sorry you lost your eye and.
Your hand.
Well, I mean, that that wasn't your fault.
Or was it your fault?
I don't think it was your fault.
No, no, I don't think it was my fault.
No, I wasn't here.
I was in I was in a prison cell.
That thing that gave me my new hand.
He didn't seem to know anything about you when I asked him.
Well, you're dealing in some different things, aren't you?
I mean, it was either that or stay there forever.
So I think I made the right choice.
Yeah, we'll sort that out.
I know that it might come in handy.
Let's just put it that way.
I mean, it already has with all you guys too soon being gone.
Like I was able to actually use some magic and and help out the team.
And Glim, I know that you wavered.
I mean, I still loved you in my heart, but I just couldn't.
I couldn't dedicate myself to you once it was actively causing harm.
I mean, a loving God is about love, not about hurting people.
So but you're back and you're here.
And now all we have to do is find the other gods, bring them here.
And save the world.
That would be a way to do it.
A lot of the gods are.
Are gone already, though.
But like not not all of them, though, right?
No, no.
He takes a big drink of Fanta, not a sponsor.
No, not not all of them.
I mean, there's a few that pass through the cell and came and went and.
I get the I get the feeling that there's there's quite a few more.
Places judging by the state of the state, the world that right now.
That there's more of those facilities and more gods passing through the
through them.
Yeah, it's an insensitive term, but passing through the meat grinder.
Oh, boy.
Oh, jeez.
Well, you know, work is he deals in
the intricacies of.
It's an accurate term.
It just. Yeah.
Out of curiosity.
What happens to all the ones that we left behind,
like the group that rescued you?
They. They left some behind.
Are they going through that?
Grinder.
He probably eventually,
I mean, the cells themselves drain the energy back to.
The abyss, I presume, is where Orcus is, he siphons their power
and then when they are weak enough, he consumes them.
Oh, boy.
What a dick.
Yeah, I would think it would go without saying at this point,
but fuck that guy, am I right?
I mean, yeah.
Oh, my glam.
She's the wait.
I love it when she swears.
So, I mean, I hate you just woke up
and now we're all like, hey, can you solve all of our problems for us?
But do you have any idea of how to solve all these problems?
Well, yeah, I've got some.
I don't see everybody here who we need.
I mean, there's the there's the one who's still dealing
with some internal turmoil right now.
We'll have to wake him up.
And then there's some others that we'll have to find.
But, I mean, more importantly, there are a few places we need to send you.
All of which give us more time.
OK, well, where do we go?
What do we do?
Some some of you and he just kind of waves his hand to
the the general vicinity where people are looking around
corners at the god in the center of their town.
Some of you will need to come back and tell me.
In Celestia, before it's taken, that this is happening.
It will happen.
So so I tell you what and tell you.
Go. Back in through time.
Oh, OK, yeah, yeah, naturally, like one does.
Well, you have the soul bridge jam, right?
Uh, yeah, yeah, so we just need to go back in time,
go to Celestia and warn you that Orcus is coming and then.
Yeah, yeah, and then just like a watch out.
Well, that's part of it.
That's that's part one of what we call Bahamut's four pronged.
Oh, wait, Sully, is your plan to just hide in the shadows
until he walks by and then jump out with this warning?
Well, I mean, no problem.
Maybe I'm not sure. I haven't really thought it out yet. OK.
That's one part.
We don't we don't necessarily that's not necessarily the first part.
But once we have all the pieces in play, that's a major part.
And sorry, it was Bahamut's four pronged plan.
Four pronged plan.
There's four prongs.
I probably should have put this one closer to the end, but that's OK.
We're here now.
So it's Bahamut's four non sequential pronged plan in no particular order.
OK. Another prong of Bahamut's
is, yeah, he's referring to himself in the third person.
He's a god. He can do it.
Another prong for Bahamut's four pronged plan is bringing your
not not your, but bringing the sexy back.
Sexy back.
Is that what he's called?
Flint, I think, is his name, but we can bring sexy back.
Yeah, I mean, he's got that deep V going on there.
That Hawaiian shirt. Yeah, sure.
Yeah, no. So we need to.
OK, so we got to warn you.
We got to bring sexy back.
He's key.
We've got to.
You may have already done it, maybe.
Recruit. Orcas's right and left hand.
Recruit meaning bring to our side, the little one and the Dragonborn.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, them.
OK, I feel like that's going to be tough.
Yeah, because they are just like really team orcas right now.
Yeah, well, I mean, once one of them goes, maybe the other one will go.
Maybe it's just one of them that we need.
Which one? I don't know.
You told me, well, I mean,
you told me that that's what happened,
is that you recruited them.
So I presume that you recruited.
What? Oh, because we've already.
Back in time and told me all of this.
Yeah, OK, so sorry.
But you still ended up in jail.
Yeah. So I won and meant nothing.
And did we not do it right the first time?
Was the hiding in the shadows the better plan?
And we screwed it up.
Well, no, see, there's this thing about time is it's a construct
and continuously moves forward in its own way.
So what happens is you come back and warn me and.
We're getting to the fourth prong, because we've got so far worn Bahama.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, we've got wake up sexy.
We've got recruit left and right hands.
Yeah, left and right hand and go to the abyss.
Oh, OK, now hold on.
Now it seems like sequence.
It seems like the sequence of these.
I understand that to you, probably time is all happening at once.
And it's not linear, but for us it is.
So the sequence of the plan is sort of important.
Yeah, totally.
And when we're in the abyss, what are we doing?
Yeah, which one do we go to the abyss first?
Stopping, well, killing Orcas.
Oh, OK, OK.
What's the only place you can actually do it
is in his home plane of the abyss.
That's new information.
That's good to know.
But also you're going back to before he takes over
all of the gods before he's all powerful and stuff.
OK, so first go back one year.
OK, that seems like the first step.
Yeah. Kill Orcas.
Yeah, OK. No, no, no.
Yeah, I think recruit second.
The hands and then kill Orcas and then wake sexy up.
No, I well, what is he going to kill Orcas?
Because I think that maybe that matters, too.
He didn't come see me.
So I presume that maybe he went somewhere else.
Oh, so these it is non-sequential
because different people are doing.
We've been sort of on this whole like our own program
where like we're doing our thing, you know, for so long.
We don't have to do all these things.
No, well, I think you use the whole group.
Right. I mean, we have we have you three.
We've got four others and then some others over there.
There's a lot of there's a lot of irons in the fire.
How many how many of us are working on this right now?
Or is that just going to destroy my mind?
That's not even going. Oh, shit.
Because what's going to happen?
Is you're going to go back in time.
And time. Changes. Right.
These people here.
Probably won't see that change.
So they're like doomed to this timeline.
If you go back and make a change.
It doesn't necessarily stop what's already happening.
It creates a new, happier timeline, hopefully.
Well, that part sounds good.
And also, like, it couldn't be much worse. Yeah.
I suppose just creating a new reality is just as good as fixing this one.
Or maybe it fixes it.
Well, you just said it. Oh, I've had a lot of Fanta.
OK, so do we talk to everybody else about this?
Are you going to have your own little side one on ones with everybody?
They're going to are we are we team captains?
They're like a town hall style meeting that we have.
And everybody sort of volunteers for particular duties.
Not the council. Right. Like.
Well, I mean, he's is he not in charge?
As soon as we walked out, he yelled, I'm the one in charge. So.
Yeah, he's been saying that a lot.
I think that's just like his go to catchphrase.
It's a neat behind that fountain over there.
I think he's been following us the whole time.
We'll give him a job.
It'll keep him busy.
That's probably for the best.
I guess it's probably a good idea to have a council meeting and.
Without me telling you who needs to go where,
you need to figure out who wants to go where.
Because if you tell us, it'll be a wrinkle in time
and it won't work out right. Possibly.
Now, I think I get this whole time.
Now you got it. All right.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season two, episode one hundred six,
starring Amy More as Thea Amastasia and Sullivan Sleight,
Carla Maxted as Yenbul Nury and Glim, Tom Laird as Tulgear Heavyfoot,
Flint Firebeard and Moot, and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Editing, production and sound design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and sound effects
from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
A huge thank you to our supporters,
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
To support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many other productions
and get access to an exclusive podcast called The Adventures Of,
bonus episodes and much more, please join our Patreon at
Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast.
You can also follow us at Facebook dot com slash Dumb Dragon Podcast
and on Instagram and Twitter at Dumb Dragon Cast.
Thank you for listening.
Have a great week. We'll talk again soon.
This is the part where just where Russ just breathes into your ears.
As Russ coming back, he knows that Amy was right.
So he's trying to like bring himself back into his body
and stop being player Russ. I mean, he'll never say it out loud.
Yeah. I don't know what you're talking about.
We know that's what that sigh meant.
And Tom and I knew it.
I knew one else singing to become one by Spice Girls in their head.
I am now the whole time when you're like when two souls
merge and become one, like when to become one.
Bork comes in, come and make love to you, baby.
Bork would. Yeah, he would.
Got to keep fucking.
I don't know if I can hold Keanu for as long as I'm going to need to hold it.
You hold Matthew McConaughey longer.
I mean, I just got to keep saying, all right, all right, all right.
You have to get back into it.
Just say, I know Kung Fu. I know Kung Fu.
This is OK.
How do we guide a conversation with a God?
Oh, I don't know.
We're all just like, you know what I mean?
Yeah. What do you ask of a God?
You don't ask anything.
You just sit there in awe, right? Yeah.
Or is Thea going to be like, can you fix my friend?
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.