Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Crashing into whatever field is keeping this place alive.
Airships surrounding the area and dark clouds pushing forward.
The sound of crashing waves is interrupted only by the moans of zombies
who have walked up under the waves onto the beach.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons, I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More, he, him.
Also with me today is Amy More.
She, her. Don't, don't worry. Don't cry about it. It's okay.
I'm going to say for the whole thing and none of my characters are going to die.
My many, many characters like Thea Amastasia, she, her.
Guile Nighthunter Oglokanu, they, them.
And Sullivan Sleight, he, him.
And Tom Laird.
That's me, he, him. I really enjoyed the Kathleen Turner vibe Russ had when we first
started the episode. He's kind of lost that since, but I would love for that to come back.
I am playing Tulgeer, who goes by he, him.
Flint, who goes by he, him.
And Moot, who also goes by he, him.
And Carla Maxted.
She, her. I will be all, all these folks. She, her.
We've got a Yen Bull. We've got Anelia. We've got a Glim.
And maybe someone else too.
There was an eyebrow raise there. I thought I better vocalize that because
this is an audio medium.
And joining us today, we normally say from Bombarded,
but he's pretty sure he's from Dumbgeons and Dragons now.
It's kind of classic. It is.
I'm thinking that's right. He, him, by the way.
And I will be reprising my role as Vorunax.
And I'm pretty sure I'm going to destroy the fucking world.
Oh, excellent.
He, him as well for Vorunax. But no, yeah, no.
It's starting to feel like a really good place to, I mean, I brought a suitcase
and I don't-
Yeah, settle in.
Just a comfy couch.
Yeah.
He's not packing the travel body wash. No, he brought the whole-
The full size.
Full size.
My suitcase is a moving van. I forgot to let you know. I'm sorry.
Oh, well, you have a lot of things.
Where it feels just like home is over on Patreon.
Patreon.com slash DumbDragonCast.
Holy shit.
To miss a beat.
For husbands.
You could be a drummer.
A drummer with how little beats you miss.
That's right. Yeah. It's all locked away up here.
But when you are a-
Oh, I was going to do it.
What were you going to do?
I was going to say, and when you're a patron-
No, you were trying to beat me to the beat.
I was.
But you couldn't. You just can't stop, won't stop.
I don't like to interrupt.
All right, well, go ahead.
And when you're a patron,
you get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron.
Kit LeBlanc.
Yay.
Oh, dang Kit.
Thank you, Kit.
You're amazing. And you look great today.
Absolutely. Looking good.
And it might be the episode where the whole world ends, but that's okay.
It's still a good one to have your name attached to.
That's right.
We're slated for two, but who knows?
You're right.
It could just be over.
And then we will love you till the end of the world.
This is so good.
Join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Where we'll love you till the end of the world.
And then you'll help us rebuild.
We'll make it better.
Faster.
Bigger. Less complicated.
Zero time travel.
I already have ideas for this new world, you guys.
It does not include time travel.
Every time I think about any future stories, I'm always like, let's time travel.
Not less.
Let's just go for zero.
A fraction of the time travel.
Fuck it.
Let's play.
Okay. So to catch everybody up, you were getting briefed by Bahamut.
B man himself.
This is everybody except Lipsynke and Vorunax.
Getting briefed by Bahamut about where the heck you need to go.
And more appropriately, when the heck you need to go.
And he gave it to us in rap form.
Did he not?
He did.
Yeah. Can we hear that rap again?
Break it down for us, for us?
We need to go back in time to save the world.
First, you got to go to the abyss and then remind me and Celestia.
It didn't have a lot of flow.
It was more free form.
Yeah.
Sure.
Time signatures.
Yeah.
Things are different in Celestia.
What rap is there is different.
It's more like our jazz.
So.
Yeah.
It's all about the notes he don't play.
Exactly.
We got it.
When, off in the distance, you didn't see until it was too late
because you were all inside a tent getting briefed by Bahamut.
But the undead army of Orcus comes knock, knock, knocking at your door.
You see airships high in the sky.
You see dragons flying towards and being careened off of this force field.
Some pressing through and the flesh from their bodies being torn off.
From the watery depths below, crawling and walking up onto the beach,
there are zombies and skeletons.
What do you do?
You stand there in sheer panic and fear for your life.
I was like running through my Rolodex of characters.
Yes, I was like, who's going to speak?
Who's going to react?
Yeah, you have to give us a little reaction time.
We all just froze.
We got to go through the list of.
Paralyze by choice.
Is everybody else seeing this?
I guess we don't really have as much time as we thought to like,
mentally prepare and commune and maybe just like kick it with Bahamut
before we had to go on our missions because.
This is so confusing.
Time travel exists.
Don't we have all the time in the world?
No, we have no time.
We're out of time.
We're Sans time.
High above in one of the airships, the largest of the airships,
we see Vorunax and Lipsynche in like a command center of sorts,
with like this panoramic view of the scene below.
The two of you have followed these refugees.
You found their underground sewer hideout below Castle Orcus,
formerly Waterdeep for those playing the home game.
Destroyed, sent an undead Kuth,
a green large formerly green dragon to wreck shit before you got there.
They decapitated that dragon.
Sad face.
You followed in behind and followed from a distance
to where you have found them at this lush green island of Mastika
that's seemingly untouched until now by anything that Orcus
or you have been dealing out across the world.
Could we get a cut scene where Vorunax is like weeping over the dead Kuth
and it's like Clarence like or you know something whatever its name is.
Oh Clarence, you are too young but it's okay.
The power of Orcus will see you rise yet again.
We shall see it come forth.
Your body once more animate with the ability of the undead
unless you were already undead and Orcus didn't fill me in on this
and that sucks if that's the case and I'm gonna have to learn.
Now more tears, more tears.
And if that's the case that really makes me sad.
Oh lip-synchy, console me.
Well the thing is his head got chopped right off so
I mean undead or dead I think Clarence is gone is what I'm saying whether he was
and I'm so sorry for your loss.
I saw a lot of myself in Clarence, the greenness part but
he shall be missed but we have things to get to.
No more time for mourning for it is the mourning of the end of the world.
Damn have you been have you been practicing that?
That was so good I'm so inspired let's go get them.
Thanks lip-synchy it kind of just came off of the tongue so.
Oh wow.
Mr. Paranox, Ms. Lip-synchy we found them they went down into the further into the
sewers and found some vessel I think we think we can release the Kraken on them.
Yes, lip-synchy please by all means give the command.
No I think it's your turn I don't want to be selfish plus
you're grieving Clarence so you know you should you go ahead.
I am grieving Clarence and they shall pay at the tentacles of the Kraken
or all the appendages of the Kraken that will slay them and then we'll
raise their bodies up and slay them again for their transgression against Clarence.
We cut back to the airship before you you see yes this lush green island it there is a
fount of of power coming from two locations one from the beach and one from high in one of
the largest mountains in this range that lie before you that appears to be powering
whatever is holding back your main forces from the air.
Well they've really upgraded haven't they?
It seems so.
From sewer to this sort of tropical paradise so
good for them it's gonna be even more satisfying.
I mean vein attempts at surviving really.
Well it'll just be a sewer when we're done so
I hope they just enjoy it for those last couple minutes.
It's true well with the arcane knowledge that Orcus has granted you
where do you think we should best lead our attack?
Well there's two sources of power so are you feeling more beachy
or more like a hiking kind of kind of mountain vibe?
I'm curious if one may weaken the other and if we take care of the one that's further out
our forces on land may be able to progress further into the jungle.
I like the way you think I feel like everybody's getting real close to the beach anyway
you know all those underwater and so maybe we should head mountain?
Yes I think we could survey from above since we have these dope ass airships.
We are in this awesome airship with this sweet console and the great view and the
binoculars and all that.
Yes we should go ahead and move forward take towards the mountain
mountain font and let the ground forces take care of that.
If there's anything that we see that's opportune along the way
we should strike and take advantage.
I love the way you think.
Thank you lip syncing.
Houndsman onward.
The orders called and the lead airship seen from the ground veers from its course
towards the beach and begins moving towards the mountain range.
Everybody below you see this and the four other airships follow in behind it
and the dragons continue their assault on this field that is protecting you at this present moment.
Down on the beach Bahamut puts his hand on your shoulder Thea and says
Vorunax is aboard.
Lipsinki is aboard.
Now is your time to strike.
Vorunax has had his memories altered.
What do you mean?
He has been started on this path because of Orcus
but he believes that the gods are the ones to have decimated his family.
But that's not the case?
No.
The town of Blackpool was once home to Vorunax and while away the town was ravaged
and attacked.
Everyone killed.
Vorunax returned and pled to the gods to bring everyone back.
That's not something that we do but his calls were answered by Orcus.
And he came to Vorunax with a vision of Pelor
and told him that he could bring them back as Pelor.
Orcus brought them back as the undead
which sent Vorunax into this spiral of rage and fury against Pelor and against any other god
who would associate himself with that.
Now I don't know if we can change that.
I don't know if we can change what has happened to him
but what can change is the course of Vorunax in his entire life
from when we send you back.
None of this world destruction could happen.
Vorunax could be redeemed.
Does that make sense?
Yes.
How do I get up that mountain?
Uh, you can follow me.
Alien 900, wait, I think we gotta lead them up the mountain.
Looks like they're going towards the, towards the, towards the, um, cat god.
Cat lord, he's up there.
The cat lord is up there?
Yep, that's, that's why it's so green here.
Cat lord hid in the mountains and has just been fond of knowledge, cats hide really well.
And yet you always seem to be around.
Yeah, uh, yeah, but you didn't notice me until that point.
Well, I mean, if we gotta go up, we better get going.
Yes, we'll, we'll take you, it's, we'll take you, there's some sort of shortcuts that we know.
All right, who's going up the mountain, who's staying on the beach?
Uh, Tullgear's going up the mountain.
Fia, obviously.
Did you just, Elia, tell that we're gonna lead them up the mountain?
Elia, 900.
Cause Opal already said that, said that.
Right.
Opal Russ already said that.
I did.
Uh, I mean, they do know the way.
It just makes sense.
I like how we're refusing to split up.
Like, Nighthunter should probably stay on the beach and like, fight, fight.
You've got three individual parties.
You're not splitting a singular party.
Right?
Okay, Nighthunter's gonna stay on the beach.
She's gonna chill on the beach.
They need to work on their town.
They make a lot of time.
Opal tears off into the forest, followed by Nighthunter, Elia.
I mean, he probably tears off, but then Elia quickly passes him, is more like what happens.
Yes.
She's so fast.
Followed by Tullgear and Fia.
We see them kind of pan up, running through this path,
making their way to the peak of this mountain.
Down on the beach, everybody left down there,
just jump in as a character who's down there.
What are you doing to set up reinforcements or calls to the Tabaxi Townspeople?
I think that Sullivan Slyte is likely going around and telling people to
get out of here, you guys.
Come on, come on, move it, move it.
Yeah, yeah, I know your hut's here, but look at, yeah, look at them.
Look at them.
Now look at you.
Now look back at me.
Now look at them.
Look back at me, and you should probably go, otherwise you're going to be undead.
Why did I get this sword if I should leave?
Well, you're going to be like the last line in defense.
If they get to you, it's too late.
Go, go.
Okay.
Sully's not sure what he's doing.
He's just getting everyone.
He's doing something.
He feels very useful.
Everybody looks towards Sully and sees all the Tabaxi run
into the forest away from the battle.
As if they wouldn't have done that anyway.
Agoth was training them to be fighters.
Oh, whoops.
They left.
Okay.
So I thought that Agoth was like, I thought they were going to maybe help.
I mean, I totally, it's fine.
I know that it's like.
Well, I thought they would just like.
Or whatever, but they can still fight.
You know what?
It's their natural habitat.
I wasn't clear.
I'm just going to go back in there and just let them know.
Like, to be ready.
Yeah, to just be hidden.
Okay.
I'll be right, I'll be right back.
So everybody else, I think.
I mean, I look at, you know, my friends like we know what to do
and it's going to be, I think, a pretty righteous battle.
I'm going to pull out my holy symbol and just like
do some extra communing with Bahamut.
Just to psych myself up.
He's right there.
Yeah, I guess I can.
Can I just like hold your hand for a second or something?
I'm used to just sort of like focusing it all on this little piece of leather,
but like, there you are.
No, no, straight from the source, yeah.
Okay, okay.
Okay, and I take.
Dear Bahamut.
I mean, I don't usually, do you want it out loud?
Okay, okay, so I take his hand, his hand in between my hands.
Dear Bahamut, thank you for coming back and being such an awesome guy.
No problem.
And for the amazing, oh, you're responding.
Right in it, okay.
I'm not used to this.
Thank you.
Just bless us, protect us, and I guess pick up a sword
and we'll see on the other side of this.
Oh, I'm not going to pick up a sword.
Okay, well, just like put a lot of power through me and I'll do it.
I mean, yeah, do you have like a sword made of light
or something cool like that maybe so you don't actually have to pick up a sword?
You can just make your own.
Are you, I don't want to be rude.
This is probably an inappropriate question, but are you, is,
how are you feeling?
Like, could you change form or anything?
Mu, Glim, and Sully, I think you're, you're closest around, like.
I've come back.
Yeah.
What did I miss?
You feel this font of energy wash through you
as it's passed from Bahamut to Glim and Mu and Sully
and you gain this radiant energy about you
and you're going to get a game mechanic wise plus five to your attacks.
Dank.
Roll or damage?
Five radiant.
Fuck it.
Roll and damage.
Ooh, Russ is feeling like generous tonight.
As you begin to like glow with this radiant energy, Bahamut gives you a wink.
Glim.
And before you, you see this platinum dragon form as if out of the ground
and shoot up into the sky going towards the undead dragons
pounding against the force field, protecting the island.
Okay.
I know Glim had like talked him up for years and years and years, but like.
Holy shit.
That was pretty fucking cool.
Right?
So sick.
It's absolutely awesome.
Whoa.
Okay.
I'm a trauma believer.
Not that I wasn't before.
We cut scene as the zombies and skeletons are right behind you
and you turn with your weapons and crash into them.
Guts and bone flying everywhere around the three of you.
Back up in the airship, you hear this roar through the air.
You turn and you look through the glass in your airship
and see this platinum dragon rising up from the beach
toward the dragon swarming in the sky.
That's.
Huh.
That's not one of ours.
Holy shit.
Is that Bahamut?
Well, that's not fair.
He's supposed to be.
No, I thought.
I thought we'd already dealt with him.
I thought so too.
Okay, that kind of changes some things.
I mean, I guess just prepare yourself perhaps for more loss of dragons.
I know you took Clarence's death real hard.
So just maybe, you know, we weren't planning on a platinum dragon being here and.
No, no, we will not.
It's a bit of a change.
We will not falter.
We will hold faith in Orcus, his abilities and the plan.
Stay the course.
You're reaching the top of this mountain and it's like there's this pool,
this well of energy coming up and out of it
and almost like this funnel going back down to the peak of this mountain.
And we cut down to the peak of the mountain where
Telgir Thea and the God's Chosen Three have arrived
and there's this opening, this cave opening just before you get to the peak.
Nopal turns to you all and says, well, if you're.
I'm pretty sure they're going to be be here pretty quick.
Elia, Nighthunter, we should probably go.
If anybody comes in and tries to get the Cat Lord,
we should probably just like hold them, hold them off here.
So we don't lose everything here.
Yes, we will be first line of defense.
We will protect the Cat Lord and the power that it provides.
OK, I know.
With your life.
Wait, with my life?
Our lives.
With all of our lives, should that be necessary?
OK.
Yes, that is what I said first time.
A formerly ancient red dragon presses through
the force field and the flesh is torn off and is falling off as it as it flies down
and screams this roar that isn't a roar anymore because it's like vocal chords
have been all like decimated.
So it's like this high pitched shrill gargle
as you see its breath weapon unleash towards you.
Roll dexterity saving throw, please.
Oh, fuck me.
Oh, no.
Well, is there something magical that I can?
I don't know.
You made your character.
I've got nothing where I can reroll a one.
Oh, no.
Should have saved that role for suddenly.
I don't want to die for a thing.
Nighthunter, no.
Nobody said you would die.
I did.
Yeah, I mean, Kyle did.
I appreciate your honesty, Kyle.
OK, sorry you got.
See, you got an 11, 12, 13, 14.
14, OK.
And a one for Nighthunter.
17 for Tullgear.
18.
OK, Opal got a 26.
I have a plus nine for Dex and that was such a bad roll.
So everybody except Opal are going to take 26 D6 necrotic damage.
Well, I'm resistant to necrotic damage.
Here you go.
You know what?
I just want to roll 26 D6 and let's do it.
OK, 26 D6 because you don't get to do that very often.
No, you do not.
Oh, I apologize, Russ.
I need to up my roll by two because I was looking at the wrong character.
Did you beat a 24?
No, I did not.
Well, then it does not matter.
But thanks for the update, Tom.
So you're all going to take, except for Opal,
who's going to take half, 91 necrotic damage.
But I'm also going to take half, right?
You will take half because you're resistant.
What's half of 9146?
As a reaction, I'm going to reduce this damage dealt to me by one D12 plus seven.
Sure. Why not?
Because I mean, like, I mean, this was like 100 damage.
So I'm just going to minus one D12 plus seven because that'll be better than nothing.
Yeah, that's pretty good.
OK, 14.
I'm going to take 14 back.
Take 14 back.
Amana, I don't need your permission.
Opal dives into the cave.
Everybody else tries to shield themselves unsuccessfully.
Above you, you see the lead airship above this font.
How would Vorunax proceed from here?
Vorunax and Lipsinki, we can cut back up there.
You're right above where this wellspring is seemingly emitting from.
It looks like there's a path down.
What do you want to do?
Would our airships have a way of just dumping undead on a certain point, kind of like airdrop?
I thought the exact same thing when you said we were in an airship.
Like these are this is fodder, right?
Like these are living, undead weapons that we can just like launch at people.
Play it out.
All right.
Center up on this point once we've arrived.
Well, you all know what to do.
Now, how many?
We're just going to go for it?
Kind of unload the whole?
I mean, why not?
The rest of them have their payloads still ready to go and, you know.
And we're clearly here.
I mean, look at all the power coming out of this place and let's just dump a lot of them.
Even if it gives us a soft landing space, it was all for the glory of Orcus.
It's all for Orcus, is what I always say.
Amen.
Above you, down on the mountain, you see a mass of undead.
First, you hear it as like these doors open, this groaning cry,
as the doors open and undead rain from the sky down on you.
You all have made it into like this cave opening
as they hit the mountain and roll off and some of them land
and they all begin climbing back up towards where you are.
So you want to get up there?
Yeah, we have to get up there.
Okay, I haven't done it in a while, but I could teleport you up there.
What do you mean you haven't done?
You know what?
I don't care.
Do it.
I'm just going to do Radiant Soul and just get some wings and just get up there.
You're going to go up there too?
Okay, am I teleporting two of you or are you flying one of them up?
Elia, why do not we stay here and fight the horde
so they do not get to the cat god?
Lord, cat lord.
Cat lord, sorry.
Of course, you're right.
I know you want to be in the thick of it.
We are needed here.
You're right.
But take out your wings, my love.
Okay.
We're married, by the way, Kyle.
Oh no, good to know.
Now I know who to use against too.
Kids got together, that's right.
Whatever, player knowledge, character knowledge, Kyle.
Get your shit together.
Okay, ready?
What were the magic words again, Elia?
Do you remember what they were?
You put the right one in, put the right one out,
right one in, and shake it all about.
Shake it all.
Okay, ready, everybody?
Put the right one in, you put the right one out, put the right one in.
I mean, I don't love the sound of this.
Snap!
You find yourselves up on the deck of the airship, Tallgear and Thea.
I panicked, it's the middle.
Oh wow, okay.
Wow.
I had open a Spotify playlist that said
22 songs for your classroom school in January 2021, and I did not recognize a single song.
That is a problem.
Yep, I feel removed from pop culture, I think is what I'm getting at,
and the general radio rotation playlist of this time last year.
Yeah, that's what we're getting at.
Okay.
So, to help us get better with it, you can join us over on Patreon.
That's a lie, we won't get better with music.
We won't get better with, we all left radio for a reason, and we're all happy with that,
and part of the reason we're happy with that is that we're doing this, this fun thing,
and patrons help us do this fun thing that we love, and hopefully you kind of like a little bit too.
Patreon is one of the many ways that we are transitioning,
transitioning, or trying our darndest to transition into doing podcasts full time.
Could you even believe it?
I couldn't imagine, but wouldn't it be great?
It would be a dream.
But the more patrons we get, the closer we get to do that, the more content we get to create,
and every step along the way helps us with that.
We've been able to get equipment, we've been able to go on trips.
We're planning, Amy just stumbled into the room.
Amy might need to go to the hospital, so we won't use the money for that, but.
No, we live in Canada.
She's fine.
But we're planning a getaway for the group here, which patrons,
the money you give us is going to help that, and you know we're going to record some sweet
content while we're down there and post on the socials, which we're not very good at,
but maybe we'll be good at when we're in somewhere hot.
We won't have anything else to worry about.
No, that would be good.
All of that to say, your support means the world to us, because it says that what
you are listening to, you are choosing to donate some money to us because you appreciate the
stories that we're putting out there, be it Dumbgeons and Dragons or Facing Fate,
or DM to GM if you're one of the 12 people who listen.
Thank you.
You know who you are.
There's more than 12.
So if you can, if you want to, because that's the other big thing too,
if you want to, visit us at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast.
We have a whole bunch of different tiers up there with rewards and
depending on what you're coming there for, we've got something up there for you.
If it's just support for the show, you don't want to see our dumb faces all the time,
you can do that.
If you want to see our dumb faces all the time, you can do that too,
and no pressure either way.
Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast.
We hope to see you over there.
Thank you so much for being here,
and we will continue to make all the amazing things for you.
Okay, bye.
Oh my God, it worked.
I thought, I swear to God, I thought we were just going to drop like,
I mean, yeah, I didn't know what was going to happen.
200 feet.
I mean, fairly good aim.
I'm going to use my lay on hands pool and heal both of us 45 hit points.
Thank you.
Cool beans.
Inside the airship, Vorunax, Lipsinki, you can change it if you want,
but I presume like you're like kids at the aquarium,
like press your face watching all of these undead falling towards the earth.
It's wondrous, isn't it?
Quite a sight to see bodies rain from the sky.
You know, you'd think you'd get bored of it, but you just don't.
I mean, look at that one just bounced.
Did you see how it went so high?
See that auger just rolling down the hill?
That's like a variable boulder.
Oh, I know.
I wish he was in the fight, but he'll just pick himself up
and get in the fight down at the beach.
It's fun.
It's going to be hilarious.
Nobody's going to see it.
And then out of nowhere, you hear a thud up on the deck.
What the?
Well, that's.
That's not the way they're supposed to be coming from.
That's unusual.
Some soft footsteps, just not walking in any direction.
Just kind of it sounds like they're just pacing on the spot.
Well, maybe we've got some company.
Definitely doesn't sound like undead footsteps.
I think we know both know what that sounds like.
Indeed.
It's been a long time since we had company.
Well, let's go greet them would be uncivil.
Let's give them a very warm orcas welcome.
Back down in the mountain.
Opal, Elia, Night Hunter.
Opal looks to the two of you.
It's I think it worked.
Yes, I think you did it.
It seems like they made it there.
OK.
Good job, Sun Kitty.
What?
Thank you.
No, I don't pass out.
I know it's been lightheaded.
You know, it's OK.
It's OK.
Get it together.
This is why I don't compliment him.
No, you don't compliment me.
It's OK.
There's some coming up over there.
Prepare yourself, Sun Kitty.
I was going to say, where's the best hold point?
Like here or further in?
Like where are we?
It's a choke point.
Is that what they say?
I mean, Night Hunter stops listening and charges
and makes the oncoming onslaught of undead.
OK, choke them, choke them.
Cut that back down to the beach.
I'm just on the floor like, why won't you die?
Back down on the beach.
Let's just do a quick round Robin of what everybody's doing.
Moot.
Moot has actually set up a wall of light on the beach
where all of these like undead zombies
were coming out of the water.
Yeah.
So as they like appear, they take a bunch of radiant damage
and this wall of light actually like also shoots
beams of radiant light into targets as well
as they are showing up if they're maybe outside
of the jurisdiction of the wall itself.
Love it.
So yeah, this light is emanating out
and getting this massive wave pushing them,
incinerating them back into the water from whence they came.
Glim up in the air and flying down towards you,
there's this flock of probably murder
is probably a better bird term for these.
Murder of rocks screaming down towards you.
I don't know.
Flock of rock is pretty good.
Glim is just has the Vorpal Longsword
and just is taking them as they approach
to try to be beheading them.
Love it.
Because that's a good way.
It's just your signature go-to move.
It's a good way to get rid of a lot of rocks,
a lot of flock of rocks.
That's right.
We see Glim almost jumping up on top of them
and beheading them as they're falling.
So you're rising in the air as this is happening
and it's like you're riding them down towards the beach.
It's so badass.
But as you're riding back down to the beach,
one of them is coming in behind you.
Make a Dex saving throw, please.
18.
One of them catches you in the back
and pushes you forward.
You're going to take nine piercing damage
as you fall down towards the ground.
Kyle, how high up is Glim at this point?
I would probably say if it's a murder,
they'd probably be spiraling.
I'd say maybe like 80 feet.
All right.
So we're going to roll 8d6 for fall damage.
You're going to take 35 bludgeoning damage
as you hit the ground below.
Up in the sky, we see Bahamut being swarmed
by all of these undead adult and ancient dragons
that have broken through the threshold.
The power is just not strong enough
to hold them back anymore.
Flint, you are groggily waking up
from the earthquake that has happened,
and your eyes crack open,
and the entire city of Mithril Hall
before you has fallen.
The cave around it has crashed in down around you.
You look over and you see Bort
and you see a bunch of other people
covered in a pile of rubble before you.
You don't see any other people
or hear any screams or anything.
It's eerily silent at this point.
I'm going to go try and get the rocks off my butt.
Sorry.
You said rocks off.
I did.
You begin pulling these huge stones
off and pull drag him away from this rubble.
It looks like he's uninjured
as his eyes begin to open.
What happened?
You know, I don't really know.
The city is destroyed and you're okay though.
You look okay.
I feel fine.
I mean, that's great news.
You okay?
I think so.
At that, there's this beam of light
comes from the roof of this cave
down to the center of town.
Does that normally happen?
Nope.
Usually when I've seen things like this before
it's like the start of a quest.
Maybe this is the way out of whatever dream
dream-hopping we're doing.
Oh, you know, that's a good call.
It probably is.
I guess.
Are you see there?
The two of you run off hopping over this rubble
and climbing up over these fallen buildings.
Flint, you're looking around
and you're not seeing any other remains,
any other people, any other injured, anything.
Like the city is empty now
where to you a moment ago
it was fully populated.
You get to where this light hits the ground
and there's this pedestal in the center of town
and everything around it is clear.
You go and look at the pedestal
and look up through the light
and you see it kind of begin to flicker.
Wait a moment and the light begins to dim
and then you hear this call
like this echoing roaring call
as a dragon comes into view above you and Bort.
Bort immediately begins to stumble back
Flint like grabs his axe.
It's not his first,
not his first rodeo when it comes to dragons.
Flint, you grab your axe and this dragon
as it comes more into view
as this giant black dragon
and it lets go its breath weapon down on you
as we cut back out to the deck of the airship
where Thea and Tallgear are standing.
All right, so what's the game plan?
Okay, so I was given a little insider information
from Bahamut that we can use
to hopefully change Vorunax's mind on this whole thing.
Now, with that, I feel more confident about that
but Lipsynche is a little bit of a wild card there.
We didn't know her for very long,
lost her in a portal.
She suffered for years and, you know, hell.
So like, not 100% sure, might have to kill her.
Don't want to, but.
Sure, no, like we're aiming to get,
we're aiming to convert both of them, right?
Yes.
That's the plan?
Yeah, but if all else fails, chop chop.
All right, is there like,
do we have like a code word
for if we think things are going south
and it's like go time?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, that's good.
We should think of a code word.
How about Dragon Ball?
Yeah, I mean, it sounds good to me.
It's one of those ones that, you know,
doesn't normally come up in conversations
so it'll really stand out.
Yeah, okay, wait, was that not the idea?
Should we choose one that's more?
I don't want it to just accidentally pop out of my mouth
and then you cut them down.
No, we want it to be a very specific word.
I could work that into a conversation.
Sure, yeah, okay.
All right, I'm really nervous.
If you say that, I'm going to hit them
with everything I've got.
Oh, no, and I expect you to,
and I know that would be a lot.
Diplomacy first, hacking flashing second.
No, I'm all on board if we can get them.
Just if you think we're not going to be able to,
you just let me know.
Hey Vorunax, I got,
you remember that thing that I did
that one time with the thing and with the,
I'm just, can I just do a thing?
Oh, yes.
Just when we, because I think you're going to like it.
I'm excited to see it.
I'm ready to do a thing as well.
So when we approach them,
or I guess I shouldn't speak for Vorunax,
when Lipsynche approaches them,
they don't know because, you know,
this is her ship, she knows her way around,
sneaks up and is going to cast maddening darkness
where they are on the deck.
So magical darkness spreads from a point.
It's very dark.
Dark vision can't see through it.
There's a lot of shrieks and gibbering
and mad laughter within this sphere.
So that's sort of my entrance
as Lipsynche.
Or it's not because you don't even see me
because you're in this maddening darkness.
It's cacophonous sound of laughter and shrieks
and cries and complete and utter pitch black
envelops you, Thea, and Talgear.
I bet they weren't expecting that.
They weren't.
Talgear?
And to follow it up, bust out the Wand of Orcus
and I cast Circle of Death,
which has a 60 foot range or a 60 foot area.
And since I know I can't see the center of that
and everything, I'll just focus it
as close to it as possible.
Okay.
And that would require them to make
a constitution saving throw DC 18.
I rolled a 20.
Nice.
You'll take half as much damage then.
Oh, that's better than all of it.
And I rolled a 23.
Perfect.
Let me roll my 8d6.
That is going to be 33.
Halved would be 17 necrotic damage.
Beck.
Whoever's going to go needs to do something
at the beginning of their turn, so.
Okay.
I guess I'll go first.
Now, are we unclear as to where they're located?
Yeah, you're in the maddening darkness.
They like plinked up like the staircase
just behind you and were peeking through
the door on the floor.
So you didn't see them.
So before you do anything,
maybe make a wisdom saving throw.
I can do that for you.
I do have a plus nine, which is pretty great.
Oh, that's good.
25.
Okay.
So you're going to take half 8d8 psychic damage.
And is it still dark?
Super dark.
Oh, it's still dark.
It's scary.
So dark, so scary.
38, so half.
So 19.
Yes, 19.
Perfect.
I guess the chatting part of the program
was forgotten by you guys.
Well, we didn't know what your plan was.
Yeah, I don't know who's married to who.
Well, you know, we're married.
I don't know.
Could be.
Russ, I have a skill called cleansing touch.
Cool.
I love it.
Which I can use my action to end one spell on myself
or on one willing creature that I touch.
Does that include their spells that are affecting us?
I think so, because, yeah.
Yeah, you can just end spells.
Yeah, if it succeeds and or if it succeeds,
I would I would say that, yeah.
I mean, it isn't even a thing I have to roll for.
It's just a thing that happens.
Cool beans.
Do it, baby.
I'm going to I'm going to reach out and touch Thea
and I'm going to use cleansing touch
and stop the crazy darkness spell from messing with her.
Okay.
Yeah, you stumble through and you bump into what you presume
is Thea, because I don't think either of you ran around
really fast in the last half a second.
That's not what you do when you plunge into darkness.
You don't just run around on an airship on an airship
for that matter.
Teleport me back.
Just shoot me right back up there.
The darkness and the whispers end for Thea.
So, Thea, you I would say you can see obscured
as if like dark vision.
So like grayscale, not full vision back.
And the whispers and screams and madness goes away.
If that seems fair for everybody.
Sounds good to me.
Except for the whispers and screams and madness
of all the undead that are just getting
bailed out at the bottom of this airship.
My favorite.
That happens.
Is there anything else that Tallgear can do?
I mean, let's see here.
He probably has some bonus actions.
Nope.
Two weapon fighting seems to be his biggest bonus action.
So, okay, he does have some spells,
but I will hold on to those for
when I get to stop that on myself.
Right.
So you look around.
Thea is no fucking idiot.
And she is going to continue to act as though she can't see shit.
Vorunax, Lipsinki, can I talk to you guys for a sec?
Do we want to parlay in any way?
Well, I don't know.
I don't not want to talk to them.
Listen, I'm not going to lie.
I think we've got this in the bag.
Let's entertain them.
A little bit.
Aren't you a little bit curious to find out how mad they were
when they finally got out of that pyramid
and they found out all that time had passed
and they'd been stuck in that pyramid the whole time
and we were taking over the world?
I know.
I think it's hilarious that most of the things that have happened
have been because of their own doing.
Like, literally, they've kind of caused all of this.
I don't know how far I would have gotten
without them coming into town
and, you know, letting you out and letting...
It may not have ever worked out.
I never would have even ended up in the abyss
if I hadn't gotten, you know, taken into that portal.
So it's really all thanks to...
I mean...
Well, then we should do it out of thanks to them.
Yes, in gratitude for bringing Orcus more fully into our lives.
Indeed.
Uh, yeah, we could chat.
Or you could do it for Aesir.
What do you know of Aesir?
Open the door full on.
Kicks the door open.
As the door opens, Thea turns and says,
Well, I want them to listen.
Nah, sometimes you just have to tie a person down
to make them listen.
So you guys have to make a wisdom saving throw
or be paralyzed and have to listen to my diatribe
for the duration.
I'm a lot more sympathetic to people
when they tie me up first.
Yeah.
Totally.
Hey, hey, they came out swinging first.
I have to also show that, you know.
I have advantage, so it was an 18.
I'm playing the game.
Oh, and an 11, so 18.
Same.
I rolled a four and a six, which puts me at a 19.
So like nothing happens.
I wiggle my fingers at you and I'm like...
That's what I say.
And then I say,
You don't think you know what you know.
I don't.
I don't know what that means.
What is she talking about?
I don't know either.
You speak in riddles, Thea.
Get to your point.
Is it intriguing enough to maybe take down the darkness?
Let us talk for a moment.
Do you have any liquor?
I mean, is the darkness even affecting you?
Because you literally just cast a spell on me, which...
Oh, no.
I mean, it's so scary.
It's very, very loud.
You can see me.
I can barely hear you.
You literally targeted me, so...
I can see you.
Fine.
No, I can see you.
You guys...
But tall gear, too.
All right.
Fine.
Just hear me out.
And then, you know, if we can keep fighting and I won't like,
you know, pull any shitty things on you,
like we'll just like full out,
like really give ourselves a run for our money.
Okay?
You saw what I did to Shamalama Bing Bong with this wand.
I mean, I didn't see it.
I don't know who you are.
Oh, this is...
Okay, sorry.
Introductions.
Tall gear.
This is Vorunax and Lip Sinky.
I mean, I figured.
Well, but I mean like,
really, an introduction is necessary.
In their young years, they have accomplished so much.
Oh, I mean, well that's...
True.
That's...
We really have written the Orcus Corporate letter
right to the top.
Lip Sinky, hold it.
We are not roles to be buttered.
Oh, well...
Hey, I mean, who else butters your role?
Well, we've got a...
That's private.
Yeah, I mean, that's private.
That's what I was going to say, too.
You're a dirty birdie and I like it.
Okay, so about this liquor.
You've got any anywhere?
You know what?
And then, and Thea pulls out a wineskin
and takes a swig and is like,
anybody, this is going to be heavy, y'all.
This is going to be heavy.
Vorunax, you especially, like for you, for sure.
If it is as heavy as you say it is,
then I'd rather be in my right mind to understand it.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season 2, episode 110,
starring Amy More as Thea Amastasia,
Sullivan Sleight,
and Gael Nighthunter Ogala Kanu,
Carla Maxted as Yen Bull Nuri,
Glim and Elia Strong,
Tom Laird as Tulkier Heavyfoot,
Flint Firebeard and Moot,
with Kyle Claset as Vorunax,
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Editing, production and sound design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok,
Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown, Devin Michaels,
Craig Zeiss, Aaron Stevens,
Darylith, Lulahan and L.A. Branton.
To support Dumbgeons and Dragons
and our many other productions
and get access to an exclusive podcast
called The Adventures Of,
bonus episodes and much more,
please join our Patreon at Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast.
You can also follow us at
Facebook.com slash dumb dragon podcast
and on Instagram and Twitter at dumb dragon cast.
Thank you for listening.
Have a great week.
We'll talk again soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.