previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
baby we're back who are you you zipped us off just to uh to saloon oh
completely forgotten about us regardless of if we would have come back with your
stuff we would have been off scot-free well no you said are you okay sorry oh
my goodness uh yeah sorry about that no you're right we would have came
back regardless because those are the kind of good people we are I guess
everybody well you've got everything on the list I will hand this over to you I
take it back and I say thank you very much and as you hold it in your hand
it bursts into flames and falls to the ground oh that's how it's supposed
to happen what was that sully I think that that sounded really bad it did
sound bad is it time to save the world glim I don't know but I think
maybe we should start and I think we run out of the rusty bucket yeah
let's head towards that explosion this one's on you
Judith I got it and up shooting from this cloud is this winged hideous demon
that bursts up into the cloud and begins flying around and swooping down
trying to pick up people that are fleeing
welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons I'm your dungeon master Russ More and with
me today is Amy More are you sure there was a little hesitation there I
am really here don't trust them and I play Sullivan slight and Tom Laird yeah
that's me I play moot and Carla maxed it I am also here although my camera
isn't working so am I really here you guys don't know this could all be a
recording that I'm playing back to then be recorded to release as the
podcast let's see if I say any weird non sequiturs also I play glim Carla
that's so funny about ham sandwiches clearly been working on your tight
five yeah sandwiches very specific Judith would approve all the best
comedy is specific Carla oh yeah she loves a good ham sandwich
mm-hmm Judith puts butter on her ham sandwiches if she does no she doesn't
it's margarine butter is just one step away from cheese
Judith uses margarine classic mm-hmm Judith she's a base l-lady
what a piece of bitch you know sometimes we do bonus content and I
feel like mm-hmm Judith would have a pretty good little one-shot I don't
think there'd be much high action but there would be something there'd be
like buttered sandwiches or margarine sandwiches maybe for this game time I'll
name my character mm-hmm Judith and no one will understand because it'll be too
soon so good so if you've played in game time in the past and Tom played
in mm-hmm Judith and are just getting it once this it once the last
episode plays there you go you were on the end yep but when you are a
patron you get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron Mika or Micah
Sabzowicz thank you thank you so much thank you Mika or Micah both great
names yeah thank you so much you can find out more about joining us on
Patreon at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast now fuck it let's play
Wow he's not even gonna produce that in no he's just doing it all
He's still going look at him go
previously there was an explosion in the center of Prosker where you are
right now big demon bird thing flying up out of the earth ash and smoke
falling all around you Eska and Moot running in from one side of the city
Sully and Glim running in from the other there's drums playing in the
background it's very intense it's big big fight going on right now like a
battle of the bands like a battle the band just a bunch of guitar stings up
from hell Satan himself with a smoking guitar riffs
Grief digger. I'm here for it I would like to continue making music noises with your mouth so there's a
bunch there's there's a demon we'll just cut in with you this is what you see
go as we run up and I see Moot and Eska running up I yell what what the
fuck you guys do you do this I don't I don't think we did this like it the
explosion was over there and we were over there yeah I know but you're doing
some crazy magic stuff and now there's something flight oh my it's picking
people up we is there any people that seem to be in immediate need of
assistance like under debris or yeah that probably makes sense on fire etc
falling from the sky yes okay slow down you can see them what do you do and
then survey the scene there are three people who have who are like trying to
pull themselves out of the rubble you hear hideous noises coming up from
the center of this split in the earth there is one person who is being picked
up actively by this big bird creature and is being flown up into the air
Sully wants to get out a short bow quick and let loose an arrow at this
thing that's the bird demon that's trying to pick up the person all
right do so okay and then let's let's roll yeah let's roll for an
initiative that's probably gonna be a good idea can I shoot my short bow first
or roll furnished it first fine that was a hard no hard no Amy ah 17 five
oh bring it up the rear someone has to put those guns away Tom never for our
listeners Tom just fLexes muscles it's true and they were big guns
it's a little AC DC for ya Sully you are up first oh well good thing you didn't
just shoot your arrow good thing because it what I will now shoot my
arrow all right so Sully gets out a short bow and he aims it at the
flying creature or the the swooping I guess creature and he goes come on
you can do this and it's a 24 24 will hit through the air your arrow flies
into this creature that has huge feathered wings like a fur back a big
eagle beak with teeth that lines at huge talons that sink into this person
it's an ugly motherfucker I hate it I rolled the lowest damage I could
possibly roll so that's a six what type of damage is it pokey yeah it goes and
sticks in and then falls out and goes to the ground but you see just like a
little guys I made it bleed I made it bleed its own blood anything else you
would like to do bonus actions move actions I'm going to use help as a
bonus action what are you gonna do oh I'm going to look at glim and I'm
going to it can help be like encouragement click on help and then you
know what help does right I keep it does it just doesn't look clickable okay
you can lend your aid to another creature in a completion of a task when
you take the help action the creature and you gain advantage on the next
ability check to perform the task you're helping with it provides so so
I mean you don't really know what glim's doing I don't so I think you
want to probably go around figure out what everybody's doing okay hold on I can
aid a friendly creature and attacking a creature within five feet of you or 30
feet because I'm a mastermind whoo that's right I know thanks and I can
faint distract the target or in some other way team up to make your allies
attack more effective so if your ally attacks the target before your
next turn your first attack role is made with advantage so I could be like
trying to get the attention of the big wing thing so that it stops doing bad
things that person and so that maybe glim can get around it and and this
is what happens when you give me bonus actions okay so what do you what
do you that you were doing to try and distract this bird oh I'm waving my
arms in the air and I take out another arrow and I'm like oh you
like that you want another taste of this for the face okay the bird drops
the person from 40 feet in the air glim it's your turn how far away am I from
that person and I try and catch the person I thought they were swooping to
get a person they had picked up a person shot a bird that was carrying a
person I just poked it like a little yeah but then distracted it so it
dropped it for you now yeah it's always having a hard time being
straight up the good guy there was not right to make all these there was a lot
on his own there was a lot of sweet guitar riffs off the top I understand
it's true okay glim yeah so what's your movement my movement is 30 feet
mm-hmm I'd say if you dashed you could get underneath that person they
are falling from 40 feet in the air however I'm gonna try and catch them
okay but they're just gonna squish me but maybe they'll just knock me down or
something okay maybe I'll just break their fall a little okay so we're
gonna do so Sully was actively trying to help you so that's gonna
give you advantage on the strength check that you're going to need to
make in order to catch this person because for every 10 feet they fall
they're gonna take 1d6 bludgeoning damage which means that's coming down on
top of you if you fail you're going to take the full 4d6 bludgeoning damage
might die you guys yeah you might I've outlined what's gonna happen to you
do you still do it well I think I do go ahead I can't imagine Glenn being
like actually I'm gonna write down I think she just think she just is
gonna do it can I can I roll the damage for her I'm gonna write down the number
that you need to pass make a strength strength saving throw in order to catch
this person with advantage because of Sully's Sully's help help we're gonna
put that in quotation marks so the first one is a 16 and the next one is
a 17 all right probably not gonna be good enough I had written down the
number that you needed to pass which was a 15 so you catch I thought it was
gonna be like 24 I'm being I'm being generous we are still baby characters
we're such little babies I haven't given Glim her third level yet but
yeah so you managed to catch the person I think they I mean you you
describe how you catch them and and avoid taking this damage like knowing
that if you just like you know dead drop them that your arms are
gonna come out of their sockets yeah I was gonna say I can take some damage I
mean it's I am even if it goes the best it can go can't go that good can
it no you probably still take half like I don't want the damage but let's
be realistic they're coming from 40 feet there's a 9 10 12 you're gonna
see you're gonna take six bludgeoning damage as are they which
knocks them unconscious yeah I think so I like just run not really thinking
about what I'm doing kind of with my arms out and I feel like catch is um
probably not an accurate description of what happens I think they probably
yeah I think they probably just kind of like land on me ish knock me down
kind of knock the wind out of me but I like break their fall enough
that I'm not super hurt but I am like the breath is knocked out of me and I'm
not feeling great about this decision except that I am cuz I saved them oh my
god Glim you're good you're a hero that was I made a really bad choice
anything else you can or would like to do I mean that was realistically I
mean I have one action that's probably all sounds good but that was
a lot yeah it was good that's good I liked it demons turn so this bird has
caught your your sight there Sullivan slight yeah and I mean it's gonna dive
towards you and try and get you with it's gonna go try and go for its
beak and one of its talons so that's gonna be 15 doesn't hit and a 12 that
doesn't hit this bird flies towards you screaming in your direction and
swipes at you you nimbly move out of the way as it swoops up and back into
the air it passes through your sphere which would impose a quick opportunity
attack oh yeah I want to do that I'm gonna say with my rapier I'm gonna try
to slice at it as it goes past me for a 22 yes that will hit and okay
Amy don't roll the lowest amount of damage possible I've rolled the
second lowest amount of damage possible I need to be more specific more
specific on your little self pet dogs seven slashing okay nope piercing okay
okay you hear screams of the the individuals who are trying to climb up
you look over everybody catches sight of these like they look like they're
all mouth like they have these stubby little arms on like these like
almost like potato bodies but it's like bumpy flesh and it's like huge mouth
and teeth and it one person is clamped down on their legs with one of
these and there's another one running up and out towards another person it
is Moot's turn I see the one that dive bomb Sully and missed and I
raise my hand and unleash three magic missiles at it now these are guaranteed
to hit but I do have to roll them these are going for the bird thing not
the coming up out of the big growth the bird thing that was trying to
trying to attack sell it on it okay first one oh that's five second one
that's four so nine so far and two is eleven eleven force damage yeah you did
yeah you found one that works good you knock this bird like off kilter
and it it loses its bAlydince and like falls to the ground and there's this
hideous shriek that it lets out as it's scrambling to get back up I picture
like an x-wing when they get hit and they like spiral out of control yeah
kind of like that yeah and you would like me to roll for the surge table
please do okay that's a crit fail roll me some percentile die to see
what happens make it good okay come on not cheap good for me don't go for the
sheep come on taller that is a 38 well you really like the 30s well that's
never a good sound seems like a bad sign he has a very delighted smile on
his face too it seems bad terrifying what the fuck is that okay so magic
missiles go off you're feeling real good about yourself is this bird
shrieking in like trying to scramble up and then perfect hurting birds that's
moods ammo I like to drum and I like to hurt them and then one like right
in front of you one more in front of glim and sully and one like 40
feet off into the side so three flumps which look like floating like pillows
with big long eyestalks and long like jellyfish like tentacles pop up out of
nowhere and they have this look on their eyes they look at you and
they're like they don't say anything because they didn't they don't speak
good but they have this look of fear and panic as soon as they see you moot and
then all three of them just bolt away from you and they're called flu flumps
flumps flumps FLU MPH flumps yeah okay eska runs forward to this broken down
fountain that's like spurting water and just dribbling water where he you
had previously seen him juggling when you had met and does the same thing you
moot you saw him out in the field just shapes this water moves it into a wall
that bursts between this demonic creature that's clamped onto this one
person and bursts it off and pushes it away long enough for this person to
scramble up you see believe them bleeding from their legs as they're
trying to scramble up and out of this pit sully so you're saying that my
poking isn't hurting this thing I didn't say it wasn't hurting this thing
I just said it wasn't hurting this thing a lot well it's a good thing
all my all my attacks do the same thing okay so he's just going to
short bow it again cuz he can see it crawling looking all sad and shit
14 yep no and as my bonus action I will use help again okay and I'm going to
run over to glim I run over and I help you up because you know well that
actually does help because now cuz she was prone now I'm not prone
anymore you don't have to use half your there we go yeah okay glim here's been
assisted up you've got this person in your arms what do you do I will I'll
put the person down are they they're unconscious they are unconscious yeah
okay I almost wonder if I was like under them I would have kind of
moved them off of me and then sully helped me up I don't know that I
would have like dead lifted them from the they're just laying on the
ground now yeah how many of those mouth creatures are there three yeah yeah
does each of them have a person in their mouth not actively one had a
person in their mouth but Eska managed to get them off with the shape water
the other two are crawling but are being pursued in this moment haven't
okay I'm going to use my fire breath on them and I guess it depends how they are
positioned because it goes in a 5 by 30 foot line I'd say you can if you yeah
if you run to position yourself you'd be able to get there for within your
movement yep okay then I am going to do that they have to make a deck
save dexterity is not their strong suit that one rolled a 17 that one rolled an
eight okay so the one that got the eight will get full damage the other
one will only take half damage okay it is baby characters um six damage or
three damage on the other one I must have rolled double sixes when I did
it on birdie and Barty because I really yeah you know those guys it was full
full damage that you did yeah because remember you were like I'm gonna scare
him away and then you for a full day and you're like oh no okay yes they
take that damage and turn and lock eyes now you see that they have many
eyes lock eyes on you the bird creature is going to get up and begin to flap its
wings and move towards sully as it does so it emits this horrific screech and
you see like the sound begin to move as it as it comes towards you you
have to make a Constitution saving throw everybody within 20 feet I'd say
probably glim to you ran back in that direction oh no so yeah no cuz you ran
away from sully it had to go to sully which it can make it there no it's
just gonna be sully 20 okay you are fine I rolled a 19 everybody yeah you
feel like you feel like your your knees waver like this thing was
trying to stun you and it swoops up back into the air kind of along like the
roof lines at this point the other two creatures the one that got separated
by the water it turns and starts running towards Eska and is going to
make an attack with its big big bite mouth and that's a 20 not natural
towards Eska who's going to take 11 piercing damage so this thing is like
clamping hard down on Eska's leg who lets out a scream in severe pain and
agony the other two are going to rush towards you glim as you had
fire breath them one's going to attack for a nine with its bite the
other for a 20 well 20 I'll do it okay that's going to be also 11 piercing
damage oh my god you guys I'm almost dead what you at one what don't do this
to Carla again that's fine yeah we didn't hey Carla
want to level up the three two is enough for you that's good that's good
clean fun is what that is removed it's your turn as yeah as you cast
that last one as these flumps poofed up and out and you feel like you're
anchored to the ground and to the air and to the flames you can feel billowing
down in this pit below and you feel like this extra surge wash over you
like you're more in connected to your spells and to your you're more in
touch unknowingly and inexplicably with nature around you you've leveled
up we'll do stats after this battle if we survive welcome to the middle
what oh I totally just like mmm right in there just like that just like that
you didn't even sing it though that's the thing that gets them to do it so
happy to not see you because that's creepy but you know just know that
you're there in our hearts in our hearts certainly and us in your ears
and maybe you in our Patreon maybe Patreon yes Patreon.com slash dumb
dragon cat we made some changes over Patreon yeah I can has Patreon yeah we
made some changes over there specifically to our fifteen dollar tier
which is awesome sorry is there a label for that tier is that what you were
it's the in world tier yeah that part in where I come in confidently say the
world tier thanks everybody yeah yeah sorry Carla you were gonna take some
actual information I was I was just gonna say if you are a patron at
that tier then we're sort of changing things around but basically you can
submit characters like name, class, race, and a quirk and then those will be NPCs
which will be fun pick make some hard quirk things or like awkward or
embarrassing yeah no awkward or embarrassing yeah please fun
embarrassings fine that doesn't rest has no shame he doesn't he'll do it
it'll be fun he'll just lean into it and it'll be great and sure I'm
something like like Jeremiah is the name elf barbarian shards all the time that
is an interesting work and because he'd have to tell us that that was happening
I guess yeah there'd have to be some Foley effects in there I mean I
thought it would be like talks with an Irish it depends how long you want this
character stick around but the other thing that we're doing at that tier is
items we I mean we were doing items before but again we're opening up the
floodgates so to speak because we've come up with a new mechanic for the
game called Zed Mart because if you shop here you're smart also a little
throwback Canadians might get it Zellers yeah we're real real into the
Canadian we got it you know what that's the only thing we got that's
different is that we're Canadian we're just celebrating the heck out of it
so come over to not Zellers it's Zed Mart because Zellers is Tim but yeah
and stock our shelves so our characters will go there we'll talk
about the items we'll save up our our gold and buy fun things and then shopping
montage and then forgetting montage which is kind of just like the whole
show basically hopefully this will help us remember a bit more yeah our new
fun cool things invented by you so Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
check out that $15 tier if that's not you can't afford that or that's
not quite right for you we'd love to find you at another tier go check
them all out and we'll see y'all next week now let's get you back to that
episode something fun is happening maybe a maze I just assume we're always in a
maze this is mooclimb and sully who's saying that they can't be their first
maze Wow big-time maze yep okay bye everybody
bye all right um I see the two that have gone to attack glim and I kind
of think to myself like boy it would be nice to throw two spells at them
instead of just one and that's what happens so I cast fire bolt towards
well I wish I could cast it towards the two of them but I picked the one
on the right and as I throw this fire bolts its way I managed to throw a
second fire bolt somehow I'm not really sure how it happens to be
perfectly honest with you maybe it's one of those like secret things if you just
you know wish it it'll happen so magic works it's just if you see if you if
you wish it it happens that is how it works so I rolled a 17 for the spell
attack that is do you have to roll again for the second one sure yeah
that probably makes sense 17 I don't even know 17 well assume you would
have to yeah because it's the second second target right so I would
think you'd have to yeah I guess I mean it doesn't say in the little write-up
about twin spell but that makes sense to me 15 for the second both of those
will hit give me some damage all right first one is a nine second ones
an eight all right so nine to the one on the right Nate to the one on the
left these fire bolts go and a glim you smell their flesh char and sizzle like
these things aren't like these things are only about like knee height so like
the flames hit and then the smells just wafts over you but they are shrieking
below as they're chomping at and around you it is Eska's turn you out
of the corner of your eye and then the periphery see all of these snowballs
begin to swarm around Eska and this creature and the creature is going to
crit fail so I'm gonna give them max I'm gonna give them max damage 18
snowball damage just like snowballs like almost like ice balls pelting
into this creature as it's like being moved around by all of these blasts of
cold Sully it seems like everyone's got a handle on these big mouth meanies
so Sully is going to let loose a short bow or she's gonna fling his
short bow into the air at the uh-huh yeah unorthodox I like it mm-hmm I
really like it no he's gonna let loose an arrow at the flying sucker oh for
a crit fail maybe you did actually throw your short bow did I forget how
to do arrows no I think how this is gonna work I'm not killing glim you
can't make me that's the easy Russell kill Carlos character no I think what's
gonna happen in this moment is you pull you draw your your bow back and
the the rope snaps yeah the bow snaps so it like it goes you pull it back
and just before it like the bow breaks and the arrow goes tumbling to
the ground I fact this is I knew I should have had one better well-made
god god he and he just shakes his fist in the air at this bird creature as if
it's its fault okay glim there are char-fried demon creatures in front of
you um are those ones dead or just crispified but still living they are
just crispified still living still chomping still screaming okay I am
going to cast divine favor which will give me an extra D for radiant damage
on a hit and I am going to attack with my war pick okay which is a 17 yeah
17 will hit okay and then come on that's a terrible roll anyway nine
damage with the war pick and then an extra fuck off one radiant damage why
did you do all of Carla's roles for because I didn't get to do my turn tell
me how glim kills one of these mouth mods I assume you went towards the
one that really chomped down into you so yes that seems that seems
reasonable I mean you said they're only about knee high so I guess I
just bring down my massive frightening looking war pick right into the side of
it and maybe it even like gets a little bit like stuck on it and then I have to
like pull it off I like black ichor type blood spurts up and out of it as
it convulses as you leave it stuck on the ground there gross as that
happens beneath the other one glim and beneath the one at Eska's feet both of
you see like this swirling black circle right beneath them it starts slow as
like smoke and dust being kicked up and then spins faster and faster and
faster until there's this hole that begins appearing below them and they
fall into this hole like it's trying to grab and scramble and then as
soon as they're out of sight the holes snap shut and you look up and you see
Charmy standing at her shop holding components in hand moving her hand
back and forth as these holes disappear moot it's your turn the bird
is still in play all right sounds like something that you would say to
someone else that you're meeting for the first time but you're both on like
the secret mission totally I was gonna say it sounds like someone's
like a codename like the bird is still in play the eagle right like we haven't
gotten rid of Judas yet that bird is still in play
fucking Judith I guess I will throw off another magic missile because it
hits every time and it's delightful right all right magic missile coming
at the bird thing once again for four seven ten force damage these magic
missiles strike this bird hard as it's moving to swoop back towards Sully
and knock it into this roof and as you look up and to this roof you see a
dwarven man coming up and over the other side of this peak of this roof
Sully and Glim recognize him as bull nil thunder axe under task and he's
carrying one of the blades of ether that he was describing it's this
shining blue blade that he then drives down and into this creature who lets
out a shriek as it curls around this blade and you see like this light beam
out until the bird flops limp on the roof I rolled my wild magic table just
just cuz it was annoying you're at your one or two and he pulls his blade
up and out and looks down to you I'll be down in a minute
God bow hill thunder under that's good you did a great job hey we know that guy
he climbs down and Charmy comes out of her shop and they're surveying the
scene and they walk over and bull nil comes up to you and says well I
thought you were out to save the world what what why'd you have to bring it
here hey this wasn't us I don't think we
brought this here also that was amazing both of you oh my goodness well
they look like you needed a little assistance oh I definitely do and I sit
down because I'm very weak I broke my bow yeah I don't have any potions or
anything but Charmy comes over to you and says this one this one's on the
house and she casts cure wounds at a very high level and brings you back
up to full thanks Charmy you're the best yeah well we make quite the team
we should all like go on the road together do you guys want to come save
the world with us you weren't mentioned in the prophecy but you're
both amazing well yeah I think we have some cleaning up here to do it's been
a while since we've been on the road together that's not probably a great
idea oh you guys used to adventure together sounds juicy let's dig into
that later is there backstory there do you know what happened here no this pit
these creatures do you know anything about that well that's a points up to
the bird that's a rock a bird demon from the abyss we all know what sound
those make yeah rock yeah exactly and Charmy says and the ones that were
biting at your ankles there they're a ma demons different part of the abyss
seems the wires are getting crossed down there you they're not supposed to
be able to come up and under cities like this well the situation seems
abysmal ha so did you guys used to date or we
shit yeah no I mean you can say that says oh we had a fling a few times we
were out on the road you know we traveled for quite a while yeah some
friends with beneficiary's but friends with friends who
friends who fucked that's right bone in buddy's bone yeah that's what that's
yeah I don't sure what you were trying to say but that's what I was
trying to say yeah yeah mm-hmm nice well no I don't think we can come
with you I think we can help you and he looks down at his blade and then to you
glim and says I asked you if you'd find the other one but maybe if you take
this one it'll help you in your journey
are you sure I know you wanted the other one back maybe maybe we'll find
the other one I can bring them both back if you find the other one I'd
love to see it but there's there's no more traveling in my future
this is for you he puts the blades hilt in your hand and let's go and as
they're having that moment Sully like comes up beside like standing there
expectantly like what presently bestow upon me kind of look on his face magical
weapon am I yeah I could fix your bow so it doesn't break as he's yeah he's
be so great yeah yeah he grabs it yeah just I'll get you on your get you on
your way here I'll take it back and fix that up for you I'll find
something fancy for it thanks Charmy looks to moot and says that was that
was a good shot there you look good you mean to shoot both of them at the same
time there well I thought it would be real nice if I could and then all of a
sudden I did Eska hobbles up behind you say I'm that was a really great
moot Charmy Charmy looks at us oh dear oh dear help this one too here's his
wounds like like hanging half off dragging himself over like the the
group of you stop and discuss your recent encounter not really figuring
out neither of them have any information on why it's happened or how
it has happened just that they are demons from the abyss and this type
of travel straight up into the material plane is both forbidden but also not
supposed to be possible bowl nil fixes your your arrow and it's strong and true
and gives you fills up your quivers so you are back to full on all your
ammunition which I know you totally keep track of totally I keep track of
that for sure every arrow I can see it every time she uses it she makes
note she's got a big whiteboard I know it's weird you don't see it Russ
because you're in the same room with her and she writes marks one
down every time you rest up for the night getting ready to head out the
next day and you fill up get to get some good grub at the rusty bucket the
next morning you walk back out front and Rolf and your carriage are out
front waiting for you I didn't think I'd ever get to see you again and I
do that thing that people do with horses where you press their face up to their
nuzzle that's the word our daughter uses that's what she what is that
the snout snout the muzzle of the horse like the real flat I don't know if
anyone here has ever ridden a horse or anything you they like breathing in
your breath it's weird but so I do that with the donkey it's a real
intimate loving moment that's nice I assume I hold you up so you can do that
donkeys are short and their heads go down they eat off the ground just making
a joke road but maybe you all climb aboard the carriage and set off on the
road to head towards Tamanthir which was where you were heading all along
how to save the world I know I said I wouldn't ask but we almost there yet
the song long road ahead is by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io all
other music and sound effects can be found at epidemicsound.com or
boomlibrary.com a huge thank you to our supporting producers Christian
Brown, Darylith, Devin Michaels, Gabriel Lynch, Jacob Madden, Jessica Babyok,
Catwater Flame, Mark Heartless, and Stevie. To find out more about how you can
support Dumbgeons and Dragons visit us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
where you can have exclusive access to 50 plus hours of bonus audio content
create in-game NPCs and items as well as play games with the cast
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast have a great week and we'll talk soon
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production