Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
.
You lose all light around you regardless of dark vision
Do you continue?
Do I get any weird like vibes? I?
Mean you you get a real will like
Kind of feel they get a real willy you get a real willy you get a real willy
For like so the has flame out and is it just like the flame is still lit
But it's just absolute darkness around it like it doesn't permeate. So it's just like a floating ball of flame
Yeah, like you can't even see it once you step into the star. Oh, you can't even see my flame
No, what's still there?
Okay, right you can feel the heat in your hand or however it normally feels
But yeah, like even the the the light from the flame tongue dissipates as flint walks forward jeez
Do I smell anything funny?
Yeah, it's like a
Yeah, like a musty
kind of like very
damp air kind of
scent and feel
the further in you go and
Do we what do we hear cavey drips?
creeping
Monsters now keep in mind Russ whatever you describe to us you have to then create
No, it's fine. Um
Yeah, you hear
Yeah drips that you would hear in a cave
You hear like soft clicking
Like it's erratic or
Metronomish
sporadic and it's coming at first just from in front of you how you can picture that this is
cavern on either sides of you is
Is is formed around you
But the further in you go you feel like the room opens up and you the clicking like this soft
Is all around you does the cavern get wider as we
Go through how wide was it to begin with like one person width
It was like one person width and it narrowed to a point and I just took it as you were just continuing to yeah
Flint yeah, you step it takes like that. It feels like you walk for about
50 50 meters, so I
Did metric what?
Weird 50 meters. I'm just gonna stick with it. I like doing we're doing metric now
We live in Canada. Damn it. Yeah, we're gonna represent a metric system. Finally
Yeah, you walk for about 50 meters and you it feels like after you a point you feel like a
coolness
Hit your hit your skin and the room feels like it opens up
Still dark
But as you the four of you file in it feels damp and and as you step like it's
slippery and slimy beneath your feet
I
Can I try I don't think it'll work but Yanbal doesn't know that um, can I try to
Cast the spell light toward the clicky clacky sounds sure they're all around you
Which direction would you like to go? Oh, I'm feel very unsettled. I'd me too
I almost don't want the lights to come on. No, it's better. I guess like
Forward and up
So like in in front of us like I can target a creature
I mean
Obviously I don't exactly know where the creatures are or if they even are creatures and would you call someone doing a flamenco dance?
A creature I wouldn't it'd be rude. It would be quite rude. Oh
Unless you're like you beautiful creature. You're right because that would be nice by me
Depending who says it like if a woman said it I'd be like, no, that's nice
And if a guy said it I'd be like, oh, can you know it? Oh, that's actually oh
Do you want to know what it does or do you just want to tell me it's not gonna work sure
Give me give me what it does
It's just cruel. Oh, I'm sorry. I'm
I have to touch it. So I'm not gonna I'm just gonna reach out and touch the wall
I guess or whatever it is. I touch I mean you could touch me if you wanted
The wall rest is like, yeah, it's fine. I already said it. You're right that that would have been smarter
No, so he touched
and
The object sheds a bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet
The light can be colored as you like. It's going to be a beautiful rainbow. Oh
Yeah, you touch the wall and you feel
Like you immediately as you touch it like it's slimy to your fingers and
Like I imagine you put your fault your palm to it. I don't think I put I think you put my fingertips to it
Okay, you put your fingertips to it. What normal person because when you don't know you reach out with your fingertips
Yes, what she feels? Yeah, once she feels the goo. She's not like
spreads her fingers
We don't know yen bull that often she could be a real freak
Sometimes just likes a gooey gooey sticky feel of ooze between your fingers this episode was supposed to be more progressive
But we're just gonna focus on this made it one foot into this room
Welcome to being in this
Pyramid maze forever. Yeah
You touch your fingers and you feel this slime like fold over them as you press
Into the wall and then you feel something move as you cast light like it moves around your face
It feels small like a size of a like a fist size stone
but also
Smooth and slimy as it moves past you and you cast light and you you see that rainbow
illumination
Come out and it illuminates you you can see yourself and you can see
Just where your fingers touch the wall and this figure a small fist sized figure with like
purplish brown skin
looks at you with its one eye and then zips out of the darkness and
Then as it zips it zips out into the darkness and as you lose sight of it the entire room becomes
Not brightly lit
But you're able to instantly see everything around you and you see
hundreds of unblinking eyes
staring up at you
From the long walls of glistening green stone the floor of this chamber
Climbing up the walls is this viscous slime that drips from four stalagmites
You
Gross do you mean stalactites?
Yes, stalactites they come from the top hang tight. No it drips from four stalagmites
from
From those say so down the sides of them. Yeah, yeah, this makes I don't like that either
I like that less like volcano
And it's dripping down
Tell you how she doesn't like me what I say and I say what I mean, okay, it's the lagmites
Goddamnit
But they seem to be friendly us they're just or at least not unfriendly
They are just staring at you these hundreds of eyes all around this room
Can I
Scan calmly and look for the exit you can
Make an investigation check
Investigate the shit out of this
13 13
Okay with the light from
flame tongue and the fire that you can now see in your hand and the
Rainbow
Illuminescence from yen bulls light beautiful by the way
You look out into the room and all of this light
About another
50 meters begins to dissipate and it gets darker
towards the center of this room and you look back to the cavern that you walk through and
It appears
Like a loop I can extend it like almost like kaleidoscope effect
You see an opening down at the far end of a hallway, but it seems like it's hundreds
Hundreds of meters away. Sorry. That's when we just came down when you just came through like it seems like it's forever away
And we do see another similar or it's sorry
We just see darkness you head you see like the room opens up wide and about 50 meters. You see
the
You see like this darkness kind of rolled down right at that 50 meters. I think we have to continue
going I
Think so too. What else what else do we do we cannot?
just
Stay here. Oh, there's so much goo you guys. It's so I touched it. I wish I had not
Although I'm happy for the light. I wish I had not
Stuck my fingers. Well, I think that might have been like kind of like, you know turning the lights on
Let's hope
These small creatures are friendly
Um as I look at the one-eyed creatures, do I know what they are?
Yes, good question make an arc and a check I
Rolled a nat 20 old in 19
Damn, I think we know things. I'm not even gonna roll
with a nat 20 especially
you recognize them as
You recognize their their makeup and their structure it looks kind of
Beholder ish, but you've never seen one this small. Oh god. We're like in a beholder baby nest
Yan bull
Do these look a little familiar to you?
I am sorry to say they do they look like you know a beholder
These are just but like tiny right like tiny babies. I wonder where's where mama is
yes, exactly what I was thinking what if mama comes home and there is
There is all these hundreds of babies. It is a bad place to be between the mama and her babies now
Are they literally?
Everywhere like we have to wade through them. They're only on the walls. Okay. Oh, I don't like that. I
Think I like that worse. Yeah
But it's all jelly on the floors, yeah, it's like this slimy ooze
After birth
Tom's face
Flint's just silence like fuck what am I what am I doing here?
I guess we just maintain a steady pace and try not to
Make anything too excited to the fact that we're here
It's a good plan
Yes, yes slow and steady
Maybe we just we walk forward
slowly
I'm imagining like flints may be looking forward Diaz looking to one side yen bulls looking to the other
Manix is looking behind
Cuz we're kind of surrounded by these little one-eyed thingies and just slowly and cautiously
Cautiously
Walking forward no sudden movements. No loud noises. Nice steady pace. He is talking sweet
Oh, you guys look so calmly
Probably nap time with every step you take the eyes follow you
On your location until you get there are four of these stalagmites as I said in there
Further in you walk you have to walk around them
and you get between them and that
This it's the further in you walk you lose out of the periphery with this darkness effect
that is following you and you get between these stalagmites and
it
Sucks up around you you lose sight of all the unblinking eyes
You see just the edge of these stalagmites and the ooze dripping down and then all around you
a voice echoes you hear this like
What are you doing here Oh
Just passing through just quietly
Peacefully
Passing through the nursery
Almost from right behind you Thea the voice
again says
No one just passes through here. Oh
God
well
May I ask why?
Because here and then the voice is behind Yen bull
Is where people come to be eaten?
Oh
Well, they would prefer not to be eaten we like strike a deal or something
We would love to just continue on our way and get out of get out of your
Out of your way, please
What?
Do you have to offer me?
What do you most desire
It's a bold strategy we probably don't have that but let's find out let's find out. Mm-hmm
How can you procure something so grand?
Well, what's grand to some might not be grand to others what is it you wish
There's a pause and then the clicking comes again
As if from behind each of you separately like this thing is moving in the darkness around you gross
And then the voice comes from all around you again as if from above
It says I wish for my freedom
I
Well, don't I have some news for you but first why why would why do you want to be free?
Would you like to be locked in a cage with hundreds of your spawn for eternity? No, it sounds awful. I'm so sorry. I asked
Well, we are here to
essentially
Liberate everybody from this flying fortress
That includes you mama
There's a long pause
And then that you hear that
clicking again all around you and like this whoosh or flit through the darkness and
And
Then like this
Murmured wine starts to well up in the room
And then it's silent all at once
By liberation do you mean death
Because so far you have brought death to everything
Well, I mean and
Yanbal Flint, I'm sure you guys will back back me up here, but
Well those things
Didn't talk to us as you have and
display the
kind of intelligence and
You know
Emotional state that you have we've been
Attacked at every turn since we've come here. So
We come peacefully unless otherwise provoked as I'm sure
You do too
Also, those zombies were totally undead. They weren't getting out of here alive. Anyway, I
Do feel for the sea creature though
The abelith of equal intelligence
Equal intelligence slightly lesser I was gonna say could have helped you
It struck first
There's long pause again you hear dripping and like
Movement in the ooze
Listen we just kind of assume that you are all working with the lich what
Are you here for?
We're here for we're here for the amulet of wonder
And to kill that fucking lich
Well, I don't think he's gonna just give it to us, but maybe he will make
Now that we know that there are
beings here held
People you know against their will I feel like it's more than that now
Things are summoned here to prevent people like you to get through to Shangalar
Summoned here against your will
There's the sound of movement behind you yen bull
and
you look to either side and you see the darkness begin to
Fold back you see more of the stalagmites and even
Goes up to the wall where you still see those unblinking eyes staring up at you
Do you specifically turn around right away or do you just keep looking in the direction you're looking?
I
Don't know that I would turn around
Then Thea and Flint and Mannix you see as this this darkness unfurls from your location a
Wait
You said that we recognize them as beholders
Like beholders you didn't get no one had ever seen
Right a teeny-tiny beholder, but do we know like what a beholder can do
Now that we know what the creature is
She rolled a net 20
I'm just saying no because if it's like don't look at it in its eye otherwise
It's gonna freeze you to death or something like that and that's information that we should have had before I think it's important
No, yes good question that the net 20. I'll give you more information on the beholders so beholders generally
In the strictest sense of terms have 10 eye stocks and one main core eye
With a net 20 you know that they don't breed
Beholders are dreams of other beholders so it's dreamed all these hundreds of dreams into being well
We assume well it has been yes certainly
Unfortunate and seems like a them problem, but whatever
Anything else you want to know about the beholder yet looking at them
It doesn't there's no Medusa effect that you know of
But each eye stock does have a different
Ability that when activated can do anything from charm up to death
Right this one just kills ya yeah, but as the light rolls back
Thea Flint and Mannix you see
Hovering above and just behind yen bull a
purple skinned
mottled
Beholder large eye in the center and two of its eye stocks appear to have been
maimed or damaged in some way
You think you can destroy Shangri-La
We've done crazier stuff I mean I mean we did fight team at yeah
and survive
Well mostly for the most part we do not know that we can beat Shangri-La, but we must try
He destroyed Kallen port sounds like he brought you here against your will
What else can we do but fight?
Interesting do you not want to fight for your freedom?
rather than
Being here with all of your dream children forever. I would fight for my freedom
And I would fight Shangri-La with you however. I am bound to this
cavern
Is there a specific way to unbind you
Maybe a magic orb or something or something that we could smash and and you could
break free and come help out in the
crux of the battle I
Have been cursed and there is a key
Feel like this is a side side quest side side side quest
Shit
Guys, I don't know what my goal is anymore. Yeah, sorry. We'll spend three years doing the side quest
I will come
We've got to find this key for this beholder I
Will help clear the way if you can release me
The key was sent to the OTOX layer. Do I know what an OTOX is?
Yeah, you fought one
No, no
Is it one of those those
Things that can change into the child no, okay. No no no an OTOX is a like a giant
like garbage monster
Eats basically everything trash monster basically a trash monster huge like almost like well
It's like hippo like formation, but like giant huge claw or teeth
and gaping ma
cool and generally
People use them to dispose of trash
Neat so the garbage room awesome. Yeah
Well, you know what I'm sure that there are many different layers of this
Pyramid
And we happen to find ourselves in a lot of the the dangerous bad ones so odds are
We will end up with the OTOX. Do you know what the key looks like?
All right, maybe it'll be we know when we see it kind of thing
Do you do you get to speak with any of the other creatures had that have been?
Summoned here against their will there are rumbles through the walls that warn of passers
Would you be able to
Rumble a little message forward that we are on the side of on your side
That we would like to not battle at every turn, but save our strength to to fight
Shangalar
We would prefer to
Gather our strength and fight Shangalar
Instead of instead of all of you who have
Really nothing you have nothing in this battle, but your freedom
Can you do that?
How do I know you will come back with the key
Well now that I know we have to come back with the key that's an important piece of the information
I thought maybe it was an orb we could smash or like
Smash or like, you know something like a something that we can mess up
we will
because you because having a powerful beholder like you on our side during this fight would be
Unbelievable, it could tip the scales. You could be the difference between
Winning and setting all these creatures free or us losing persuasion check. I
Think I'm being pretty earnest
Um
Seventeen
You see the darkness lift around this room and
In the direction you were walking you see four caverns
I will tell you which one to go down
Now
Thank you, do you have a name
Yes
I'm thea
I'm yen bull flight and i'm manic's
It floats up higher into the room
And says I am for booksy
you
Thank you for booksy
We'll meet again
We will return with this key and you will help us fight for freedom
The beholder before you squints
The eyes
Around the walls flitter between you and the beholder
I'm watching watching mommy have an important conversation. Uh-huh
You look back to the caverns that became clear and now there is only one
We'll hurry then and for buxy moves higher up towards the ceiling and you lose sight of them in the darkness
Um
I walk forward to the the one exit that we have and as we do I go
Oh my god, I can't believe that worked you guys
That was awesome
You carry forward through the room
The slime squishing beneath your feet the eyes following you as you continue to walk towards this singular passageway before you
You carry through and it winds down a long dark corridor
You walk for
Several minutes
before you see
Light the floor beneath you gets less and less covered in slime the farther you walk
You see light shining up ahead
and the sound of
Chomping
like grinding of teeth
and
sludge
Like being forced, you know, like you slurp mud through your hands
Like say you were some kind of trash eating monster. Maybe maybe
excellent
Perhaps we can find the key sooner than I had thought
Yeah, I kind of thought there'd be a few more to get to but
How hard could it be
Well for you you have fought a dragon it is probably not so hard but it is a a fierce disgusting creature like
I'm thinking like needle in a haystack or we uh fought one of these a long time ago
And they've got a lot of uh
Well, there's a lot of like teeth on their tentacles and they got really strong chompers in the kind of the center there and
I want to say something to do with like
Mind powers as well, but it's it's been so long. Oh, this is good news
I too can speak telepathically to creatures that can speak telepathically
We could have maybe another creature on our side. Perhaps we can talk to the garbage monster
Maybe you don't call him a garbage monster though when you talk to him. Oh, yeah, that's probably good
All right our um, are we ready?
Does anyone do you think?
I suppose we are as ready as we were going to be. Yes. Yeah
You carry forward and the passage opens up more as you walk along the light gets brighter and inside you see this
yellow
Illuminescence
Lighting this room you see heaps and heaps of garbage and dung
And beyond you see movement of a large creature like the back of it over one of these mounds
you see
Cut through and like a passageway through you see
skeleton walk by
carrying
a mound of
You can't quite put your finger on what it is nor would we want to or would you want to
But carrying it over you see it
Walk by with this material
You hear like this drop sludge drop and then the skeleton walks back in the same direction that it went
Um, so as you walk in
You're like face to face with a perimeter of this
Bile and feces and just garbage material you can see through and over a little bit to see
At least one creature
To get around it. You'd either have to go over it or
There is pathway around either side in order to walk around the garbage refuse
How tall is it?
um
If you can see kind of in spots over it like it's probably going to be between five and six feet and then another
10 to 15 feet like deep
Into the room
And areas it is piled much higher
As you walk around
Or as you as you know as you look down
What if?
You had a magic carpet
And you didn't have to
Trudge through the bile and feces as you just described it
I mean, it's what it is
Careful carly's gonna do something awful to your magic carpet. I know
I can't just trudge through the grossness. Yeah when you have an option not to walk through
Shit
You gotta take it. How far away is the creature from me?
um
You could probably say from where you can see it that it's about
50 feet away
And I can see it's like the it's back. Yeah, you can kind of see it like moving
You know the back of it moving towards one of these piles
Um, then i'm going to reach out to it telepathically
Um, because I can do that up to 60 feet, okay
Um, and we don't need to share a language if it can also speak telepathically. Yes
Hello, please do not be alarmed
We are entering your home
Please do not hurt us
You haven't magic carpet lifted yet. You're just still standing on the ground
I didn't want to like start just like up here and startle it exactly. Hello. Um watching the the creature you
I'm gonna say that you sense two
You now sense two creatures when you reach out telepathically within this range
And you see the one that you were you had eyes on like raise its head and its tentacles move up
And it begins to look around and says who who's there?
Hey, we're in the middle now nice to see you
How's everybody doing?
Amy's dying. Amy's dying. I'm dying. It's too hot hot. Everyone's melting
You know whenever it is too hot. I always think ah, remember when it was not too hot and I was like
I'll never say that it's too hot
Now's one of those days when i'm like, ah, but maybe it's a little too hot
I don't really feel like I ever say that because I I just want temperate like this is why I live in a temperate climate
I just want it to be not too cold and not too hot like mid-20 celsius for
ideals
For summer perfect. Yeah, it's good five degree day. That's 25 would be like 80. Whatever the number is. It's like comfortable
Yeah, it's it's warm enough. You can go swimming and my garden still grows, but it's not so hot that you
Think you're gonna perish exactly like right right now me. So that's what we're talking about today is how we're all
Perishing from the heat and how we're gonna take a few weeks off coming up in august
Uh four to be exact, uh, we won't be releasing episodes of our own
Starting august 12th through september 2nd. We'll be back with new episodes on september 9th
But no need to fret you're not going to go without anything in your ears
We have some pretty cool swapsies going on
We do we partnered with some of the fable and folly network to bring you some new shows
We don't want to reveal all the details quite yet just to make sure that you have something to look forward to
But there's some pretty cool shows that we think you're going to like
Some that are in line with what we do. Actually. No, that's not true
None of them are in line with what we do. They're entirely new stories entirely new
Producers and we think they're just really awesome and we want to share them with you totes
You're gonna like it. It's like our your little summer vacation from us
You get to go hear new and exciting things and then come back to your old favorites
Us, yeah, it's like you're doing the reddit secret santa exchange
And you're getting a new podcast to listen to instead. Yes
It's like you're going on like our metaphors are overnight camp. Keep it going amy. These are so good
And and you're spending some time away
And you're going to change and you're going to experience new things. You're going to come back
You're going to be different but a better version of yourself
It might be like that
It's like when you go to your grandparents house because your parents don't want to see you anymore
This might be the most accurate one
But they but your grandparents make you go to bed at six o'clock because that's when they go to bed
No, no, no, no, no, you're going at this the wrong angle
They let you eat mcdonald's they let you do all this stuff
You're not allowed to do at home and at first you're like this is amazing
I love this so much. I never want to go back home. Then after a while you actually crave old mom and dad
Consistency. Yeah. Yeah
That's what we bring to you
Dumbgeons and Dragons homie vibe
That's what we've got so long story short all these analogies aside
We have some really cool shows that we're going to bring to your ears
Throughout august and the beginning of september before we bring you some new episodes
and
more adventures
So we hope you enjoy them all and please once you hear them, uh, go
Check them out because they're all amazing creators
And I think you're going to love all of the stories that they've got coming your way
And now let's get back to this episode mommy and daddy. Love you
We will miss you so much while we're away
And we're looking forward to seeing you. No, we're still here next week. We're still here next week
That's true. We're just prepping you right? That's what it's gonna feel like you're like what it's goodbye already, but no not yet
But soon next week, we got that cool guy keith amann on the show. Oh wait, that's happening too
So we've got that coming up super fun. Then we'll say a formal. Goodbye later. It's fine
He really knows how to play dnd. He wrote the books about it and it's amazing. You're gonna love it
Okay back to this episode. We're done talking to you. Okay. Bye. Bye. So it's kind of like
Like
Hello, my name is yenbo
What is your name?
we
We don't have
What
Is this your home you hear stomping of feet and then the second one comes into view and they're looking around at each other
Yes home food
I'm going to appear do not be surprised. Okay, so I take out the carpet and I say yeah tear
And then it is flying we can get on it
Oh, I oh I hop on see is like my friends come on on I am I'm trying to communicate with the creatures
So hopefully they do not immediately attack. Does anyone have anything?
Delicious they could offer the creatures
Oh
Thea um goes into her bag and shamefully pulls out like
like a double
cloth wrapped sack of like
Bad cheese and bread that she's been meaning to toss
But like hasn't just in case you get desperate. Yeah
Well, she's like I think if she were in high school in the bond with the back
She'd have quite the messy locker like there is a questionable top of our container back there
Yeah, so that's it she hands you her questionable topperware container
Okay, you rise up above the filth and the awful and the the stench as you rise
it
It you didn't like it was it was a bad smell
But the higher up you go it is just rancid in this room
And as you clear these piles you see these two creatures who then turn
To your direction you see their tentacles waving wildly towards you
and they
Look to you and then begin
Like stomping like almost like a dog does when it's excited about you going towards the treat cabinet
That's kind of the picture. I want to paint here
Food you brings food
Give food
What is your favorite kind of food food?
There we go
That could have been a dangerous question. Yeah
But but
What are you going to do for the food?
Do we eat food?
Yes food. Yes, I have much food for you, but
I'm looking for a key
Do you know this key?
They cock their head and their tentacles kind of wave around
Can we go?
Like because we're still quite a ways away
But close enough that I can like tear off a couple of pieces of bread and throw one to each of them
Sure. Yeah, you could like a little move around and as everybody else I assume first taste is free
That's right. I assume yamble you're focused on the two creatures. Everybody else. Are you looking around the rest of the room?
I'm on key duty. Yeah. Yeah, I figure i'd be looking around like maybe it's hanging from a wall somewhere
Sure. Yeah you uh
Make an investigation check as you're looking around
Went great nine it was it was on 17
And then flick to the seven. It could have been a 19. It's not super strong 15
Stronger than a nine
Huh? This is true. How about Mannix? What's that dead weight doing that world of two? Yeah, right?
You know why he touched a mirror and now he hasn't been the same since he's useless
Has anyone else noticed that?
Totally. God damn it. All of a sudden. He doesn't know his daughter's dead and he's like
Life's great. I have no motivation to be helpful, right? Why am I even here? I don't know. It's fine
I just thought i'd help these weirdos
Um, okay, you're looking around the room flint you catch eyes on
Uh on this skeleton that you saw and it's walking back and towards the like the right as you're looking in the room
Uh, you see a crack in the wall and you see this skeleton like disappear
Beyond it, uh thea you're looking around and it's just
Everywhere is just piles of this refuse. I just say to flint what a dump
Um, okay back to Yenbul. Sorry, uh, you toss a piece of food
Yeah a piece of uh
A bread to each of them
Um, they snatch it up and say it's barely there
If you want the good food, I want your help
What?
I am looking for a key
They look around you know what key is
uh
Yeah
key
Give food. I give key. Well, let me see key. I give food
Make a persuasion check
It's a good old fashion persuade off. Yeah, it's a good old fashion
You give me the goods first and then i'll give you the stuff
I have advantage on persuasion roles. Of course you do. That first one was 20
Not a nat 20 and then a bad roll. So let's go with 20
What you give
What food more little food?
We eat you
No, you don't eat me
Yeah, we ate others
No, why would you eat others they put in pile
We eat
one of them begins to move over and is like
nosing through the refuse
You find key
It stops and looks back at you never mind
And goes back to going through the piles
I have this very delicious stinky cheese
Is small but very delicious
Small need more and then begins to walk over to another pile of refuse and nosing through it
You hear the clacking of
Bones flint at the wall you were watching there where the skeleton disappeared and you see the heads of two skeletons
uh begin to enter the room
while these uh otx are
Nosing through this refuse they haven't explicitly said they're looking for the key, but you get a feeling that that's what they're doing
Um, I guess I should tell uh flint and thea what's going on because they are not hearing this telepathic conversation
They I I think they are looking for the key they want food they want more food. What else do we have?
Good question. Um
I mean, I look in my pack. I mean we certainly all have like rations rations and food with us
Yeah, like any prized christmas hams that maybe I forgot about in my stack
Maybe you seem like a man who carried like a lot of meat around with him, you know
That is certainly true a lot of cured meat. Yeah like flint's turkey legs
The two skeletons at this point you see that they're carrying
um
piles of
like animal carcass and like plant like decaying plant refuse and
um
That type of material and they walk to the center of this room and both of them drop it without paying any attention to you
And turn and leave the room
And the otx stop turn
Uh to the material and run over to it and say they brought more food no job
And they begin eating the material I made this food come
You asked for food. I asked for key. You look for key. I make food appear
Um, how does the magic carpet work?
Like if it were to have if you were to have to make a dexterity saving throw
Would it be you that would have to make that?
I think so that makes sense. She controls the carpet. Yeah, so um
It moves according to my spoken direction, okay, so it's a deck. Yeah, so i'm controlling a deck saving throw then
Nat 20 fuck yeah plus three and I get a plus one on save so 24
Uh
Right before this tentacle jumps out at you the otx says
Go find better more food and then this tentacle snaps out trying to grab the magic carpet, but you whip back
So
You want more food?
I bring good more bigger food. You give me key
Yes, like this food and they are eating the food that the skeleton brought it or food quote unquote
Yeah
Um, it's the only exit this like crack in the wall where the skeletons are emerging to and from you would have seen
I like that. We're going on a side quest of our side quest of our side. Oh, yeah
A lot of side questing happening here
um
Yeah, there's uh, so off to uh the right in the room
you saw where the skeletons were coming to and from off to the left flint thea and
Manix you would have by this point seen that there is a another opening off into the left
They want more food bigger food rotten dead food
oh
um
Do we go forward try to kill creature bring creature back give to them or
Do we go back the way we came get giant dead ogres?
Oh
How do we get them back here?
I don't know. What's a dead ogre way ross
Give me the weight on a dead ogre or the dead or the giant creature. Yeah
Oh the apple probably like five or six hundred pounds
Then that's no problem. The magic carpet can carry 800 pounds. Shit
You suck should have been like one million pounds sucker
But I don't know if we want to go back
If we want to go back past the beholder
Past the creatures get large dead thing and bring here
If
I mean
If that's how we get the key
Should we all go?
Will there be room to carry it back on the magic carpet?
I will state that the cavern to get into oh shit was really small layer became very small
Right. Oh, we can't get big things. That is a good reminder. Thank you. Um
That would have sucked to go back there pick up the body bring in then russ being like nah
Bro, the opening describes it as you have to squeeze back through this cavern
It up into little pieces first
There's that um, there's a whole episode of us. Just just cutting up mutilating bodies do
Like I can conjure like I know that's what I was just i'm just looking at my spells to see what I do
I bring an animal into this world just to be eaten by one of these things like
Like
It feels it feels really wrong doesn't seem like a super druidy thing to do well flint. That's really judgmental
I don't tell you how to be a fighter. Well, uh, I mean, what's the plan?
The song long road ahead is by Kavin mcleod of incompetech.film music.io
All other music and sound effects can be found at epidemic sound.com or boom library.com
A huge thank you to our supporting producers gabriel lynch joshua dixon cat water flame devin michaels jacob madden christian brown
stevie jessica babyuk and darylith to find out more about how you can support Dumbgeons and Dragons visit us at Patreon.com
Slash dumb dragon cast where you can have exclusive access to 50 plus hours of bonus audio content
Create in-game NPCs and items as well as play games with the cast
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast. Have a great week and we'll talk soon. Yeah
Really your highness kind of thing like minotaur and a strap on there
Okay
Whoa
Wow, the fucking will begin
Hold is this the fuck room? No, maybe it's dark. Uh, let's play who's in my mouth
Uh
Do I do I smell any weird
Jesus christ you guys go into a fuck room one time and you don't even bring me
Is all around you now based on your hand motions i'm imagining it's a castanet no i'm just
A tiny mariachi band surrounded by flamenco dancers. It's incredible
We feel them whooshing past us in beautiful spins, what if he was your guy?
Um, then i'd probably be like what?
DJ i'm gonna give aiden a call after this
Every single family needs to start calling me a beautiful creature. That's right
And be really weird about it. Yes
winks
tongue licks
Fingers tapping together you beautiful creature. I don't know. This is all horrible
It's almost your anniversary. So please give him these hot tips
So many hot tips if you want to make it 10 years like we have just had my 10 year anniversary, buddy
Here's what you gotta do. Let me give you some advice
May I ask what happened?
I can't remember what the first fucking question was. Hold on. He was they were gonna say something
Oh, right. I'm sorry. I interrupted you. Yeah
You just asked if yen bull turns around right away. Yeah. I know
Yeah, I was gonna do like a like a says something cool. Oh, i'm sorry. It's all right. It's gone
Um, I mean just note this as a part where you want that to happen
Yeah, and when you remember at like 11 35 editing it say something cool
cool
and then the beholder's just like
Something cool
sup bitches
You did it
It sounds so out of place though to fight shango bar
Shang shango boy shango boy. Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production