Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons, I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More, he, him, also with me today is Amy
More. Yeah, she, her playing myself. And Carla Maxted. Also she, her also playing myself also sitting in the same room as Russ and Amy. We're touching legs like all the time over here. We're sharing an armrest right now. It's incredible. And Tom Laird is still representing the Victoria Guild. Yeah, yeah, that's me. He, him and also playing me. And joining us today is Kyle Glassett. Hey, hey, he, him just
being myself. Yeah, love it. We're all here to celebrate and wrap up. I would say season two, but really, it's season one and season two. We did a little prank there. Tricked ya. Were they? Gotcha. Two became one. Yeah, yeah, yeah. We are recording with all of our patrons today. If you want to be at events like this, you can join us on Patreon because just because the season's done doesn't mean the
show's over. We're going to be releasing more content and a season three at some point in the future. We'll talk more about that. That's your hook to keep listening. What a good, I used to be in radio. Can you tell? But yeah, join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast. And thank you for everyone who is here. We love you all so very much. And you're all, you all say very nice things and the dog is going to be painting
here shortly. Somebody VAMP. Oh, my goodness. I mean, painting or? Yes, I think he said painting. No, I think painting. He's never once touched my paint supplies. And now I want to. He said to VAMP. But what I want to do is get up and go see what's happening because for once I'm in the room so I can see. The room where it happens. Exactly. Right. So I did a little tally before we started recording. And that's really what the technical issue was. No, it was it was much bigger than that. But counting by five
times is hard. Pulled pulled some dates. So season one started in January 3rd of 2017. So we've been doing this for a very long time and ran until May 15th, 2019. Seemed like a long season at the time. Did. Yeah. I was only 83 episodes, 84 if you include the Q&A that we did. Wow.
Season two started in June on June 5th of 2019. Notably, Kyle Claset joined us in November 13th, 2019. It does not seem that long ago, but dang it was. It was so long ago. It turns out it's a long time already.
From like the before times you were recording with us. That's how long ago it was. That's wild. That's why you're a regular cast member. We met Kyle in person. That's true. That was the whole impetus of the situation as we had met out in L.A. and had a good time at the Wizards at the Coast event. And then it was like, let's play D&D together. The rest was history. Let's do it. Why not? And then, of course, season two ended.
Just this last week here, September 27th, 2023, with 155 episodes. That didn't quite double. We're doing it right, right? So season three will be like a 289 episode season we're on track for.
So total episodes we've done so far, 278. I just like numbers because this is what I do for my day job, is look at how big podcasts get. And in that, 892,146 downloads.
That's a big number. Y'all are nuts. That's crazy. That's because of you guys. That is unbelievable. Russ, those KPIs are amazing. Yeah, really? The ROI, the KPIs, the element of P's? Yeah, we're just checking it.
Now there's a new way to measure it is how many cumulative hours people have spent listening to us. Are you ready for this one? No. It's more than you think. 573,564 hours cumulatively.
That works out to 24,898 days, 797 months, or 66 cumulative years. Wow, jeez. You guys have listened to us for like somebody's lifetime. Yeah, to retirement age. That's crazy. That's amazing. I don't know how I feel about that. That is wild.
Like, I feel good. Oh, I love it. But also, yeah, but it's like staggering at the same time. That's wild. That's the right word. Yeah, it's a lot. And I just wanted to start with this before we dive into all the reflection and the what did we forgets and all of that sort of stuff.
Yes, looking forward to that section. Just say thank you to our patrons and to our listeners and to everyone for being here with us. Because without you listening to us for 66 years, it might not have happened the same way, right?
Can you imagine? It never got off the ground. Nobody was listening. We all got kind of busy with our lives. We were in Korea. And then maybe, you know, we stopped playing as frequently. So many things. Well, I wouldn't be sitting here because I would not live here. Absolutely not. No chance.
Did we owe all of our, like, best friendships? Would I have even met my husband? Like, let's be real. A lot has happened in the run of this podcast. We owe so much to these people. Geez. Life changers. It's wild. You guys are. Season three is going to be bomb, you guys. You've earned it.
We haven't been trying yet. We're going to really try this time. That's right. Just you wait till we unleash it. That's right. We're going to learn how to play D&D starting with season three. Get ready for the practice.
I mean, Jess says she never would have met her boyfriend. So thanks for that. See? Life changing stuff. You guys, everybody's connected. I know. Get all deep and emotional stuff.
I did structure Kyle's question document to end with comments that we're all going to read. It's just the fucking nicest things that people have said. So we will probably cry by the end. So just prepare yourselves for that.
But to open and before I throw it to Kyle here, an open question to the audience and to the group. Feel free to drop them into the chat or into the Q&A section, probably the Q&A section, because that'll help Kyle be able to pull them quicker.
What were the highlights? We've said the life highlights. What were the highlights of season two for you? Could be a scene, could be a goof, could be an arc, could be anything. Amy's got notes.
Guys, I prepped. I don't prep for shit. I did not. I moved two days ago. I got nothing. Well, not I've got nothing. I'm still going to say something. You can just say ditto to everything that I say if you want to.
There are a couple from some people who pre put in. So I'll start there from Chris Sifnakis. Thank you, Chris. Their favorite was when the two shows, so the two streams merged was the favorite moment.
I think he even tweeted to me about it, which I do remember where, yeah, Mook, Clem, and Sully decapitate a dragon, a lich dragon.
That was a badass way to come into a timeline. Yeah, I think that was even surprise to you all, right? Because we didn't talk about that before, did we?
No, no, we didn't talk about it at all.
Yeah, yeah. Great cool moment to be able to build towards, like had it on the docket, working our way through. Did anybody jump in?
Well, I got stuff. Well, you said you did, and then you put your phone down. And then you started talking, so I was giving you the stage.
My mind is only filled with moments. It doesn't, it doesn't pick up whole things, but a few of them is how thinking about a bag of dicks will stop someone from reading your mind.
Yeah.
And that's just life lessons I've brought into my own personal business. So Sully's Night Garden, I think about that daily at least.
Like I have, if I was any sort of artist, I have it all, I would have it all sketched out. I know exactly what it looks like in my mind.
That's fair.
When Tom chose a claw for his mage hand and we were all like,
so committed. Yes. To the end.
And now, whenever I think in a one shot, I had a mage hand and I had to make it a crab claw. Like I can't even conceive of it not being a crab claw.
Absolutely. You've changed the game, Tom.
I bought Baldur's Gate 3 and I've been playing it lately. And yeah, you can cast mage hand in it and then it shows up as a little hand and every time I'm like,
do these people not use their imaginations or what?
No, you can summon a familiar that is a crab. And I will look more into that.
Futurama for mine and name him Citizen Citizen Snips.
Excellent. And when Sully invented pizza, because that's now just how pizza was invented.
Yeah, that was fun. And this was a long season.
I did deep.
It's a piece of food.
I have a few. The Pirate Isles, Pirate Isles mix up was one of my that we just like completely steamrolled brats and we're like, we're not doing your fucking thing.
And it's not often we do that either. Usually we're like, we follow direction fairly well.
We try to be considerate of like his plan and the effort that he's put in. And so like, no, we're going to a store.
We want to shop, bitches.
Hominem Sucka. Yeah. Yeah.
When Sully used the scroll and like actively gufied our low level enemies.
That was really bringing some chaos that was like some game time kind of energy.
And I like, yeah, I just I don't know if I would ever use the scroll otherwise, you know, like you got to just use it.
They know what it was going to do. They know I forget that stuff a lot.
So I used it and I don't no regrets. No, of course not.
They deserved it. I don't regret blasting those guys that touch Rolf like that's the other one is a donkey gate.
That was the right thing to do.
I mean, it wasn't it was dumb, but it was the right thing for Glim to have done.
Yeah, I don't know if Kyle knows that one.
So for a couple, we should fill in a little context.
So we were on like a sneak mission to go and collect something, to collect something else, to do a thing, you know, D&D.
And MacGuffin, you know, et cetera.
And we didn't know they must have been from Cult of the Dragon. Yeah.
I think so, because Sully was hiding from them.
Yeah, it was all disguised.
It was the yeah, it was the two that in like the opening scene with Sully that were like telling you to kill the family.
So Sully had escaped from the Cult of the Dragon.
And there was these two guys and they ran into us in this town and we were driving with our donkey and they touched the donkey.
And I like straight fire breathed them like blast.
Like in the face.
No warning.
Absolute zero to one hundred.
I mean the role made it much more aggressive.
Because he rolled great.
Oh, that's great.
But still it was like very much glimpsed.
Like these are my people and like absolutely.
You don't touch them.
No.
Get your hands off my ass.
I think we've got a few in the Q&A that are popping in.
We do. We do.
So to throw it back before I got really excited before we actually started recording and doing things.
So we're going to take it back to the top with Kat Waterflame's question of was there anything that you wanted to have happen that didn't.
And it also has to be something that can't be brought into a new season.
Well, I mean, we're going to we're going to talk more about season three towards the end.
But season three is going to be very not connected to the world.
So basically anything and everything.
Right.
We're saying what didn't happen that.
That's a good question.
I never get to find out what that fucking druid book was all about.
Never.
And I never will.
And I will.
I will be sour and bitter and all the flavors about that until I die.
I can't help it that you're a scribe who never said they opened the book and then you threw it and sacrificed it.
I thought that's what you wanted.
I'm a people pleaser.
I mean, when she decided to do that, I was absolutely of the mindset that that is what you wanted her to do.
It seemed like that was the way to solve the puzzle.
Thank you.
And you know how bad we are at solving puzzles.
We didn't know yet how bad we were at solving puzzles.
That was part of the information.
I thought it was this.
It was like you have to sacrifice something.
I'm like, this could open up like this could unlock my past, my future.
Turns out my husband's a dick.
Was in Rise of Tiamat season one there, Kyle.
So they go into this this abandoned citadel and they get through and the cult or whoever is there is having to make sacrifices to this divining pool to get wishes and get insight and future visions, that sort of thing.
But as the pool gets more and more things like the the scale of which you have to sacrifice keeps escalating.
Like, you know, when you're playing Mario Party and you give one coin to the swamp and then the next person has to give more than one coin to the swamp.
It's like that.
So I was not I had zero thought in my mind that they were sacrificing a book.
I was like, there are dead bodies all around.
They're missing body parts like I'm like, you need to sacrifice like flesh to be able to get this out of here.
And then like a book.
I do not believe he said flesh.
There was implications.
You go back.
There's implications that say that there should have been flesh.
I'm pretty good at breaking old subtext.
The clue's right there.
Yep.
But yeah, I got the book, which threw me.
So we had to rerecord that scene because the initial response I gave because I was like, they fucking threw a book in there.
I was like, well, you got nothing because it's a book.
Which sent Amy off the deep end.
I have never been so mad in a D&D game.
Like it was I was I'll I'll be willing to admit this.
I was unreasonably angry.
I was like, we're going to talk about this later.
Kind of like we don't often bring our marriage to this game.
But it was talked about in the bedroom.
But this was like triggering because when we played around the table and Russ like made you lose all those potions.
So like see, look at her face.
God damn it. You drop it.
It smashes on the ground.
I'm curious.
Hungry bitch.
Russ, I know as a DM, sometimes you only start to plan something once you know it's going to be acted upon.
Yeah.
Do you know what was in that book and would you share it with us or are you going to take that secret with you?
I mean, the secret's coming with me.
But that book was like Bort.
So along with those two, that was gifted to our group in a crossover with Bros and Dragons.
I feel like it would have been a better gift than Bort.
It probably would have been a better gift.
But they went to like the Dead Library and Amy picked this book.
Bort's actual character got beheaded and his soul got sucked into Flint.
And I can't remember what Nulara got.
Did she get that fucking dagger then?
Oh, the dagger was another time, which we can get to the dagger.
But yeah, like I didn't know what to do.
I mean, part of me is happy because I didn't know what to do with this book because it's like the world will bestow upon you the worlds of information of druids.
I'm like, good fucking Lord, I don't know.
I feel a little better knowing that like my action solved your problem.
So now I can feel a little hearty about it.
One extra spell slot.
Yeah. Yeah. Those moments are nice where it's like I've given you a powerful thing and I'm not sure how you're going to use it.
Oh, good. You kind of wasted it.
That's good.
Oh, good. It's probably a good thing.
Yeah. Did I did we answer the question?
I believe we answered that question.
There was one there. Yeah, I'm sure one thing there.
I'm sure we'll come along some others as we go here.
Yeah, for sure. For sure, for sure.
So, well, let's let's go to let's go to a comment from Amy G.
Getting back into our reflections from Amy G.
Just Glim and Thea fighting.
It's just a comment. Just Glim and Thea fighting and then awkwardly trying to avoid each other.
It was one of a moment and also the surprise Elia and Night Hunter romance were some things that they really liked reflecting back on.
Yes, they like you two fighting and also just adoring each other.
At least for me, the fighting like I liked it and it made sense, but it also was so uncomfortable because I love you so much.
I was like, this is so hard.
I'm like, how am I mean to someone like I can't at all think about like.
Whereas the love was just like perfectly natural and beautiful and Amy sang me songs at karaoke.
I really did. It was gorgeous.
But yeah, I liked that they had that headbutting, but it was challenging.
I want to I want to have more of those moments.
I think going into season three, because we are very much all happy family, which is like, I mean, that's that's just us.
But like there'd be nice to have a few like conflict moments, you know, stretch our acting muscles a little bit, not just being our sweet selves.
Can I come up with a safe word?
Our sweet selves. I just said bag of dicks like two minutes ago.
Just like you don't understand.
OK, bag of dicks. Bag of dicks.
Yeah, bag of dicks. That's our safe word.
Yeah, that's right.
Wait a second. We use that too much to be a safe word.
Yeah, totally. Sure, we never get anything done.
Awesome. Awesome.
Yeah, I guess that's kind of that said, we do play with, you know, safety tools and that sort of thing.
If we're ever in a X card and red light, but we've never needed to use them because we all know each other.
Stupid. Well, none of us would like we just don't.
We'll say a lot of inappropriate shit, but it's never at least to us and hopefully not to you.
Like gross or like like pointedly like unkind, you know, about a specific anything or anybody.
Also, Ruben just said the happy family vibe is the best reason to listen to it.
Thanks, Ruben. Yeah, that's great.
Profanity spewing happy family.
That's absolutely right.
Yes, we don't punch down. Thank you. Well, we try not to try.
We try very hard. I'm not going to say we don't.
I think there's only been like maybe counted on one hand any time when we've been in a session where one of us has said something.
Usually it's me.
No, I've definitely been there where I'm like, I think and there's just a look in the group that that's going to sound wrong.
You need to you need to edit that out.
You need to I usually catch them in post if there is like just an off color thing because we'll either the group will either gliss by it or there's just this hang this moment of like, did you really?
Yeah, I heard it.
It wasn't good.
Like, let's rewind.
Almost never.
To notice right to acknowledge those things is like, sometimes our mouths, my mouth just runs away.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Six years if we can only counted maybe on one hand.
We're okay people.
Good.
Speaking of six years Russ you've been doing the show for a while writing and getting everything planned out.
I believe it's Iraq and asks how much was plotted slash sketched out over the course of the second season.
For the second season.
Yeah, let's go with the second season.
Yeah.
So I mean season one was Rise of Tiamat.
So that was pretty set in stone.
Like you're fighting Tiamat by the end, whether you're ready or not.
We were ready.
Maybe you didn't make it there.
Season two, like I had Orcus picked kind of within the last 10 to 15 episodes of season one that that's who I wanted to be the big bad.
I had two options.
That said, I had two options.
Both kind of would have looped back to Orcus in one way.
But the first one was, you know, Undead Horde.
Great.
You know, figure that out and go from there.
The second one was a worldwide pandemic.
Oh, yeah.
This was before the COVID.
Yeah.
Goodness.
Right.
And it's like we started this in late 2019.
It would have been uncomfortably topical.
Yeah.
It would have been too much.
So yeah, I think there's early season two.
There's like just one little offhanded Leosan comment where there's like and some illness is happening over in this region, which they're all like, yeah, no, let's go.
Which they handle.
For the beach vacation down in Kalimbor.
Yeah, that'll work out great.
That'll work out great.
Awesome.
So yeah, so had had the the big bad kind of formulated, but didn't have really any idea of what they would do with it.
And then implementing both time streams, both stories kind of overlapping each other allowed us to have what I really liked of, you know, getting to know the little characters and playing young characters again,
but also dealing with the big problems that were happening.
So.
Right.
Working together to merge.
It was a nice bAlydince for a while.
Yeah.
And then it was.
And it got dark.
Well, yeah.
And it was this timeline.
I was going to say one of the things I really liked that we got to do was Carla, Yumi and Russ figuring out what were the scenes that really like, like the dark things that happened between Varanagh, Trinidad,
and oh, my gosh, why am I blinking on Pipp Dickens?
Because I was like Miss Pipp Dickens.
Yes.
Yeah.
Because we had I mean, we were the left and right hand of like the ultimate evil taking over the world.
So we kind of had to explore that.
Yeah.
Right.
It got really dark.
I might I might have taken a little bit darker than it needed to go with, like, oh, yeah, we'll make sure you have a spot in our army.
Yeah.
Look, we we lost listeners on that episode.
I'm sorry.
One.
One out of two hundred.
Someone who didn't know and listen to it.
Like, I love you.
Yeah.
Awesome.
You know, I could see where it wasn't for everyone.
Yeah.
They don't know how dark we really are.
We're only we're only as dark as we let you see.
I have no no real regrets in that episode.
Like, I feel bad that some people were uncomfortable with it and maybe didn't come back to us because, you know, we did try to bAlydince and it got really dark, which I wanted season two.
Like it needed I felt like it needed to get really dark before we brought it back because we played very like we play very dick jokes, nonchAlydint, like whatever.
But I wanted to try and explore that space with everybody.
Yeah.
And like just the unrelenting despair of the darkest timeline was fun's the wrong word.
But but fun was the word.
We're like, how do we get out of this?
Yeah.
And what Russ wants us to do and what we do are often two different things.
So I totally feel from his perspective of like, I got to put you guys in a dark place.
It's hard to make dick jokes in a dark place.
I tried.
You guys are like, where did all the dick jokes go?
And I'm like, I don't know, guys, I'm depressed.
We're working on it.
But it was good because we like there was genuinely stakes.
Like, it wasn't just us like in our little baby characters, like rolling along, getting lost in Mesa.
I'm fighting some goblins who are blocking this road.
Yeah, like there was stakes.
Yeah.
And we still make dick jokes because honestly, that's what I mean, humans, we weren't all humans.
But you know what I mean?
Like, that's what we do when things are really hard to say you do still make terrible, dark jokes.
This is true.
We've got to put some levity in there.
Exactly.
That's how you get through the darkest timeline.
That's right.
Yep. Coping mechanisms are very real.
Standard Jess, you are correct.
Well, let's let's throw a question out to everyone.
LA has a question that's are there any aspects of gameplay that you'd wish you'd experienced or explore?
Anything that that can cover anything from like mechanics to tone?
Kind of talked about that already, but like maps and mini maps as well.
Anything that you would hoped hoped to see or hoped to see moving forward?
I missed our round table whiteboard.
We tried to bring a zoom whiteboard into play.
And we just drew a dick.
We did not set out to.
When you give somebody a blank space, there just ends up a dick there.
It's inevitable. It's one of those.
Was there anything that we haven't done?
I hope so.
For me, there's nothing specific that was like, oh, I really hope we get to do this thing.
But I do feel like we just so barely scratched the surface of what is possible that there is like.
Yeah, sure.
An unlimited number of things we can still do.
Like looking back. Yeah.
What do you use? Way more spells.
She would have played the game way more.
Well, I mean, I'm a I'm I'm conservative with my resources because like, I don't know when there's going to be a long rest.
I don't know. You know, right. And I think I played too much and I didn't let my character play.
Sure. Right. I hear that.
Yeah, yeah. Jess in the chat.
I really enjoyed the skill checks that were bigger in season one.
Be cool to see those again. Yeah, we did a couple of them in season two, but they were definitely more prevalent.
Like the skills challenges.
Well, yeah, that's fun. That's a fun mechanic.
Yeah, because those are those are a lot of fun to increase.
Well, chicken. Yeah.
Yeah. Make up.
Think on your toes. Yeah. Yeah.
Think on your toes. Yeah.
Think on your feet.
Think on your toes.
On your on your whole foot.
Think on your whole foot. Got you on your heels.
To the tips of your toes.
That's right. That's right.
We got another. Let me go to the Q&A.
Give them a little treat.
So I'm going to ask about a couple of things with the next season.
But first off, Cat Waterflame asks, will season three involve the Black Knight?
Mostly a joke question for the love of Stan.
Oh, no. And Stan has already left.
Stan already left.
You know what? Maybe he'll listen back.
He'll listen back.
No.
Is the answer and everyone knew that was the answer.
Stan knew that was the answer.
It's very sweet of you, Cat, to do that for Stan.
So for those that for those that haven't listened,
Black Knight is one of our best seasons of anything we've ever done over on Facing Fate.
So please go listen.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Cat said they actually meant Carl.
Oh, yeah.
Also. Oh, Carl.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, of course.
I feel like Stan is at Cat's house with like a knife right now.
Oh, maybe.
Go to bed, everybody. Good night.
You ask.
Well, to continue off the off talking about next season from Stan or Jess,
if the next season is brand new and we don't encounter any of the old characters,
what is one thing moment for each character you might want to impart on us
as their last memory for your listeners to hold on to?
Guys, I wrote touching once, but I want other people to go first.
I would say that for Vorunax and the story that ended up happening for him,
it's never too late to reevaluate what you're doing
and set your path right for yourself.
And, you know, mistakes can be made and you can always move forward
and learn to forgive yourself.
Yeah, I mean, Lidsynkey, yeah, same thing.
Like sometimes life takes you in a direction you don't expect, and it's a bad one.
But that doesn't mean that that's life.
Like, you get to get up tomorrow and make choices about who you are every single day.
And like, that can be totally different tomorrow.
And you can do that.
Like, everybody can do that.
Hillip goes to jail for white collar crimes.
I mean, oh, obviously.
How much embezzling has been going on between his bakery and his Zumba business?
He has made no money.
She wasn't looking for the profits anyway.
She's not asking to see the books.
Awesome.
Hit us with a touching one there, Amy.
I have one for each of my characters.
Yeah, we have lots of characters.
I love that Amy came so prepared.
It's so unlike me.
But I was like, our listeners deserve it.
I may not plan for game time until 45 minutes before we play.
But this.
I did it.
Two hours.
Two hours before.
Three.
So for Sully, it would be the people you surround yourself with will change you.
Also, you can keister just about anything if you try hard enough.
Yep.
Coping mechanisms.
I am childish cat.
Yeah, I am.
For Thea, it's all about the importance of found family because she wasn't close to her family.
And she had the opportunity and the privilege of finding so many people along her life's journey.
And she's an elf.
She's got a long life to share that with.
And also, like, you know, just like personally found family is important.
I just smashed my headphones into you.
And for Nighthunter, it's don't let the grief of the past hold you back from your future.
They lost their entire family.
Yeah.
Found Elia.
And Opal, who I think we both like Elia and Nighthunter.
It's like the most annoying little brother you can have, right?
Like you drive me crazy, but like, but nobody else better.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah. If someone's bullying you, they talk to me.
Only I can say those things to you.
Yes.
I don't know you like that.
Do you get that feeling too?
Like they're going to get jiggy and then the door knocks and you're like, fuck this cat.
Yeah.
And I think I'm like, I don't know.
I love that girl's positivity.
Oh, like even in the darkest timeline, like even when I got rattled, it was still like,
yeah, looking, looking for the light, even if that didn't turn out to be Bahamut,
because that guy kind of sucked.
Unfortunately, never meet your heroes.
It was a real never meet your heroes moment, that's for sure.
Yeah. Yeah.
For Flint, something along the lines of like, if you try your best,
you can't ever truly be disappointed because you gave it your all.
And for Moot, like, don't let anyone shame you about your third plate off of the buffet.
Yes.
You've zeroed in on all the good stuff you want now.
Live your life for you.
Heck yes.
These are good words to live by.
We all learned so much and grew so much.
I know.
Right?
It's a wild journey.
So this is like a combination of two of the questions that have been asked.
What details do you wish you had got to explore and what do you impart?
Like the Pirate Isle one, like I feel, I, so it does exist.
Like it exists over in Space Poddy, which is the only four episodes they've ever released.
So it's like a little side Dumtion's feed that you can go listen to.
But so, Hillup, what you would have found on that Pirate Isle journey.
I don't know if anybody on the call has listened to it.
No, I actually have not.
Okay, cool.
So this is going to be surprising for you all.
Hillup is clones.
Hillup was created and cloned and you would have come across like the
The wonderful Paradise Island where Hillups are just all there.
It's how he shows up everywhere and is always running up behind you going, hey, you guys,
because there's a hill up in every fucking town.
Okay, so we could have gotten rid of him, but we would have found him again.
It's like Officer Jenny or Newstarch Joy.
Yeah.
Oh my God.
So the Abyss.
So there's an unlimited number of Grandsises.
And an unlimited number of Hillups.
Grandsises not cloned.
They're just other other time streams.
But Hillup was created as like this clone servant.
I mean, it does.
Oh, like in Rick and Morty.
Did you ever kill any Hillups?
No, no, no.
No, no.
Hillups died.
Wasn't I think I was shot by an arrow?
Shot in the knee though.
That was by me.
Yeah.
Whoops.
Also, if you want to know the name of Cruelty, his name is Russell.
What?
Unlimited number of the two NPCs where we're like, God, you irritate me so much.
I think I saw a question here from Lawrence.
Yeah.
Hillup or Grantsis, who's hated more?
That's a good question.
That's up to you.
I love them both.
I love them both too.
Grantsis.
You hate Grantsis more?
Yeah, or our characters hate more.
I mean, either one.
Amy hates Hillup more.
Fuck that guy.
Oh, OK.
Sia hates Grantsis more.
But I mean, at the end, you realize that like sometimes you can't also choose
your found family.
Yeah.
Sometimes they're just there.
Yeah, sometimes.
I think Moot would just be like bemused by Hillup.
Yeah.
Like, oh, there's Hillup doing his thing again.
And Glim, like, I mean, they were working together.
I mean, yes, he was fleecing her completely.
100 percent.
She probably didn't even care, honestly.
She must need the money.
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
Where was all that money going?
Who was making the Hillups?
Did they get all the money?
Oh, it's just white collar crime.
It's just there was some corporation that made this.
Hillup is a pyramid scheme.
No.
Now, what things can't go into the third season now?
We have a pyramid scheme.
What's that, Kyle?
Now, what things can't go into the third season?
Uh-huh.
Oh, my goodness.
Uh-oh.
Yes.
They're the weird uncles you invite to weddings because they're not unpleasant.
Yeah.
This is it.
Like, they are total weirdos.
Oh, Sam.
But like, they're not malicious.
Harmless.
Yeah.
Harmless weirdos.
Grantsis, I don't even hate.
I just love to pretend to hate because it's so fun.
It is.
We got a few comments in the Q&A I'm going to run through real quick.
Even pancakes.
I reckon says the darkest timeline is when the podcast went from good to great.
So thank you.
That's super nice.
I'm glad you liked it.
That's when we got Kyle.
That's when Kyle popped in there.
Regular cast member Kyle Placid.
That's when we really hooked him in.
We seeded with a little bit of Kyle early in 2019, but then really brought
him back in that straight.
We're like, do you want to come back for a small arc?
Yeah.
Just four years later.
This is how we make friends.
Yeah.
It's OK.
I liked it.
It was a good way to make friends for me, too.
So I appreciate y'all wanting me to come back.
Catwater Flame also says, I love the running gag of Sully's jobs.
Yeah.
So many jobs.
So funny.
Always good.
It is very funny.
And then we had a little glim meeting Bahamut.
So those are some good moments that got mentioned in our Q&A here.
Nice appointment in your voice.
Well, because it started out OK, right?
Like he was like a chill dude.
And it was fun.
So cool.
And he's in his hammock, and it all seemed OK.
All right, all right.
He was Matthew McConaughey.
Love hated him for that.
And then he was just as like.
Just fucking TMS.
Fucking.
Yeah.
And like not making deals.
And then he opened his mouth.
Yes.
Yeah.
Oh, we missed Kat's first one.
Yes.
And Kat loved the whole moot board situation.
So.
Oh, fun.
I love what you guys did with it because like Russ said, like it was like we didn't
choose the Flint board situation.
Yeah.
That was thrust upon us.
But I loved it.
Like it.
Yeah.
I didn't.
It made me cry.
Oh, I know.
But for that reason, it added a lot of like emotion.
OK.
Honesty.
I only just listened to the last episode, like two hours ago.
So she'd only just prepped before.
I'm in the corner of the couch.
Just like I was listening on two speed so I can make sure that I can listen to
the entirety just so that like my my brain is fresh.
And then I had to slow it down to one speed when Tom and I had our thing.
And I was like, I know.
Oh, yeah.
I was like, oh, my God, I sound so sad.
And then once you get Tom.
Oh, my goodness.
Like the voice crack.
I was like, yes.
It was my whole goal.
Yeah.
There was some solid like that.
A lot of survivors guilt that lives in the.
Yeah, for sure.
I mean, it's tough.
Yeah.
So that's that's actually one question we have from old school gamer is
they can't help but wonder and my name is D.
What is the head space now?
Even at the end, she seemed reluctant to go with the group.
Mm hmm.
I know this is labeled the head for that.
Let me tell you something.
Yeah, I do.
OK, so.
In the end, she did decide to go with the group because found family and
the is not like.
I feel like she needs to be with people.
We needed you to, like, come be an adult.
You're the only one who's a thousand plus years old.
So it's true.
Yeah, I guess I'd live a long time.
But she definitely found someone to talk to about all the loss that she
experienced.
She went out and sought someone in what the whatever village we decided to
settle ourselves into.
She lives with Donnie and guacamole in the forest, just the three of them,
but she visits her friends often.
They've got like a weekly dinner thing going on and she's slowly finding
peace as she helps the trees and plants to regrow and the animals to
thrive because healing them helps to heal bits of her heart.
But she is worried one day that she is going to be dragged out of
retirement for just one more job.
Yeah.
Just when I get out, they pull me back in, right?
They'll like.
Yeah.
Thea is like the woman in the woods that's like.
That all the little kids make stories about.
And she lives for so long.
And that's the part that, like, really got me is that, like,
you know, like, like new Laura was a human ranger.
She was going to live to like, I don't know, how long would a ranger
live, like 60s?
If you're lucky.
A dwarf.
Also, I think a similar lifespan as a human, if I'm not mistaken.
I think a tiny bit longer, like a one point five.
Yeah.
And then what?
I'm living hundreds of years having lost you got like the amount of
trauma.
Yeah.
Oh, man.
But then you still came with us because you knew that the love
that you get from your found family is worth the sadness.
It is the only thing that can help you.
Thea is Baba Yaga.
It's not chicken legs.
It's actually owl legs.
Yeah.
You can be my warlock.
Yeah, in that way.
Another one or a moment that standard just liked was the time
that they helped blow up the moon.
So.
Oh, yeah, that was for a.
So snuck into a game time, some lean world lore that was basically
the trigger for the darkest timeline is that there was a portal
on the moon that they had to go shut down and try and stop.
But there was a failing scenario.
Like, there was no way that they were going to stop it.
Sorry.
But the DM1.
And then it connected when we were playing with Lindsay Bowen,
Nampon 9.
At the end of that scene, like, yeah, moon goes dark and everything.
And you hear the zombies start coming out of portals and drop that
in the feed. And it worked really well.
So, yeah, yeah, absolutely.
That was great.
How many times did I try to use, like, my moon beam spell
and then went, fuck, the damn moon.
So many times.
Oh, God.
Well, you know, it sounds like you'll have a lot of good moments.
Standard just wants to know what some of the favorite moments
each character had throughout the years.
Is there a quote or joke that really stuck with you that you can recall?
Mm, Judas.
Why was that so funny?
It's always the dumbest thing.
What a one-off.
And a standard Meredith.
Just a standard lady.
You know how much I describe people as a standard.
Like, that is a person type now that never existed.
Yeah.
My namesake.
Just a standard Jess.
Just a standard lady type.
Setting it up in hard mode.
Yeah.
Oh, man.
Judith was good.
Potatoes was fucking expensive.
Oh, God, they were so...
The economy in this place is just ridiculous.
Five gold for a plate of potatoes?
Russ doesn't understand currency in this world.
Oh, that's too much?
That's too much?
All right, we'll adjust the pricing.
Don't worry about it.
Forks, there's a fuck in the road, which was a mistake, but I love it.
It was very good.
One thing that we, for whatever reason, stopped doing is Sully stopped keystering things after the first 20 episodes.
It was freaking Glim out.
So maybe didn't stop keystering things.
Stopped mentioning that they were keystering.
Yeah, just a little more subtle about it.
A keyster's gonna keyst, am I right?
Yeah.
Keysters out here be keystering.
Taylor Swift's next hit single.
Next big hit.
There's so many more things I can't...
I always just like blank.
Beefy Stew?
Like, what's he up to now?
Beefy Stew in the Season of War?
I think back on him often.
Absolutely.
I think back on, you know, fictional characters frequently.
Yeah.
Jaypes.
I liked playing Jaypes.
Jaypes, yeah.
Jaypes was good.
That whole arc that just kept like popping up.
We could have won the whole fucking thing, Kyle.
We could have won the whole thing.
That was a fun arc that confused a lot of people
every single time at Pop Share.
It got to be like, why are these people here again?
Margaret and Lex.
Guy.
That stupid voice that Tom did
because he thought it was going to be a one-off.
Perseus, yeah.
I liked it.
I thought it was really fun.
And it became what I didn't know at the time,
is that little arc like bridged some of the issues
of jumping ahead 10 years in time
in that we could continue that one,
but then have like the timelines kind of line up,
but not really line up.
So it was like one of those Marvel throwaway lines,
like, well, when you hop times,
some things are different.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I think I said at one point someone was like,
but what about this?
And I was like, willing suspension of disbelief.
That's how we explain that one.
Imagination.
I think a lot more about just time jumps
than I ever did before just in my general life.
Walked into your house and you're like, all right,
prepare to be transported back to the 1970s.
Carla, I love the transport, come on now.
Oh yes, I gave Russ the option
when he came to my new house.
I was like, do you want to go in the backyard first,
or do you want to be transported in time
to the 1970s?
And he said, you know I love time jumps,
let's go to the 70s.
Go.
I should post some pictures, y'all.
Maybe once all the boxes are gone.
It's incredible.
Get those curtains in there.
You keep those velvet curtains.
Wait till you see the mural.
Like, my god.
The mural's pretty great.
It's incredible.
Fucking wild things about Carla's mural.
The DJ booth.
It's unbelievable.
Like, I just.
The giant tub.
The tub room.
It's a room with nothing but a tub in it.
There was some wild sex parties at my house.
Oh, I got it.
1980s.
That's why they got the fan in the middle of the room.
Do not take a blacklight to that tub room.
No.
But I mean, now I kind of want to.
Just for science purposes, yeah.
The people were in their 80s at this point,
so hopefully it's fine now.
What did you mean?
Those were wood paneled walls.
That absorbs.
So far.
Oh god.
Can we get out of this?
What's the next question?
This has nothing to do.
We're actually at the end of our reflection.
Are you not moderating, Kyle?
Oh my god.
Get me in line.
We're actually at the end of our reflection section,
so we don't need to reflect on that anymore.
Perfect.
Get off the rails.
Moving forward, let's...
Lawrence asks,
will Kyle continue to be a permanent cast member?
Putting us on the spot here, Kyle.
Russ.
Oh my god.
That's like asking, are we boyfriend girlfriend?
That's right.
Are we doing this?
Yeah.
I'll let Kyle talk.
It's a conversation that I'm open to having.
Of course, I've got a lot of things going on,
but I love playing D&D with these people,
and I would love to continue doing it
in any capacity that is feasible
for both Dumbgeons and Dragons and myself.
That being said, no spoilers, I guess.
TBD.
Because we basically stole Tuesdays from Kyle
for four years.
That was a while.
We had some vacation time.
Let's take a break,
and we haven't really recorded anything.
In the offseason,
which we'll get to exactly what we're doing,
but Kyle's popping up in some offseason stuff.
But we have done and played
what I really enjoy with our show
is playing with a whole lot of different people,
and we'll list all of the guests that we've had on,
because it's an insane list of amazing people.
It is, yeah.
And we are fortunate, hugely fortunate,
to have had Kyle not only come and play
an amazing character,
but come back and be like,
well, you sent me the PowerPoint
to say this is what we're doing now,
so you have to come do this with us.
Kind of a package deal.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
My PowerPoint, not PowerPoint, right?
It was the most powerful PowerPoint I've ever seen.
You don't want it to be lengthy.
Straight to the point.
Yeah.
But yeah, we want to do a little bit
of just the four of us again for a little while,
because we haven't done that in a long time.
Like play an arc, and we don't,
we'll talk about this more, I keep jumping,
but we'll talk about that later.
But we do want Kyle to come back in some capacity.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
That's why we let him moderate.
I knew these questions were here.
You don't just ditch your friends
when you find out that they play D&D.
I could have deleted all these questions
from the document to be like,
no, Kyle, you're never coming back,
but we love to play with them,
and get out of here.
There are ways to import them up to Canada.
It's true.
We got to make that musical.
There's a lot on lists.
No, whatever happens, happens,
and I'll be glad to do whatever we do.
I'm going to love it.
Maybe you're sex tape.
Do y'all want to move on to the next section
and answer some questions about
whatever happened to,
I feel like it's almost like a Jackbox game.
This section of Jackbox, whatever happened to?
Amy and I are about three quarters of a box.
Oh, this is why she wrapped.
Before we do that,
I think there's one other little question
in this First Reflections.
I just want to touch on it quickly,
because it is about how amazing Kyle is,
less about how great Orcas is.
The Faust question, if you want to read that one real quick.
Yes, sorry, I did forget about that one,
and I meant to ask it.
Russ, what inspirations brought you to using Orcas
as your primary and boss,
especially since Undead are an annoying and multi-step fight
that brings a bit of difficulty to a lot of normal fights.
Also, if so inclined,
would love that pancake recipe from Grancis,
which I'm going to second that last bit there.
100%. I will share the pancake recipe,
which I think I said.
I will put a baller pancake recipe in the Discord.
We will match it with our pancake recipe.
Okay, we had a brownie out, but my pancakes are legit, okay?
Fair enough.
I believe you.
Throw some recipes in there.
Let's do it.
So, Orcas.
I've always really liked Orcas,
because as far as abyssal monsters go,
he's not the king.
That's Demogorgon.
And he's a chaotic, weird, goat-man monster
that I was like, this is cool.
And he likes Undead and souls and all of this.
So the picture I had of the Tiamat battle,
which I did describe in there,
is like souls getting sucked into the sky,
like out of the battle.
And that's Orcas siphoning...
That's Orcas Vorunax,
siphoning souls into the background
to power the gates that are to come in the Darkest Timeline.
So the battle in and of itself is fueling the next big bad,
which I really liked in that moment.
Once Kyle came in to play Vorunax graciously
in that first Welcome to Blackpool,
I had it in my mind,
which I don't think I voiced to Kyle.
I was like, you're Orcas' right hand.
You go open portals.
But I was like, Orcas is too chaotic,
which we felt once we got down there,
that he was just all over the place.
He's rushing things.
He's thrown off.
And he doesn't have Vorunax to do it.
Vorunax really is the big bad,
which our players switched.
They converted him after a point,
which I thought was really cool.
And now we have this huge big bad
that we have to go fight
that doesn't have his brain behind him anymore.
So yeah, that's why I liked Orcas.
And I don't know if it would have worked out the same
if I didn't have Kyle in that seat.
So thank you, Kyle.
Yeah, I was stoked when you asked me to come on
because I was like, how can I help you?
Because as a DM, I was like,
I know what it's like to have players.
Let's make your shit work.
And how can I help you do that?
I got you, bro.
We can force some others to happen here.
I so love that.
Man, I had not thought about that.
But of course, Orcas is so chaotic
that he needed Vorunax to be the administrator
to put everything in motion.
You need to make your plan and check the box
and put it together.
It wasn't going to be the lich dude.
I did not connect those dots.
No, it's so obvious now that you did.
Oh, Shangri-La?
It's not like this that we don't connect dots.
Oh, Shangri-La.
And you saw Shangri-La trying to...
Daddy!
I hated it so much.
It causes a visceral reaction to me.
Vorunax gets flipped in the darkest timeline
after he realizes everything's never...
The goal is not there for him anymore.
So he sacrifices himself.
But then in the past timeline,
after he converts,
Shangri-La does step up and try and fill the seat.
But he's dropping bottles and walking around like,
I got it, daddy, don't worry.
We'll just pick this up.
Vorunax will never know what we're doing.
Yeah, no.
And then it set in motion
the destruction of everything
that led up to the end there.
See, I think things through
even though there's nothing on my page.
It's all in there.
So, yes, thank you all for doing that.
Very revealing.
I know, I was like, I had no idea that all that happened.
I sit beside the DM and still...
All makes a lot of sense now that you say it.
Yeah, when you lay it out that way.
Works out.
Well, in the whatever happened to section,
we kind of have a similar question
between Hannah S. and Victor.
What happened to Donny?
He just went poof.
Unless Donny with a N-Y and Don E.
No, one in the same.
Okay, just making sure.
But yeah, did Donny need crackers,
couldn't make it out of the bag anymore,
just went poof?
What's up with that?
So, Donny did disappear
once we got into the abyss.
Upon command.
There is a scene,
and I didn't go back and listen,
but I'm pretty sure I remember a scene
where he pokes his head out and says,
oh, what am I doing?
And then it's too dangerous for him,
shoves him back in.
And there wasn't really a point
because everything was bang, bang, bang, bang, bang,
like bad, bad, bad, bad, worse, worse, worse.
He has like eight hit points.
He's a tiny little...
Thea could not.
Like he was just a little baby.
He was like a cat.
It was probably when we came across the dude
taking a piss.
Oh, yeah.
This is too much for you, man.
Is that Smiler?
Fuck that guy.
Also visceral reaction.
He was just unnerving.
And to know that that guy lives somewhere
in my husband,
just think of me occasionally.
Just think of me occasionally.
But yeah, I don't think Thea could
have handled the loss of Donny
because Donny's the only thing
that connects her to Nulara.
And now the only thing that connected her
to, and probably the only thing
that's going to live as long as her.
Also got some fun
backstory, like not backstory.
Donny now.
Consult the PDF.
That's right.
I know what's happening with Donny.
So Donny
definitely from the point
of Nulara's death onward
had been struggling with the loss
of Nulara.
We think about how we lose
our pets and how
devastating that is to us.
And the
flip side of it,
Donny was a mess.
He also,
Thea and him share a therapist.
But Thea has also found an
artificer who is making another
collar for him so that
when he's ready
and healing, he can
transform back into the gold
wormling that he was.
And move forward.
Yeah, he'll find
his power again.
He and Thea, they're healing together.
Guacamole is just like fucking, I don't know,
eating all the mice. We've got no rat problem.
That's lovely. I love that.
Yeah. Awesome.
Awesome.
Welcome back, Arachan. I'm back, baby.
We missed you.
Awesome. Since
Arachan came back, let's
answer one of their questions about how
the evil duo
came into being slash play.
The evil duo.
Vorunax and Lipsenke. I'm assuming
so. I guess
that would be the evil duo.
I assume that's Vorunax and Lipsenke. Correct us
if we're wrong there, Arachan.
Yeah. Yeah, or, you know,
we already talked about Hilape and Grancis,
so that can't be them. Yeah, that can't be it.
The infinite number of them.
But I mean, also
Fitz. That's who, yeah. So, Vorunax
and Lipsenke. Yeah.
Well,
I mean, we kind of covered that a
little bit with
Russ' talk about you reaching
out to me and me saying, like, I'm down to do
whatever and then you filling me on on
what it is. Lipsenke,
on the other hand, that was
pure chance.
Like, and also
it was Carla wanting to play
into it, really, and going down
that road. For sure, because there was
after Nulara,
then there was, like, several characters
and then
as kind of always happens, one just,
like, hit. I think,
like, Lipsenke just was fun.
Fun to play and, like,
kind of had a vibe from the beginning.
Like a character you can dig into? Yeah.
Yeah. But it was short-lived
too, though, because Lipsenke was only
in those Blackpool episodes at first.
Yeah. And was
a listener
creation.
Ooh.
Yeah, Devon.
I couldn't remember, like, a
patron made up
like the basics
of that character to be
like Pippi Longstocking, which was
so fun.
Yeah.
I don't know. And then it just was fun to be mean.
Not even mean, but just, like,
evil. And we didn't know.
And we didn't even know. No.
Like, when
we came back, like, when Lipsenke
came back
and, like, appeared and was, like, oh, no,
I'm hurt. Like, we
kind of didn't know until, like, then
what was going to happen.
Like, was Lipsenke with
Farnox? Was Lipsenke
actually needed to be saved?
Was it a trick? Like, all of that kind of
just happened?
Organically?
Like, what felt right at the time?
So that was very fun. Totally rude.
Very rude.
I apologize.
Thea was so upset.
She's our responsibility.
We broke her out of this place.
Now we've lost her into
a portal. Like, what the fuck?
And then you came back and I was like, oh, my
god, redemption time. No.
Well, that one landed harder
because that was a quick, like, two-character
turn that you had in that little
two episodes because you had Lex
and Lipsenke come up
in both of those. So you started
with Lipsenke and then we had Lex
and then Lex was escaping
Blackpool.
So we were like, well, okay,
well, we're into Lex now. And then Lipsenke
was, Lipsenke
as much as both characters
were great, I think Lipsenke hit
harder in terms of, like, character
dynamic,
which is why Lex got their own spin-off
series.
That's right.
Yeah. And because, yeah, Lipsenke,
they're really, it felt like, what happened?
Like, she fell in that portal
with Vorunax and then like
Yeah. It allowed us to play
a little bit in that space off
screen for a little while. Yeah.
It was like a lifetime that happened. Yeah.
Because time. Because time.
And things were, like, real, like
bad. I mean, she was, like,
in the abyss and then, I don't know,
like, worked her way out of the abyss
to be one of the bad guys.
When you're nice to the prison guards.
To be supervisor of the abyss.
We didn't, you know,
we talked about it, I think, in that
in that Darkest Timeline episode,
episode 80, where
where everything's bad.
But we alluded to the fact
we didn't go into it because why would you need to do that?
Lipsenke was hard,
like, tortured.
Yeah. By Vorunax and by
along with Grancis, who was
cellmates with Lipsenke. Which I mean
was torture in and of itself.
Right?
We really knew how to put the
screws to somebody. Yeah. So there
was a breaking point and there was a turning point
and Lipsenke was one of those, like
may not, I think
I think we, it kind of worked
out that we played it that Vorunax
maybe took
a liking in this
familial way to Lipsenke
and convinced Orcus that this was a person
that they needed on their team.
Yeah. That's how I read into it.
Yeah, I think so too.
Which was why, and I mean
that makes sense, like, psychologically
that, like, why
Lipsenke would
just love Vorunax so much
because he, I mean,
Stockholm Syndrome, but also
like, then he
did also save her
and, like, give her power to,
I mean, evil power.
But evil power just
is power when you have none, right?
And, yeah.
Anyway, that was the question.
Something about, nothing related to anything.
This brought up the question to me, like, what happened to the
voices that you could hear, like your
was that
a one-time only thing that you had
access to in your brain
or did the abyss break you
or? No, because the
voices, the voices we
revealed as, like, Orcus's power
granting all of Lipsenke's
power.
Which didn't know until they went
to the abyss and kind of
unpacked and revealed that.
Yeah. Yeah, he was like my
sponsor in
power, like where my power was coming
from. Yeah.
I really like that we
eventually got to spin it into Vorunax being like
no, Lipsenke is going to replace
Shangri-La, and that is
that is kind of the motive behind it.
What a weirdo.
Absolutely. Even when we showed up
I love Shangri-La so much.
Shangri-La was a lot of fun to
hate, I'll tell you that much.
That was a lot of fun to get to just play that kind of relationship with.
I don't know if you've noticed this.
I like to play characters that people
just despise.
We love to hate
the characters. We need that because
Amy and Tom and I are like
I love you. You never split the party.
We're all best friends. Like we need a little
conflict. We need someone to be like
oh fuck this guy.
Otherwise it's got to be one of you
and that's just a weird thing to have
for a hundred and fifty five
episodes. I mean we could barely do it for the
darkest timeline. Exactly. For like two episodes.
Then we're like we're fine
now. Yeah, we got to work together I guess.
Alright.
Let's
do a couple quick ones from the question
and answer section.
Kat asks how fast do you think season
three will devolve into butt jokes?
Episode one.
So we've
already drawn a map for it and it's the shape
of a dick. I wasn't joking when you said we
worked with a whiteboard and we drew a dick.
Yeah.
We are who we are.
But we're going
back to our roots, okay?
Just putting lipstick on a pig over here, okay?
It's just
what we're doing. Your roots being so far in
5E, does that mean season
three is going to be in 5E?
Lawrence would like to know. Are you going to do like a
different tabletop? Yes.
5E is probably what we're going to do.
We're not, we won't be
inherently
into, what am I trying to say here?
We won't be locked to the forgotten realms
as we are. We're going to go
a homebrew world
which is very exciting.
Only mildly terrifying.
But like keep mechanics that
are familiar.
We don't use mechanics anyway.
I mean.
Just use a character sheet that we're familiar with
in case we roll something.
Well, on
the point of character sheets, Kat
also asks, was there anything in the character
inventory that never got used
or only got used once?
Probably.
Okay, so here's my iPad.
Remember how in like. Literally everything I have.
100%.
Like the last like
four episodes when I was like
oh guys I have all these aura effects
that will like keep you safe.
Give you extra power. Do this
and this and this and it's like. Oh gosh.
Well, I mean at least I noticed
before the very final
battle. Yeah, it was a perfect
timing. Yeah. Yeah. So
I would say so much more than
even that. Like.
Times out by five if you're
looking at my character sheet like a god.
Because we just would always get so
into RP.
Which I love.
Like that's. Yeah.
That's the heart of it. We would sort of
just like maybe not look at our character
sheets like ever.
Well, I think once we found out it was slowing
us down. Yeah. Cause
they're like early on
like season one there would be like
five minute pauses
where we're like
hold on I need to consult my sheet.
Just gotta look this up.
Just give me one second to look this up.
Well, this kind of goes
hand in hand with this question.
Amy, Chris wants to know
like what happened to Thea's levitation
boots. So maybe that's something on your
inventory that you know didn't quite
see the lie today. I think this question
came up maybe a little bit
before that final battle because I
think you did pull them out because there was like an
earthquake and you were like I've got levitation
boots. I'm like great. They don't move.
They just levitate.
And that was the thing is why I never use them
and I do remember that I had them.
But the thing is is that it would levitate me
but I had no way to
propel. Yes.
I couldn't just swim through the air. It wasn't
a flying ability. It was just like
okay now you're off of the ground.
Like you could either be
pushed to a certain extent
and then stop or like
use something. You have to hold hands
with somebody. Yeah.
Give me a push. Exactly.
It was just more awkward
RP wise than it was
useful.
Kat is asking about those stickers
and we did get
them. Which stickers?
I was confused
to use them and I
was too embarrassed to ask.
I mean there was tons of stuff
that we got.
I'm sorry.
The
Zed Mart which is
where patrons could put in items
and our players could go buy
them. I'm sorry.
They would get really excited and be like yeah I'll get
that one. I'll do that thing and I'll do
and then they just go on the list.
So
season three we'll try and use the items
that you gave to us. Listen fam
have any of you ever bought anything
and then been like
I totally have a purpose for this.
I'm just going to put it in a safe place.
And then you never
see it again. And then a year later
you're like oh yeah
I bought this thing. But what was that for?
I have a bit
of a theory as to why those things get forgotten
about because a lot of times it's at the
end of an episode that it's like a
reward. You get to go shopping.
And then you get this new
ship but you don't pay attention to it because
you're done. Russ is like I'm going to add it to
your character sheet. Yeah you don't introduce
yourselves and then immediately say that
person's name three times to be able to
lock it and you're like great I'll remember
that next time. Or let me practice.
Yeah or it's just ADHD.
That very well could be
awesome.
Well Russ
Hannah asks, whatever happened to
slash what was the end
goal for Nulara's ghost
appearing to Thea?
Was there supposed to be a story arc there that
got passed over for the Darkest Timeline?
Yes.
End of answer.
Well we can't do it anymore.
So that
was another like from
when Nulara got the dagger like
there was intended to be a big bad
monster that was attached to the dagger.
Some soul or some beast that
was like you know
which in my mind was
like a Strahd type character.
And we would
had we pursued that in any way
would have gone into something like
Curse of Strahd. We probably
wouldn't have run the module but it would have
been that type of adventure.
So Nulara's ghost
when we didn't yet know
Darkest Timeline
or pandemic happening on the other side
of the mountains or whatever
that was actually one of the other options that I
kind of forgot about until this question
was that Thea
could have pursued the
dagger because she was getting these visions
of Nulara's ghost because New
Lara as we found out
with all of the souls
that you know were taken
by the dagger is trapped
in the dagger
which end up by the end of the
season saving the day
and resetting timelines.
But
could have
decided to be like
no we're going on an adventure
we're going on a quest to track
down why I keep having these visions
and why I keep getting it. And as soon as
we chose which direction
we were going it's like well I can't keep
bringing this back
otherwise it's just going to be this nagging
thing that we'll really never get to.
You know what my
whole thought process on that because we
never talk this out.
Never once mention this.
I don't tell you things that's why.
I know. But my
whole thought process on that was
I was having these
visions about Nulara
but she was
gone and the pursuit
to save Flint
was more important.
Because he was still alive.
I could possibly save him.
And so I think that
Thea's subconscious
literally just like squished
Nulara.
You know how you can do that right?
Just repress things.
Any other things
had to take priority.
Exactly and I think that's what Nulara would have
wanted so I think that's why her ghost didn't
come out
and bother me as much. Also those were freaky
moments.
Horrifying.
I had dreams about it guys.
That's good.
Well
speaking of freaky moments
so were Tiamat
and Bahamut actually like
an Alabama special or
Samantha would like to know?
So that's actually
Forgotten Realms lore that we pulled
in. That wasn't us.
No.
Let's just be clear.
That was like oh what?
This was not of our doing.
That was like pulled off the wiki of like
okay what's the relationship? Yeah there's sister brother
oh she's got a thing for
oh she's got a thing. So in the lore
Tiamat has a thing for
Bahamut and Bahamut's like
no but of course they do.
Because that's what gods do
is they fuck each other.
So yes?
Yeah.
But we're not to blame.
No.
We just read it and then
reset it.
And Flamikins? She had her own
agenda.
Flamikins just wanted to fuck a dragon
and it was a blast.
Yep absolutely.
Oh dang dang dang.
Jennifer from Spotify
asks what happened to Yen Bol
and will it be seen in the future?
It also made
also they made the mistake of listening
to it at work so their co-workers have
officially seen them cry.
Sorry Jennifer.
Thank you for listening but sorry.
Yeah.
So Yen Bol we
sent after the
pyramid.
Right like to test
to see if the portal thing
would work like if they could travel
through time. Right?
Yep. And the idea
I think was that Yen Bol got
to like
go back and
try to like get her
her loved ones like
it's happening now.
The bad thing is happening now
like we need to get out of the city
and got to try
to like save
her people. Went back to her
original timeline to try and save
the people she cared about
because that was sort of
the reward for being the guinea pig
to test if the portal
was going to work like if this
doesn't work who knows
like goodbye forever I guess.
But if it does work you got to heads
up to see your family. You can like try to save
the few people that you can get to
before the city is destroyed.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Which I think we had
intentions of going back to that
scene but it never really seemed
to fit. Yeah.
But yeah the way we left it which again
thanks to Kyle and Kristen for playing Yen
Bol's parents because that's another like
just little. The layers.
You're here you're the parents now go.
But yeah like we left
that you know ushering
the parents going to
the city leader to be like
we need to get moving
storm rolling in thing happening.
So we assume
that there's a warning that they didn't have before.
Yes.
And then in my
mind they made it. Yes.
Of course I did. Yeah. Yeah. At least had
a better chance at the fight
that Shangalar was kind of
rolling in with the pyramid. Yeah.
Like get as many people as they could
and just like tried to do
something. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
A lot of stuff a lot of stuff in that dark
timeline which we've kind of
threads kind of talked about it a little
bit. I know there is that one one
story beat that you had mentioned Russ
but Lawrence
wants to know with the darkest timeline influenced
by the pandemic. And
for me personally I don't think
it was directly but maybe subconsciously
like at least
like you know playing it out.
Yeah like it
wasn't you all know
I'm not going to say things that are new. It wasn't
a fun time. No. For any
of us. No.
And as much as we say like well
good thing we didn't pick the pandemic on
the other side of the mountain. Like
it was still there was still
that flavor that was in it
which is a bad term to say. But
there was still that feeling. It's fair
though. Of like
okay I've jumped them.
It's the worst it can fucking
be. Yeah. Like everything is
dead. Everything is dying. Those that are
alive are basically prisoners in
their own city or in their own right.
So yeah there was a
lot of influence of like how we
I think we were collectively feeling
or at least how I was feeling in the moment
of like there's a lot of despair
and sadness happening. Yeah.
And used
the darkest timeline
and the Destiny's Children
as like the bounce back and forth of
like okay let's live in it for a
week and then let's not
let's go do dick jokes. Let's go to
Jason Halfman Zukus' party
and go along
and like
who fucking cares but then go back
into it right. Like the levity
of it allowed us to place them with some
really serious themes
and then pop in and out.
And you know ideally
for the listener if you weren't just following
one stream which I know some people were following
one stream which is maybe why
it got too much.
Sure. Because you were following just a
specific character. You need the escapism.
You need the bounce back. But we designed
it so that you could bounce back and forth
and you could be like okay well next week I
know there's going to be just silly silliness
and then we're going to be back in it for
a little bit and then we're going to be
okay. Yeah.
Until it merged
and then even when
it merged. All dark all the time.
It was dark all the time but
the merge was
the merge was also a good point
of like there's
hope right.
Okay now all the teams are
together. Well they came in and chopped
up a fucking dragon head.
They're figuring shit out.
They weren't alone. The cavalry
is here bitches.
So yes
I think is the answer to that question.
There's influence.
Definitely so.
Well we've covered all the whatever happened
twos. That's not as many
as I thought there'd be. I know right.
How many threads are left loose in this
thing. It's okay not to pull at them.
Kind.
There are probably more that have not been
considered but they will forever
lay within
the ether of storytelling.
Exactly.
So there's some questions
for guests from the season which you know
some of it's been touched on but
Kat asked can we just kidnap Kyle
and make it official.
Bombarded episodes are missed of course
which thank you very much. I'm glad you enjoyed
the show. But
they think I fit well. I have
agreed.
I couldn't agree more.
100 percent.
But Amy mentions like
Megan more than just
me a regular adding
Kristen to that list as well.
It feels like there's some vibes.
It was fun getting to play with Kristen and it did
feel very much like all right cool
good transference of energy
between people playing and
Russ keeping up with all the
extra new antics that you know
come in every once in a while. So yeah.
I thought it was all good.
So chance of regulars coming
into the next iteration as
far as like anybody
we've played with in the past we want to
play with again. Totally.
We've been so lucky to have just people who
just so great.
Just fit.
Yeah.
But yeah so we
want to play with everybody again and
maybe this is a good point to say who the
hell we've played with.
Oh yeah.
Thank you.
The thing about Kristen I think just to interject
that's so fun is that
a goth was so like
stern and
Kristen
is not that
she's so chill and like
warm and great. So it was very
fun for her to be
a goth.
Absolutely.
So yeah.
Kyle and Kristen who again
amazingly came along with us for
for far too long.
Not at all.
As guests. Yeah.
But we also got to play multiple
times with Cicero Holmes who played
dance on the show.
That kick economy.
One of
many people's favorites.
We got to play with Celeste Konowich of
Venture Maidens.
Nice little couple
bottle episodes there.
With Professor Dr. Smith.
They're so
fun. They're such fun listens to.
Sean Howard at the
time in Other Bothers. Of course season
one TMS.
And then Gru in season two.
Before we were
like we can't play with that character
anymore Sean.
Still alive
in the world obviously.
Out there somewhere.
In that spin
off episodes as Margaret
Rev DeShane. So thank you
Rev.
So great.
From Spoutlore
Sean O'Hara and Abdul Aziz
who played Bonesword and Boob's
McFrankenstein.
So good.
And then they took them to
Jason Halfman-Zuchas
house party.
Why wouldn't you?
That was right after you opted out
of my Pirate Isle campaign too.
Pirate Isle arc.
Absolutely you're welcome.
Thank you.
I mean those guys are like legit
comedians.
Improvising comedians.
I guess with everyone
they just like get the
vibe kind of right away and that's why
we've been so lucky.
I'm very choosy about who
I asked to be on the show also.
Also I think we're very
explicit in the
tone
of how we play.
So throw us a little credit there too.
You're choosy but we've got a
very specific tone that we go with.
Every guest we have, we'll get back to the list
here because we're still going.
But with every guest we have we try to have a little
banter off the top of
every record. Like I don't know Kyle
do you recall your first time?
That's the litmus test.
We joke, we have fun.
10 or 15 minutes we start a little late
but we're like okay whatever. We just make sure
that we know that we're going to just have fun
this episode.
But yeah that way we know that they're
going to be comfortable
because we want to make sure that they're
comfortable and that's going
okay. Well yeah that's where I drop just a little
dick joke and just see how it lands
and then I know
where the line is.
That's where I increase.
A lot of times it was I can increase.
Green flag.
Also from the broadswords because Kristen
is of course from the broadswords but Victoria Rogers
joined us.
And in separate episodes B
and Tracy, B Zelda, Tracy Gibbons.
I fucking love them.
Z and Z.
And then early season 2
we had Tiffany and David Alvert of North by
North Quest in the
Turd Goblins, Circumference
and Squire Root.
Circumference killing
and the jam.
That one really went off the rails.
And the puns in that one were just
very good.
Lindsay Bowen
is Nampon 9 which helped
which he didn't
know going in was going
to be the trigger episode for the Darkest
Timeline. I didn't prep him
on that.
So he came in like we're going to have fun
and then by the end he's like sacrificing
himself to save everybody
and let them get free and then it's
like boom it's here.
What happened?
It wasn't enough man.
Love Lindsay.
Thank you so much.
And then
Keith Amann who
writes the books How to Play
Monsters and basically
knows how to play everything better
than anybody else.
We learned a lot.
But he was so fun.
Also like really
yeah was doing
like because that was Flora's Lava right?
Yeah Flora's Lava.
But yeah knows the mechanics and knows
how everything works so well which
I mean everybody always knows how to play
play D&D better than us.
Anyone can play D&D.
But yeah he was
so great because it was very like he
clearly knew how to play ten times
better than us but that was
he just went with like our level.
So gracious.
Optimized his character.
He was even like super kind of it too if he'd be
like I'm going to do this common sense
thing and we're like ah.
Yeah first episode
with Keith was interesting because
he came in to play
the game and like I was like
I sent him a couple episodes to be like listen to these
because these are going to set this tone
for like what we do.
Here's the expectation.
But everything was very quiet like for the first
episode and then it just clicked in that second
one and he opened up and he was like okay
we're playing we're doing we're going we're exploring
okay yes we're here.
It is the story. It is the story.
The game is secondary to
the story. Yeah Keith was great.
Go buy Keith's books. Go buy them all.
Very wonderful. And then a few
one shots which
were canonical non-canonical.
Madame Magenta
and Bernard. Lindsay
Sharman and Laurence Owen.
So fun.
Fantastic. And then the whole spout
lore crew for the Halloween Bonanza.
Dum Dums and Dragons.
For the wild Santa
Claus Christmas episodes.
And then we had Carla and I had a little
one shot with
the Greetings Adventures folks Tim Lanning
Jennifer Cheek and Mike Bachman.
Who were just wonderful. So fun.
I got to play on their Patreon
which patrons are getting
those episodes as well. So
we've got Tales
from the Foaming Tankard episodes over on Patreon
that you can come get where we play with them
in one of their games.
They're very fun.
But like so many
people and we want to do that
again. Like it hit a point in season
two where we were like we need to stop
introducing people.
We have a universe to save.
We need to like stop having these fun
adventures. Yes. We got to get serious
you guys. Yeah. Yeah.
It's time to stop taking all the electives and
now start to dig in. It's season three.
So.
You know what that means.
Are we ready for season three questions?
I think there are.
We do have one in the
Q&A. If we want to knock that
out real quick from Iraken.
Iraken wants to know how about
the choice to let a certain someone
have the wand of Orcus?
I liked the choice.
I thought it was a good smart wise
choice. Of course you did.
But yeah.
What do you think Russ?
Which certain someone are we talking about? Are we talking
about Vorunax or are we talking about Opal?
I mean
the fact
that we did that.
Whose idea was that?
I just feel like that whole thing
was so
ridiculous. We didn't know what to do
with that thing. Well it's so powerful
and we just didn't want him to have it
and. Just yeah. Not right there
right then. Yeah. So
we did what we had to do.
I thought that was
all. I mean it all worked out
okay. But yeah giving
Vorunax the wand of Orcus
set him
made him an imposing
figure right out of the gate which I think
we really needed because if he didn't have that
like he was he was a much higher level than
everybody else. But
still action economy like they could have taken
him out. But with the wand of Orcus like he
could have power word killed one of them
basically at any moment as the zombies are
attacking and all that's happening. Well it took him from
like middle management to like some of you
actually take seriously.
And yet if he's like Orcus's
right hand dude
like he would have all the
power. He had all the passwords to all
the bank accounts like he knew how to do all the
stuff right. So it made sense
that he would have
the Boomer piece of paper that had all
the password on it. Orcus
did not know what to do with his taxes.
No. No. Unless Vorunax
was there. He needed to edit a PDF
and Vorunax was there.
He's like what's Google Drive?
It was you know it was
a responsibility to bear
to have the wand of Orcus and know that at any
moment yeah I could
power word kill.
But I think the
reasoning in my mind of not
going to that was
that Vorunax
felt cocky about the situation.
He thought in his
situation he's like I'm backed by
Orcus and I have the power of Orcus. I can summon
undead and create portals. I'm
not concerned about some adventurers.
And in the least I
can always just escape easily.
So like do I need to
use this awesome and amazing power
against them? Not yet.
They're not really messing with
too much. This is one small
point in time and there's plenty
of time. Like would it almost be amusing
to him like let's just see how this plays out.
Like this is cute.
What are you going to do? Look at them
trying so hard.
So I think the only person
I actually used against was
Shangalar I believe.
Yeah and fuck that guy.
Which I did want to kill him
because I had the protege
Lipsinkipip Diggins ready to
step in. Ready to go.
And he said daddy too much.
It was so very
disconcerting.
We were all worried.
I don't recall
how much we talked about
like I think we talked about the relationship
between Vorunax and Shangalar before we
played that session because that's when you popped back into
the pyramid and then it
was at the same time we're all going to go fight him
so like you were there helping
not helping but helping.
I think we talked about a little bit of like
you know you're
one and two in line
but loved how we
played into the he's the suck
up and you're you're really
in charge.
Listen you want to work with your friends.
Yep. I think that is
just a universal like you want
to work with someone who's cool.
He wasn't cool.
Lipsinki was cool. You did what you had to do.
That's right. I did what I had to do.
But yeah those
questions on the horizon for season three
we've talked about some of
them of course. Brian yes season
three is going to be set in 5e as
confirmed by Russ.
And Victor wants to know
Russ will we ever see more
mm Judith.
I assume that's how you say that.
That is how you say it.
Mm Judith is
another interstellar being
obviously. So maybe maybe
in Judith will be in season three.
Cause there wasn't mm Judith in every town as
well. There was.
I assume like a standard
Meredith.
So I think we're I think we're conflating two
separate characters here.
So mm Judith was only in
the one time.
And it was right before
the Rick and Morty
introduction happened
with the Meeseeks.
And Rick and Morty showed
up and you were in the library like the
you were unpacking the library
that they were holding all the books
in then Rick and Morty showed up outside being like
we got to take this back. Yeah Rick
we got to go.
Which we didn't explicitly say
Rick and Morty but you know
that's what that was.
But mm Judith was there. What you're thinking of
is Meredith Grey from the Patreon
episodes.
She just keeps popping up.
I was totally writing those in my head.
Yeah.
Same lady. I was just hoping that there
were just like lots of both of them.
Yeah. Maybe.
Like there's a hill up in every town.
There's mm Judith. That's right.
And there's a Meredith Grey.
It was a five minute scene.
One episode.
It was us with so many listeners.
You know how I looked back at the
caught giggling one
and there were just so many mentions of like
you know how many times I say
mm and then just Judith
comes out of my mouth.
And like some people even forgot
where it came from until they
looked at that like that
feed and they were like
and now I know why I say
mm Judith.
Yeah.
That's funny.
It's funny how those things stick.
Yeah. It's wild which
NPCs, listeners
and fans will like imprint upon.
It's like you are mine now.
You are my
baby child. I will take care of you forever.
Imprint upon.
Yes.
Well Zach asks
about the new season following
an adventure model or will it be a home
brewed campaign assuming
since we're in a home brewed world
I would assume we're going with the home brewed
campaign. Yes.
Home brewed world.
Likely a home brewed campaign.
Looking ahead to all the other questions
I can hold off
on anything else. So yes.
We have had a session
where we're building the world.
The quiet year.
No.
What was the game we played?
Oh. Oh.
Oh it was a great world building game.
You guys.
We have a channel in the place
I can just look it up.
This is relevant because Nathaniel
recommended it to us.
It was so great.
World building.
Scrolling up to the beginning.
Notes notes notes.
Ex novo.
That's what it is. Which is a city
building game. So yeah we built the city
the history
and the time.
It kind of goes through all of these
things to like build out
the authority.
That's badass.
It's really fun and cool.
Yeah or like a conflict in
the past that has happened that has
shaped this. How has it rippled?
Yeah. Yeah it's really
cool. Definitely recommend.
Yeah and it's something that I think we want
to continue to use so
um
like
how much do we want to share? Maybe we can share
some things. So like season three like we want
to be set in a town. We have been
very end of the world
for a very long time.
Which is hard stakes to keep up
and escalate from.
Like we've saved the world now twice.
Like it's
time to take it back. We're going to just like roll that way
back. Yeah. Where do you go from there?
We're finding lost dogs.
We're saving
cats from trees. Exactly.
We're cleaning up the mean streets.
We're getting those teens out from behind
that 7-Eleven. Exactly.
So we're going to keep it small scale
community like
there will be a big
bat of some sort. There has to be an
opposition in some way shape or form.
But landlords.
It's a great way
place to start.
There's definitely going to be
some
gentrification. Yeah. There's going to be
some like class warfare because we always
just try and bring that in a little bit.
Capitalism. Absolutely.
Real enemy.
Let's make a real
political statement with season three.
I mean if
season two was a comment on the pandemic
then season three is clearly
this depression that we're in.
World economics.
That's where we're going.
Getting down to the nitty gritty.
The numbers of it all.
Just in case you're listening and
for some reason this is the first thing.
We're joking.
Don't listen to this first.
This would be a wild first.
Go back and listen to season one and season two.
And then join
the Patreon and listen to all the great content
there as well.
And then three years from then.
Come back to this episode and then it'll all make sense.
We'll be here.
Awesome. Awesome.
We got a couple
from Old School
Gamer D. My name is D.
Asking. They talk
to Russ about an NPC named Eugene
and if Kristen returns
can we have that chance encounter?
Yes. So D.
I do have the notes
for that character. It was introduced
to me too late
in the game in season two.
It was at that point where we were
like I need to stop introducing new characters
and new side arcs and new things
but I love it so much
so I'm holding on to it for season
three.
I'm not going to say anything more than Eugene
but it
is very good. Nobody else here
knows because I don't tell them any of that stuff.
It goes to a Google form and it disappears
forever
until I remember to go back to it.
We don't search it out. No.
So yes that will come back and if
Kristen returns maybe
yeah maybe that
would be a good Kristen fit so we'll see.
Love to see. So
Old School Gamer D. also wants
to know how much of like
the deities are going to be rolled into season three
asking like with just Tiamat and
Godmiss left what are some of the ideas
you've had for season three's
BBEG? Like
no spoilers of course just thoughts
process or are you going to wing it?
And let the muse speak to you.
Everybody looks to me.
So I do. I mean I feel like muse
but that's just because we never know what's going on
as we just said. Yes.
So not revealing anything
because Carla, Tom and Amy don't even know
anything but I do have ideas
for so here's the
thing we don't know what characters we want to play
yet but I do have ideas
for four
individual different
things that could happen.
Okay.
Oh I like that the future is in set.
Within this story there are
you know we don't know exactly
but like hierarchically speaking
like there could be four things
that they pursue for
like season one and then
we can work them in for not season
one season three. Season one of season three.
Season one of season three. Yes of
course. Season one dash season one
dash three a three point one. Yes.
And then
you know follow that through and then
bridge off. Well I mean in terms
of gods too we're like
we're literally
world building so we are
we are making decisions
about things like what gods
and magic
and everything looks like. The whole structure
of society is like
being decided which is
super fun and cool
and yeah. As far as the world
we're leaving though Tiamat is
the last god surviving. Yeah.
So let your
imagination run wild with that. You're welcome
wizards of the coast.
Boom.
Can't see why they don't call me up to make this
canon.
Whatever Flameykin's taking care of.
Flameykin's has destroyed
Tiamat. No all the gods
are reborn because of Tiamat and
and Flameykin's so.
No.
Refuse. No.
We don't speak that into existence.
That's not canon. Not at all. It's called
Manifesting Kyle. Don't do it.
I won't manifest that. I'll stop it. I'm sorry
Amy. I didn't mean to upset you.
So close to bedtime.
It is. Well before we get into
our final section we've got a couple
more questions lingering in the questions
and answers. So Sandra Jess
wants to know with the new season being a homebrewed
world will the Patreon
GameTimes be getting new stars
too? What ever happened to the
Dapper Pelican
in the aftermath?
So for
context for those who don't know
part of our Patreon you can play in Game Time
where we have introduced the world
of the Dapper Pelican which is the Adventures
Guild that also existed
within the same world as
Season 1 and Season 2. We had
pop-ins of Flameykins
and Hillup and all sorts of
different characters coming through.
Haven't yet decided. We're still
going to play within that world for a little bit.
What we do with it.
We may for a
little while keep going until we really
figure out what's going on in Season 3
and then
take a turn
and see if there's something else
we can build with those games because
those were
and continue to be fun sandboxes
to destroy the moon
without my players knowing.
Absolutely.
Awesome.
What about Tim's Game?
Tim Tom?
Tim Tom's Game?
Tim Tams?
What about Tom's Game?
It's Tim Tams. I'm all ears.
What about your game? We've been
monopolizing. There's three of us in one room.
You talk.
It's a great question and the answer is
I don't know.
Because it's been very busy lately and
I haven't had time to think about it.
Tom's Game, which is the
Patreon exclusive game The Adventures of
will be continuing with
Opal, Elia, and Night Hunter
because we love them so very dearly.
We've just gotten started on that love story
and we know how it ends
but now we're doing the flashback.
Gotta do the middle. Exactly.
Gotta see it unfold.
That will continue to exist
in the world that we have built.
There are clear connections to
everything that's happened so maybe we'll see those characters
over there at some point too.
Yeah, there's still a lot of journey
for those characters.
You have timey wimey stuff.
There can also be interdimensional things that happen.
You never know what might pop up.
Russ, I'll have to show you my PowerPoint
over interdimensional travel.
It's really, really riveting.
Wait, it's one slide is and it just says
why aren't you doing it, you loser?
I can't get one past you anymore, can I?
It's obviously very convincing.
It was very convincing.
It made me laugh hard.
That's the point.
It's supposed to make you laugh.
You know what, that's so stupid
but you're right.
Let's do it.
Why aren't I doing it?
Next day, jump 10 years.
Here we go.
I think Kyle's a bad influence on you.
I think so too.
Absolutely 100%.
A little aside,
if you're ever dealing with time travel,
never jump into the future.
Never do it ever again.
Jump to the past. Do it.
That's fine because it's already written.
You don't have to come up with everything
for the last 10 years.
Going to the past is great.
I can attest to that.
One more question from Iraq
about the city that is being built
in y'all's new season,
for y'all's new season.
Dicktown.
What is Dicktown built on?
Rock and roll.
It's built on rock and roll.
Thank you, that's what we were looking at.
Absolutely built on rock and roll.
Yeah, that's great.
So what I mean,
is it on a
landlocked,
is it in a landlocked continent?
It's near a river.
It is landlocked.
There's the Mii Mountain
off into the
west.
There is, what is it called?
Can we share?
Since you've used something
that created the city, is that something
that you can share?
TM.
Not in the game.
And it is beautiful.
So I think Ross might be about
to share it with you.
We've spent a lot of time
watching each other try to move
small images
across the screen.
Just make basic shapes and move them.
It was really something.
My whiteboard function stopped working
like 20 minutes into the call and I was like
what are they talking about? I don't have any of this stuff.
It was behind the lake and he's like
what are you saying?
There was no lake.
Are we seeing the thing?
I see the thing.
Can we get a close up on the dick?
Enhance.
Enhance, yes.
Also, if any of these
names or images
pop up anywhere,
shame on you.
Shame.
It's really
funny that Jel got a
peen in there because when I was thinking about
the Land of Beats art from
Bombarded, I wanted to take the shape
of the highway
system around DFW for
inspiration and then I looked at it and
shaped like a dick.
Yeah.
And I was like well
maybe I shouldn't.
You know when it happens.
We set it up purposely though.
I was like
and I mean mount me.
Mount me.
Which is apparently a mountain range
in Australia.
Very exciting.
Art imitating life. How about that?
So that's it.
Now stopping screen sharing because
Standard Jess is screenshotting
things.
Shame.
Shame. Intellectual property and
stuff. We are recording
this so I guess we're okay.
We don't need to mail it to ourselves.
Moving into our final
section of the night. We have some comments
from our near and dear friends.
Russ, it seems like you want to have
the cast read through some of these.
Yeah I want them to cry.
Y'all want to roll initiative
for it one last time before
moving into season 3.
Thank you. Good idea.
Dice out.
There's dice in that box there.
Oh you get to see my box in person.
It's beautiful. It's more beautiful than I could
have imagined.
Oh my god hello.
Gorgeous.
Maybe they'll roll better for you.
You roll in the middle.
Carla, what are you doing?
I don't know how your fancy box works.
Oh what?
Guys it's a 20.
I rolled a 10.
Carla got a 10.
Of course.
One baby.
The tables have turned.
The tides have changed.
Season 3 is here baby.
Russ got a 1.
So Amy, why don't you kick it off?
What? On Earth?
Yeah you got the highest mission.
Is that where winning is?
You get to go first.
I didn't expect that.
No.
Does that mean I get to choose the one?
I guess you can if you want to.
Yeah you can choose whichever.
That's the beauty of it. You get to go first
so you get to pick the one.
It's like being the team captain
in drag race. You get to pick your team.
Nice.
All right.
Charisma. No.
Do we want to say who it's from?
Yeah everybody's giving me okay to say it.
Otherwise they wouldn't put their name to it.
This one's from LA.
And LA says
You should all be proud.
It's clear how much heart went
into everything, Dumbgeons and Dragons.
You all have completed not one
but two entire long
forum campaigns and it all
kept getting better. I'm excited
to learn what's next.
We love you.
That's nice.
Tom you're up next.
I've got that if you want to hold it closer to your face.
I'm up. Okay this one's from
Jess. I just wanted to take a
moment to thank you all for everything. The amazing
storytelling. You've all taken the time
to contribute to the welcoming
community. I've had the absolute
pleasure to be part of and just the overall positive
influence. Each and every one of you
and the community included has been in my life
these past years.
Thanks Jess.
Absolutely.
Fill my heart
with joy every
damn day.
Well Carla that
you're up next in the order.
I've got so many options.
You can scroll
at your heart's content.
Okay.
Well I kind of just want to read Faust the heavenly
demonic monster because their name is Faust
the heavenly demonic monster.
So let's go with that.
Russ for every NPC
you introduce and the variety of character you
bring to each of them. Nothing made me smile
more than knowing you had a gimmick or quirk
picked out for very specific ones
and watching the group either scratch their
heads or become disdained by
your presence.
It has been an honor and a joy to have listened
to you for all these years. Thank you
so much for your dedication and time.
So
disdain.
There was
almost never no reaction.
Either we were like we love you.
You're one of us or like oh my god.
Get away from. Burn it with fire.
I guess you're also one of us.
God we're so accepting.
Oh boy.
Okay my turn.
Victor
loved the show. Loved the chemistry
and storytelling. I love
listening to new episodes right
after they come out.
That's really nice. That feels like
I praise because I got a long queue
myself. Oh yes. Yeah.
Yeah. Absolutely.
Awesome. Awesome. Well
you know what I'll jump in here.
I'm going to jump in there as a regular
cast member. You should definitely be the real one.
I'm going to take what's mine.
No. Brian
says
I've been playing D&D since 2.5.
I've fought Tiamat and died
gloriously. I absolutely
love how the Destiny's children
were the only party ever to my
knowledge to befriend and get gifts
from the mighty Tiamat. An amazing
twist. Love y'all.
Keep it up. Yeah.
It's all about when you interact with these things.
How they're doing. Because if they need
something from you they're happy to play ball.
Yes. You know how long it took us to like talk with
things? Oh so long.
We get to the end of something and rest
and be like you didn't even ask their names.
Yeah. I think
it was yeah that session we played with
Doc where I was like so
you know how you walk into a bar and
talk to people? No. Never
ever. No. No.
We don't know how to interact. We're going to do that with everybody
now okay. And I forced
them. And now we do it too
much so. And now I know how
to socialize so. You're welcome
everybody.
This is your oyster at this point.
Are we back to the top?
Are we continuing on? Back to the top.
We're just reading. We're reading the
we're patting each other on the back now.
Okay I'll read
Lord Arachans.
Just got home from my ride
and listened to the campaign's ending episode.
Like Jess.
I was moved
right off the bat. Such tender
roles playing between Amy and Tom.
I'd like to think I could pull something off
but I'm pretty sure I'd force a dick joke
in. Just because
I was uncomfortable with sincerity.
It's hard to get past.
The discussions
of power, divinity, and what to do
with such things will have me contemplating
for some time. I may still
be influenced
to bring some of those ideas into my campaign.
Carla playing Glim's
journey from Bahamaniac
to the final discussion of gods
and their power was such
an important part of the campaign.
It made the party's final decisions
natural and believable.
I held it together until Kavin McLeod's
long road ahead began to swell.
Beautiful Russ
beautiful Russ work. Beautiful Russ work.
Beautiful Russ work.
See I can't even do it on purpose.
Beautiful work Russ.
And I absolutely lost it. I had to
stop riding and wait for the entire
episode to end. Happy tears
feel so cathartic. Such a
perfect listen on a spectacular fall day.
Thank you so much to everyone involved.
You, like this community,
have made my life better.
Aww.
Yes.
Very nice.
Aww man.
Alright I guess I'm up last here.
This is from Hannah.
I started listening to you in January
of 2021 and I plowed through all
of your content and got current within a
year which is absolutely
wild. That's commitment.
I assure you I was listening non-stop.
Yeah. Absolutely.
I can truly say that
after all that y'all feel like family
and I appreciate the dynamic you guys
facilitate on the show. Forever my
favorite podcast. Thank you Hannah.
That's so nice.
We got another one in the Q&A
from Kat Waterflame. Carla
can you see that there? Would you like to read it?
Yes.
I absolutely love listening to your show
because it's so easy to tell how much you love
and adore each other. Your friendship
leads over into your characters in such a
wonderful way. Thank you for sharing your
stories and bits of your lives with us. You are
truly a light in the darkness.
Kat!
Come on Kat.
You.
I see there's one
final question there Kyle.
Before we walk on a path,
Lawrence wants to know, at the end of season 2
it sounded like there was one set of feet
walking a path. Was there a
hidden meaning there?
Night Hunter was carrying
everyone the whole time.
Everyone, every single person.
One set of footprints in the sand.
I...
I'm sorry. I have to make a joke
when things are feeling real.
I wanted
to like
yeah so everything
fades to black and everybody
is teleported to
their respective places.
It was tough to
have
a dozen sets of
feet walking.
But one person I think
was going to lead that
group onto whatever
comes next. And I felt like that was
Thea.
It was on the outskirts of a
town, an unnamed town.
Everybody appears
who wanted to be there because Night Hunter
wanted to go back to Elia.
And the
single set was the person
taking that first step into
whatever is next for them.
Which we have found is just
a whole bunch of potlucks and
Baba Yaga in the forest. But
I mean it sounds great.
Yeah. Sign me up.
Yeah.
Thank you everybody.
Yes, thank you everyone.
That's the questions
for all this.
I hope all the people in
the chat and everyone who joined
us tonight, you got your answers
questioned. And man, like
I gotta say, I know
I'm a
de facto member more or
less and really appreciate getting to
be in on this opportunity.
Y'all obviously have some amazing fans
that care about you, really love
the stories that you're telling. It's very
apparent how much y'all care about them. So
it's an honor and a privilege for me to
get to be a part of something like that. So thank
y'all. Thank you.
Thank you for being here. Thank you sincerely
for coming along with everything.
Absolutely.
Fuck you, you're making me
cry.
Ah, shit.
No.
It wouldn't have been the same literally
without you in the season.
So thank you and thank you
everybody for
supporting us for so long. Like I think back
to the Q&A for season one, which admittedly
was four years ago, but there
are names in the chat
that were there when we recorded
that Q&A. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Which means you've been part of our Patreon
community for that long because that's who
got invited to them, right?
Yeah. Yeah. There are some folks
that have been with us for
so long. It's
great. Yeah. Yeah. So thank you
everybody. Found family. Yeah.
Can't wait for season three.
In the off season, like we are
intending to start season three by
January of 2024.
So in the off season there's going to be
lots of fun stuff. We recorded a Halloween
special with Kyle. Yeah, we did.
Yeah, that was so good.
We did some cool
some fun
Grant Howitt
one shots. There's going to be lots
of Patreon stuff that we're just kind of filtering
in trying to get people tell all your friends
that's cool. That kind of vibe.
And probably
record a couple of things leading up to that
before we really dive in and know what we're
doing for season three. But yeah, we're excited.
We can't wait.
Yeah. So thank you. Thank you everybody.
We love you all. We love you so much.
Thanks everyone. Thank you all.
And with that we will
leave you to go to bed
at your respective times. It's probably
past midnight for many of you in the East
Coast. And we will
see you all in the Discord
and at the next Goo Kang
and Game Time and all that some fun stuff.
That's all continuing. So thank
you all. This isn't goodbye. It's see you
later. Yeah, that's right.
Love you friends. You have a great week and we'll talk
to you soon. Love you guys.
Bye.
Dungeons
and Dragons.
The Q&A to
put a bow on it. What did we call
this episode? I don't know.
It's the end of season two. As we have said
many, many times already.
Thank you so much for being with us along this ride.
Huge thank you to all
of our guests who
we have had along on this
journey. An amazing thank you
to all of our patrons. All
200 plus of you that have
joined us in and out throughout season one
and two. You are
there are no
words to say how wonderful
you are for coming along on this journey
and supporting us in this story that we're
all telling together. I want to say
a big thank you to Amy, Tom,
Carla and Kyle for joining me here
not just tonight but for
the last many years
collectively. It's been
a wild ride and we can't
wait to tell a new story in season
three which as we said should drop
in the feed in January
but don't worry there will be lots of content
coming out between now and then
with some Halloween specials and some
fun Christmas special we're planning.
And if you just can't get enough
we'd love to have you over on Patreon.
Episodes of our The Adventures
of series continue
throughout the next few months. Nothing
stopping there. We have monthly gook hangs
we have live shows scheduled.
We have so much happening
in the community and we can't
wait for it all. Patreon.com
slash DumbDragonCast.
We really hope to see you over there
and we're super excited for season
three. Can't wait!
Alright, that's it from me. You have
a great week. Halloween episodes
coming out next week. I gotta go
get started on that. We'll talk to you soon.
Bye!