previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
nothing too it's nothing like that got it gives you a big wink sully zips down
there pretty quickly glim you as you're lowering the door behind you it
kind of thuds shut sorry and you hear miss man meow meow's voice well the
meeting tomorrow is gonna go really well we got the book now and
everything will just come together up on the podium as you kind of round
the corner you see the book that you stole looky looky what I found
middle of the night very dark but you see a horse and carriage with two
figures of what you can presume to be moot Sully it's okay this is my friend
quicker the small child's with you okay get in we got we gotta go guys
can we go to the Fallen Tower yeah we're gonna make this real quick
guys all right welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons we're a D&D fifth
edition actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Russ More and with
me today is Tom Laird hey that's me I play moot he is a half-orc wild magic
sorcerer and Carla Johnson I play glim a dragonborn pAlydin and all I have in
my head now is how funky is your chicken how loose is a goose cuz
before we started you said ready okay
you've been watching bring it on lately I mean not lately but it's
probably pretty deep in my brain yeah and Amy More that's all right that's
okay you're gonna pump our gas someday I mean go Toros go Toros Tom do you
have anything to add to this uh brrrr it's cold in here there must be some toes in the
atmosphere all right and I play Sullivan's
light a light foot halfling rogue we're all big fans this episode now called
bring it on gonna be taking on something not sure what that is yet
where we might make some more bring it on references after this episode comes
out is over on Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast maybe more on
the discord but Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast when you go there
and you become a patron of ours you get an episode dedicated to you like
today's patron Rachel Red Cloud Johnson thank you Rachel Rachel's the best now
fuck it let's play D&D we hear the sound of creaking carriage wheels and
the clip-clop of horses going down a very quiet street as they move towards
tower where the ruckus is a little bit louder Glim and Sully have just broken
out of jail Moot and Gabriel are leading the way to get back Glim's items
Glim how do I is your room locked how do I get in I don't know what do you
guys think they don't know they saw me get taken away by the guard should
I just go in and say like everything's fine and scoot up to my
room is that easier yeah we totally do that I think you could probably do that
because they're not gonna stop me from going in my own room no and I mean if
we're just real quick about it I think we can be in and out of there
before anyone really notices okay moot can you go in and make sure
there's no guards in there first oh yeah no city guard yeah yeah I'm
gonna I'm gonna bust on in no I'm just gonna walk in normally you hop
hop down and up to the door stepping over a couple of drunken people you
look back and you see Gabriel kind of look longingly at them you swing the
door open and you look in you don't see any any guard there it's a kind of
half-packed house from what you are used to they're at their busiest but
no guards okay yeah so I like poke my head back outside and give glim the old
like man head motion over here then I scoot inside I said to Gabriel be bad
to leave without them right well yeah well yeah cuz I mean he wanted to get
her you're kind of just a tag-along hey I am essential to the outbreak of the
prison situation the outbreak like an illness so you carry along bad omens
with you is that what you're saying now I just sometimes say the wrong
thing he takes a sweet from his flask hey wash here he hesitantly hands it
towards you I take a moderate-sized sip for a halfling it's empty and I say
douche and hand it back to him inside glim you enter into the bar everyone
seems mostly busy they don't they don't really see you come in and I
assume you're trying to just be quick and to the point not really catch
the eyes of anybody yeah I'm just gonna like I just got back just gonna go up
to my room yeah you yeah you absolutely can do that you make it up the stairs
and to the door and as you open it your room is destroyed like nobody
obviously cleaned anything up from when it was tossed earlier your porn mags
are everywhere housekeeping came and then just like so yeah I mean you got
to kind of look around a little bit underneath some stuff possibly to find
everything and is there anything you just grab all of your stuff yeah
basically okay yeah you load up a bag and I grab a couple blankets okay
stealing blankets from me you walk back down the stairs and you catch the eye of
one of the bartenders I remember I mean you've been there a while you've
probably met them all at this point yeah Barlick that's the one that I
keep flipping to so you were so close with the organ man he he kind of
sees you come down with the blankets you put them in your bag or are they
in your hands how big is your bag well I'm pretty big so it's big like okay
it's a back it's a proportion proportional size backpack okay sounds
good so he sees you come down with all your stuff is like everything okay
you leaving I ran into some friends so I'm gonna go we're just yeah we're
gonna we're gonna go uh I'm gonna go hang out with them I think I
probably owe you some money right have I been paying do you prepay in Dungeons
and Dragons hotels I don't know I mean we'll say that you have you have been
paying we'll say it's a silver a night I don't know how much money you
actually have me neither you have it on your sheets but I don't know if I
do oh my god we'll say that you've been spending kind of a silver a day
food and and bored we'll just kind of make note you've been there for I don't
know say six days seems like a lot going minute by minute yeah 24 in there
for two days but whatever all right no we can go yeah we'll say two days
cuz yeah I think it's early yeah it's only the middle of the night you met
moot and then he went and so two nights yeah so we'll say you spent two
silver maybe you settle up right then okay hey I'm not sure when I'll be back
so I should I should settle up and I okay yeah I heard you got taken taken
out by the by the town guard it was a total misunderstanding they like I met
this guy and he stole a thing like you know wrong place wrong time I'm
always so friendly so right they assumed I had something to do with it
but obviously I didn't obviously not all right yeah so just a couple silver
and hopefully see you again I mean it would be great even though I didn't do
anything if you could just like not mention that you saw me back here I'm
trying to persuade then roll a persuasion check I'm going to look on
roses faces like I'm definitely gonna say something right as a 17 I'm very
persuasive it's the PAlydin in me it's my burgeoning PAlydin powers yeah sure
I mean as long as you say everything's okay then it should be should be good
I'll keep it on the down low trust me when I say it was definitely all a
misunderstanding okay yeah yeah of course no problem no problem at all
and I quickly exit not too quickly that it looks suspicious I normally exit
the building ever try to do a normal thing normally never no I mean yes
that's my hope my whole existence is trying to do normal things normally and
being an awkward weirdo okay yeah you make it back out nobody really
pays too much attention to you after that and you get back out and
I assume you you didn't say you went in with her so I know I already left I
thought yeah no that's fair yeah just making sure and so everybody's seated
up in the carriage are we are we laying in the back with blankets over
top of us Tully's for sure sleeping in the back there's no booze what's
even the point yeah I mean I'd probably like trying to hide now you
hop in pull the blankets up over you and as Gabriel goes to snap the horses
again he's like hey moot could you uh he pulls a flask and a glass out of his
did you go fill those like back in the bar yeah here here's a he hands you a
silver piece so yeah it should be enough okay do I just ask for like
your usual is there anything in particular just just fill it fill it
with beer okay fill it with with fire okay it's fine right shuffle back off
the carriage and hop on in they're a bartender available yeah Barlick's
there he catches your eye and says yeah what can I do for you you're back
again Gabriel yeah here yeah I know actually we're just heading out for
a quick night magic lesson he needed a refill on these a quick night magic
lesson yeah apparently it acts differently in the daytime and at night
I don't know I'm new to this I'm just going with what he's telling me okay
so just just a beer and this is for him so okay yeah he said fire I'm
assuming you'll know what to do it's fine yeah he pours a amber red liquid into
the flask and then he fills up the beer and hands it back to you it's
silver oh yeah okay here you go then I like flick it up over to him perfect
I'm always trying to do the moves right make a dexterity check that is a
seven he rolled a seven as well so that goes wide as he tries to catch it
and fumble it and it falls to the ground says really kid sorry I thought
it would look cool I heard about your lobster claws but I wasn't so certain
that that's how fine go hands work all right with your night magic you go
back out as Gabriel sees you he's taps the horse say come on catch up I mean I
wouldn't think you would want me to potentially spill these for you but
don't spill them boy so I what increase my step a little bit and then
does he get the horse to start and then stop I think that would be funny
but yeah make it make a dex check is you're just see how much of it you
don't spill cuz they're spillage oh that was an 18 oh no there's very
little spillage like it just kind of dribbles off over the side as you
kind of hobble up there and sit down beside and say nice work you're
learning it's good all right all right it was this a lesson he hands you
the rope and he takes the drinks from you what's the flask back in his
pocket and says where are we to I don't know I mean I guess we need to get out
of here or we need somewhere to hide or we need to go somewhere anyway right
well all them all them soldier types are moving out tonight so there's
increased guard at the at the gates that's not really that good no no what
a night for a jailbreak am I right right well I mean if you're gonna do
it probably tonight's the best night because so many of them are heading
down to the well of the dragons there anyways well I guess we could maybe head
back by my men does there oh he's got ideas sure there was a nice a few
opportunities to hide in that building yeah yeah sounds like it sounds like a
good plan to YouTube back there yes yeah I don't know who Menda is but I
mean I trust you guys Menda Menda got us those thieves tools oh great yeah we
should we should get those back to her him him yeah yeah okay I'm good with
that moot you know the way Glim and Sully you're covered up by a bedsheet
so you don't know really where you're going but you hear the sound of
rushing water the farther you go kind of sounds like you're going over one
of the bridges and you make it back to Layton Mendez Gabriel goes up and he's
like do you remember the knock on the door I tried to write it down but you
made me tear up my notes you're supposed to remember you just but that's
how I remember things as I write them down he goes up and does the knock
again so you listening well I'm not allowed to write it down so I'm
paying more attention this time all right it's a couple knocks three knocks
couple more knocks and then kind of a did it got it couple three couple that
uh okay I think I got it cool all right a little while passes actually
kind of a long while passes because it's the middle of the night and then
you hear I assume all four of you are at the door now I mean I would have to
think so are you in the back I mean no because I mean I said that I trusted
them wherever they were taking us so sure I am crouching in the wagon okay
just wait sure quite kind of a long while passes and Gabriel's kind of
just rocking back and forth drinking his drink pretty good one good I'm
I'm glad he'd the the bar at bar Barley Bar Bar whatever his name was I'm glad
he did a good job yeah did it did a great job you hear soft shuffled steps
and then the slider opens up glim you're seeing them for the first time
but you see light coming from behind a face and you see black eyes with
bright golden flecks in them and the slider closes back up a few locks go and
the door opens up and he says you're back so soon yeah we well we we got
our we got my friend out of jail and you brought them here we didn't know
where else to go okay just come on in come on in Gabriel you're coming
into yeah yeah I guess and I look back at the carriage and I kind of say it
short one you coming hey that is not a very nice nickname of course I'm
coming it's just more comfortable to sit up here than it was to stand down
there so yeah all four of you go in very rich tapestries and very warm
woods as you enter you smell incense kind of burning that has been burned
throughout and you enter into a very comfortable living space and this is have
a seat draws make sure the curtains are drawn and kind of peeks out and so
you acquired a mode of transportation yeah we we figured we needed
something to to get our friends around town it is it is it yours just
rented for the night okay good and where what are your plans from here you have
two fugitives hi I'm glam it's nice to meet you yes pleasure pleasure he
extends his hand sorry I didn't give a description of Layton Menda to you
but he is a bald headed tiefling two large horns come up and out of his
forehead and wrap down around his ears deep purple skin and yes golden flecked
black eyes like there's no whites to them they're all black and he's in very
luxurious brown and purple robes extends his hand he says yes glim
pleasure to meet you my name is Layden Layden Menda and you my friend oh
yes hi Sullivan slight sully I think these are yours and I hand him the
thieves tools he picks it up and swiftly opens it and closes it yes yes these
are mine thank you thank you oh thank you they came in quite handy good
also this is a really nice place also your eyes are like crazy like it is
like looking at a starry sky mm-hmm yes yes well I don't know what to tell you
there but you know the beautiful it's all I'm saying like you got some
cushy stuff around here it's a great place for someone to take a nap
I'm gonna go take a nap do as you wish the adults will talk hey I'm an
adult I'll be listening my eyes will be closed where my ears will be open yeah
cuz we should probably make a plan sully you don't want to be part of the
plan making you're the one that's so good at all the sneaking ah geez you
and your compliments yeah okay I'm in all right really easy it's a hard hard
sell there said to butter that bread a little bit we broke out of jail
together I feel like we got a little bonding going on so the Gabriel I assume
you you will be staying here and these three will be going on their way and
Gabriel says well yeah yeah probably be easier to sneak three unknowns out
rather than than myself yes yes of course what is your plan what is your
story three three of you what where have you come from and where are you going
well like I said my name's glim and I have a destiny to save the world a
destiny to save the world how cute I'm pretty sure these two are meant to
help me I think they have a destiny too Wow did you know about your
destinies I just wanted to learn magic once I met a girl named destiny
and she was like super nice at first and then she was like kind of a bitch
later I can't keep a straight face and do my shit when I see you guys it's
just so like accurate and I love it not about people named destiny but
that no just only would know like that that would be what Sully would
say makes me happy fair enough fair enough okay so save the world is there
somewhere you want to be that you wish to be information you wish to have
because we're getting you out of Neverwinter so which direction should
you go not north okay I mean that's pretty specific well I mean not
really there's three other directions well if you were to go west there's
there's water if we could put you on a boat take you somewhere perhaps far
away from here maybe I don't know don't know where the boats go we
could just roll in with it here we could sneak you out amidst the troops
as they head down to the well of dragons and you could split off perhaps
towards water deep perhaps somewhere else would get you out of out of the
eyes of the sons of alagondar I assume is who you're now running from the
sons of alagonquin who and the what now is that the is it like an eye
and like like and then I like make horns but then I'm embarrassed because
he has horns and then I'm like like is that awkward but I just kind of make a
face like realizing and then there's like the tassel is that that think we
saw that in the basement of the prison he makes no real emotion or flinch on
his face as you're freaking out about this says yes and I horns he taps his
head and looks like some sort of beadwork or dripping liquid from the eye
perhaps that sounds terrifying it is it is it is not it is not pleasing but
you have seen this this image we we saw it in the basement of the prison
as I'm saying this I'm realizing I also have horn so I like had no reason
to be totally weird about that do we can you tell me again what they were
called these sons of alagon are yeah you know that the prison warden yeah I'm
familiar with her yes miss ma'am meow meow oh yeah well pretty sure she's
working with those sons alagonquin yes are they are they related to the
call to the dragon I need to help defeat the call to the dragon I'm a
follower of Bahamut and they're trying to raise to you Matt and he does like
no bueno for me I feel like you're gonna get a pamphlet out and we might
all moods been writing in his notepad and he says how do you spell a
like a la gondar exactly like it sounds go in there if you actually want it it's
a la g o n dar oh my god it's like literally the only phonetic spelling
that ever has existed in Dumbgeons and Dragons no X's no mystery why no
apostrophes in the middle for some reason I like it the sons of a la
gondar believe they are the true rulers of never winter and that Lord Dagle
never ember perhaps is a false ruler a phony hey that's why they wanted his
ledger it was ledger yeah this ledger I open my bag and I bought a peek in
interesting yeah I don't know what to do with this I mean I can't give it
no no that would that would not be good Lord Lord never ember has got a temper
that one Lord Lord never ember has a temper oh I'm pretty sure anybody with
the first name Lord has a temper that's not his first name it's only just so
confused what's what's in the ledger that I don't know this language I pull
it out and I serve fanning it do you know how books were fluffering through
it and I was like fluffering isn't a word it is now you know exactly what
I'm talking about might I take a look at the book yeah all right he opens it
interesting he flips through none of you none of you could read this no
language is this I don't know I didn't I didn't look at it he shows it to you
it's written in under common he says no definitely not yes no you see it's
kind of vaguely elvish but very different in the intricacies of what it
is it's interesting that they would want this book but seems that they
did it is a list of names no real association beside them are there any
names you recognize in it there are a few town officials yeah many many well
um under their meetings not gonna go very good tomorrow I can just say that
what what do you wish to do with this book do you wish to keep it in
your possession or try to perhaps offload it well if it's important to
would it be worth perhaps relocating fugitives well you want me to sell my
book and then you'll relocate us but a mere suggestion I mean there is
always something in exchange for for goods and services as moot knows he is
he's he is owing a certain thing for the thieves tools that you have
returned to me tonight yeah the routine that Gabriel knew right yes yeah
like a dance routine see that's what I thought but apparently not oh why
I don't know if I if I if this book is so important then we should probably get
it back to the rightful owner well yeah but I mean he's gonna be so mad I don't
think he will I think we did him a great service by getting it from miss
ma'am meow meow yeah but the only reason miss ma'am meow had excited I took
it but he doesn't know that and if you return it I'm sure you'll
appreciate it I don't know what about your friend Merv are we gonna try
and save him or yeah I really like to I just really can't see a way to find out
how to do that I feel like we have a lot of things going on right now and I
don't know which one is most important who's Merv Oh Merv is a really great
guy fishermen stuck in the clink with me just for doing like fishing stuff
not fishing well enough efficient too well anyway arrested for not fishing
well enough I don't know anyway if this town is harsh he helped me to liberate
this book from Lord Never Ember but in the middle of that a giant portal
opened up and these guys jumped through and they stole Merv like a
giant poor Gabriel can we can we make giant portals you can make a
giant portal no I'm asking him if we can yeah you were just good at the
hand jobs it is possible to open a portal I don't believe you are
presently able to open one it's funnier because you said it
intentionally it's the only dirty thing you've ever said not on purpose you
know it's the unintentional hand job sometimes it just happens when you're
supposed to sneak up on you're fluffering a book and I'm sorry what
I don't remember portals it is possible to open portals using magic I don't
believe you have that capability I don't have that capability is that like I
don't have that capability yet perhaps or just in general I mean they're the
magics exist and tapping into wild magic you can do many things it is
possible that given the right motivations you may come across that one
day cool and mood just writes portal with two underlines in his book
exclamation mark hey Sully what were the guys like they took Merv
well it all happened so fast you see I don't remember I think they were in
robes yeah I they people in robes seem like the kinds that would jump out of
a portal don't you think seems like also mystical and magical and they
jump out of a portal and then disappear they knew kung fu oh and they
were very strong and that is why I could not save Murph hmm so they
kind of like digs his foot into the ground like obviously embarrassed that
he was absolutely useless not fight and they took his friend and he's like
well I don't know who portaled in to take your friend or where they might
have gone it sounds like you three need direction need to figure out
where you're going where your destiny is taking you Bahamut you say well
ultimately my destiny is going to take me to demand Thor I need to go to to
Jared time or on the eastern side of the sea of fallen stars because I
need to declare myself to Bahamut but I think I don't think I'm ready to do
that yet I think I need to see a little bit more of the world before
we go do that so I want to stop the cult of the dragon mm-hmm okay so what
if we went with the if that's where the soldiers are all going well let's
go join the fight what do you guys say
oh yeah um listen so the cult of the dragons like really big right and they're
like super mean and stuff and like we don't want to be mixed up any when you
those guys and I'm sure that there are other people working on this and
like like you know what are three inexperienced two inexperienced and
one highly handsome person gonna do in in the grand scheme of things though
really I mean like we probably shouldn't go in there I can't go back
there well glim is this is this what you think your destiny is with your
saving the world I'm not sure yet I don't I don't know for sure and I
might maybe know for sure if it was but it certainly seems like the right thing
to do but Sully if you don't want to go join a crusade I understand but what
do we do then you don't think we can find Merv and you don't want to go
join the fight what should we do instead you're making me sound really
indecisive if I might make a suggestion we need to get you out of
Neverwinter because I feel the bells will be tolling soon signaling your
departure perhaps we send you in a caravan disguised amongst the troops
there are many mercenaries many people who are just off to fight the
good fight it's not like you're marching off in a troop full of
armored soldiers marching line in line you would blend in quite simply
and you split off perhaps move towards water deep there are many people who
have gathered there you could certainly be far outside of the sons of
Alagondar's reach at least for the time being if they feel they need to
pursue you that might change later in water deep you will find a temple
of Bahamut where maybe you can get some more direction on your destiny if we go
this way out like when we're gonna be not traveling with the cult of the
dragon though right no that is hopefully not the case probably never
even see them cult of the dragon are at the well of well of dragons
right which is where these soldiers are marching to and water deep is halfway
give or take yeah okay hey magic man you think you can work on that Porter
thing on on the way I mean yeah it sounds like it's pretty advanced but
I'll they'll see what I can do is there anyone there to teach me magic
where do your abilities come from good good moot well Gabriel has been
telling me well and he's not the only one but apparently just wild magic
good I hate to say that you're on your own but I feel like this trip will be
good for you it will push you in ways that might bring you closer to the
wild magics have you had any incidences why I broke I broke
Gabriel's mug when I was freezing his drink is that what you mean he
chuckles looks to Gabriel as Gabriel is reliving the moment and it's very
disappointed
no that is not what I mean but just be warned that tapping into wild magic
sometimes has consequences and to be aware that some dangers could come
from using them oh well Gabriel how come you didn't say anything about this
there's a controlled environment we were down by the water I felt like
anything that could have come through we could have just drowned in the
water so wait something can come through no you're fine come through
what come what do you mean you're coming through tapping tapping into a
man sometimes you know when you're when you're trying to do something
trying to think of an example like you're trying to write down what you
learn today oh I do that all the time sure yeah trying to write down what
you learn today and then your mind drifts and you write down a recipe
for your grandmother's or father's pilaf like a rice dish yeah yes that's
why I like to take notes as it happens then I can then I don't have to think
back at the end of the day fair enough fair enough so I mean all I'm saying is
sometimes you're trying to do one thing and says that thing might work
and then something else might happen like maybe there's a big fireball or
maybe there's little gremlins that come out of nowhere who's to say
don't know till it happens or maybe a portal opens and that'd be cool or
maybe a portal opens and that'd be cool let's hang our hat on that one good
good job you're so fucking who just kind of looks at his hand with the the
feather necklace wrapped around the wrist and he's just kind of like no
fuck don't worry you're doing really good it hasn't happened yet
usually it's happened by this point so maybe you're in your clear okay
maybe
hey we're back to the middle of the episode now I got to do it for once you
did you were quicker on the draw than everybody else that's right now's the
time when we tell you that we have another contest going on another
contest for us another contest we just had a contest we just love
contests and we've got all this sweet stuff so we have another ghosts of salt
marsh to give away to somebody awesome that's the adventure module with
like pirates and stuff right yeah it is that's awesome I really want to
play it but that's not well maybe whoever wins it will play it with
maybe but if you want to enter this amazing contest you have to tell
about us yeah it's really easy you can share an episode on Twitter maybe you
know your favorite episode or maybe just the most recent one whatever that
either one works for us using the hashtag dumb dragon cast with that
just to make sure we can find oh yeah that too yeah yeah they'll also be a
post on Facebook you can share but maybe comment on that too because
sometimes we can't tell who shared things based on you know settings so
share it tell us that you shared it and that will get you entered as well
I'll link that one down in the description that's what people say in the
podcast thing to say totally and now Amy's back and we've just finished all
the details Amy's here now to say goodbye to the lovely people Amy
goodbye lovely people thank you for doing so and we wish you the best of
luck in the contest yeah good luck win it to win that ghost of salt
marsh it's gonna be good let's get back to that episode yeah
hey it's me again your dungeon master Russ More popping back in here with
that sweet sweet music to ask you if you check out a new podcast I'm
working on with one of my good good friends Sean Howard from the end of
time and other bothers and Alba Salix the podcast is called DM to GM where
Sean and I answer your questions and hopes that we can help you feel more
comfortable around the gaming table so whether you're a new DM or GM or
you've been running games for a while and need some new inspiration or
confidence to know that what you're doing is amazing listen to DM to GM and
then send us your questions we need them just search for DM to GM that's DM TO
GM wherever you listen to podcasts to get your game started
anyways if we are to get you out we should probably do so swiftly is that
what you want to do this sounds like a good plan if we head to the temple of
Bahamut I know they'll take us in and I can learn more about my destiny and
they'll love you guys because you're the best so maybe that's what we
should do oh can't believe I'm seeing this yeah okay all right I shall make
arrangements he walks out of the room and leaves you for in there comfortable
in your chairs Gabriel when we're on our way out are you able to take the
carriage and the horse back to the stables yeah I'll take the carriage and
the horse back to the stables do I have the ledger you didn't say you
took it back I follow him through the door I mean so you follow him through
the door and he has gone down a set of stairs to a basement I follow him I'm
like excuse me mister he turns and looks at you and says yes and his eyes
glow gold for a second and then flashback yes sorry hey we didn't finish
our conversation about the book for the getting us out of here situation right
right but you have the book it just seems like a thing it was just in my
hand I swiftly walked out here's your book thank you would you care for a
flute I have no need for a flute what about a large smooth gray stone
just just a stone well I mean I don't know it could be more than a stone but
I take it out of my pocket does this mean anything to you he looks at it
yes yes it does oh I could tell you but that seems I'm giving you yet another
thing oh but what if you tell me what it is just to satisfy my curiosity and
then I give it to you if you want it so I've I've given thieves tools to
break you and your friend out of jail you got those back I still owe a favor
that's not my favor though no moves on that I've given thieves tools to
break you out of jail you and your friend I am getting the three of you
out of the city through means to pass by the local law enforcement and now
you're asking me for yet another favor nothing in return fine okay no rock
for you I don't need the rock okay I can explain to you what the rock is
oh yeah but I'm a busy man I have to get you out of the city I'll give
you the flute for the information about the rock make a persuasion check 18 so
persuasive so persuasive oh well go fuck yourself oh 18 don't mean shit
look okay listen can I love it with you for a second of course you can I
don't really want to go where the cult of the dragon is going uh-huh why not
well I kind of was like working with him for a little bit mm-hmm um and I
just um I just really can't go back so I'm putting a lot on the line here
for well for glim and I'm not entirely sure why it's not really not
really my thing but like you know I'm just I'm trying to I'm trying to make
some good choices right and I'm gonna be honest I don't know what kind of
what kind of you know level you're on you've given me something you don't
want to go okay you're associated with the cult of the dragon no well not
anymore not by choice what you hold in your hand is a stone of illusions you
think of something and you put the stone down and it creates an illusion
of that something I put it down and I think about myself there is a unmoving
image of yourself that pops up right above the stone oh holy man you don't
want this rock I don't need this rock are you sure this rock does not have
the same value as what we are trying to negotiate here for oh fair enough
listen I just don't know what your intentions are with the ledger so I'm
trying to be a good guy the ledger holds very important information that
decides whether Lord Daigle never Ember remains in control of the city
or the sons of Alagondar make a move to overthrow him whose side are
you on I am a middleman oh that's a dangerous place to be you would know
well how about I how about I just owe you a favor okay the favor can't be for
me to give you the book though that's fine
ain't no dummy I feel after you arrive in water deep there will be a favor I
don't kill children why would I kill children I thought you were a child for
the first five minutes that we met well yeah I get that a lot um just making
sure been in some sticky situations before not in the business of killing
children fantastic I put my hand out shake on it he lowers his hand down
do you I grasp it and I and I like I'm a vigorous handshaker like he looks so
put off by this but takes his hand back so small join your friends take
your ledger I will arrange for the necessary facilities to get you out
well thank you so much I really appreciate it if you didn't tell
anybody that I was working with them not anymore but I mean it's just
something that follows you around you know he smiles and says of course your
secret is safe with me not thanks really appreciate it I pick up the
rock and I'm like this is so this is crazy like I got a magic rock in my
pocket as you pick it up the illusion disappears play with it and put in my
pocket and walk up the stairs just tickled we see Leighton Menda turn back
and begin working at his desk and he is seemingly talking to himself and we
go back upstairs and after a little time passes he comes back up and says
appropriate arrangements have been made if you'll please come with me
everybody he ushers everybody to climb back into the carriage and directs
Gabriel and moot to head down to the southern part of Neverwinter you pass
through some wrecked areas from the earthquake that tore through
Neverwinter many many many many years before and much poorer places than you
have generally been staying north of the river has been very well kept and
very excluded from a lot of the goings-on with the cult and refugees but
this section of the city is just littered with people they're packed
tight shoulder to shoulder you get to a certain point and you have to get
out of the carriage because there is physically no room for it to go and
play moves you through the crowds to the edge of the city and beyond the
city walls there are guards but you seem to just walk past them with little
to no problem and there are three carriages waiting and he says this is
your caravan you will ride with them you will become their friends you will
integrate yourself with them and you will blend in and move far away from
Neverwinter at least for now they will turn off and move towards water deep
once you're in water deep I suggest you search for the temple of Bahamut at
least to start well thank you so much I'll remember you when I'm going to
save the world thank you for your help I feel like we will meet again
sooner than that and I still owe you the one yes you owe me the one
and Sully you owe me one I do finger guns and I write down Sully one moot
one of course and for saving the world that is the one you owe me Glim I bid
you adieu and he tips his hand and blends back in with the crowd and
disappears beyond he's kind of creepy hey he's seen he was very mysterious
mystical as shit you want to know what my rock does obviously you tell them
as we kind of like grab our stuff you're loading into the caravan and yeah
what do you see you put down the stone what happens when you put down
stone I'm thinking about Glim and Glim appears oh and I like jump back like
what the how and I like go like kind of try and poke it I assume my hand
like goes through it goes through it yeah it's a yeah it's not a physical
illusion but yeah as soon as you touch it it kind of wavers yeah is it
always Glim that's amazing no it's not always Glim I pick it up and she
disappears like it's an illusion stone anything I think about and I put the
rock down it shows up oh that's really cool can you believe he didn't
want that stone I mean it seemed like he had a lot of cool stuff at his
house so maybe he already has a few is Gabriel still with us or where'd
we where'd we go yeah I guess we could probably say adios to Gabriel
yeah Gabriel helps you with your stuff into the caravan and he says I'm sorry I
didn't tell you about the possible dangers yeah what do I like what do I
do if that happens sometimes it's not a big deal probably just you know just
take it easy you know do what you're comfortable with slowly push the
boundaries you'll probably be fine okay but what if it's a big deal oh we
can probably kill it with fire probably kill it with fire I have fire breath she
has fire breath look at you've got a crazy told of hooligans you guys I
told you it was destiny this is pretty cool pretty cool but yeah if
something comes through maybe just ask it if it's cool hey hey you cool
hey stop killing that guy you extra dimensional thing that just showed up
you cool sometimes like sometimes it's just an extra spell that happens
sometimes it's something they're not always bad things it's asking if it's
cool or not and if it turns around tries to eat your face then maybe use
the fire breath can it ever be good things you're talking about a lot of
bad things sure sure yeah it could be good things okay wouldn't it be great
if you accidentally magic ice cream every time you cast a spell that'd be
so great see it could be something like that cool that would be pretty
cool is that something I can like think about what I'm guessing magic you can
think about anything you want move you do have cold magic so it stands to
reason at some point you might conjure some ice cream by accident or
otherwise very least maybe I'll put your illusion thing down and say
ice cream and then like to do it like to motivate him no to make him think he
did it oh yeah no for sure yeah he'll probably write it down he'll get
distracted it'll be fine oh we're gonna have fun hey Gabriel I think I
think I speak for all of us when I just say how much we appreciate all
your help and I hand him what's a drink cost at the Fallen Tower you think the
silver got him two drinks cost a silver I mean I think there's cost a
silver but on economy of this town makes no sense I know I thought that as
soon as he was like silver like we don't really like do the whole money
thing you don't know what he put into the flask that's true well that's
true um some real top-shelf food I can give well we established the good
stuff was water was water I give Gabriel a silver and say buy yourself a drink on
me okay thank you it's been a pleasure getting to know the three of you and I
hope that I will see you again very soon I'm sure I'll be back for more
lessons in no time great I hope to disappear into the night someday and
never be seen again I'm gonna save the world three real
different directions I can't wait to see what happens next as you hear the the
sound of the caravans beginning to move out yours begins moving in one of the
people at the caravan who was helping you with your stuff will say begins to
call you and say we're heading out okay Glim I guess I guess we're gonna
go save the world with you
hold please holding just if you could just hold for a second you just play
some music god damn it I literally just read this
intermission I'm trying to see what my destiny stuff is but I think I have to
do a bunch of stuff before that when she passes each one she passes goes just
gotta open roll 20 I know I just saw it it's not in this sheet sorry
from she passes each one she passes goes which is also super creepy I would
give my heart gladly I'm happy for this to keep happening or I can I'm
ready now okay but each day when she walks to the scene she looks straight
ahead not at me go for it the songs know our land umbrella pants
virtues instrumental shores of Avalon red letter and long road ahead are by
Kavin McLeod of incompetech film music dot IO licensed under Creative
Commons by attribution 4.0 visit creative commons.org slash licenses slash by slash 4.0