previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
see anything but I know I definitely saw something it's all I wouldn't understand
you take care of yourself dead dense if you guys see us in town you you
will definitely have a seat right up in the front we wouldn't miss it that's
awesome
welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons I'm your dungeon master Russ Mourn with me
today is Amy More yes that is me I came at this with a very different energy
than I had previously and I play Sullivan slight and Tom layer yeah
that's me I play moot also with me Carla Max dead that is me I play glim
joining us today a very special guest she's a writer streamer podcaster
from venture maidens and also author on that little book you might have
heard of it Rime of the Frostmaiden it's Celeste Conowitch
I'm so excited to be here we're all silently clapping I realize we were all
trying to do it I'll take it should I say who I'm playing today yeah let's
do that I'm playing professor dr. Smith today for this podcast and I'm
excited about it I am a loving the accent work I love that it's professor
the name I love everything that's happening already two degrees the hard
way oh I was assuming that your first name was doctor perhaps I am also a
Smith by trade I am multi-talented professor dr. Smith is a is a character
created by one of our patrons to Devin Michaels thank you Devin thanks
thank you Celeste for embodying professor dr. Smith today yes I hope I
do them justice Devin thank you if you would like to join us on Patreon you
also get an episode dedicated to you like today's patrons Cedric Bozzi again
awesome name that's what I was just thinking what a cool name somebody for
patrons of such cool names I know it sounds like a character name from a
movie but it's a real person or is it or is it oh maybe it's a pen name of
some sort I thought you were gonna say Panda could have some sort of credit
card and sponsoring us monthly yeah you don't know Amy right you can join
us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and now fuck it let's play
Mook Glim and Sully you've been hanging out in the great city of
Gerard Tamar the dragonborn homeland for about a week or two since you've
separated ways with dense he's gone off and joined puff the magic dragon
on tour across the realm what have you three been up to for Glim after
you know making a pledge to Bahamette and maybe like trying to
make friends with that one person that worked at that one temple that was
kind of just a room I don't know how that worked out did that work out are
they my new friend they absolutely they're your new friend they revered
you when you showed up if you were called yeah so you could have spent
much time there okay I again now that you just said that I take it back
because Glim doesn't like to be revered Glim likes to try and
proselytize I think she is interested more in folks who aren't that
interested in what she's selling so yeah she's probably been maybe checking out
some of the other temples because I know you said like there's sort of a
little bit of this and a little bit of that all over there so I think she's
pretty interested in in what else is on is on offer in Gerard Tamar if
you've managed to check out many of the the temples there's temples of
probably been a good stop for you there is a temple to Tiamat which isn't widely
used especially since well the recent events of I don't know that she's that
open yeah it's a members only club to get into that one you need you need the
code yeah I think she might have avoided that one maybe some like gave
it some real mean looks from outside Sully has been talking to pretty
much every person who has a stall in the general market area also has snuck
away to for sure draw dick on the door of the Tiamat temple love it didn't
scroll his name like he maybe normally would have but definitely just a big
penis because that's what he thinks of them mood has discovered a thing
that they have in Gerard Tamar that they don't have in other places that
he's been to it's called a buffet and a lot of competing restaurants have these
buffets and he has been going real hard and his well his clothes are fitting
a little tighter than they were when everyone arrived here in town what was
your favorite buffet that you went to there was one that they served this
like meat that rotated and they were like shaving bits off of it and he
didn't even get the name of it he just he smelled it from the street
came in ate his fill and then like staggered out the door so when when meat
is Hillip's idea it's not a good idea but when it's your idea it's a good
idea that is correct. Listen, Hillip's not even here to be upset about this Russ. No, it's fine. Compartmentalize. Just throwing it, just bringing it. It's a callback, right? Anyways, throughout
your travels you'd seen that you've seen like signs and had heard
mentions of this wonderful apiary just on the edge outside of the main pyramid
of Gerard-Thamar right where the plains meet there's a small grove of trees and
you've been told that this is a place a site that you have to see while
you're visiting. Okay you guys I know you don't love the like touristy
thing but we have to go to this apiary like every temple I've gone to
they've told me that it's like the one place you have to go while you're here
so could we please just go? I'm really sorry to bring this up I just don't
normally think that girls enjoy going to the apiary it's really because
well just it's so hard to get the stream over the edge you know you know
I'm saying like and he's making like lewd gestures from his crotch and and
pointing down and like and I just don't I think it's really more for you know if
you are more anatomically outward you get what I'm saying? I don't maybe I
misunderstood what an apiary is but could you explain what you mean? Well
yeah it's so like so an apiary is when most of the like latrines are
full right and it's also kind of just a special experience because you
go up high right in this like you're up and like almost like a balcony kind of
situation and it's when you're peeing over the edge into the air but moods
just frantically writing down pee balcony question mark you have to see
that I mean it's not the tour okay well I don't maybe we should just go
see I'm not I feel like my understanding of what it is and your
understanding I'm not sure you're supposed to just go to look I mean
that's really this place has changed you but I mean I could yep and he
wiggles around a little bit he's like yeah I could go the three of you
uncertain what you're walking into head off and out of the pyramid and down
towards the location wherever it is so he's gonna be there where he's made
that abundantly clear there may or may not be public urination well we'll
see there will be but as they approach round over and down a path what do they
see so I think as you're traveling towards the outskirts of town here you
know the houses are a little error the buildings are a little bit further
apart so you can actually start to see you know glimpses of nature on the
outside edges here and so right on that borderline between like urban
and natural settings there's this cute little like whitewash shop that has
this big sign on it painted in like happy gold and black letters it's a big
B and then a plus sign that makes up the sign here so B plus and you know
there's a little set of double doors and shop windows have been set up in
this little front stand area and there are a variety of honestly just
trinkets inside it's sort of like walking by like a bath and body works
where you look in the window and you're like what is actually in this
window every once in a while there's like little bottles of stuff that have
like amber colored liquid and lots of like baskets and like decor that all
seems kind of be like honey themed and then you can tell behind this
building there is a large patch of land that has been like concealed with
high fencing on all the sides so that's what you see B plus in front
of you okay Sully before we go in here I just want you to promise me
that you're not going to pee unless you see several other people already
peeing so like okay more than two let's say four or more people I can also
join in the urination sure what if I just find a bathroom yeah that's great
oh then you can go right all right I just wanted to know like there's so
many rules also I'm not sure this is exactly what I think it is yeah I think
that might be the case I'm going to go try the door the door is opened and
like a happy little like there's like a little fat like bee wind chime that
kind of like bangs and like you know lights on sound I think as you
step inside it definitely looks like a gift shop of some kind you see a lot
more of that same product that was in the window around like neat kind
of shelves that fill this area here there's like little plushies of bees and
then you see like a little glass cabinet that has like all of these
little jars that are labeled different floral sounding names and then there's
a counter on one side and you see that there are a couple different signs
here there's purchases is in front of one side of the counter here and then
tours is on the other side and of course these are both on little like
painted signs hanging on the different parts of the counter here this place
smells good I guess would I be you could or or your or or your your your
assistant could be there I bet my assistant would be here I don't think
I'm working the counter I have that's right I don't work the counter
yeah you you step in you get that initial look around the room and then
stepping out from a back room is a taller man he's long and lanky very
rustic clothing he steps out his head kind of protrudes a little bit like out
from his shoulders in a way that like you know you should probably see a
chiropractor and he comes out and he looks at you and says welcome what can
I do for you I'm Derek hi Derek I'm Sullivan Sleight hi Derek nice nice to
meet you we're just visitors to Girathamara and everyone said we
should come here so like I guess a tour oh what do you guys think and I
look at Moot and Sully like I don't want to buy things in the gift shop
until I do the tour right right he goes over to the tour side of the
desk and says just come over come over here it's like five feet away maybe
switches hat or something or put on a pin that says tour guide on like a
safety vest below the desk and pulls out a clipboard and says just write
your write your names and as you're writing your names on the on the clip
board you look up and he does have a different hat on and a different
vest says well I whether the tours starts in 15 minutes well I'm off for
browsing I guess can I touch any of the stuff in the bottles what's in the
bottles hold on he pokes his head in the back professor I'm having a question
here I don't know if I've ever had this question before can they touch the
things in the bottles oh we have a curious mind amongst us one moment and
you hear like tumbling from the back and then stepping out from behind like the
little like gold curtain that separates the doors leading backwards
you see a very squat kind of middle-aged to late age gentleman his
face is very small and kind of like his his chin comes forward a little
bit like almost like a snout and his hair is cropped very shortly and has
this like wide stripe of silver white just going down the middle with the
black on the sides here and he looks at you through little like gold
spectacles and he's like mmm a question I do I am extremely qualified to answer
questions is this of a medical nature or a physiological nature I want to
stick my fingers into the little jaws of the brown stuff more of a touch
you see why I I I didn't have an answer uh yes I'm sorry is this um are you
hoping to buy things do you want a sample you want a sample I think is
what you're trying to sample oh wonderful well we do have this
wonderful why didn't you offer them samples Trevor yeah Trevor I didn't
know your name was Trevor I go by Trevor when I have my tour guide hat
on professor dr. Smith calls him a different name every single time he
narrows his eyes he's like when did you change your name no it's fine it's
fine tour guide Trevor here you can sample just don't we had a Trevor
working here last week the same young man you fired Trevor I'm Derek oh well
Derek or whatever your name is go give them some samples they're in the bin
back over there yeah have you given them you're useless Trevor Derek or
whoever you are welcome welcome to be plus the finest apiary the only
apiary in the entire city here we produce many fine honeys waxes all
sorts all manners of varieties of great creations that we source to the
meter ease around here do you enjoy mead we probably had something to do
with it I do enjoy me yes well you cannot make mead without bees I brought
the samples here which one brown brown one yes so we sort of and I'll like
arrange them on the table and you see it my nails are very long almost like
claws as I arrange these these little like pots of honey for you on this
table and that all of these are influenced by of course different
floral sense that we have incorporated I I'm sort of a an artisanal honey maker
if you will if you will of course and one of the parts is like empty on the
thing and I look at it very sadly and say unfortunately I cannot give you
my greatest creation my fondest creation for lack of materials but
Trevor removes his hat and puts it to his chest oh my god who are you sorry
I'm Derek without the hat I'll put it back on I was just I was just morning
morning the the the lost sample is my sight isn't what it used to be you
all smell the same to be so all all of the samples are different yes oh
yes my lad we have we have many varieties of hives on the property
and of course I do a little of this a little of that some of its nature some
of it of course is alchemy to create these different flavors so here why
don't you try this one it's a it's a lavender and then this one here we
have a cinnamon blend and I'm scooting them closer towards you with
like little dippy pieces like wooden pieces Sully's for sure got his
fingers in there and in no time is absolutely covered in honey like this
kid is sticky oh so sticky my goodness it's everywhere I don't know what
happened I thought I put it in my mouth I wish at this point we would even be
surprised by that but it just happened so often oh oh please mr. buffet why
don't get it all over myself it just all goes in me and I mean of course
if the honey won't delight you I do have several other objects that you
might find interesting I do a bit of artificing here as well so I'm sure
there's something oh what about the bubbles oh the bubbles yes you do look
like and I look specifically at slowly I'm like you look like the sort
who would enjoy something like that oh I would like bubbles yes yes please
I take out a little like wicker basket from behind the counter no no we
haven't set these out for everyone yet so this is sort of a first look but here
we are they are bubbles and there is a little like printed logo that's been
put on them that says ever bubbles with an exclamation point and it said
made with equal parts joy and depravity and their honey flavor you tell me
these bubbles yeah well she first batch didn't go go so well well regular
bubbly bubbles are useless because they pop so we made some that don't they
don't pop so don't eat them because they'll never pop and you'll just have
a bubble sitting inside you for all eternity so I must express please do
not eat I'm saying it would probably only stand you till you get to the
poopy area am I right well mm-hmm Trevor's not here for a reason
oh well okay I maybe I won't play with the bubbles but I'll watch I'm
definitely not gonna eat them but I'm interested in the joy and depravity so
what does that mean well the depravity part is it can be
destroyed with a sharp metal if you have the ever bubble liquid of course
then they turn into a combustible sort of situation we're still working on it
but this is the first launch and we are very excited to test them on a
market so would you say it's more of like a soft launch oh yes that is a
great way to put it yeah I don't have a degree in marketing so you know
that's a that's helpful advice friend anyway yes we have a ton of these if
you would like to buy them could I see these bubbles in action yeah what do
what do they do hmm Derek why don't you show oh yeah um okay so well you
take take take the bubble one you take the one yes always start with
put it put it in the bubbles yeah dip it up and down up and down up and down up
and down and then not too much no sorry yeah right you're creating some frost
oh you need the specific right liquid to mixture ratio liquid to mixture
ratio right I forgot that mixture ratio three to one right yep okay and
then you purse your lips and blow just so just so a gentle blow more of
a whisper sorry and then a bubble forms out the end and it it floats in the air
and it's shimmery appearance to it as it floats down professor doctor could
you hand me the the sharp object I know you told me not to handle them
but you also told me to sample this well I'm honestly not quite sure who
you are just give it a shot I can't do a pair of scissors from like a high
shelf or something like okay well um all right ready oh we probably
shouldn't do this inside should we that's oh no no no we should not get
the bubble out I'm waving the bubble with like a piece of paper out the
door follow me it never pops can you just pick it up in your hands you can
try you can certainly try I would not like I would not like to try we'll
continue fanning we get out front and he's like already here we here we go
don't don't be surprised I start I hide behind glim a little bit it's very
surprising I feel like it's a little late for that Derek Trevor goes to pop the
bubble you are with with the scissors and it explodes and there's this mist
that forms and then from it almost from like inside of it a giant ball of
flame engulfs and goes up into the air there I see why you didn't want to
do that inside why you wouldn't want to eat that so also that claps yes Sully is
like so impressed on on second thought perhaps we shouldn't have made the
bubbles so delicious yeah really discourage that but like I was saying
I would absolutely love to try this mixture one more time but of course
with the materials gone I cannot if only there were some
adventurers who could help me with this task alas here I am on the outskirts of
town unable to make more bubbles professor dr. Smith just just says this
all all the time I'm not only if only no no Derek you must stay here you
must mind the store Derek I have two degrees I cannot stand behind that
counter what would the people say Derek what would they say Derek yeah Derek
Derek come on yeah Derek get your head yeah Derek oh you're so not smart I
miss Trevor to be quite honest Derek puts his hat back on it's Trevor too
oh my gosh there's this strange man who insists he works for me and I
don't know what to do about it quite honestly next time I see him I'll I'll
kick him out good just punch him right in the snoot I'll punch him in the
snoot what's he leans down to the to the group what's the snoot I think I
think he means the nose right oh you're in the face area I have to
punch myself in the face yeah you should probably do it fast okay well
maybe I'll tell okay no it's all right I'll figure it out yeah okay okay
yeah I'll watch I'll watch I won't let that other person watch the
store a Glimer sounds like a good thing that like something we could do
to help maybe yeah is the material I assume is the same one that you're
missing from your most favorite honey that you normally have indeed indeed
it is there has been an alarming shortage of hell wasps again oh you
have to go this is Trevor again I got that information I mean yeah I got I
got that information flip knows where the hell wasps are in the in the
forest is the thing that you need for the like when there's a really big guy
and you call him tiny so these are no no they're wasps from hell so you can
imagine why I am just there's just out of sorts out of sorts without them for
how can I make more marvelous bubbles for the children if I do not have
access to more of this explosive venom you're giving that they carry giving
the bubbles to children sure the bubbles of course you give bubbles to
children adults should not play with bubbles exploding fire bubbles I there's
only one kind of bubbles so I don't know what you're implying perfect got
it it's just it's a different culture so oh I well I hmm guys my story it
brought us into this I feel like we're a little bit like kind of like
where obligated to do this I was totally like was like oh we can help
with this but are the hell wasps in hell currently or oh I don't know my my
last assistant was researching it Trevor could you could you get them
could you get that information from them yeah yeah he takes his hat off
changes clothes again both my character and Celeste are so so it's it's all
genuine yeah hey Derek here I know I was the guy you didn't want to see
watch he puts his hat half on his head and punches himself in the face oh yeah
oh this is the stuff anyways I got that information you just have to go
into the meth wood forest and meet up with flip you know flip he hides out in
there and then deals with all the bees and the wasps and all the stuff that
is native in the in the in the forest he said he saw some hell wasps
and you could probably go there and Bob's your uncle you got the whole
wasp I just uncle Bob have to do with this there's so many people we're
meeting today I this is just an extraordinary how much business we've
had I'm gonna I'm gonna put my hat back on so oh look Trevor's back Trevor
thank you I chased him off professor you know what Trevor you you should get
a raise I know you're an unpaid intern but I will I will pay you more
in wisdom that the the most valuable of all commodities more valuable than
money sure I shall remind you once again what my mom always said she's
like Trevor Derek Derek Derek she starved to death she said sustained
us all money is for the week the week money is for artists money is for
artists this really is a different culture it's the middle baby what are
we talking about today jingles and jangles no doubt oh maybe some stuff
jingles and jangles holiday season yep that one coin purses all of these
things and more are coming your way somewhere some way somehow you'll know
it when it hits you but we're explaining it right now for you that
we're not gonna explain it but what we do have that we would like you to
check out is Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where how many patrons
are we up to now as as it stands right now as we're recording yeah maybe we'll
let Amy take this one what did you say 69 oh Amy said 69 she said it all
sultry too I did yeah yep so we couldn't even wait for our episode
69 which is in two episodes because you beat us to it patrons yeah I'm
talking to you thank thanks for being so great thunder yeah yeah thank you yeah
just a little aggressive coming at you with that love there we have a thing
going on new and upgrading patrons get some cool stuff and then for every
five we get we record a bonus episode there's a lot going on is what I'm
saying and it's all like pretty great and for 2020 how many times has
someone said there's a lot going on and then followed it up with the
sentence and it's pretty great you just heard history breaking ground here on
Dumbgeons and Dragons Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast new and upgrading
patrons every five bonus episode plus those patrons who are new and
upgrading get some sweet merch in their pockets in time for Christmas if
you sign up December 9th 2020 because that's the year we're in hmm yeah
yes that one I mean yeah if I 60 because currently have 69 we would like to be at
70 because that means bigger community more people we want to get to know you
I mean let it linger for a little bit if you see it there's like admire it
and then just do a nice screenshot screenshot so you can remember it yeah
don't wait too long though cuz someone's probably doing the same
thing and they're gonna tip it over to 70 like an accidental sign up when
you're trying to screenshot yeah that would be that would be tragic so
you miss the boat I think it's just that our patrons see the value in this
awesome deal and all the like stuff cool stuff we want to give them and
obviously 11 people thought it was totally worth it so thank you yes
thank you thank you so Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast we'll see you
over there and now get back to this episode with Celeste who's just amazing
isn't she so fun go check out all of Celeste things at her website Celeste
conowitch.com then go listen to her at vent on the venture maidens cuz she's
great over there and then go get that rhyme of the frost maiden cuz she wrote
that that's so cool so cool oh I saw a thing too on DM's guild she wrote like
a book of puzzles yes she did and it looked really cool she's got so many
things out there she's such a talented person and so nice and so fun
and it came late a game with us which is like makes me question her
judgment a little bit but in all other ways she's like Celeste really did
nothing else going on gonna end on that high note here where we're
questioning the guest who you're gonna come listen to but gushing but gushing
yes thank you all for being here hopefully you're having a wonderful and
safe time and we'll talk to you very soon okay bye bye bye okay so if I get
this straight we have to go into the meth forest sorry sorry takes his
hat off meth wood puts his hat back would I don't what the fuck is the
difference between the wood and the forest I don't know word so the mess
two syllables as well and flip which what kind of name is that even three
letters what mm-hmm what is it FLP yeah they didn't even have a vowel
that's fucked up I'm getting very agitated with this there was an
exploding bubble I'm still sticky it's getting to me you guys and now
there are hell wasps yes how do you not get stung by a hell wasp oh you
will probably get stung but the good news is that you all paid for a tour
already didn't you so that way I can provide you with some bee keeping
gear and I shall be there as well and I do consider myself a bit of an
expert with bees wasps insects of all varieties so as long as you stay by me
you should be more than safe is is that what you're a professor of is is is
bees or you're you're not a professor yeah you cannot profess bees what
college offers a B degree no absolutely not I am I am a professor of B
physiology to let you know to clear that right up I am also a medical doctor
of bees but no I do not have a degree in bees or something like you are the
person to call yes I can save a bee having a heart attack okay I don't like
to talk about it too much because you know flaunting my heroic status
seems a bit vain don't you think but yes I can do open-heart surgery on a bee if
it is required well if you're so why do you need adventurers because I am
old young man I am old and tired and I need help I thought with all the
wisdom you'd be able to handle it who knows what's on the way to get to
these bees I can deal with the bees and the wasps and but there's the
whole lot of forest between here and wood forest all places I don't want to
be I just need I need the hell wasps and I need to come back here will will
you help me it's really the bottom line I mean I feel like we sort of
already said we would before really getting the facts of the scenario so
that's a life lesson I think maybe for us I was just trying to be so like
glim you know like helpful and stuff and I really put my foot in it this
time I'm not gonna lie cuz you know what we actually ended up paying her to
go and help her find hell wasps so that's really it's doing the
community a service think of all the children think of all the children
enjoy the end result of this it's gonna be a check in the wing column for us
either Trevor standing behind professor Dr. Smith and he's like you didn't pay
mouthing oh that's true that's true I mean I'm not doing anything else I
guess but do you have like a wet wipe or something to these sticky the
situation yes oh I also run a business in cleaning products it's amazing what
you can do when you work in honey you do have to develop quite a few things
to get sticky things off so yes here are my my my dr. professor Smith wipes
here you are I like hold out some wet wipes that I've rebranded with my
own name when I pull one out it continually goes and I like shake it
like a towel it's like towel size I'm like oh my god yes you get very sticky
working yes maybe maybe one day I'll actually take you on the tour and you
can see what I what I spend my days nobly doing I think we're gonna get
like you know the behind-the-scenes how to capture hell wasps to a
very exciting invaluable than the mountain knowledge that we're going to
going to be astronomical yes yes you are being paid in wisdom truly it's the
best currency that is that is the rumor that's right Trevor or Derek and he
narrows his eyes and looks at you is like this is how Tarek got his name on
HGTV I just have I guess one question do you have some sort of special container
or I have two questions is there a container yes our hell wasps the same
size as normal wasps just extra mean or are they just okay they're from hell of
course they're larger you have to be so big to survive down there what those
little guys down there just hanging out with Devils like oh I'm a B size
and get murdered right it was a silly question so so do we like dogs
they're honestly they're like dogs like a large dog I'm not I'm not kidding
around a large dog that flies and stings people yes cool cool yeah let's do more
of that extremely poison it's arm and I'm like scared yeah I think I think
that's a good call Sully while this conversation is happening Tarek is
going around with a tape measure measuring everybody's like dimensions
arms legs in seams and then he rushes inside okay I'm so glad you you walked
into my store and and were able to help me you know most people just run
the other way when I ask them for things I don't know why no idea
definitely not disappointed that I'm not peeing off a ledge right now
I was gonna say do you usually lead with the hell wasp information because I feel
like that would send people running instead of easing into well I do have a
variety of projects I until very recently I had enough you know ground
carapaces and everything to last me quite a while but you know there are
always new projects and it seems people don't want to go after fire
elementals and then give me shambling mound parts and sometimes they don't
want to give me the heart of a gelatinous cube and I just don't know
why people are just so generally unhelpful so this is just such such a
delight selfish really those other people it truly true I mean it's all
for science especially with the amount of wisdom I give every day to all
those around me you think it's no it's my turn it's dr. professor
dr. Smith's turn no no it's not just standing near you good good what I am a
doctor did somebody say they need medical attention I cannot help you
unless you are a bee oh yeah I mean I mean my my great-great-grandmother my
father's side was a bee but I mean other than that oh that's fascinating
congratulations there I do feel superior than others Derek runs out mm-hmm with
four beekeeper suits and says here you go now is this made out of like a
magic material or something that's gonna protect me no it's just mesh
just mesh and then you have the big the big hat in the big mesh it'll
come down and sort of them so when they fly at you they get confused and they
can't sting your face except that they are the size of large dogs so yes that
is true okay that is true but we look great I've always been perfectly safe
inside of one of these suits nothing bad has ever happened to me in
my entire life so I think you should trust me turn around and Trevor is
trying to put on your suits for you like just trying to feed your arms into them
it's like getting in lifting your leg like it's important to make sure
everything is sealed so those little fuckers they'll get right into your
cups the dog-sized fuckers will just get right in there I have a feeling like I may end up right in one of these things by the end of this
encounter I'm gonna put on my B suit I'm gonna help Trevor Derek help me put on
my B suit I'm gonna stand there like I'm getting fitted for my wedding day
and let him put it on for me could you just lift your leg could you lift
my leg for me Derek professor he's not lifting his leg oh my lad you
must lift your leg Trevor is is apparently incapable of doing so you can't
just find good help nowadays can you and I lift my leg I'm being paid in
wisdom it doesn't feed me very well but it's the best currency I'm sorry are
you complaining about being game queen because there are plenty of people out there
look at that I'm all zipped up let's go my hat my hat fell off that was
Derek sorry Trevor's back I missed you
really reminds me of my floppy Sun hat guys I love it yeah where they happened
to that floppy Sun you know I think I just left it back at the B&B so many
things behind oh bees I know about bees of course maybe you should open
B&B also professor Dr. Smith does not put on a suit so okay well I'll just I'll
just hold on to it back here for you professor Dr. Smith yes I don't look
cool in it I'm I'm going on an adventure yes so I need to look cool totally not
cool yeah hundred percent also all my weapons are inside my suit yes see
that is gonna be very hard to deal with that is why I did not want to deal
with that would it be okay if I unzip my suit no I mean if you want that
if you want to open up that chasm that chasm for those little bee feet to crawl
inside that's up to you that's on you man I don't know what to do I unzip it
like a little bit of the way and I hold the zipper I make a tisking sound
I feel shamed we we fade out on the scene as Trevor Derek Derek waves and
says hopefully you make it back alive that was ominous you'll punch yourself
Eric Eric Eric and we flash ahead and we're in the methods for the scene
idiots in a suit yes sir dude very cool very cool professor doctor aside
from that the scene is dark the canopy is very thick the sound of of birds and
insects is like ringing throughout the forest there's a path that you're
following as much as you don't know where you're going
Derek Terrick Trevor told you just to follow the path and that will lead
you to flip so do you do you all peruse many forests is this is this like a
new thing or is this old old hat hey just you know I'm walking very
strangely also kind of in the middle bouncing in a great time
yeah oh yeah professor dr. Smith doesn't get out a lot no no no I spent my youth
inside universities and inside B hospitals and I just never quite got
around to doing the adventuring thing I mean sure there was a little time in
my youth when I did a bit of artificing but now I mean I sort of
just do projects in my garage as it was this is all very very exciting yes in a
few forests yeah we've we've traveled a bit flip the pathway opens up into a
large clearing and in the center of this clearing there is a small hut from
the distance that you you see you see like there's a small smokestack with
plumes of smoke coming up and out of it the door looks closed you don't see you
see like a low glow of fire coming from inside but no signs of anybody moving
in around the area hey move why don't you knock on that door there that's I
think I'm just gonna knock hello oh sure take it away glim hello and I
knock knock knock I say knock knock and also knock oh you're one of
those people also taps her wrist when she's asking someone what time it is
oh the horror has you knock knock the door slowly creaks open that's that's
never good hmm excuse me is someone needs to oil your hinges I do have oil
if you have money to give me flip is it is there such a thing as bee oil yes
of course oh I'm learning so much I really I realize now I just don't know
that much about bees oh well there's a wide variety of products you can get
from bees and I started listing I'm like wax and pheromones are forming the
basis of soaps and candles inside this house don't like the wisdom my god are
you in here Sully you go into the house yeah anything to get away from all the
knowledge and wisdom Sully doesn't like the wisdom it's an empty empty
cottage it's a single single room there's a bed a table two chairs a little
kitchen area and like a stove fireplace that is has a fire going in it but
then there's a note like a sealed envelope on the table and it's
addressed to oh professor dr. Smith yeah this is for you the same look at
it oh who do you think it's from if I had to take an educated guess they
didn't they didn't put a return address on it it's just poor poor
penmanship I'll say as I'm they also didn't mail it it was just left in
their own home oh god somebody lives here in the middle of the woods how
uncomfortable so what does it let us say maybe it will be oh yes yes and I
use one of my ridiculously long like nail claws to open it up in a sharp
motion and I will take take the letter out delicately you unfold it and begin
to read it and it says dearest professor dr. Smith help I have been
kidnapped how would you be able to write this if you were kidding okay by
by the fiercest Latavus this means nothing to me does this name mean anything to
anybody else that platypus I guess so oh no Latavus is that oh it's hard to make
out here everybody can make a history check obviously professor dr. Smith
knows nothing about last ten seventeen thank goodness oh you would know too
wouldn't you yeah you read a book about him I write a lot of things down
the the name catches you as odd at first but then you remember that Latavus
is a green dragon who up until recently had been known to mostly live
or reside in the western areas of Faerun but has since moved more central
is he also known for writing notes for the people he captured his serial
killer move green ink instead of leaving a joker playing card at the
scene he writes a neat little note yeah the note continues need to bring
hell wasp honey to Latavus's lair sincerely not Latavus your friend
flip PS definitely not lot of us still not lot of us okay so now I don't I
frankly don't know what to do since flip was going to show us where this this
honey was and now we need it to go get flip I'm feeling a little out of my
depth here does anybody know how to locate honey in a forest I've got an
even bigger question yes do wasps make honey well it's actually interesting
most but hell wasps in particular what they make is not so much of a honey
substance but more of a this this strange honeycomb substance of which
they build their infernal hives which sort of actually look very similar to
termite mounts if you are viewing them from from that perspective from an
ornithological oh wait that's not the right word I look at glim and I
stop listening first technically not true honey but I mean hey when you're
from all over the plains it maybe we could just go and yell buzz buzz buzz
buzz is there anything that how wasps like to eat one of those oh look at
me and all my flesh mm-hmm I mean that would certainly work if you were
anywhere near them where they could hear you I just walk over to where
professor dr. Smith is standing and I said can you just just like a step to
the left oh yes well I think maybe there's more of the note on the
ground because there's another piece of paper on the floor that you were
just standing on oh my oh my goodness oh what's on this mooch you
look at it and it appears to be a map honey here exactly perfect extremely
convenient thank you young man me and my big big feet how many times have I
heard that save it for next episode Celeste are you regretting inviting me
just I mean big feet episode 69 like that's a gigantic feet everyone tells
me especially women I don't know why
you
the song long road ahead is by Kavin McLeod of incompetent dot film music
dot io all other music and sound effects can be found at epidemic sound
or boom library dot com a huge thank you to our supporting producers Gabriel
Lynch mark heartless Stevie cat water flame Jacob Madden Christian Brown
Jessica Babyok derelict Devin Michaels Aaron Stevens Luke I guess and Ray
Sir back to find out more about how you can support Dumbgeons and Dragons
visit us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where you can have
exclusive access to 50 plus hours of bonus audio content great in-game NPCs
and items as well as play games with the cast Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
have a great week and we'll talk soon welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons we play
games it wasn't because I was mouthing a lot it was I saw you out of the
corner of my eyes I don't know what Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb
dragons production