previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons
We've got it. We've got to be getting close now. Perhaps we should land
until it gets too dark and
Try to rest. Even just short amounts of sleep would be
Would be good. I think perhaps just to watch
One sleep. I feel the same way
Okay, Talgir, you you sleep. We will protect. You
Here and
See branches explode out in front of you
pincer legs like long pointed legs one out in front and two kind of behind with this
Almost humanoid figure at the center of these legs. Zombie crab. I kicked Talgir
Yeah
You see like ripples through the air as it looks up and screams
Receiving this blinding pain where you strike it these creatures jump out
Towards you as you lift up through the canopy
So we're all facing away the creatures are all in the middle and the sacred flame can get them all
you feel the heat pour over them and they shriek as they release and fall back down towards the canopy and you
zip off as quickly as you can you crest over this hill and you see the light coming from the tower of the
arcane brotherhood and
Noise that hits you like a wall and it's the noise and sound of undead and then
Amidst you catch we need to get to the tower quick
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. I'm your dungeon master Russ More
He him also with me today is Tom Laird he him and I'm playing Talgir heavy foot a dwarf pAlydin
Tell me more Tom I was gonna say more things but then there weren't there weren't there weren't
Also with me is Carla maxed out she her I'm playing again bull Nuri
Kalashar cleric and Amy More
She her and I played the amistasia a high elf druid so excited to be here
I'm going to use this intention thing again
I'm really gonna put it forward in this episode man
I'm gonna roll over 10 every time and I know that might not still succeed every time
But I think just you know
Over 10 every time at least you're giving yourself a fighting chance. It's a it's a reasonable thing to put it
You're not being greedy the universe you roll 11 and you're like, oh, but you're not like rolling a three. So
Yeah
Intentions boom love it the intentions in the darkest timeline get it girl
You just get it girl me I did I felt it felt right it sure did yeah
No, I felt like it's all right, you know, where else it feels right is over on Patreon Patreon.com
Feels so right over there. So right we have a loving and dear community over there your favorite pair of PJ pants
Yeah, that's what our Patreon community feels like that's what
We've got all that sweet lovely bonus content where we'd play other games and give you an entire other podcast over there
Because we love love you so much. So Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
And when you are a patron you get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron Nicole Pio
Get it girl
Yes queen
Treat yourself
But I I think Nicole should do that treat yourself episode over on Patreon part of the adventures
101 ways. I do believe to treat yourself roll yourself in butter. No, oh, yeah, that's was one of them
I'm sure that was one of them. I thought it was roll butter in sugar
No, there was one where you just have to spread the butter all over you
I think these are the ones that I was coming up with and Tom. Yes, I did them
So that's why they're there into it
So come on over to Patreon you guys treat yourself. That's right Patreon.com slash dumb dragon Cassie over there and now fuck it
Let's play
Did you guys hear that I heard something what did anyone hear it more clearly it sounded not dead someone
They need to get to the tower someone somewhere
I want to like peer over the edge of the carpet without risk of having to make a dexterity saving throw. I mean
Sure, so you kept going over the city. Yes
Yeah, okay
I want to assume that when we were hit with a wall of sound of undead
That we like we slowed slightly to survey. We're not just like and we're here. Yeah
Well, I was gonna give you a description again of what you do see but you know
You're already been starting out dialogue. So we don't do that ever. No, I love it. Like here's something new. Love it. Do it more
So you're over the city now you see like if the ground is moving beneath you like the streets are felt
You see the the light at the tower spinning like there's there's
Light from within the tower. You don't see anything else
Any sign of life anywhere else in the tower just at the tip just at the peak
What's the top of a tower called? Just know just the tip
Exactly how to say that just for a second and then a second
What's everybody's passive I know yours is 20 so you probably heard you would have heard things the loudest
18 18. So you also would have been are we talking?
Insider investigation perception
9 so tall gear you wouldn't have heard it. I mean you played it
Well, you wouldn't have heard it nearly as well as yen bull or the uh, so roll investigation at disadvantage tall gear yen
Bull just roll straight. I
Mean you have disadvantage on everything. So everybody just roll at disadvantage
Even me, but you're at the level one levels. Okay, I'm giving this dice one last try
This one failed me so many times the intention to really the spectrum
19 and a one
My first one was an 18. Oh what?
And then a four what's what 14 plus what 20 20
Plus 20. Well, no, sorry. What am I investigation? Oh, I thought we were rolling
I thought we were selling passive perception. I'm so confused
Four plus investigation. Okay is six. Okay, not as good as that 18
I rolled I rolled a two and then a two so those are it's a four. I'm looking oh we can combine roles now
Yeah
Everybody gets a four and a four a two and a two
So you definitely heard it coming from the city
But now that you're looking and over top you can't you can't see for the life of you where this that shout came
From there's no sign of like torch or anything like that and you can't see any distinguishable point where
Where undead are like?
Convening right like they're not trying you can't see where if they're like trying to surround something
There's just so much movement down throughout the city. I
Don't know if you can see something but all I can see are undead and I
Feel terrible saying this but I think we just have to go
How do we help people we can't even see them. This is their city if they know how to get safe
They will get safe
Guess so it doesn't it doesn't sit right with me. I heard them
We got to keep eyes on the prize though
Okay, yeah, we will hope they know how to get to the tower
We will hope we can get to the tower as you make this decision to begin to move towards the tower
You're closing in on
it and
Thea out of the I guess Thea and Yenbul out of the corner of your eye you see
Like this the light swings through
Once towards you are you trying to stay in the light or out of the light as it's passing by like because you're flying
In the air is it proximity to the light? Are you trying to stay?
Lowish to the ground are we noticing that we are being like
Like flock of bats inundated by things in the air if we're not in the light
Yeah, that's what I was gonna say to you
Like it would kind of depend like is the light just lighting is it is it doing anything to the creatures?
like I think we'd stay in the light if we felt like
That it was that would help them
But if they're not I think there's no reason to announce our present. We just stay below it
Yeah, agree farther out into the city. You don't notice as many
But when you get closer to the tower itself, there's almost like a dust cloud
Surrounding the top of this tower like and it and the light is cutting through it
I guess dispersing it as it cuts through and then you see this
This cloud move quickly in through this faint aura of light coming off the top of this tower
So it does look like it's carving a path through
So if you were to try and keep up with it and maintain that position and kind of like follow it sideways
I mean, it's you've got the magic carpet which takes your direction. So you I would say you could do that. No problem
If that's what you wanted to do. Yeah, I think so in that like does the light go
Like is it going all the way around in a circle or in a half circle all the way around in the circle?
Yeah, so how many points of light are there just one?
Yeah to remind you how Luskin set up like the arcane tower is like in the center and then there's a river that
splits the city
So the tower is close closer to the coastline the river splits up the city. So there are two
Sections of city on either side you're coming up from the south side
Yeah
So I think I mean we're going to kind of head just towards the tower
Rather than trying to like do a huge spiral to stay in the light to go around the tower
I think because otherwise if there's a chance that there are some good people in there
It'd be great to just like get there
You make your way and the closer you get you see this cloud of creatures and it's a mix of creatures
it's some that you've seen before like the vrocks and the
Hairy hand McBats. Thank you. Yeah
Yeah, but others that you haven't seen of all different shapes and sizes and levels of disgust that are
repelled by this light
you're able to
Thea and Yen Bol for sure
Are able to see that this cloud as it cuts through and you're able to kind of see through like there's almost a
a
bubble
That the swarm is trying to get through like there's some sort of level of protection around the top of the tower that they can't
penetrate
More than just the light that's carving them like it looks like they hit a point and then they they're trying to hit against this
force
It looks like there's some sort of force field around the top. Maybe like a protection spell. Yes, I see that too
Do we see and we still can't see anything in
You said there is dim light in the tower, but we can't see like there's no signs of movement
I mean, there's so much happening around it, too
It's it's faint and you only really see it as it like carves through and then it gets covered up by all of these
Creatures you do see that the creatures like they're less down near the bottom and then they kind of they're swarming up and like falling down
And then swarming up like their moths like they're drawn to where yeah, they're they're drawn to this location
Have you been here before is there must be entrance?
Down lower not everyone arrives on magic carpet. Should we go lower to try to enter the tower away from
All the creatures I think so if there if there's some sort of protection spell or force field or something above
We may not even be able to get through it
And I don't know if we want to put ourselves into the middle of that's warm
yes, I mean I've got something in my back pocket if we desperately need it, but I
Prefer not to need it. Stop staring at my stuff Russ. What you got in your back pocket that the Donnie
Yeah, I know I was real quiet there in the dark when all that bad stuff was happening cuz it was real fucking scary a
but now like
What you got in your back pocket the I've been in your satchel for weeks what you got in your back pocket the
Oh my god, Donnie. It is a sunburst spell. Oh well. You didn't have to tell me that that's fine
I think she just meant
Like figuratively she had something in her back not not a literal so I thought it was like like a snack bar or something
No, you've literally eaten everything out of my bag. I'm sorry
This is the darkest time
Right no snacks in the darkest time
Yeah, just I see a Pringles shop down there, but only for desperate Donnie only for only for desperate just kidding Pringles
Just kidding Pringles. We love you. Once you pop the phone don't stop. Advertise with us
So what is Yenvel hasn't been here before so what is like what does the tower look like is there like
Entrances part way up the tower do we have to go down to the bottom where there is perhaps swarms of undead
What's the word?
Okay, so the tower of the arcane brotherhood is like this
hand that is
Standing up in the center of town. There are bridges that lead to the
Platform that this tower is is on there are spires that come up that look like trees
And it looks like a tree growing up out of the ground at the top of this tower is where that light is coming
Out of there's this room up top where this light is emitting out of and you see this dim light. There are not
many
easy looking entrances
It looks like some of these
Down on the grounds you see some of these branches for lack of a better term have
Broken off where they broke off from there's growth over top of where they snapped off
Down at the bottom. There is an entrance
but there are no it looks like a lot of the
Entrances windows or otherwise that would have appeared up top have been allowed to grow over
Within this tower that looks like the only
Now that we fully describe it for us. Good job
It looks like the only
Somewhat living thing in this vicinity that you've seen that hasn't been created by Thea
So the only entrance you see
aside from the
Room dim light up at the top is the entrance down at the bottom
Which is over ground?
No, the answers down at the bottom is not all of the like if any branch is broken off or if there's anything
So you see a door down at the bottom
There are like falling flying creatures that kind of drop down to the ground and then shoot back up
So but the swarm is not nearly as much and because it's on a platform
It is not like in a sea in the middle of a sea of undead because it is raised above that
Correct. Yeah, so the platform comes up out of like the mouth of the river
So the river comes together and then there's this platform in the middle
The closer you get you are able to see that the bridges have been broken. So the undead
If there are any over there are a few and far between
They it isn't the sea that you see on at least on the side of the city that you are
And most of what you see is is
fallen flying
demon type creatures
That are have injured themselves and just battering
and they're
Not doing great or there they get up and they start to fly back up
right
Well, it seems sort of boring but perhaps we just go to the front door can't hurt
There you went in doubt knock on the front door. Yes. Let's try this
So yeah, well well fly down towards the front door and see how friendly they are to
Strangers. I mean, I'm a stranger also probably a stranger. I'm not
I'm gonna need a stealth role
We'll make it a collective stealth role. It's a disadvantage
Obviously
Eight
Twelve was your bad five was my bad one. Oh, wait 13. I'm on plus one
You haven't been seen by the swarm up above
But as you get closer to this platform and you're you're zipping as quick as you can towards the door you hear
the the cries of these creatures begin to shift and
A cluster of them begins to rush towards you
How big is the swarm the swarm covers like the entirety of this tree?
But a branch like a piece of it has broken off. So there are
Probably a dozen creatures rushing towards you at least
Question for your ass, please. Are these fiends? Yeah, they could be fiends at least some of them
I'm gonna bust out a skill
How close to us are they like they're intercepting us? Yes, I am going to channel divinity
abjure the extra planar
So as an action I present my holy symbol and each aberration celestial
Elemental fae or fiend within 30 feet of you that can hear me must make a wisdom saving throw on a failed save
The creature is turned for one minute or until it takes damage
That's a nat one. Oh
So it's not good
Perfect, so it turns them. Yes. Yeah, I grab my holy symbol of
tear and I
Like just point up at them and say
Leave us be yeah. We'll say they disperse
But yeah, you you you grab your dick and throw it up at them or whatever
Just grab your dick and throw it up
Fiends out of there
Look I gotta try and make it light
Dick
Joke quotient. That's right. It has not been filled
Very low. Well, we were making some just the tip
The tear symbol is a set of scales resting on a warhammer. So I think we could just change that
It's basically a deck and
Yeah, we'll say that okay. Yes that succeeds enough that they disperse
And even you you even get some that are not part of the group that's coming towards you
But even some of the larger swarm disperses and flies off into the darkness around you
Which allows you enough time to get down to the door?
You move towards the door
Naturally, it's locked. Do I know the special knock?
Because of you know the times I've been here the last time you came here you tried to break in
Yeah, we broke in if I remember correctly good thing. You've got a whole new team now, Thea
They won't even remember call you out on it
Well, I do the special but no they I don't think they gave you a special knock. They weren't most of them weren't super
Excited to have your group there if I recall
Yeah, they weren't thrilled if I remember correctly, like my cough was your only real touch point
But everybody else was kind of like yeah at that point they they didn't care too much
But now that things have gone to pot. Maybe they'll be excited to see perhaps maybe look at us. We're not undead
That's what I yell I knock on the door you knock on the door and yell look at us
We're not undead. Yep, not undead out here as you hit the door like it ripples like the the door it almost
illusory ripples
And then before your hand connects the door and as you yell out
You hear bolts go large mechanical like bolts release
And the door swings open, but nobody's there. It's like one of those creepy
Okay, I'm not gonna look at gift horse in the mouth. Come on. You guys come on. Yes. Let's go all of you enter
Into the tower and you push the door closed behind you but not before a large
Clawed hand reaches through and grabs both the door and the wall and
Begins to try and pull the door back over push and pull the door back open whoever
Was trying to close the door is going to need to make a
contested strength check
Let's do it. I was I was on door duty
I was gonna say I probably went through first and therefore wouldn't be closing the door
I'm weak Yen bull you could assist which would give him
Advantage which would negate his disadvantage. So it'd be a straight roll. Could I also help which would then give him advantage
I mean you can both say that you help but one person only gets to roll with advantage in this case
It would be just a straight roll. Okay, which is still better than disadvantaged. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, totally
This is a saving throw correct just as just a strength check. Okay, perfect. So I don't have disadvantage
Okay, so yeah straight ability. So roll
roll
Tom I think he wants you to roll what you're gonna want to do is I'm not sure
That is a 21 strength roll
He fucked it up you guys
Let's play this glad I have a plus eight right let's play this out
So you you get in there tell gear you go to push on the door and these huge claws
Tear in through the door before it closes and like latch into the wall and latch around the door
Little help. Yes, of course, of course tell years old hat man. Nothing faces him
You guys got this and are you just?
You're doing great. Yeah, you're doing you're doing great here. Let me blow on it. We're doing a great job
I throw my shoulder into trying to close this door
You can do it put your back into it as yamble comes and helps you and you you like pull back giving it
Just enough time to push open with a little ease
You throw both your weights into the door and you hear the arms of this thing
crunch under the door and
You give it another one and the bones snap and when the hands go limp but are like flailing inside of this room
Can I sacred flame those? Yeah sure you can
Cuz gross the new snack that's going across the realms the fried fiend fingers
It's a new delicacy who knew 15 the claws before you begin to bubble and
Icker begins to form underneath these blisters and
The hands are like pulling back as you're pushing on the door
so the skin begins to slough off and into the room and
You hear the shriek from the other side of the door as you finally crunch it closed and a couple of clawed
fingers fall off into the ground and there's just
skin
That's good right up until skin goo
I like it you keep that. Yeah, that's good
Skin-goo need a t-shirt skin goo
The three of you are in a dark chamber
There are no torches or candles or anything lit. It's it sounds empty like
Just the sound of it. You hear like the thudding of the bodies of these creatures outside
But you don't hear anyone inside like there's like this this cold sounding wind
And just the wind not not cold sounding wind like cold sounding like room tone throughout this
Throughout this large entry chamber that you're in
And you said it's quite dark
Yeah, okay. Well, I'm gonna cast light just like I guess on my sword or whatever side note
Yen bull has a sword. I know I was just looking it's like do I have a sword? No, I have a mace
Okay, it's like it was like wow
I had no idea never use my actual like martial weapons because they do so much less damage than like
That old sacred flame cantrip amaze will just
time you illuminate the area immediately and
Like the chamber is empty except for a singular desk. That is about
30 feet
Ahead of you you see two corridors that go off on either side of this this wide chamber
They really could have remodeled since last time it's been such a long time
I want to walk over and look at the desk. Is it like the guest book? What's happening here?
Look at the desk. There's there's nothing on top of it drawers. Are there drawers? There are drawers. I look in the drawers
there is a singular quill I
Take it out. I
Take a piece of parchment from my satchel and I write
We're here to help and we need help and I sign it
Thea
Cuz I'm guess I'm not with the decimator of dragons anymore. Ah
And then I leave it on the desk does something magical happen
Does it puff and smoke and somebody gets to read it somewhere safe, I don't know this is what I'm imagining
yeah, I like always you write your note and
Wait a moment and then as you're looking around and just waiting for something to happen
the writing begins to fade into your paper and
then you hear a
A
Like the loud crack of a door down the chamber off to the right
It's the middle
It's just a quick little last time we got a whole rendition
The quick ones always catch me off-guard. Yeah, I was going for like a like an NBC feel of it
Yeah, like yeah just a little quick little staccato
But you didn't do a little he did a slight little head nod bow
Sort of to indicate and I am done
But we all still just paused and waited just in case he was incorporating dance into the whole thing
It wasn't totally that would be something wasn't totally clear
So yeah, it would come across in this audio medium because you just be able to hear all the bumping and crashing happening
Swishing by
You can't flip your hair back and forth, you don't have almost
No, he did a pretty good bang flip there is pretty good
There's a lot of hair here more than you live with a boy band over here. Yeah, I got a bunch right now, too
It's a little bit ridiculous
Ridiculous. Hey same here. I
I don't
Right, yeah, yeah, you came to the middle of this podcast to hear about everyone's hair
Right the middle of quarantine somewhere probably if you're listening to this in the future and you don't know what quarantine is
Well, unless you're in New ZeAlydind or Australia, that's right and well done. Good job way to go
We're all jealous. Good on you lots of Australian listeners lately. So you you did good. Good job
Rocks all in you are model world citizens. We all need to be more like you
while you're all you know, either free to do what you will or
Confined to your house. You should come join us in our Facebook group the reckless play guild. It's an amazing space
It is it's so great. We share it with many different lovely
Podcasters have similar genres. Yes, like the end of time and other bothers dark dice and the lucky die
You should go check out the lucky die
They're an amazing podcast put lots into their editing and their story and their characters just really pop
I think I think you're gonna love it
We'll link it down in the description and you can find them at the reckless play guild if you go on over there
You know what do that come join us in the reckless play guild. That's better
You know, I'm not gonna put the link down of the
But I do yeah, probably do it also join us in the reckless play guild cuz it's nice and everyone's great and
Wonderful. Yeah, we'd love to see you there big group. Talk D&D talk podcast. It's great time. That's all that's all now
That's not I've not he not it again
To signify and done and we're done. Let's get you back to the episode pretty sure it's a dark timeline
Maybe it's not we're recording all these interludes ahead of time
Okay, bye the magic. Okay. Bye I
Think message received
Is it just the one crack grass how many cracks do you need?
Well, sometimes there's a crack and then footsteps that come after the crack, right?
I'm gonna follow the sound of that crack. Yeah me too
You move towards it's all about butts now
You move towards the corridor lit by yin bulls
Sword it winds off into the left like it's following the perimeter of this this tower
you begin walking down and
You're walking for at least an amount of time that you would presume that you come out on
The other side like that's what it feels like
But it it doesn't it keeps going like you're walking in circles and you do so for a few minutes
Before you hear like just the faintest Creek
Up and around what feels like the corner and you get to a point where it clears and there's a
large wall that goes up quite high and there is a
Door open just a singular wooden door. It's cracked open
And there is a dim light coming from inside of it
Gee so they don't make this easy do they it's no problem and I fly up there
Remember I can fly I forgot
Hey, why would I waste my energy flying when I can ride the carpet
But you know it's just to wow us every once in a while we could all ride the carpet up there
Or I can just go check. Oh, I mean you might as well just go check check
I'm good either way Johnny. You want to go check that out, too? Yeah. Oh, yeah
I want to go check it out me and yin bull we haven't had a lot of time together you stuff of me in
The bag and all hey stretch your wings buddy and also keeping you safe. Be grateful
Yep, yep. Yep. All right, then. Yeah, I almost called you Lenny Len bull. That's not your name yen bull
It's it's it's very close. I'm a yeah dragon in the darkest timeline. It's really bad for me
I think I've got like seven hit points
Hopefully, I don't get hit by anything wonder why you've been in the bag Donnie, right?
Yen bull and Donnie fly up
What's the power or spell or something that gives yin bull the power to fly again?
It's just a class feature. So like like divine you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed
Oh son of a bitch. I
Can't fly dudes. Why can't be inside and do it. Oh
Okay, Johnny go on up there check it out for us. Oh yin bull. You just have to flap your wings
You just have to like this you just have to believe what's what's the problem?
You can't you can't fly you can't fly inside no, okay, I'll go check
Donnie zips up and checks. Uh, yeah, it's like a little box
up here
Yeah box like there's a there's a little bit of a light in here looks like a candle
There's some buttons on the wall
There's not much in here
Nope, nope. Nope persons. It's just like a little like I mean the three of us could fit in here
Yeah, it's probably like ten feet
Give or take you squeeze in this look like where the light is coming from what the light in the room. Yeah
No, oh like the outside light or this light in this room like the outside light. Oh, no. No, I can't see outside
Okay, and there's nothing else in the room
Which is the buttons on the wall?
Well, let's let's go check. Okay, we can get on the carpet and scoot up there
The carpet can do with the dirty work for us the carpet does work indoors double-checked
Just that's cool. Don't want to sound like a big idiot again
We all stand on it and you're like giddy up and it just lays there like I'm just a regular rug
I've been flying for three days straight
You fly up and open the door and you look in and it is a
paneled room
Like Donnie described about ten feet by ten feet on one wall, there are
several buttons
How many buttons?
Who knows? None of us can count
Yeah, right
There are many buttons they're labeled too, but we realized we can't read
There's no no labels
they're just in a a
straight line down the wall
Let's say there are
Ten of them. Oh
Okay, so ten floors ten levels were in an elevator. Yeah, but elevators don't exist in this world. Of course they don't neither do trains
Well in magic lighthouses they might maybe
Arcane Brotherhood
super
R&D has developed elevators. I want to touch the button at the very top
Hold on to your panties the door slam shut behind you
And you feel movement you feel like you're moving upwards
Slow at first and then the velocity picks up quickly until it it doesn't slow. It just suddenly stops
You get that stomach lurch feeling and then there's this little ding
A little bell ding and then the door just cracks open again
Hello
You hear the sound of the creatures outside louder now
And if we look out that crack it is just darkness or can we see anything out there?
There is a dim yellow light that comes through
You peek around the corner and you look out and it looks like you are now in that top room of the tower
You swing the door open and you look out and
You see this giant revolving light in the center of this room
you see the creatures beating themselves against this unknown force and
off
And to the right of this room. There is a single desk
There is a letter like an envelope a sealed envelope on top, but what catches your eye is a
Figure slumped over beside the desk
I rushed to this person
Once you get to them, it becomes clear that this person is deceased
Well, I had a feeling do I recognize this person from no, I mean you only met a couple
I know you met like the maitre d. I think you called them
McAuth
Sounds condescending
Sounds condescending enough to be believable, but nobody that you had direct relations with
During your time here. I didn't have relations with anybody while I was here. Damn it. I think i'm still virgin you guys
Well dark's timeline isn't gonna help that
Okay, they are in a male elven figure
Look like they are
Aged beyond
Anything that you have seen
Their hair is completely white like their skin is like
Almost to the point of mummification
It's a real crip keeper situation here they're
Huddled over themselves like grasping at their knees. You don't touch them, but it looks like they're like clutching their knees
Um and like rigor has long set in like there's no movement or anything in this body
I'm gonna go grab that letter
you grab it and the
Insignia is of the arcane brotherhood, which is like a
triangular tower with
Um almost like antlers that kind of come down and that's pressed into the back you crack it open. Yeah, let's do it
you break the seal and
Now you have to pee for the rest of the night
Ah
Like dust falls from the letter as you pick it up and even as you crack this open it's been here a long time
And you open it and it's written in
elven
Do you speak elven? No
I do
I do too
You know being an elf or whatever tall gear looks for long enough that you think that he can read it
I
What does it say
What what does it say is it?
Kind of kind of waited too long to tell you that I couldn't read it now. I'm embarrassed
Oh, oh
That's that's fine. That's okay. Not everybody can read who who speaks. No, I can read
I just can't read whatever language this is who speaks a bunch of languages. Oh
Why I think we both do a few. All right, well and he hands it over to yen bull
To whom may find this letter?
The arcane brotherhood is not lost this beacon of hope is meant to guide you to our location
Finds the arcane brotherhood in ice wind dale
There's refuge there
A place where the undead have slowed and cannot keep up their unrelenting force
Macoth the crimson. Oh shit
I
Assumed this dead elf was a person who wrote this
Well, I I think we did the right thing by coming here to read the letter
but now
We have to leave here again
Should we?
Explore the tower more perhaps rest
Resting is probably a good idea. I I'd bet dollars to doughnuts
That the tower is empty for anything that we could
You know salvage out of it. I I would imagine as they left they took anything of value
And left enough power to send this light off for a while before it'll finally fail probably at some point
Yes, I bet this fellow was
The last one in the tower, uh, well, I I think I think resting here is a really great idea
I also think maybe looking
Throughout the tower to see if there's anything helpful
Might also be a good idea. Can we do both? Yes. It seems like the creatures can't get in here. So
Let's do both
I don't feel comfortable sleeping in here though as I look around and essentially i'm seeing like
Yeah
Yeah, sure. Yeah. Yeah just like and a desk and a dead guy. Exactly. Um more of a
Uh, maybe like i'll sleep in the elevator
Anybody else want to cuddle puddle in the elevator? Well, i'm I mean i'm sure that they have beds here
Wizards need to sleep just like anyone else. So they say let's go down a bit lower
See what we can find pile back into the elevator push the second
From the top down button
Button nine, okay
It goes down slowly
Does not speed up
And then stops and opens onto into what probably were once luxurious offices
Covered in dust a lot of things have been torn and like
thrown to the ground
Shelves that line the walls
With books largely empty. There are a couple around nothing of any real consequence or value
Uh, but no
There's no chambers here, but this does look like office space
You check each of the floors finding nothing until
You find a room that has a few small cots
oh
see it clamors into one and it's just like
okay, i'm just just for a couple and just
And she's out i've never seen a bed look better than this
And I climb onto a cot
snuggle into my bedroll and just
I'm out being a dwarf tulgar thinks this cot. It's like pretty dope. Actually. It's quite big for him
Yeah, the cots are not comfortable but they feel like you are sleeping on a king-size plush mattress
Based on what you have been not sleeping on for the last several days and in my sleep. I grope around
to find donnie
And i drag them
Okay, good night good night
Dumbgeons and Dragons season two episode 76 are they happy to see us?
Starring Amy More as the amistacia carla maxed out as Yenbul nuri
Tom laird as talgir heavyfoot and Russ More as your dungeon master
Editing production and sound design by Russ More this episode featured music from epidemic sound and sound effects from epidemic sound
And boom library.com season two cover art is by chrissey torr illustrations a huge. Thank you to our supporting producers
Gabriel lynch jessica Babyok mark heartless stevie cat water flame jacob matt
christian brown devin michaels aaron stevens and ray serbeck to support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many other productions
And get access to an exclusive podcast bonus episodes and much more
Please join our Patreon at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
You can also follow us at facebook.com slash dumb dragon podcast and on twitter at dumb dragon cast
Thank you for listening. Have a great week. We'll talk again soon. Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production