previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Arvid yeah, this reminds me of that one time that you and I
You know back in
Bartholomew. Oh, you've been to Bartholomew. We have a package for that too. Gnolls begin to pour out of the tunnel now
Lead the way the mysteries of the universe will have to wait from now
We need to go come bring it with you. Just just bring it with you. Japes and
Perseus are not part of this group though. They got torn away from the from the
Mass of you. If we're going to get them, we've got to go fast
Remind me next time we see him to put a boot up Uzumaki's ass. Who's Uzumaki? Oh, don't worry, dear. Well
Well, Margaret did we should do we help help?
help
the
Kobold I could
Go on. I could. You could what? As this
Explosion happens behind them shooting this main
Mass of all of these gnolls off into the side giving you just the briefest moment to bolt through them
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. I'm your dungeon master Russ More. He him also with me today is
Carla maxed it she her I will be playing Lex they them and Amy more
Yeah, she her and I will be playing
Flanks he him and Tom Laird. Yeah, that's me. He him. I will be playing
Perseus who's a he him also joining us today the lovely and talented rev to shame
Hey, he him and I'm playing Margaret broad cloak. She her class. It's here. Yo, yo
He him and I will be playing flanks. No, I'm not playing flanks. No, I'm flanks. Who are you playing?
I don't even know anymore like james james prot spin. I just to give him a last name this time around
Okay. Yeah. Well, I got to write down all of this information. Did you write down flanks last name?
What was flanks last name lake?
And I may be I'm pretty sure I'm also gonna be playing Vorunax this episode shut your face he's dead
Yeah, he is. Never mind that james is the new bad guy. We just haven't gotten there yet story art
We've got a couple more time jumps to go through for that one. That's right younger james. Well, we'll see what happens with james prot spin
You can listen to the downtime that we did for the last episode which a spoiler alert
Because we didn't accomplish anything
Of great importance
There wasn't a lot to talk about but we still had fun diving into what happened between
Last episode and where we're gonna pick up in this episode. There's
So go check it out Patreon.com slash dump dragon cast where when you're a patron you will also have an episode dedicated
To you like today's patron
Lawrence Welsh jr
Just gonna say our fanciest listener maybe are you royalty when you're a Patreon member of Dumbgeons and Dragons you're absolutely royalty
See this is why we keep inviting Kyle back
Say you're like the very talented and also other great things rev and Kyle's here
I
Noticed it was very distinct. It was Kyle. You're here. No, I understand look and
Look, I read hopefully make you feel good every day
I read the script as commas the lovely and talented rev to Shane and Kyle class. It's here
No
Me just showed up
Com slash dumb dragon cast. Please join us over there Kyle's there, too
See if you can find me
Fuck it. Let's play
We join the group being led by Japs and flanks as Japs has gone into a
a tour guide mode
I was gonna say about of dementia as they have evaded the pack of gnolls that was
Chasing them deeper into the underdark. You see and that's stalactite over there
You can tell by the guano on it that
Bats like to stay there when they sleep and
So how is that different than the other all those other stalactites that also?
Had the bat guano is that yes. This tour is very guano based. I'm noticing
Yeah, well, you got to know where get ready to get the good guano
So that you know if you need to hide down here, you can look like a piece of shit and not get noticed
Should I be writing this down mood? It's in your hand, but you'll see
I see some branding some like hand cream
Yeah, it's good. It's good gives you nice supple skin look
I don't have many wrinkles and why do you think I don't do you sell that t-shirt back at the store?
No, but if you make it before me, I'll kill you takes this branding very seriously. That's right
I should it be like one that says like I don't look like shit. It's just the guano. Yeah, that's good
Okay, you're gonna go far in this business. I'm telling you flanks. Thanks, sir, or perhaps. It's a product placement guano
Blend in by looking like shit. Yeah guano. You didn't the further you go into the underdark
Don't advertise that
Right in check that we cannot catch the jokes might get a little deeper but not much better
Quick Russ interrupt us
The further you go into the underdark the it's gonna sound silly but it's gonna get dark darker it gets
That makes you've entered an area where the the bioluminescent materials
seem to have been
eroded or
Like removed due to heavy traffic
You look up ahead and this cavern that you're in
Funnels to a point and leads down a long hallway
Even those who are so inclined to see better than others in the dark have trouble seeing down to the end of this
hallway, all right
Right this way hold on flanks goes through his pack and pulls out a torch
Ah
Yeah, it's good another that bio light and it's gone, you know, I
Kind of just get a feel for it. My feet feel it out
I gotta take the shoes off a little while ago and oh your barefoot. Oh, yeah
You get a real feel for the underdark with these toes
Flanks lights the torch. I said take your shoes off kid. I'm sorry good
Don't forget you're getting paid to be here
You follow the code but he's a cobalt so I think you just like had like bread bags
I don't understand the shoe mechanics
Special order
Yeah, the benefits didn't quite cover the whole thing
Yeah
I never do japs and flanks with torch and no shoes in hand
Lead the way down this tunnel leaving the four of you back just a just a hair
In order to have any conversation you might want to have well, we're still alive. So
That's
Something yes, and
At least it feels like we are going
Deeper so we're going the right direction. We got away from those gnolls
So I mean maybe all the other tour guides would have been
even stranger and had a bushier eyebrows and never wore shoes you follow behind japs and flanks and
This tunnel narrows so much so that you're going single file
You hear
the scurrying of
What could be rodents down at your feet
like bugs
spiders
moving along the ceiling and there's this it's
Deathly silent except for all of these over accentuated
Noises coming from whatever wildlife is is existing in this space
You hear japes mumbling up ahead
Yes
No, and that one's furry and the echo that's reverberating down this this tunnel
dampens as he enters into this wide open chamber that is
Completely dark as flanks follows in behind him the light from his torch disappears before you
Four of you
stop
to evaluate before proceeding forward I
Take my mace out and see if the light from it
penetrates his darkness
It begins to illuminate and then it shone shone's on the walls and you can see
Like bugs scurrying back into holes and everything disappearing
but then it's like there's this wall of blackness before you and it if it was reflective you feel like it would
Reflect the same as the walls around you back to you
But it's like it eats the light. Do you hear them? Mike? I can't see them anymore. I don't I don't particularly love
this
should we
form a
Chain, I don't
Does that sound silly but if we join hands we would
Be together
We would yes, we would be at least not separated much like planks and japs
God rest their souls wherever they are beyond this dark void. Oh
Blanks japs are they are it are they I don't I don't hear them. Oh
Oh
And I will put the mace away and and take out the daggers
That I that I got when we were shopping we talked about this right before we started recording trying to figure out what it was
They glow as they get closer together in case we lost each other in the dark
So we would could use them like way finders to find out. Yes. Okay. That's what it was. Yep. Thank you
It was yes, we're together
Amazing yeah all four useful. I mean Arvid pulls his out. Yeah. Yeah Lex as well. Yeah
Yeah, Margaret will hold both her hands out
Let's give it a shot
the four of you proceed forward Margaret in the lead everybody else following behind daggers glowing and as you
Step to and then through this darkness
Everything kind of just shunts around you sound is gone
Any
Visuals that you have are gone. You can still feel the hand of the person behind you
Who is?
Sweaty I feel like Lex is probably at the back. Okay, Lex is at the back
So we'll say I'll take maybe Perseus then Arvid. Okay. Okay, who is Perseus?
Who could be sweaty Lex wouldn't have been sweaty so that that would have been a clarification
Just a more of sort of generally clammy at all times, yeah
And everybody else as you step forward and through you see like there's it's like it's almost like walking through
Putting your hand through murky water like it you lose all visual of it
Margaret make and
It's
Spooky in here, it's real scary make us check. I mean
But make a perception check at
Disadvantage I have advantage normally. Okay. Yeah
For all your good rolling needs yeah, so 27
As you step into this you
in your years of
Monster hunting take a moment and just kind of hold
Perseus back as you try and get any sense of what you're feeling and seeing and
Although you can't see anything you you feel
Minor
Vibrations coming from the air around you like it's these clicking noises that are
Distant at this point
Where you are?
If you proceed forward
The clicking even as you take a couple steps like the clicking becomes erratic and
As you stop moving it slows
Does this sound
Like anything that I have encountered before as you take a few steps just trying to to gauge without
Going too far as to potentially run into something you get a feeling that it is it sounds like
some sort of undead creature or creatures and a lot of them
Who are
more
stationary
just kind of like
Muscle twitches and bone cracks
Oh boy
Like we can't go back
One because I guess we don't exactly even know where back is I mean
We'll say that I mean yes, it would be skewed
So you might not be able to make it back or anyway, but you walked in a straight line, right? So
Perception in the dark perception in the dark would be skewed
So yeah, you're right would have to turn a complete 180 and be pointing the exact same way
we can kind of feel that we're in a big space, but visually and
Even kind of what we hear it's yeah, you can't see this you you and you specifically are hearing this
Just I'm giving you that because of your super monster hunting
And
Experience that your character has like knowing that it seems like we're supposed to go through here to try and get
To wherever we're going next
I don't think I can do anything except
Try to use that clicking sound as a like, okay, I'm gonna go a little this way now and try to navigate between
The clicking it's like a reverse
Echolocation yeah, yeah, I like it
Russ I'm assuming that this total darkness that we are in counts as total cover
because if not I have divine sense and
I can detect undead within 60 feet. Oh, you're you're but
You're detecting all over the place your Geiger counters
That's what's making the clicking
That's what it is, but yeah, so okay, so yeah Margaret you sense
All around you which you can equate to
Closest equation is is some sort of undead
More surrounding you the further you go in Lex as you step into this darkness like yeah your your sense of
Undead is
Just through the roof, right?
Do you want to do anything or attempt to do anything with that you as we described it in terms of walking order?
You are holding Arvid's hand. I don't know cuz I think right now
Like being as silent as possible is the best
Option rather than yelling guys is undead
Scatter they can't get us all
Okay
You all proceed forward with Margaret leading Margaret roll me a
joint
I'll let you pick here either
insight
Going off of
where you're sensing all of
Where like the sounds are coming from and trying to locate those as you're getting closer or farther from them or
Perception yeah
perception if it's
listening very closely to get a gauge of how close those clicks are and then finding
The direction where it's a little quieter because basically trying to
Walk around
Okay, this is like that Mario Party one where you try not to step on all the banana peels
But the banana peels are undead
Exactly. That's the one that
Margaret begins to move forward and is listening to these sounds and like we can
you know from the cameras point of view like we're we're we're spinning around and swirling around all four of you and
Margaret you're sensing as you get closer and using your
Hand on Perseus to kind of signal as you're turning Perseus roll an insight
That is a 17 you definitely sense that Margaret senses something based on the the pulses in hers in her squeeze
And is guiding you through and you're able to to pass down the line as well
You're weaving in and out of these noises that are getting louder and quieter like it's almost to the point where you feel like
Like something brush up against just the edge of like a sleeve that you have
Until you get
You've been walking for what I presume is very slowly
for several minutes and
And then you hear this this pulse
In this darkness around you you hear like a
Crackling and almost like this sucking noise as it pulls in towards you
From the outside looking in it pulls in towards you until the room is clear
And you are in the middle of this
Almost military line of this room of complete of undead of
mangled monsters of pieced together beings
Who are all standing at all
What could be described as at attention?
facing one direction towards
The this this raised dais this raised platform at the end of this cavern
You're in the middle of this
There's this clicking of all of these joints is like the the muscles are spasming in and hands are shooting out in different directions
But they're not moving
Is there anyone on that raised platform not immediately roll a wisdom saving throw?
17 20 dirty 13 Arvid rolled to an 11
Margaret and Arvid are going to take which isn't on your character sheets
12 sanity damage
Russ looking around at these things now that we're able to kind of see them better like do they resemble
What Lex is like yes, there are definitely element like yeah
They are pieced together beings of many other beings most of them
majority of them humanoid in fact everybody make a
Perception check
Margaret and Arvid at disadvantage for 10
Everybody sees that they are
Very similar in that they are pieced together from many different beings and humanoids and and perhaps even other
creatures, but Lex you specifically notice that the the facial construction of them is all
Very similar not not to yourself. Just be clear about that
but all very similar to one another and
Even looking at them like the build is
Almost to a design point very similar to one another
The the the parts maybe have to been taken from many different
creatures or beings but the size of them is all
Like almost cookie cutter do they seem to be?
Creatures of the underdark piece together or like not necessarily the gangs all here. Okay, the gangs all here
Yeah, yeah, there's a lot of more humanoid and even human
Probably majority is human or humanoid and how many are there you are in a cavern that is
Let's place it at
200 to 250 feet across on all sides and they are all in lines
Standing at attention and are they nude? No
Great question
No, they all appear to be in
Damaged or not great condition, but they all appear to be an armor and have weapons
swords axes maces
Degrees it looks like we've we've found someone's
Army. Yes, isn't that what we were afraid?
Was being built and we've also lost our guides
looking back
At like the door that we came in. Yeah, does it exist? Is there like a film over it?
No, it does exist. Like there's a
I
Think there's no real light coming from it, but there is you can see where you came in
You would place yourself probably pretty close to the middle of the room
Maybe a little bit back from middle so closer to the tunnel, but still
150 to 175 feet out and the only other way out of this room is that is the dais?
Yeah, there's a raised platform
Which you can't quite see all the way back but yeah, that's the only egress that you can tell are
the tunnel you came in or
What's up there?
Well, I suppose the only way is
forward
Right Arvid Marcius Margaret. I don't
We know what's back there. It's many many
gnolls who
Truly dislike us. Yeah, they were not fans
No
so
it seems we have a
Moment here and I'd like to get away from this army
Before they decide to wake up
Yes
Yeah
I'm with you Lex like always is there stairs up to the platform or am I going to awkwardly try and jump?
Like I did in the stage in high school when I was like getting up on the thing and then you like kind of can
Get up, but you forget you're short and then you're just kind of like roll on to it
Anybody else yo every day. That's right. I imagined it like a
Mahin dais
Yeah, I don't know
Steps up there
And then like
Yeah, yeah, I like that one that's a door that's what I had written down every time we say door in D&D
I am like it is a drywall door. That thing is
Golden knob you have to turn it to lock it. There's this one door jam just in the middle
So my brain does okay?
before of you looking around
evaluating your circumstance
Begin to go forward towards the the dais and
As you begin to move forwards, and you get another 50 feet
there's this crackle of energy above you and
You look up and you see two swirling portals and out of them drop tied to chains are
japes and flanks
Are we gagged I'm gagged nice
Japes is gagged by him by himself
One of his socks is off. It's in his mouth
The whole like I can fit my fist into my mouth and like no you can not
I can here's where we're at for you to you walked into the darkness, and you were like vacuum sucked
Pneumatic tubes yeah
tubes okay, so you two are dangling from these portals
Midway above
By chains, there's this swirling purple black energy above you as
That happens like it reverberates through the room and the clicks from all of the undead around you begin to increase in
frequency and they are almost
Pulsing with the energy and the sound that's flowing through the building
To the building fuck like this is a warehouse
Cavern and
As you stop and look at that you hear just like this slow clap
Begin from the far side where you were walking forward to guys
It's almost never happens, and if this could baby not reflect on your review of the company that would be great
Please please be shush
I
Know what he said slow clapping begins, and it gets louder and louder has you are
Stopped I presume unless unless you don't want to stop you tell me what you want to do well. I mean if that's a
Clicking and popping of all the weird
Frankenstein monsters are getting worse like I would think we'd be moving quicker if anything
Are they gonna start pop and lock in yeah?
So long as they try wouldn't it be cool. Just turns in your just electric slide
You're actually part of a flash
There but you're there now it's worse than an undead
Yeah, no I agree I think yeah just
the sounds increasing would like increase the speed of
Even though we're walking towards some asshole that's slow clapping
Guys we're gonna need to we got to get out of here. We got to move quicker
But I know I know there's but let's just go for it. We need to move
I don't want to be stuck right in the middle here if they
reanimate
Four of you begin to run as quickly and as as nimbly as you can trying not to bump any of the undead
that are just
Sporadically like shooting out an arm in front of you and you're ducking below them
And you get up near the front and as this clapping gets louder like you're losing
perspective as this person is walking forward or this individual is walking forward as
This person as this individual steps into view this long
white blonde hair is like it's being blown by fans and
They have this dark
Purple ebony skin as they are clapping and
Smiling down towards you when they say
lax
My goodness, it's been so long
and
My vision that I saw like I recognized this person
Okay, the instant you see them
They are the one who came in being carried by undead floating into the room to murder Nick real
That's how we're starting that's a great start
That's it just as exasperated we're here welcome to the middle everybody
We'll break from the action for you
It was a whole it was a whole wild session that we just recorded which wasn't the session that you're listening to you
But this one is also a wild session
But look forward to that because whoo boy epic coming your way
What also is epic is we are doing a live show for our patrons when you join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
We hit 90 patrons so for that goal. We're gonna do a live streamed improv show
Where we take suggestions and build the build the session and and world that we're in and play the characters through
Whatever you want us to hear so if you want to be at that
That's not a thing
You want to hear if you want to be at that no no
Whatever you want us to hear is what I said no whatever you want to hear or whatever you want us to say
You know because you give us a suggestion
During the improv so yeah that makes more sense
But join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast on or before March 30th
To get your invite to that live show
So if you are a patron you can check your email that you subscribe to Patreon in
You should have a calendar invite. That's that's waiting there for you to click. Yes
Attending yeah to click that yes smash the button. There's no no or maybe click the yes, maybe is wishy-washy
Definitely not a maybe yeah like
But I mean like say yes, yeah, it's gonna be great the last ones we did were great
I mean, I think I can safely say we have literally no idea. What's going to happen
Yeah, but that's I mean most the times when we play that's like every record session to the hundred percent
But this time people will be witnessing it live. They might think it's like we put it on
They'll see us process everything in real time and be like oh, no. This is what it's like
Editing does rust do a lot folks a lot there there really was only three bullet points for those episodes
It's wild and one was sexy goblins always is you never know when that sexy goblins gonna pop back out, baby
So join us today at Patreon.com
Slash dumb dragon cast live shows baby get back to the show
Legs it's it's Prim's bottom. Oh, I know
I've been hoping to meet you. We've met before but it's so good to see you again
The memory the memory yes, I've been hoping to meet you when I knew yeah, that was
What you are ah
Thelonious Prim's Bane pleasure to meet you
I'm here to bring death and destruction for the sole purpose of just I'm bored down here in the underdark
Really, I kind of piggybacked off of some other things happening, but you don't know about those
So murder of Nick a real murder probably of all these creatures, that's not enough no
Yeah, Nick a real Nick a real Nick a real was a victim of circumstance see Vic
brought Nick a real in on the ground floor of this whole
Organization that I have as you look around here. You see an image
One of my dear dear friends
Leon in glory jam
Brought them into the organization also at the ground floor because they had just the physique that I was looking for
Nick a real had the power Nick a real had the the abilities
You know combined with my just garish good looks and excellent charm and ability to get
And sorry pure disgusting evil
Well, it's all in the eye of the beholder we have one of those two hiding somewhere around here, but uh, that's neither here nor there
It's so good of you to come home and bring me
new subjects
No, what we've brought is
Death and the end of you
Is sort of more
What we were thinking and all of you just given the circumstance
And he looks to the rest of the group here and even up to flanks and japes all of you feel the same
That this is a winning scenario
for you
Well, you do have an undead army, but if we can kill you I suppose that's enough to keep them immobile
Mm-hmm
Right I should mention the two from the ceiling really
They seem to be the master employees I don't want to
This isn't they triggered the initial trap that I was hoping was for you because we saw you coming and then
But they were I don't I don't agree with the health and safety conditions employees are put in by
Take you away or come away with me or your safety is our number one priority
That's right. Oh, you got your fist out. Yeah. Yeah, it
Kind of my jaw dropped when I saw how what an amazing army
You've got down here and for you fine for we've we've delivered you to where you need to be. Yes. Yes, you should
return
To your storefront. Yes head home
unharmed and
Undamaged Oh right primsbane. They will just they will just they will just leave this place
unharmed and undamaged
Sure, he snaps his fingers and the chains suck up into the portals
clothes and
They're gone as I get sucked up a bag drops
From my like how big is this bag?
um
Yay
Yay, surprise. Okay, I was guys surprise. I like bag a holding situation
More of a satchel. Yeah, okay. Got it. Okay, it it just falls. Nothing. Nothing happens to it
I don't know what you put into this bag. So I know but
Player knowledge character. No, I know that's Ross. That's that's fine
It's awfully shiny though
Very gemmy the bag is shiny bag the dazzled bag. I love it. Yeah
Flanks releases a bedazzled bag. You hear the scream it falls to the ground
And you hear it like bounce off of one of these undead who begins to snarl
Primsbane snaps his fingers again and it stops and the clicking comes back. I
Don't know what that was but
They're gone they've they've left
Totally unharmed as previously arranged
So what's the next move?
As he asked that question, I want to cast misty step to the location of the bag and go grab it
Okay, what is misty? Yeah remind to me remind to me remind to me
I am briefly surrounded by silvery mist and I teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that I could see
He he's he asked that new
Mist kind of envelopes you and you appear
Right at the bag
What's in the bag?
You want to know what's in the bag? What's in the bag reaches down picks it up and opens it our receipt
And
A comment card for us to fill out bag 39.99
Okay, so well, I mean this has got to be care every player knowledge because there's no way for character to know this
This is the bag of devouring it is capable of killing an unsuspecting party
It takes the shape of a bag of holding
Hiding its malicious nature like a wolf in sheep's clothing. But once the player reaches into the bag
There's a 50% chance that they're pulled inside
Any creature who starts their turn inside the bag is instantly and entirely devoured
Other players may attempt to pull people inside of the bag out
But first they must avoid being pulled in themselves and second. They must beat a DC 20 strength check yummy
Just open you didn't say you reached any just said he opened it and looked inside
So don't let this knowledge sway what you do with the bag
I was hoping Thelonious would have
Case era, okay, we all say sometimes
No, it's it's the bag of devouring. I know what the bag excuse you. I'm not gonna look at all your other stuff
That's right. I've been texting with Kyle
That's right secret stuff
Obviously we can do now that we're dead in a
Somewhere no return
Your last words as you were pulled through the portal was it's all blades in here
Perseus you grab it. It has like the this intricate was it's it's bedazzled
It's completely bedazzled it has like this almost face bedazzled into it
You open it up and you look inside and it looks like this black void
Make a an arcana check. I've got a great arcana bonus y'all. That is a 27
Okay, you know
Or get a strong sense that this is a bag with an extra dimensional plane
built within it or
Crafted within it being as it previously hit one of the undead things that was it was next to
Can I like?
Put it over said undead things head see what happens. Yes, you're still surrounded in miss
Stepping around making shit in an instant. This is happening. So misty step
You pick it up you look at it and Thelonious is kind of just observing what's happening as you you
evaluate that this this could possibly be a bag of holding and you put it on top of
The head of one immediately beside you
Roll me a d20
High it doesn't take it away low
It does take it away ten these teeth begin to form around the edge of it and it begins to chomp down on
this this zombie creature and swallow it whole as like this clicking and and
groaning and
Trashing begins to happen around this
Until it's completely gone, which is no more than a couple seconds
And the bag lies on the ground beside you does it comically burp afterwards?
Yes
I'm so satisfied right now
Well, that was fun
Is that how you're gonna get them all?
Gotta catch them all in your back. I
Mean I could just go like this
He snaps and a zombie right beside Margaret begins to turn and
Throws out its arms and then he snaps again and it stops holding its place. I could do that
This is a fun game
You decide what you want to do and then I activate all the dead know the dead done dead. It's just great
I think that
Or you could let me take your friends back to my place
Turn them into
helpers and
You come take your place here, which is where you were supposed to be. I mean he was giving you sentience
He was giving you memory you were supposed to be mine
I
Think I'm gonna try and shoot an arrow at him actually across Bobo cuz that's what I have is across bow go for it
It's not gonna work guys, but he's really pissing me off
Let those emotions run free
16 will hit well, that's a terrible rule. That was a four
You can do a thing where I can give him there. It is
divine smite
He is going to
Get an extra 2d8 radiant damage plus 1d8
That let's just say like 4d8. Sure. Love it 12d8. Let's do
Like per level
So 12 plus 5 is 17 plus 5 is
Radiant damage
In like a flash like over the heads of everybody else this this crossbow just quickly
zips towards Thelonious and impales in his
I won't give you a kill shot. Where do you want to hit him? I wish I could remember what he did to
Make a reel, but let's just be honest. I'm gonna all I want to do is hit him
So I'm aiming for like the mass of his body. So sure
You hit him like in the in the chest and the ribs they often to the left and he he crumples
And like snaps it off
Why
Why I mean I
What why why why why why I
Brought you into this world. I could take you out. I'm gonna try and hit him with another one
Oh, no, that's a nothing 17 he's prepared on this one. Yeah, and a shield goes up around him
In this huge dome and it glances off and shoots off into the into the distance and he turns and you see him
Throw his arms up into the air
like looking back down the catwalk away from
And you see another figure walk out a
Larger imposing dragonborn come out carrying this this long staff
It's kind of swinging it around like a baseball bat
It's probably not good. Did you name it Lucille walks through and into
He walks through and into this dome. You don't hear anything that's happening
But you see them conversing inside
What do you what do you three do
What do you three do
For do it's Thelonious is clearly throwing a temper tantrum to whoever this other figure is
I think still approaching like at least for Lex right now. That's
They're just having kind of a one-track mind like
This is the MF er that killed my daddy. So I don't like you
So just advancing as I can because obviously my best weapon is not my crossbow I want to get
up up close
Perseus is trying to cut a swath through these guys with the bag of devouring
Okay
and Margaret
yeah, I
Put away the dagger and get out the mace in the shield and just shoulder to shoulder
Well, not really shoulder shoulder shoulder to thigh
Okay, and I get Arvid Arvid's following him behind
Just making sure that nothing begins to move behind you as you're moving forward and as you get closer
you you you see you begin to climb up this dais and you see Thelonious turn around and his eyes have gone from a
Like a milky white to a deep black
And everybody make a dexterity saving throw as like this heat energy begins to form
14 as
you're climbing up this dais you feel like this is this heat energy forming beneath you and
And
Thelonious turns and his eyes are completely black and then there's like this
this flame
Radiance coming from him as he screams
But you don't hear anything because of the shield that he's put up around him and this other this other figure and this fireball
erupts blowing out the stone of the dais and blowing
Lex and Arvid off and back into the mass of the army
who begin clicking and throwing themselves into like these fits of rage and
groaning as you fall onto your back and take 46 fire damage
Margaret you're gonna take half of that. You don't get blown off the dais, but you are kind of resting on top of it
And Lex also only takes half
Because of the ring that Margaret gave her so long ago. I take half of Lex's damage
Son of a bitch, right? Yeah
Rev play in the game
Thelonious's scream begins to echo out as the shield around him waivers this fireball
erupting and creating heat throughout the entire space and with an echoing crack
Thelonious throws his hands together and every single undead creature along the floor of this cavern
begins to move towards
Dumbgeons and Dragons season 2 episode
116 starring Karla Max dead as Lex Tom Laird as Perseus
Amy More as flanks with Kyle Claset as JAPES rev to Shane as Margaret broadcloak and Russ more as your dungeon master
Editing production and sound design by Russ More this episode featured music from epidemic sound and sound effects from epidemic sound boom
Library and sound ideas a huge. Thank you to our supporting producers Gabriel Lynch
Jessica Babyok cat water flame Jacob Madden Christian Brown Devin Michaels Craig Zeiss Aaron Stevens
Daryleth Lulahan
Charlie Warley and LA Branton to support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many other productions and get access to an exclusive
Podcast called the adventures of bonus episodes and much more
Please join our Patreon at Patreon.com
Slash dumb dragon cast join us on or before March 30th
2020 to join us for an improvised live show exclusive to patrons have a great week. We'll talk again soon
We cut to a chamber just off the back of the dais and we see a different perspective we see
The figure inside of the dome and felonious his face who's
arguing and screaming at him and then we see
Flanks and JAPES who are bound by the chains just off the cavern
What are these two fucking arguing about back here? They're saying a lot of shit about undead and taking over the world
I don't fucking get do you think they figured out how to use that fucking bag?
I don't know. I really hope so. I was only about 50% sure to use it myself. Maybe they need adventuring guides
Maybe they're on their own adventure and we can guide them wherever they're headed
Well, you got a you got to work on your pitch kids. So batter up
Because that one was carrying a baseball bat thing. So, you know, I thought it was a shot at my voice
My mom said I'll leave it out. No, no, I mean we kind of have almost a similar voice really
Yeah, so do I get to go through an older person be ready at some point?
Yeah, it kind of happens towards the tail end of things, but you'll get there maybe what do you mean?
Maybe I you'd have to ask the other five whenever you get to where they went
Everybody tells too tight you guys
It's getting serious it's getting serious I'm loosening my ponytail I don't plan that far
He doesn't know what's making the click
Deal
Somebody did some slam poetry somewhere and everyone just like Jetson the Sharks pop out Perseus rolling in sight
Time that better if I tried
That's great these are my own feelings and facial expressions Russell you don't need to interrupt your diet try to react to my reaction
Sorry
Let me hide self
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production