Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Well, they've really upgraded, haven't they?
It seems so.
From sewer to this sort of tropical paradise.
Vorunax could be redeemed.
How do I get up that mountain?
Uh, you can follow me!
The Cat Lord is up there?
That's why it's so green here.
Cat Lord hid in the mountains and has just been fond of knowledge.
Cats hide really well.
And yet you always seem to be around.
Alright, so what's the game plan?
I was given a little insider information from Bahamut that we can use.
Vorunax, Lipsinki, can I talk to you guys for a sec?
Listen, I'm not gonna lie, I think we've got this in the bag.
Let's entertain them.
Thea pulls out a wineskin and takes a swig and is like,
anybody, this is gonna be heavy.
Y'all, this is gonna be heavy.
Vorunax, you especially.
Like, for you, for sure.
If it is as heavy as you say it is,
then I'd rather be in my right mind to understand it.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
I'm your Dungeon Master, Russ More.
He, him!
Also with me today is Karla Maxtec.
She, her, that's me.
I will be Lipsinki, Yenbul, Elia, and Glim.
All she, her.
Who's your favorite?
Ooh.
Oh, no, thank you.
They're all a special part of me.
Couldn't choose one.
They're all Bahamut's children.
That's right.
And Tom Laird's here.
Yeah, that's me, he, him.
I am playing Flint, Telgir, and Moot,
and they all are he, him as well,
and Moot is my favorite, hands down.
And Amy More.
Yeah, she, her.
And today I am playing Thea Amastasia, she, her,
Gile Nighthunter, Ogla Kahnu, they, them,
and Sullivan Sleight, he, him,
and you know, just like your own best personal therapist
in the game for, in the game.
It was just kind of like a lingering hang there.
Or it could be yours.
Guys, if you just need to talk.
Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, I'm not actually a therapist,
but I'm a good listener.
And Kyle Klassen!
He, him!
What's up?
I'm back.
Playing Voronok Zatrucheth,
I can't say his last name
because I made it a stupid, difficult last name.
I was just going to say like, he had a last name?
I feel like Lipsinki's been working with this guy
for a decade.
I didn't even know he had a last name.
Lipsinki just whipped her head around
and was like, huh?
What?
I thought it was like Madonna or Shrek,
you got a last name?
Zatrucheth, I don't know.
It's a mouthful.
Those are, those are letters together.
Yeah, exactly.
But he, him, and maybe unnamed in PCA.
That'll chime in out of who knows.
Look, Kyle was just feeling left out
because everybody has eight characters.
That's fair.
You know, level one, like a sword.
I got dropped from an airship.
I'm an ogre.
They roll down the hill.
He's like the one talking undead creature.
That's right.
Yes.
Unique, special.
He's going to have his own spinoff.
It's going to be fine.
If you noticed, it was in, you know,
hopes for how this conversation goes
that we're going to have here.
Almost right out of the gate
as soon as we start playing.
But I dropped the, and you know,
special guest because maybe, who knows?
I'm just putting positive vibes out here
because I keep wanting to play with Kyle.
So don't kill him, Amy.
We'll see how it goes.
I make and no promises.
Do it, I dare you.
What happens over at Patreon?
You get to, at certain tiers,
give us NPCs and items in game.
And as this goes on, some of those NPCs
become fewer than farther between.
But don't worry.
We're storing those names everywhere
for future games, for Patreon games,
for anywhere we need a name.
That's where it's going to land.
You also get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Amy dropped my Excel spreadsheet.
You're the best.
Today's patron, Sebastian DeLeon.
Thank you, Sebastian.
Sebastian, thank you so much.
Yes, that's right.
Yes, a little fun fact about Amy.
From ages six to about 10, I was like,
if I have a boy, I'm going to name him Sebastian.
I thought that name was the dopest.
I don't think I ever heard that name
when we were considering names.
I said ages six to 10.
She was very specific about that.
Usually it comes.
Okay.
No, but listen, listen, listen.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, it does.
The never ending story.
I thought Bastion was Sebastian.
Well, and while I mean he was a great step
and father figure for me, I think that.
Sebastian from Little Mermaid?
Yeah.
Come on.
He was looking at her.
A little crabby at times, but you know.
He was way more of a dad than Triton ever was.
What is this podcast?
Long story to say, thank you, Sebastian.
If you would like to join us at Patreon.com
slash dump Dragoncast, we would love to have you
and now fuck it.
Let's play.
Yes.
Explosion, explosion, explosion.
The world is podcast over.
Yeah.
Right.
You wish you wish you wish.
I think I have the good guys.
I'm trying to like fix it.
Down on the beach set off of the beach
and a clearing in the trees.
Yumble and Leosan are in possession of the sole bridge gem.
But do they make out first?
I hope.
I don't, I don't.
I had pals for years.
I feel like, I mean, I know there's an age difference now,
but I mean, just saying.
Chemistry is still there.
Well, off screen we'll leave whatever you imagine.
Your head cannon is what happens.
Are they together?
Are they not?
Does it just remain awkward friends?
Who knows?
It's up to you.
Does Yenbul just keep writing from some future past about her kitty?
Who knows?
Oh my God.
What if she's writing from?
Don't do it, Amy.
Is this?
Don't think about it.
Is this the lake house?
Are y'all doing the lake house?
Yeah, we are.
I think we might be.
We've stumbled into a lake house.
Are you there?
I know Kung Fu.
Yeah.
Leosan played by Keanu.
Yenbul, Sandra Bullock.
A great Leosan.
Yes.
Oh, that's so great.
That would be good.
Okay.
Send us all of your celebrity castings.
Down time we'll discuss casting for the movie.
Down time casting.
All right.
I've written it down.
It has to happen now.
Back to the story.
Yenbul, we need to test this now.
I feel like there's going to be the need to use it right away.
Are you prepared?
Are you ready?
Yes.
I don't want to leave when it is chaos here.
But we must test the stone.
We must know if it will work to send the others where they need to go.
So tell me what to do.
Hold the gem.
And he begins to cast a spell.
The gem in your hands begins to glow as the sound of battle is erupting all around you.
Energy is being drawn up from the earth, up from the ground beneath you.
Roll a D100 please.
14?
Carla, I don't think this is Call of Cthulhu.
I was saying the same thing.
I mean, that would be a great Cthulhu roll.
Before Leosin, we see Yenbul begin to waver.
Like the image of her begins to waver.
Rushing in behind her is a group of fast-moving, demonic beings that are so hard to describe.
They have huge claws and hair that just comes up in like these razor-sharp tines
across their back and these massive teeth.
And as they come within a couple feet of her, they begin to waver.
She blips out, the Soulbridge gem drops to the ground.
Leosin quickly picks it up and begins running further into the forest.
Good thing all those cat people are in the forest, ready to give them some food.
Yeah.
Pick them up, pull them up into a tree or something.
Big, what, like what?
Big crab hedgehogs?
Yeah.
The fuck?
If that's what you pictured, that's what it is.
That is what I pictured.
Sometimes I just start saying things.
Now I got a craving for pickled soul gem.
I've heard good things.
Leosin runs off into the trees and we fade back to the beach
where Sully is surrounded by this horde of undead.
Blood is running down his forehead, his rapiers in his hands.
And we have one of those moments, like in the movies where
everyone's only going to attack you one at a time.
But there's a pause, a moment before it happens.
And he decides to whip around really fast and create a circle in the sand with his foot.
And then he points to the ugliest looking motherfucker and gestures,
come at me, bro.
And as it does, he slides underneath his legs.
And as he bends back, he lifts his rapier and chops him at the thighs below.
The icker begins to pour down.
And he bathes in it with his mouth closed.
And then just piped over some loudspeaker at the back.
I thought it was going to be rain on me.
As we see Glim tear across the beach towards a new wave of what do you see
and what are you tearing towards?
New wave zombies.
Oh, no.
British invasion.
They have all this floppy hair.
And they do.
I think after Glim had her hard fall,
she's going to approach all of the undead as they are coming out of the water.
And I'm picturing not just, you know, like humanoid skeletons,
but probably larger undead creatures as well that are making their way.
This hulking ogre is like water's pouring off of it as it's coming up to the beach.
And I've got the Vorpal longsword going.
And it's just glowing basically because it's all of this divine power
that I have coursing through my veins from my one-on-one sesh with Bahamut right before we went.
So that fall kind of knocked the wind out of me,
but it did not like at all take the wind out of Glim's sails.
Like she is just flying in bloodlust, but also like religious ecstasy.
We see the Vorpal sword churning through all of these undead
as Moot has found this high point on top of a mound of undead that has been piled up.
Moot sees a group of undead coming towards
and he puts his one good hand up and his one crab claw up
and kind of points in their direction.
And like a half second later,
there's this dim greenish light that starts to spread out from the middle of them.
And all the creatures that are caught in this sickening radiance,
not only do they suffer exhaustion, but they take a whole whack of radiant damage.
It's like popcorn exploding as this radiant energy waves through them.
They're exploding along the beach line which leads us down and towards one lone
tabaxi sitting huddled on the edge holding just this quarter staff.
Kyle, it's you.
Jeez, what is going on?
Why am I in this situation?
I'm not ready for this at all.
Where do I go?
What do I do?
Just tell me what to do.
They say we have nine lives, but I don't really.
It's a lie.
Well, here's what you do.
Find yourself an elder god, make a pact with them,
and then you'll have some kick-ass fucking magic to work with.
All right, I can do that.
Okay, which elder god?
Doesn't really matter.
Just appeal to the broadest spectrum you can.
One of them will pick you up.
That's how I lost my hand.
All right, what about that one that's like controlling all the undead that are around here?
That seems like a pretty good one to go with, right?
I don't think he's really like an elder god,
but, you know, maybe.
Well, what about you?
Can you get me in touch?
Do you got a contact?
So, you know, like reference player?
I do have a contact.
I'm not sure if he's taking new applications.
I'll let you know as soon as I can.
Sometimes there's like a bit of a delay on the communication side of things,
but like, I'll try.
I'll try and see if he's up for another disciple.
Okay, cool.
Then I'll just tag along with you then.
By the way, he loves taking hands.
So pick which one's your favorite and offer him the other one.
Oh, well, I don't know about that.
I kind of like we've made up and out of this conversation.
What the fuck?
Oh, this guy's making all these things seems pretty cool.
Moose like, yeah, it's an option.
Vorunax is creeping into your NPCs, Kyle.
We fade up and out of this conversation and into the heart of the mountain
where Elia, Night Hunter, and Opal have barricaded themselves into this cavern.
Behind them is this massive black panther.
Four of them are waiting.
They hear the moans of the undead and the rumbling of the mountain around them.
So, so we found the cat lord, didn't know it was an actual cat.
It's pretty cool.
What do you think it was going to be?
You assume?
Maybe a lord of cats.
Well, yes.
You know like that traveling one man show cats I did?
Yeah.
The memories of it were just outstanding.
Yeah, I mean, some people did really, really like that one, Night Hunter.
You have to admit that.
Some people did like it.
It was for one audience.
Good play is for everyone.
They told me that I had to change the costumes because
they didn't like the anatomically correct version.
It was unsettling.
The costumes were a bit unsettling.
And pointing right to the audience.
Very aggressive.
It's like they were screaming.
Yeah.
You speak like this in front of your cat lord.
Cat lord, is this okay?
Cat lord.
Turns and shows its anus to you.
Apropos.
The cat lord looks and growls and readies itself towards the opening in this cavern.
Cat lord is so strong.
Are you type of god to imbue strength upon your warriors?
There's a pause and then this radiating energy comes out of his paws.
Which he's sat up on his hind paws and is paddling the air.
Night Hunter would never say ah but in her mind she's like oh.
Yeah.
Coming out in waves and you feel rejuvenated.
Like you have you've been you've taken some damage and all of that you feel the wounds and cuts
begin to the blood begin to slow and the cuts begin to heal as the next wave begins to enter.
They're about to come in like the the mass of them is that what's happening?
Yeah so like yeah they're they're pouring it there it it's a
what we were talking about before it's a choke point so they're
coming in kind of one or two by uh by two this is the arc.
So Elia is going to use her her empty body so I'm going to spend some key points to
become invisible and gain resistance to all damage except force damage
and then also I am able to walk vertically now up walls so at that choke point I'm
going to just be sort of up there invisible waiting.
Taking heads.
Taking heads and and I mean mostly mostly punching and kicking very quickly and I can
do some pretty fucking rad punches and kicks now guys whoa.
But that's Elia's plan I guess before she does that she gives
Night Hunter a quick kiss and says see you on the other side of it.
Blushes just hardcore because we do not do public displays of affection so she is like
front of a cat lord right now get your shit together if not now then I really can't.
Be safe Elia.
Night Hunter takes out corpse grinder her great axe and presses the button and extends
the head of it and begins to swing it above her head in preparation of the horde to come
through and as she does so decides decides to just makes like a really rational decision to
rage because when she woke up this morning she chose violence and is raging out hardcore
while swinging corpse grinder above their head.
Elia punching and kicking and Night Hunter churning through a new batch of zombies cuts
through and Opal centers himself and grabs his keytar and plays just a few pounding notes on it
and it unleashes this shimmering lance of psychic power from his forehead
that blasts towards the creatures coming in and like back and through taking out
I don't know that's 12d6 taking out a whole shit ton down this hallway that
explode and like coked the walls of the hall down in Icar.
The cat lord rushes through and everybody follows in behind as we find ourselves back
up on the deck of what's your airship's name back on the deck of Bode McFloat face.
It's it's actually ew David
as we find ourselves back on the deck of the Bode McFloat face.
Sure nobody else wants any of this
because we're about to have a real moment.
All right just for me.
Thea takes a big drink of her courage juice it is just water she's actually really
like who nobody else wanted to drink from it because she was totally just listen.
You think you know what happened all those years ago in Blackpool but you don't.
I don't I don't know what happened to my family back in Blackpool.
You bring up a name which has not been spoken by anyone I know.
No where did you hear who told you this.
What if I told you that your family
Malice and Acer they weren't killed by the god of light.
I'd say you weren't there so how would you know.
You asked Paylor to do something that gods don't do.
As this speech carries on this way this light from the platinum dragon flying around being
swarmed emanates itself down over Thea and Vorunax and it's as if a scene is playing
out as she is describing it if gods won't do the right thing then why do they exist.
It's not up to gods to do the right thing.
Really they're just a bunch of entitled way overly powerful beings that seem to kind of
do whatever the hell they want. Then why should they not die.
I'm not saying they don't deserve to die but you thought they brought your family back
as monsters and they didn't. Look around you. Who brings to life monsters.
You may see them as monsters. I see them as a way of continuing on.
We see them as a way forward without the emotion without the need the greed
of our kind forced upon them.
This scene begins to play out where you see yourself Vorunax coming over the hills
outside of Blackpool. A path that you've walked many times and you know this time you know this
scene this is when you came back and the entire city was decimated. You see the look in your eye
the carefree nature the enjoyment and the excitement to be home
and then you see it shift as you see the first body.
Why are you doing this?
You were set upon a path that you thought you were choosing for yourself
but you were fooled you were tricked your memory was altered
and now you continue on living out somebody else's version of what your life should be.
One of these undying gods.
Scene shifts to the center of town where Vorunax you see yourself holding malice and acer
crying to the heavens. I don't want to live this again. I
stop showing me this. This is this wisp of blackness that rolls around you that you don't
you manage to look at yourself and you see that you don't acknowledge it
and it forms in front of you slowly as this
this goat-like abomination creature that forms into what you recognize as Paelor the god of light.
The scene is playing out there's no
there's there's no sound to it but you know that this is where Paelor has come to you
come to you to tell you that he can bring everything back and make it all go away.
See see the image that I'm forced to see once again the loss of
the people I held dear you're going to sit here and tell me all of what I've done
is but a ruse put upon me
who's cruel
who's really cruel in this world
everyone there's a crack a loud crack that rings out over the entire scene
in Vorunax the scene shifts it's almost like static and Paelor's face warps into that of
Orcus I fall to my knees
shimmers back and forth and you see him holding the wand of Orcus cackling behind this facade
down towards you as Paelor to you casts his blessing upon the entire city who then begin to
rise as the undead that you had to push back I want to believe these images false
who gives you this who gives you these visions for me to see who do you think
you
it was Bahamut earlier wasn't it
it was
I know what I must do then
I grab the wand of Orcus and I try to use it on Lipsinki for uh
fuck for powered kill whoa now now how can you just believe them
you're just gonna you just see a vision and all of a sudden the god says oh no it wasn't
it wasn't it wasn't Paelor it was Orcus and you're just gonna believe it after all we've
been through together after all of the worlds we've taken over after everything we've done
Thea runs in front of Lipsinki between the wand of Orcus and herself the scene
is playing out around this chaos that has erupted and we see Vorunax in a corner of this
house of this cabin he's rocking back and forth and these whispers are coming through to him
and there's this enlightenment period there's this this glint in his eye as he lifts his
head from the corner and looks over and sees the wand of Orcus laying in the center of the room
and it's as if Orcus is standing behind him guiding him towards it as I reach for
the wand do that just look I'm not even looking at Lipsinki but I'm looking at myself
I'm just like I know it's too late don't don't do it it doesn't have to be too late
it can change it can all change Lipsinki
I mean I don't like listen frankly I don't have like a giant story for you
the path that you're on right now the suffering that you have endured
is because of Vorunax and that can change well I mean it started out as the suffering I was
enduring at the hands of Vorunax and then we now we together as a team inflict the suffering and
we don't suffer anymore okay yeah okay but for how long you are not immortal you will be one
of the bodies that get dropped from an airship from whoever takes your place
that's a noble calling
you know what else was a noble calling a gnome that I once knew that did everything that she
could dug an entire city up to find a mystery to help people
it doesn't have to be like and what was my reward for that torture then yes
but we have the opportunity to change that how are you going to change something that's
already happened we're here now taking over the world we're almost done this is our last spot
and what will be your reward when it's done well there will be no more pain to inflict
you will live out your life until you too die and then what pleasure will you have
there will be none warm kiss of sun on your face as you walk the laughter of children
eating your favorite meal
holding a loved one nothing it will mean nothing it all means nothing but we can change it
it or I can step aside
as I'm very aware that Vorunax probably still has the wand of orcas pointed at my back to Lipsinkie
as the scene carries on Vorunax in the cabin reaches down for the wand of orcas and it
disperses no
it's the city of Blackpool fades away and you're back on the airship fuck you
Bodie McFloat face
Ah
Hey everybody just me tonight for the middle would like to just say thank you for listening
this is a really fun episode to play through everybody's so fantastic in the convincing of
each other to come to the good side or the bad side or who knows what's going to happen next
right it's just a blast everybody's lovely one thing we would like you to do if you
are so kind and so inclined is sign up for our newsletter been a little slow on it for
those that are already signed up for the newsletter in the new year but have a plan to
get back on it and give some fun stuff out to people notifications and reminders and
some some in-world things coming your way when you sign up for that in order to do so go to
our website dumbdragons.com if it's the first time to our website there should be a thing
that pops up that says hey sign up for our newsletter and if it's not go to the contact
us page or the contact page and there is a a little form to fill out to give us your
name and your email and we will send you a newsletter every now and again at least once
a month maybe more and it'll have fun in it so check it out dumbdragons.com newsletter there's
some other things over there we're working on a redesign of our website we'll let you know when
that's up to uh but until then we'll keep it short we'll keep it sweet thank you for
being here talk to you next time okay bye
so
what's it gonna be because i don't have all night or is it day not sure yeah we got
places and times to be
if anyone were to end me it should be lip-syncing
me i have led you astray because i have been led astray that amongst many things is my sin
and i am
i apologize lip-syncing
me i truly believed in what we were doing
because i truly believed
what the gods had done to me
i can't deny what i'm seeing what i've seen
and call me a coward call me a traitor
all of them are deserved i've betrayed you i've betrayed the people of this realm
i've made an enemy of everyone
at this point
the rest would be a grace undeserved
but i ask for it
from whoever's hand may give it to me
i walk over with the wand of orcas and i kneel and i offer it to lip-syncy
so
thea readies herself to punch lipstick in the face if necessary
i need to just grab that real quick i don't want i don't want that you no what is it's all been
this is just nothing it's just been nothing this whole thing our whole lives everything that
we've done has been a mistake everything you did to me everything we did together
is for nothing that's what you're saying yeah and now what we just give up we just walk off this
airship you don't have to give up
i've led you astray i think there's a chance for you
well a god manipulating someone is one thing
a person manipulating another person is a whole nother grievance
well what man it doesn't even make sense what manipulation came first you got tricked and
then you tricked me and we just tricks all the way down it's like orcas's own mlm
you were in my downstream
um
multi-layered murdering
oh god yeah and we became the two most successful mlm's we we run this whole
show everyone is in our downstream i enjoyed every company vacation with you
we got the vehicles we went ask yourself i believe in what i've seen can you
all i want all i ever wanted was to not feel weak to feel strong to feel like no one could
ever hurt me and i have found that no one has hurt me in years and no one has been able to
hurt me in years and now i give that up for what for what the i give up power and and the
world to what well think of the opposite lips and key you've never let anyone hurt you have you
ever felt love in these years well no but did i ever yes i have my friend Vorunax and i
we we care about each other and protect each other and i don't know that i ever felt that
before all of this happened i was in prison when you found me not for doing anything wrong just
for just for being strange who put you there yo
Vorunax did you ever care for lip sync like really care
i reciprocate the love that you feel lip sync
key which is why i feel like it should be you of all people to end me i don't no i don't
no also also i gotta shut this down right now i'm sorry Vorunax you are not going to get the
sweet release of death right now i understand number one if you did orcas would just bring
you back oh yeah and then you would be literally nothing but a puppet you guys lip sync key
are you in are you out well
what what what's in what are you even saying i'm gonna just turn around i'm gonna go scoop up
all the undead i just dropped on the beach what do you want us to do i mean you haven't
even told them the best part yet well okay well tall gear i was like kind of saving it
because it sounds fucking insane but i mean i think i think you need you really need to tell them
tell us what so what's the trade we give up all of this we don't kill you
and what do we get in exchange for that your life's back we go back in time
and kill orcas yeah tell us about the time travel so
we have the ability to time travel we don't know how many times but this one would be
rather important we are going to go back to a time before orcas has taken control of the
gods he will be weaker and it it is our best chance of defeating him with your knowledge
and power that you have we would stand a really good shot of saving all the realms
and make no mistake i know you're in the middle of dominating this one but it's not stopping here
and once all the light is drained out of all the worlds what will even be left
if there's but a Glimer of possibility that acer and malice
that acer and malice
would look down on me favorably from wherever they reside currently
lip sync i'm sorry i'm going to take it this is where it all started and i'm just going to take
this if you don't mind because i feel like you're still on your knees holding it out to
her and i'm just gonna like put it be careful that that's going to don't don't that it will hurt
you i wrap i wrap it in a cloth he's never even let me touch that can i hold it with like this
you can try okay and can i like i want to wrap it in a cloak she has one of those grabber
claws okay well i wrap it in a cloak first this thing i look like fucking evil yeah the cloaks
block all evil right that does it's a cloak of protection against evil right that's right
um just gonna just because she's a wild card right now so i have a couple questions
when when are we going back to you say orcas will be weaker do we go back do we go back
far enough to save Vorunax family do we go back far enough to save blackpool do we go back
before i ever even had i guess the misfortune to run into y'all could we do that could we go
back and save blackpool no i've been selfish enough i'm sorry for asking our first and most
important responsibility is protecting all the worlds but that's not to say that
that the power may not exist to go back and to change some specific events i can't make
any promises i i mean you guys look at me i i'm not entirely sure how time travel works
but if we are successful there could be an opportunity for a second trip
so where do you intend to go then i understand doesn't make sense to just go fix fix what we
would want fixing what do you what are you gonna do and how do we even know you can do it how
do we even trust you how do we even know you're stronger than orcas we could all just fight
right now you could all just be gone our plan is to go to the abyss just before
just before orcas is able to capture the gods he hasn't gained the power from them yet
you are both in the mix at that point which will create its own set of challenges but
you've already lived those moments you will be far more an asset with more information
and power than we could hope to have on our side
we can change things would our past selves be there yes that would be fucking weird
lip-syncing maybe walks to the edge of the airship like i want to get a sense of how this
battle is going we are just here having a nice chat and there are an enormous battle
happening everywhere and how's that going yeah you look down and you see your forces
over running like there you see the beach is being held by essentially three individuals
you see who you've been told is bahamut being brought down from the sky by your dragons you
see the undead that you you dropped below climbing back up and inside the cave where
there's this this large panther that explodes out and is being followed down and tumbled
down this mountain i don't think things are looking so good for your side and if i want to
be on the winning side of what i want is is power and safety i don't know that your side's
gonna give me that looks like we're doing pretty good here Vorunax that take a look
i step over to the edge and take a look we're just gonna give this all up what are we giving
up now that we i mean knowing what i know now i have already i've already lost
everything i held dear and i sought to take that away from others i took that away from you
and if i have the chance to ride it
to make this world
what i think is better and not what i have been convinced is better
it's what i must do
now i'm not going to use my conventional methods against you like i had in the past
but i will ask one more time Lipsinki join me and i hold out my hand
thea has conjured a flaming sphere in her hand and is just waiting
well we have been through a lot together
we have from torture or torture e to co-workers co co-rulers it does sound good doesn't it
it does sound good doesn't it
and the elf makes the point what what happens i guess i got kind of so caught up
in the killing and the and the destroying and the screams and people running away and
kind of forgot that once we get to the end here this is it
it what happens then no more no more downstream to sign up you know what i mean right so
i guess at the end of it
in in my whole life you've probably been the only one who's ever really
been there for me so
i guess if you're wanna i
and i grab his hand i pull in Lipsinki and embrace her the extinguishes her flaming sphere
mithral hall is rubble and standing in the middle of this
decimated dragon are flint and bort
two of them look across at each other their weapons dripping
um and as if from some divine place steps begin to appear around this light moving upwards
large platforms moving up towards the roof of the cave i guess this is our way out i guess so
uh as your your home i guess you first
yeah it's takes uh starts taking like big old steps up flint and bort are climbing these
steps and it's some time that passes and you reach the top and you enter into this
void space it's this blank clear white room
and as you step in you turn back and the hole that you climbed up through is gone
you look to each other and then
then behind bort you see a pedestal appear you see bort looking over your shoulder and you quickly
look behind and a pedestal appears there and on those pedestals are two daggers
you check your body and your armor is gone your weapons are gone the two of you are
staring each other down
so i kind of get the feeling this is where we part ways
bort just stares at you
and there's a flash of light a hard crack the sound of a bustling street comes
into the scene and we see yembol standing in the middle of kalampor full of people
going about their day sun shining bright the warmth of that sun and the heat of the sand
coming back up is like nothing she has felt since since she left here
just stunned she starts to slowly take off layers because she's been it's this is finally
in the in the heat and the sun and the dryness again i
i can't believe i'm here and and the market is here and the people are here and it is
it worked it actually it actually worked i'm here and and i i don't know
oh can i look down and the soul bridge gem is no longer in your hand and and and i cannot return
so i must find out when then this is so that i can
and stop stop what is to come and save my city and save my people
yembol rushes off down the street
as we fade up over the city there's a looming storm cloud
up and over a mountainous range off into the distance
so
Dumbgeons and Dragons season two episode 111 starring Amy More's the amistacia sullivan
slight and gael night hunter ogala kanu carla max dead as yen bull nurrie glim elia strong
and lip sinkie tom laird as talkier heavyfoot flint fire beard and moot with kyle Claset as
Vorunax and Russ More as your dungeon master editing production and sound design by Russ More
this episode featured music from epidemic sound and sound effects from epidemic sound boom
library and sound ideas a huge thank you to our supporting producers gabriel lynch jessica babyuk
cat water flame jacob madden christian brown devon michaels craig zeiss erin stevens darrell
eth lulahan charlie warley and la branton to support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many
other productions and get access to an exclusive podcast called the adventures of bonus episodes
and much more please join our Patreon at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast you can also
follow us at facebook.com slash dumb dragon podcast and on instagram and twitter at dumb
dragon cast thank you for listening have a great week we'll talk again soon what oh
oh hello who what's happening sorry i was not ready at all
as thea is about to attempt her persuasion
as a thea is about to start her speech just basically just go speech
speech speech speech speech speech speech speech speech speech speech okay
i don't i don't know it'll happen to my own family
this is pretty much yeah you want to try again i do no yeah no it's fine making it cool
well i know i didn't know if you were like just cutting me off and being like and cut to
the beach and i'm like yeah i just started we gotta drag this out i just
bahama does like the av stuff as well as right he like total av nerd i love it it's cool i'm
really sorry about that i can't always cut it i really didn't mean to i thought i had like
more is mostly in yours it's okay do it again well no i just needed to fit wait it's
almost like hold up guys hold on just once wait got it you don't leave any gin at the bottom of
that glass they found love in a hopeless place we're just co-workers who love each other okay
it's platonic it's fine of course yeah well no i didn't say what kind of love
yeah it's like uh starts taking like big old steps up and as he does it's actually a dance
dance revolution and it's like combo Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production