hey real quick this is the penultimate episode we messed up the count and the
last episode where we said there were more episodes coming there's not so
there's there's only one after this one so so the last yeah that last one
was a thrultimate yeah thrultimate yes yeah we've decided that was a
word that love it that's how the thing goes so there's only one more
after today which is is wild and crazy but that that said I the way I phrased
it made it sound like it's forever over
it's not just the season season just this story arc yes yeah I'm glad you
caught that yeah what it has an email oh yeah you can send us your emails
but it's not over I mean the show's not speaking of emails we're looking
for questions right for Q&A yes we need questions Q&A in the in the disk what
are they called summary description in the description there's a link you can
click mm-hmm yeah in the episode description just click on it and send
us your questions because we'll do a question episode after the next
episode that's right yes and we're gonna record that with our patrons at
our next gook hang so maybe join us over there because that'll be a lot
of fun too to have you over there okay they're not gonna keep you any
longer get to the episode okay bye previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons I
assume you're screaming some sort of valiant battle cry can you just write
like some or get a sound effect of a really angry like pen scratching on
paper okay you charge forward you're screaming your battle cry and orcas
turns and looks at you he is actively trying to crawl as much as he can
towards the portal right now yeah he's trying he moves as much as he can and
then like the tension in his leg where he's restrained is holding him back see
him reach he's trying to pull himself forward and then everyone hears this
booming voice throughout the room
orcas is voice booms throughout the lair and lands on one creature of orcas
is choice and they're subject to power word kill the buzzing sound from down
the hall intensify and flying in on backs of these winged creatures are
thousands of grants that begin pouring out and down through the portal you
got him did you get him I mean he doesn't have a dick anymore so welcome
to Dumbgeons and Dragons I'm your dungeon master Russ More he him also
with me today is Tom Laird hey yeah that's me he him I am playing a moot
who also goes with he him and Carla Max dead she her that's me playing
lip-synchy pip diggins and glim both also she her and Amy More yeah I'm
here and I can speak today huzzah and I am my pro dancer she hurt and
I'll be playing the amistasia she her Sullivan slight he him and night hunter
okla khanu she's a and Kristen Flemmons hi
there she is somehow unprepared she her playing a goth godlust
Kathua lovey also she her and the horse racks he him and Kyle class it
hey hey he him gonna be playing Vorunax also he him lovely to have you all here
we're getting so very I don't even I can't even say we're getting close
because who knows who knows what's gonna happen right we could shenanigan
for so many more episodes okay maybe not eight years but we are getting
close and it is very exciting and then we just I guess this is just a
reminder that there will be a season three we don't know what it is but
could be anything you don't know where you don't know when but season three
will happen that's right it's behind you right now yeah look out when you
least suspect it in the backseat of your car you know what we've already
started it's in another feed you have to go find it we've left Easter eggs
throat is that what they're called Easter eggs yeah all these past
episodes those little things that you hide yep Easter eggs got it shut
where there are Easter eggs for well some characters that show up in this
good season is over on Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where
we have a new not a new we have another podcast that is available for
you it's called the adventures of that has crisscross the applesauce
all over it everybody's very confused looking but that's what it is
yeah it's all over there and when you're a patron you get an episode
dedicated to you like today's patron Nathaniel Teeter Nathaniel is a druid
aspiring I mean I feel like he's I feel like he's there too because he's
always posting like here are the things I am growing and druid
we're middle of winter and eating fresh fruit out of the garden yeah it's
actually kind of rude it's depressing and uplifting yeah both at the same
time I don't know how he manages it I think they call that necromancy yeah
thank you Nathaniel for being a necromancer I mean I drew it in in our
community and now fuck it let's play
there's a stunned silence throughout the room this droning buzz of these
massive demon creatures being ridden by grants is pouring through the portal
before you Vorunax is helping night hunter back up through the portal
who's been holding this like sick like arm curl and looking really badass with
nobody to see them except the people down through the portal water deep who
are being attacked simultaneously attacked and saved by different demons
grants us of course being the savior it's a confusing time it's a
confusing time I will say Vorunax is definitely looking down grabbing the
chain with one arm just looking at her like yeah one arm lifting I can too she
she gives him like a smile and a nod like as night hunter climbs back up
in in with Vorunax's help we pan over to a goth what does it goth I think
after taking a quick pause at like taking in the scene around a goth is
actually just going to drop the flail that is in her hand and start like
pushing her way through all of these buzzing demons passing by and just
pushing through and just make her way over to orcas's face where he has
collapsed on the ground and I don't know if there's any rubble we need to
like clear that out of the way maybe position him optimally and then
just wind up and take the biggest sucker punch right into kisser like this yeah
it takes a moment to get him propped up in like a seated position kind of
weekend style helping too because we want this for you we want to make
sure that you know business continues as usual everybody expecting orcas to
still be alive that kind of vibe of setting him up and then almost like
Scott Pilgrim kind of fight scene like winds up and just clocks him through like
this hails through his face and he blasts back and off of this chair that
you have to be might have to repeat that exercise a few times as you're
going to set it up again Grancis comes down off his
demon creature and says so I did what we said I released all the Grancis they
they're helping but I also did what we said and I let go some help there's a
loud thump from down the hall oh yeah so we don't actually need I don't that
yeah there was some it's I mean your time is great to get the the other
demons and like okay get down there amazing but we don't really need like a
monster kind of great great great point I don't know if this is one we can just
turn off what do you know about demogorgon I'm gonna do a check okay
no no no who's that night hunter night hunter no shit me too
oh you rolled a nine I rolled a nat 20 so I guess I don't know okay oh plus
nine so twenty nine total just just a twenty nine moot got an eleven that's a
27 for me and Sullivan's light actually did not do poorly oh minus one yeah okay
so okay demogorgon huge fiend Barnax you probably have a good sense of
knowledge being very attributed to orcas demogorgon and orcas not best
friends in fact arch enemies trying to take over the entire abyss for a very
long time demogorgon was previously thought to be the step above orcas but
it appears that due to the fact that demogorgon was in orcas's prison
demogorgon now free demogorgon coming your way
um so we probably don't I know there's a bit of a power vacuum and I didn't
think it's someone would be trying to replace orcas so quickly but um we
probably are gonna need to I mean like step in here either stop him here right
away stop the portal right portal somehow is that is that something we
can do is that something you can do okay I don't know maybe I don't think
no I definitely I have no portal magic but I have like zero magic whatsoever
so also everybody else he's like the million grant this is right oh yes yes
they're old guys flying everywhere what the hell's going on I don't I
don't think I can close that portal yeah no I can open portals and
sometimes they close this is I think I think we're stuck with the portal
everybody cool cool cool okay um okay okay so like what if demo we're just
like hey demogorgon this is your area now don't go through this portal and
you can keep this space because you are the one that the the king now like
do you think if we just rope it off he'll he'll he'll respect the rope
is it like a like a red velvet I was gonna say if we put a red velvet
I mean people are usually pretty nobody right not even here oh wow I didn't know
that was I guess that's universal we take our cues very seriously the
entire room shakes on this next thumb and we have no plan there's a half
second and then the door to orcas is thrown room the wall around it just is
shrouded in shadow and then the entire wall bursts open and towards you
everybody make a dexterity saving throw okay if you got below a 12 you get 13
bludgeoning damage as rubble flies forth towards you you turn and you
look and you see this two-headed gargantuan fiend like skeletal
jackal maws one a jackal one like this monkey it's got this long snake like
tail with pincers and barbs on its hands are tentacles like two
tentacles coming off of each arm and has these giant reptilian feet as it
comes in I would just like to also say that when night hunter was pulled
back up by Vorunax they are for sure like just wrapping they've just wrapped the
chain around their awesome their hand because I mean you don't know a sad
I'm not gonna let that fall into no the real world what if it falls through
the portal and hit someone an innocent person at the bottom on the
other side I mean I don't know if night hunters worried casualties it
happens
okay so everybody was kind of just chatting all together so we're all
assuming that we're gonna start in a more central location yes it's why
we're not a feared and yeah cuz yes why you're not a fear you're all
clustered around glim the might yeah and also we had all just been
moving Orcas's corpse around yeah that's true yeah that's kind of a like
we're all gonna talk about that later have some group therapy the way you
puppeted him Vorunax was really awkward and I just think we should have said
something at the time what I guess I've been able to like just like
grab a souvenir before the Demogorgon sounds like a tooth or
something sure yeah so yeah you yeah Orcas too I want a tooth yeah yeah it's
it's Kyle describe Orcas's teeth having been like prime on the benefits
package for the Underdark well also yeah true it's true yeah it's I had
some firsthand experience well you know anyway Orcas's teeth are
surprisingly they're large but they're like blunt it's one of those
things where like it's not they're not sharp but they're gonna pierce you
regardless and it's gonna be more like a serrated kind of experience so yeah
like a large like blunt spiky serration okay so Demogorgon's up
first and he's going to swing his tentacles through the crowd he gets
two tentacle attacks one is going to be towards Vorunax whom he probably
recognizes just based on contextual clues yeah one's gonna be towards Glim okay
the one towards Vorunax is going to be a 32 probably not yeah hits the one
towards Glim is going to be a 21 yep that'll do it but we are very close
together so I think I will I cannot help a 32 but I will use a warding
maneuver for Glim so sure you can see within five feet hit by an attack roll
1d8 and add the number to your AC so yes post it no oh bad bad roll but a
22 so it'll work all right okay so Vorunax you're going to take a 28
force damage and if the target is a creature you're a creature yeah you must
succeed on a DC 23 Constitution saving throw oh everything in a creature is it
alive so your hit point maximum is reduced by the amount equal to the
damage taken which is 28 which is 28 and happens until you finish a long rest the
target dies if its hit point maximum is reduced to zero holy shit nice nice
knowing y'all no I'll be I'll be good I'll be all right it's if the maximum
so there's like two levels you're playing with you're playing with you
know you're you're active and then also your maximum is catching up
behind yeah right yeah okay those two tentacle attacks happen and he lets
out this grotesque scream into the room it's Grantz's turn catnap he turns at
you and he says it's time for the catnap no it's not now then when he's
probably a little buffed for a catnap but we can try we can try
thousand of you guys there's a thousand of us we can all catnap but no what I
was gonna say is if we kill him here he just goes back home so that that
gets him out of here if we can if we can kill him and orcas was like doing
things to him down there like like hurting him not like weird things
see I get your mind under the gutter I wasn't thinking weird things like it was like trying to make it
like I'm you know weaker like the gods and he was probably gonna try
to take his power so he's probably not full strength so what I'm saying is
if we just hit him as hard as we can as quickly as we can maybe maybe you'll have
a cat now I'm gonna cast cat now are you cat napping him are you not cat
napping him I'm very confused on the subject why do we allow him to
monologue I don't know you all just kind of let it happen that he runs
the game I can't tell him to shut up I'm married to him I think it's my
keeps talking you make a calming chest I don't know is this even gonna fucking
work up to three willing creatures no no if the target remains unconscious no so
that's not gonna work how about we cast fireball yeah firebomb may follow
you depending on how this works out okay okay let's cast it high you know
go big or go home I think it's go big or die that is relevant so yes to
make a dex 19 saving throw that's a four on the die let's see how dextrous I
mean surely he's not a plus 15 plus 10 so that's a 14 so he still misses it
so that's 14 d6 oh yeah as this fireball erupts can you roll them one
at a time or seven oh no three ones that's okay that's 47 fire this massive
ball erupts from grants us and out towards demogorgon and explodes in this
fiery blaze around him you smell it before you see it as the smoke begins
to clear like the flesh blistering on his chest and it is night hunters turn
well old guy had some moves and some advice I think that is why we let you
talk night hunter is going to grab corpse grinder and try to grind some
corpse that is a 24 yes that will hit 17 well they're gonna do it again just
gonna keep hacking that one's 21 does not hit no does not hit oh she's mad
I'm on a rage fucking rage really mad that that last one didn't hit and
that's a nat one I got too mad you guys love it
you've trend you've crossed over you hit him once and his tail swings around on
this second one and that's a natural 20 plus 17 doesn't matter it's gonna hit
you for 40 bludgeoning damage plus 22 necrotic damage okay so that's 40
22 is 62 total damage okay all right oh damn that's okay I'm fine but I am
going to do I'm going to I don't know I don't know how else to say it I'm
gonna do stones endurance I'm gonna do it okay and reduce damage dealt by 1
d12 plus 7 to a goth I'm just gonna look at the group so we are not
talking then she's like almost started pulling some hemp and rope out of the
bag puts that back in yeah no I think we're just hitting I don't think he
speaks the language of love don't know my god I wasn't even thinking about
it not even once not even with the tentacle arms you look like you're
into some freaky shit the look on the face is just pure like that we
weren't afraid you didn't ask very afraid of this I will scoop the flail
back up a goth is now gonna go up there with night hunter and start
wailing on it perfect that is not amazing that is no but it is a plus
12 so that is still an 18 18 does not damn it all right all right let's
try again three attacks oh my god 20 that doesn't hit no final attack
encouragement a six and eight and a three three you can do three attacks
none of them hit I have a plus 12 on this weapon you just tired from you
know kicking orcas's ass no I guess hey Ross I did the spiritual weapon near
the end of the orcas fight is that still up or no that would I mean there
was a I feel like okay they're probably enough happening because there
was a lot of propping him up with different with different like hats and
stuff taking pictures the novelty sunglasses yeah it's one minute duration
okay so yeah you would have to okay I'll recast it because why the fuck not
does it get an attack right away it does you have this okay it's a 19 so
does my you have this do anything it is motivational dog if you are a
bard that's right I guess so one one character class we don't have a goth
not feeling great but demogorgon is you know look down at you oh down his
nose look down upon you make a wisdom saving throw please gaze is fourth
upon you okay this judgemental eyes I'm gonna reroll that one let's get a real
dice out here come on buddy okay much better that's a 17 plus 9 so 26 there
we go okay that's good you have succeeded against his gaze ability
okay I don't know what it would have done but you know it wouldn't have been
great but you feel like this this this impending sense of doom that washes
over you as he looks down at you and it's more that you I mean you moved
out of the frighten frighten zone but we've kind of passed that so it's not
quite frightening it like something bad would happen yeah let's just leave
there listen moving on great moving on flame of kins flame of kins is
okay that looked really cool
it's not really a time for sarcasm seems kind of rude yeah no that's fair I
apologize um I'm going to I'm tend to put him in a meant who I can dominate
monster holy shit guys it's not even in a sexual way okay isn't it isn't
it always isn't it always isn't it it's a little closed demogorgons it did things
so he can't say anymore uh okay how wise is he mmm I'm pretty wise that's
a 24 against a 19 well shit um okay I gaze back at him and it doesn't do
anything is it you dominated him right now you're doing it look at it yeah
look at it I love Flamikins kins meta knowledge
does he get half damage no does he get a little bit does he feel a little
something from the eye contact though he feels a little he feels a little
dominating yeah you know what's coming
uh glim got all the heavy hitters up first except for flame of kins and go
ahead and hit him hit him um I'm going to use my fire breath haven't done
that in an age so he needs to make a deck save 17 that's an 18 on the die
plus 10 really not a minus three weird okay well he'll still take half damage
so it's 24 on the dice I'll take 12 damage which isn't a lot but it looks
pretty cool looks badass yeah no like a goth and and night hunter run
forward and and neither are doing exceptional yeah I mean there was
contact a lot of people staring each other down and then a blast of fire
comes out so there's a lot of things happening it's moving it's shaking
anything else glim would like to do yeah he's got a couple heads so I really
want to use the vorpal longsword just in case it works out for me just
to see if it works out this time it didn't but that is a 25 25 will hit
great I can't remember where your vorpal sword does if you get a nat 20 I think
it if I roll a 20 I cut off one of his heads which is awesome so it could
happen yeah 13 and then also 7 radiant damage love it yeah big cut in so now
they're oh and then I'll do more more yes okay as a bonus action I'm
going to do ensnaring strike because I hit him with my weapon attack so writhing
massive thorny vines appear at the point of impact and he needs to make
a strength savings throw I mean you have advantage because you're large or
larger I assume it's a 25 yeah so I mean that'll that'll but it looked
cool I shot fire I stabbed him I shot some vines you know I'm just
throwing it all at the wall seeing what sticks flavor of it like he he
struggles a moment and then breaks free just to you know just to make that that
land okay moot have you closed the portal yet I don't I don't think I
know how grant this oh just remember back to your teacher Gabriel Gabriel he
would have he would have given you a lesson in closing portals I'm sure of it
are we having a flash off-screen one yeah off-screen lesson oh yeah you there
was something about that but like it only worked on small portals is that
the one that when he used to use a portal to go from one bar to another
bar and then close up before the other bomb and got mad yeah so no no I
mean I'll need a little help I think what would you do if I sang out of tune
now keep going that's it that's a classic has grants has ever sung in
tune no no all right everybody moot gets by with a little help from his
friend moot gets high with a little help from his friend all right Russ do
I know how like do I know what to do here like seriously though you want to
try I mean I'll give it a try yeah come up with something something maybe from
your character sheet and then directed at the portal and see what happened
okay because there's clearly a power source somewhere maybe Arcana you can
try and judge where the where the power source is coming sure let's give
it a roll to start that is a 19 okay so yeah you listening to the
sweet dulcet tones of grants is trying to encourage everybody to sing to you he's
running around like in everybody's faces as they're trying to fight
Demogorgon it's really just a wild scene but you get a good sense that
the portal is drawing energy from the floating now floating orbs of color
that are moving through the space what color are these orbs and how many
orbs are there they're like the god orbs that expelled from him when he yeah oh
okay gotcha gotcha so there are many colors like you could say the colors
of the rainbow okay take a look what about the colors of the way yes they
are blowing on the wind moving about and like there's like sparks and little
shots of energy being drawn to the portal itself I guess try and like
take out a cluster of these things okay like I've got a fireball I've got
lightning bolt love it we can we can make some stuff happen here all right so
you're aiming for the for the god presumed god aura yeah the god balls
the god balls yeah the god balls the main thing calling rate for the god
balls they need to make a deck saving throw do they have that
capability since they are just orbs of energy don't they just hang there I've
rolled for something well you had to beat an 18 love it you can you can
continue with your spell okay uh it is fireball and if you didn't pass then
you're taking a bunch of damage give me that damage baby all right fireball
10d6 41 secondary fireball goes off into the room towards these lights the
lights themselves get struck by the fireball and where the previous fireball
exploded out into his embers everywhere this one hits and then lingers and
then gets sucked into the balls themselves and they begin to now move
closer to you they've where they were previously up in the air they've moved
now 30 feet down and are we'll say probably another 30 feet away mo I feel
I feel like you need a like a big butterfly net yeah and is this gonna
go bad or good like what are we thinking here last will we use some
of those last time so I don't think they're inherently bad okay yeah so it's
just like the you know the spirits and powers of the gods so maybe they're
gonna come and help help us okay I said confidently cat catch him gotta
catch him Oh God boss anything else you want to do on your turn or just
reflect on the state of God I think just just soak it all in okay
moment perfect little talk middle talk it is time to middle talk it's the
place where we ask you to fill out your questions and send them to us
because we're almost done the season if I had to guess if Russ had to come up
with a tune like on the spot that it would be off the spider-man theme song
absolutely that would be my guess yeah yeah yeah yeah just because he does a
quick glance around the room and it's like what am I wearing oh it's a
Marvel shirt all right let's do something there I'm real on brand today
I was chilly I needed something to keep me warm there's only one episode left
after this one in this season so like one and a half episodes left and that
is wild and crazy and exciting and thank you for being here with us
couldn't have done it without you couldn't have wouldn't have or could have but just would
have been like talking to no one well I mean maybe we would have just been
playing a game if we weren't releasing it but that wouldn't have been this
fun because we wouldn't had you along yeah we would have home this true as I
said in the song we are taking questions for our end of for our
regular end of season Q&A episode because we did it after season one so
now it's a regular thing if you do it twice so you can send us those
questions we need to have shorter seasons one question per episode that
would be unmanageable so what we're saying is there's a lot to draw from
if you're wondering about some stuff so questions comments concerns
wonderments you name it send us send them to us and we will record that
after the finale drops with our patrons so if you want to join us
for that as well you can join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
we'd love to see you over there okay we'll let you get back to this episode
this penultimate episode before we get to the season finale have a great week
we'll talk to you soon okay bye love you bye bye
Sully you're up oh no speaking of god balls speaking of god balls okay I
think Sully would just feel like it would he would just be so tickled if
his frightful sort of reflection worked just once so he is going to like run
up and slice at the Demogorgon's like toe or whatever wherever he can reach
ingrown oh I bet it hurts it's I bet if he stubs that thing he's gonna like
let loose a string of swears oh oh 23 23 will hit oh oh Sully hits him with
the the sword of a frightful sort of reflection and what happens is you
get eight eight damage but then also the pommel of the sword shimmer gloom
has a name gives the gives the attacking and a sense of fear and so you need to
make a Constitution saving throw so how how I yeah so Demogorgon is immune
to fright oh okay well then that's fine I'm just down there poking his toe being like this thing doesn't work
here's what happens though so you go up and you hit his you hit his
ingrown toe and it feels really bad and he's like he's hopping up and
down now so you got to watch out for that but he's feeling really bad about
it there was a demon right behind him who was sweeping sweeping up some of the
rubble and you you like show the sword to to Demogorgon and by the whole
one of these jump-ups the demon behind him sees the frightful sword of
reflection gets very scared and and drops his broom and runs away I'll
tell you is Demogorgon gonna step on the broom and it's gonna hit him in the
face yes yeah the broom which magically grew 12 sizes that day now is a rake
and he lands on it you didn't say how big the demon was that was doing the
sweeping yeah I imagine this enormous demon just trying to scooch by just
being like janitor here don't mind me yeah it's fine
boronox seeing somebody attacking the orbs realizing that that's a that's a
solution he's gonna take note of it and he's gonna do a real test he
says let's see if that power is actually gone and I pull out the wand
of orcas and I am going to use three charges off the wand of our orcas to
cast circle of death around the god orbs so I need all the orbs to give me a
Constitution saving throw DC 18 if this if the spell actually works okay
yep great boronox remembers what happened last time he destroyed one of
these I think he liked it okay so that happens they rolled for something
and did not beat your DC so 8d6 and that is 29 necrotic damage so this
necrotic energy begins to swirl out and it like it acts is acting as
like this river of air moving these orbs around this room and sparks begin to
shoot off of them they get wrapped up in like this black
Icarus or around them and then get dimmer and dimmer and the
encircling space Titans and at the same time the portal Titans as well the god
orbs themselves get closer to the position of everybody else on the
ground perfect and I'll use my movement to move up close to a goth
and hopefully give a little bit saving throw bonus thanks okay the um he is
gonna do something that she often forgets to do and she yells out
everyone's feeling okay yeah yeah I'm fine pretty good
demoralize the big guy and then didn't have a little unsettling yeah
don't let that get you you guys are doing a great job
so she saw she saw a goth go like which was probably very hard for her to do
and so she's going to run up to a goth and cast cure wounds oh 12 sorry
which is you know not a lot but but better than better than nothing something
and then she's just gonna take both her daggers and just um just like jam it
in his calf and yell Charlie horse is one of those daggers the dagger that
she picked out of the hallway no okay just my old regular old daggers that
is 24 okay are you still sticking with your two regular daggers got it okay
cool love it I'm scared of that other dagger and I'm not sure why I
have it because you took it yeah those hit five plus six eleven and then
she like skips backwards and it's like ah you take an attack of
opportunity what because you just get back do you know I tricked you I said
you could trick I said you could walk away I was like I shall never do that
damn I did can touchdown dance showboating 27 get kicked I'll do the
warning maneuver again since this is for a goth benefit that she came up
so so you get four to your AC but if that does it if the attack still hits
you're resistant to it so you get half damage if it still hits okay that only
brings me up to a 23 so it would still hit yeah yeah only take half the
damage so you're gonna take great 14 force damage and you have to make a
saving throw this is a tentacle attack Jesus why is it so low how about a 10 no
so your hit point maximum is reduced by that much as well so you reduce
by 10 oh by 14 yeah oh okay lip-synchy okay I am going to cast psychic scream
at ninth level on the demo Gorgon okay so he needs to make an intelligent
saving throw oh yeah please dumb as a sack of bricks that's right do you
dummy 19 okay so that means he won't be stunned but he's still going to take
half of the damage which is 14 d6 so that's 50 damage so he'll take 25
damage 25 and that's psychic damage that is psychic damage what does it look
like when lip-synchy cast you know it's actually not that impressive because I
just am like scrunch up my face and like give him a really mean face and
I'm all fLexed up scowling so hard so I mean honestly he doesn't even
notice I'm so small he doesn't even see it coming she okay I am also
going to hurl the demo Gorgon through hell when you hit a creature with an
attack you use this feature to instantly transport the target through the lower
planes at the end of your next turn the target returns to the space it
previously occupied or the nearest occupied space and it takes a whole
schwack of damage when he comes back okay so he's gone cool he's gone there's
no save you she's punches you into hell deal with it okay so there's a temper
tantrum and then I like I think we've established that one is like the the
hell scapes like open up underneath them because we did use that one in in
a in at least an episode probably the episode that scared everybody and
turned them off of our podcast probably yeah but now I'm using it for good
right open opens up beneath them disappears it closes behind you're now
in this space the the necrotic energy swirling these god orbs around the
portal had shrunk by half we are back up so it's Demi Gorgons turn Demi
Gorgons not there right now it's not here man Grants is his turn okay what
do you guys figured out about this portal business I just finished the third
round of the song and I feel like we're really just bringing it home you
sound really out of breath well it's I've been in I've been in the prison
for a bit no no moot you're not gonna tell me not good I mean yeah
haven't no for knocks you got it we're working on it no I imagine we're
gonna be dealing with the orbs that are going on here that no one over there
seems to have a good idea of it so I figured I'd follow suit it looked like
as orbs get closer porto close okay okay so we should target that all
right you want me to do that I mean I know I sent him away but he is
coming back like pretty quick so if you want to I could get him to take
yeah okay cool cool cool cool he's gonna cast what are you hitting it with you
here with fire you hit it with some necrotic I'll try I'll try cold he
does and it's gonna take some damage 98 40 damage wow spicy okay this orb
gets thrown into the stream of necrotic energy and explodes and it leaves like
this blizzarding effect that everything kind of casts through and they begin
to close even more down to like about five feet and everything is spinning so
fast and light is shooting off of this the stream that is happening in
the center so that's what I got and then it's night hunters turn night
hunters looking at all the orbs and all the magic and it's just like and she
she backs up a few paces from where the Demogorgon was and is just with her
chain just ready to I don't know hit it once it comes as soon as it comes
back she wants to like wail on that thing okay so readying action for
attack yeah got a return a goth same Z's I am a goth is also going to ready
an action to to do a hit okay readying action Flamikins is going to also try
and hit the things with lightning bolt this time we've got fire necrotic
we've got cold we've got lightning blasts going out and it charges this
spinning charges the spinning energy in the center and they're shooting out
everybody feels like the hairs on their body stand up and it's in this
spinning ball in the center the portal is near closed you can still see
light streaming up through it and hear the battle that's happening on
the other side we go to glim um I think that glim's just going to also
ready in action I think with the with the purple longsword love this like
trio so far of badasses just standing waiting for this big monster to come
lip-synchy was like coming back yeah we're all like good we weren't done yet
moot back to you all right I'm gonna cast burning hands Russ and I'm gonna
I'm gonna make a break for the globes if someone can give me like a boost
okay we've got next in turn Sully Varonauts Thea and lip-synchy I mean
I feel like Sully could give me the old double hand brace as I like step up and
try and go for it I love that okay just like we practiced okay so moot
dashes from his location towards Sully Sully what do you look like as you're
preparing yourself for this jump okay so you would assume that it would be
your standard hands you know fingers linked right yeah foot there it's not
love they've actually been practicing this for a while what he's gonna do
moot's gonna run up then swan dive love it then like waist he's gonna
Sully's gonna have him around the waist and propel him back behind him
so much like Swayze except except propulsion and we've had the time of our
lives so it totally tracks okay propelling you forward you are soaring
now soaring soaring through the air that's how on point I'm gonna make
your role cuz you practice everyone marvels the sheer mechanics of it are
mind-boggling moot burning hands hands ablaze reaches connects with this
spinning sphere of god orbs and is sucked inside oh no oh guys I I this
was his idea you saw that the whole time I was just support because my
friend wanted because my friend wanted to do something and I wanted to be there
um forum that's your action that's rude should I not try to continue
destroying the orbs they are spinning faster you can see as you watch them
you can see glimpses of like moot's face and it changes every single
time it's like panicked it's excited it's like throwing up it's it it is
all of the all of the emotions that you could be going through he is going
through right now inside of this churning laundry of God or the classic
emotion of throwing up mm-hmm so it's not like he's inside of an orb no he
is not inside of an orb he is appears to be him or his is his bodily
state is inside of the vortex that was create that is being created well fuck
um that rules out a oe I mean you don't know it's true that has crossed my mind
I mean you do what you got to do moods a tough boy he can handle it you
might even get a hellish rebuke for your efforts who knows oh that's cool
yeah I can come to that yeah I'm gonna throw a fifth level fireball at it
that's what I was gonna do anyway okay so Dex saved 20 being as I'm spinning in
a vortex for us do I have the ability to I don't even think you have the
the consciousness of the state of mind to know that a fireball is coming
to love it at this point yeah give us that fireball 32 fire damage
it's fine right food it's fine everything's fine probably so as this
fireball goes the end lip-synchy what before before I'd say what happens what
do you two do in your own internal preparation because all this is
happening come like at the same time right so the oh the minute that moot
got sucked in there she's trying to think of us like does she have a spell
where she can like yank somebody out of someplace and so she's just trying
to think of her mind is splitting do I do I help moot or because the
Demogorgon is gonna be right back or so she's got like two different spells
she's waffling between at the moment okay so your action is to choose in
action I'm choosing to waffle once the Demogorgon comes back it I'm
actually just gonna hold my action and then cast a spell when he comes back
lip-synchy well I know that guys coming back right now so I am going to ready
my eldritch blast marking the end of my turn at which point Demogorgon comes
back and takes a bunch of damage from psychic damage okay what's the psychic
so he gets 10d10 hmm yeah imagine they're all 10 imagine imagine all the
damage so he takes 53 psychic damage Jesus it's wonderful hopefully all
those readied actions like like I want it to be overkill oh he's been
dead for a moment and we're all just still yeah blasting okay a lot of things
happen all at once okay fireball hits the spinning ball gets sucked into the
ball in the sphere there's fire there's electricity there's necrotic
damage there's moot's face all spinning by all at the same time the
ball itself sucks into like a tight like grapefruit side and then as
Demogorgon comes back with the hideous thud and scream the ball itself explodes lights go
everywhere portal waivers and it explodes everybody make a dexterity
great with advantage I'll tell you why later okay okay everybody regardless of
your role is like blasted away from this the center sphere I believe it was
just two of you that rolled real real bad you're gonna take 16 bludgeoning
damage as you're blown to the sides but then all of these orbs explode out and
begin spinning back around the room the portal is closed there's a rubble
point in the center of this throne room now where the portal once was
everything around you quiets considerably because you can no longer
hear the battle below you and we see all of you as being encircled by your
own individual aura there's these lights that are now around you you
all pick yourselves up and the readied actions can go you're going to add 20
additional radiant damage to every hit you roll with advantage so we'll start
with night that was the order of which we held actions night hunter is
feeling energized and kind of weird they decide to hack at the legs of
roll down Gorgon so let me see here there's 18 plus 13 I think it hit yep
19 plus 13 I think it hits 15 plus 13 I think it hits okay so all three of them
hit 35 damage plus plus 60 plus 60 I got all right three attacks with the
9 plus 12 21 that's a no right that's with advantage yeah it is okay better
12 plus 12 yeah there we go we finally have a hit I don't know what it's
resistant to but acid was working well before so let's go with acid so so
that's 20 points of acid and then the 20 radiant on top of it I guess and
there's one more attack okay double 18s on that one plus 12 so and that
one is 19 acid plus the 20 radiant okay glim okay I'm gonna attack twice
with the purple longsword Wow that was really bad because it's 21 isn't it so
that was a 19 was my best roll but that's but I just I'm gonna try again
it's better because it's 25 there you go 15 slashing plus 23 radiant I added
my extra radiant to that 20 okay thea thea is going to let loose moonbeam at
what level seventh level okay so they need to make a Constitution saving
throw they don't oh they don't they don't oh okay my silvery beam of
light blasts down upon this poor sucker 35 that's 20 yep and then she is also
going to take her longbow out and shoot an arrow at it just because she
can yes all right that's a 25 give me damage nice and it's gonna be seven
damage plus 20 yep lepsinki final held action I like this perfect I'm gonna
eldritch blast with four beams right at my guy so that is 32 damage plus that
20 rate there's a 20 for each be a question good question Kyle it is a 20
okay explosion lights everything swirling and Demogorgon comes back and
is attacked by this onslaught of God powered mayhem I guess it's probably a
good description everybody unleashing absolutely everything they have down into
him and as this moonbeam and all of these attacks are hitting him he's
like shriveling up on the spot there is nothing that is left from him he's
like this this what's the you know like the creatures in Little Mermaid
the seaweed creatures that everybody gets sucked down into yep that's what
looks like now was this huge gargantuan hulking creature now this little big
bug-eyed nothing down in the center who wants to step on oh could it be
racks everybody allows racks through and just stomps down on top the room is
entirely quiet and you're all looking at each other moot you were blasted
through the air but then suspended in place and you come down and you meet
the group and all of a sudden you are these lights begin to spin around you
quicker again and they're spinning in this this swirling vortex and
everything's becoming blurry around you and you're all being lifted up and
there is you look and you see Bort and Flint's body also lifting up in
place and you're all being propelled upward and there's this this light above
you and there's this snap you're all standing in this white room there's a
basin in the center of this room that's rippling with water and you see
like streams of light rushing through them
the you look over and you see Flint's body lying on the ground
scaleless but standing behind that body is this glowing aura of Flint as
you knew him
Dumbgeons and Dragons season 2 episode 154 starring Amy More as Thea, Night
Hunter and Sully, Karla Maxted as Lipsinki and Glim, Tom Laird as Moot
with Kyle Claset as Vorunax, Kristen Flemmons as a Goth, Godloss Cthulhu
Alavi and Russ More as your dungeon master, dialogue editing by Karla Maxted
and sound design by Russ More. This episode featured music from Epidemic
Sound and sound effects from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas and
a huge thank you to our supporting producers Gabriel Lynch, Jessica
Babyok, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Christian Brown, Craig Zeiss, Old
School Gamer D, Perry Matey, Aungurong Kiersen, Kayla Littlejohn, Nathaniel
Teeter and Destiny. Do you like the stories that we're telling? Season 2 only
has one more episode but that means that season 3 is right around the
corner so we're very excited for the next episode the finale of season 2
coming very soon. How can you support us going into season 3? Join us at
Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast while you wait for season
3 which shouldn't take too long to get to new episodes after we wrap up
season 2 there's a whole slew of bonus content including our Patreon
exclusive game the adventures of DM by Tom, Amy, Karla and I have a whole lot
of fun Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast we hope to see you over there we
can't wait for you to hear the finale for season 2 and don't forget to get
your questions in. If you're a patron we'll be recording our Q&A episode at
our next Goo Kang which is October 3rd 2023. Sign up today to join us
but if you can't do that submit your questions and we'll answer them for that
episode. Link is in the description where you can send them in. All right
that's it for me thank you so much for being here with us we hope you
have a great week we'll talk to you soon everything that we're working
towards. I'm just really waiting for the other shoe to drop because it
seemed like things went knock all the wood pretty good last time so what kind
of mean thing is Russ planning? That's my concern. Like my characters aren't even mostly dead.
Exactly. Not even mostly dead. This portion of it might get cut out
but I was talking to Tom after the game last week and he was just you
know I guess I was like I'm super nervous on how that went and then I
have to remind myself that we've been playing this battle this battle since
the middle of September. That's true. It was like it seemed like it was just
over too quickly but it's not. It's not. Carla are you sacred oath? Yes. Same. What's up?
Two sides of the same coin here we got orcas on one side, bottom left on the other.
You can't build pAlydins two different ways. So six battle episodes with orcas
and then one goofy dumb demogorgon episode to wrap it all up it's great
I love it. Yep. Anything else you want to do Sully? No. Sully really at
level 19 and still only has one attack. I mean usually rogues use their sneak
attack but you opted against that every time. I forget that I haven't. Also okay the whole
thing about sneak attack is this is okay listeners this is why I don't use it
because in Amy's brain she thinks in order to sneak up on something they
need to not see you and every time we are in battle it's like boom there's a
demogorgon in front of you and I'm just not gonna be like um like it can see
me I don't the mechanics of it I get because it's like it's just the thing
that happens but in Amy's story brain it sure you can't you're just so
sneaky that's already looking at you. You're in the shadows and you also
have people distracting it at the same time. That's why I've never in it
I never even think to use it. Well that's that's your that's your your
good one so you know for next time. I haven't been using my good one. Moot back to you. All right are
these orbs like within reach? Yeah yeah yeah if you want to so the portal
will say is like two and a half feet across the balls themselves are
spinning like just above it like they're almost making a sphere in and of
themselves as they're spinning in this matrix above them mm-hmm yeah I mean
you'd have to maybe propel yourself or get some get some upsies but you could
reach them if somebody like assisted you in some way. But I mean is
reaching them what I want to do is that gonna disrupt what's going on?
That was your that was your go-to that was like you that was the
first thing you thought of so you know trust your gut. What about your
what about your crab claw? I haven't seen the crab claw in a while. Don't touch it with your hand hand. It's like permanently attached to me
but yeah I could I could I could send it on its way mm-hmm mm-hmm just the
thought mm-hmm no no pressure I don't know if it's a good thing to hold
those. I mean yeah I don't know either like is that portal just gonna open right back up?
Right? Okay just looking through my spell list. Oh shit I do have
portal closed. Damn it! Son of a bitch! Turns out it's 6th level. It's 9th level in everything. It was a cantrip! God!
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production