previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Oh, you're home.
Hi, Arvid.
Hey, Adog.
You brought an interesting friend with you.
Oh, yeah, this is, uh, this is Lex.
Hi, I'm Lex, and I...
It's, I think the pleasure is all mine.
The energy stops flowing, and you feel yourself crumple to the ground.
Perseus rushes to you.
You know, this is my very best friend in the whole world, Perseus.
And I just kind of, like, stroke his back and say, like, it's okay, it's okay, I'm okay.
Lay with Perseus and this man in the alleyway for quite a while, until you
hear footsteps walking up the alleyway.
You look to the side and you see Arvid, and he picks you up and walks back with you to
his office.
We'll, um, get you cleaned up here.
I told you I'd see you later.
That you did.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We're a D&D 5th edition actual play podcast, and I'm your dungeon master, Russ More.
With me today is Carla Maxted.
That is me.
Also with me, Tom Laird.
C'est moi.
And joining us for no particular reason taking the spot of Amy tonight is Rev from
The Crit Show.
I'm lost and wandered into the room.
Welcome, Rev.
We thought we'd take advantage of him being lost.
This is a comfy seat next to us, though, I have to admit.
Isn't it?
Yeah.
She gets the better seat, so you're welcome.
I mean, you didn't have to put on Amy's pink robe, but it looks great.
You know, if it's soft like this, I just, I can't resist.
That's fair.
Where we have lots of fun and do lots of cool things is over on Patreon.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast, where after this episode today and after every
episode, we talk about the episode that we just played in a dungeon's downtime.
And that's for patrons at $5 up.
But also when you're a patron, you get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Matthew dash undead.
Thank you, Matthew.
Matthew, what a spooky name you have, right?
It starts out so normal or what a condition.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, you're right.
Thank you, Matthew.
You can find out more at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And now, oh, fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
We find our characters.
I guess we should say that we're doing something special here today.
Last time we saw our first character, Lex Lexington, they were not so good off in an
alleyway being carried back to Arvid's office to be fixed back up.
We joined back with Lex and Arvid, probably a couple of weeks later,
after some some good R&R, some health recovered.
I guess I need to know, am I pretty healthy again?
I would say the state of Lex is not 100% because of your condition of, you know,
dealing out health, you lose health.
So I'd say you're probably around 50% of total Lex health.
Perfect.
Until which point you're cured.
But who knows if that'll happen.
It's been a couple of weeks, so I'm feeling better.
I'm really wondering, like, what the vibe is with Arvid and Lex because there was
some real tension, there was some real flirty energy between the two of them.
The door bursts open.
Arvid rushes in carrying a plate of fine baked goods.
There's a lemon curd, a spring roll, and a bunch of other things.
A sprinkle of icing sugar and says, oh, um, I brought you some breakfast.
Thought you might be famished.
Oh, Arvid, I am famished.
Thank you.
You remembered my favorite lemon curd treat.
You're so thoughtful.
Oh, just stop.
Well, you enjoy.
We do have to discuss future plans, though.
Oh, you did say don't, don't put the cart before the horse, my dear.
We, what I was more talking about was your adventure, your journey, your je ne sais quoi,
your need to spread your wings and soar to the mountains as you so described it the other night.
It's very poetical language.
Sounds more like something you would say, Arvid.
But, um, yeah, so not our future plans.
But my future plans to return to the Baldrick Mountains, find my creator,
deal with him in some sort of way, and then get on with my life.
In, in a roundabout succinct sort of way.
Yes, that is exactly what I was saying.
I, of course, would put a little more color, a little more flair to it, but that is fine.
Um, so that said, it is a long and perilous journey.
Donnie, the two of us could make it, but perhaps you, you have others
that we could invite.
Well, my friends Flint and Thea, I don't want to ask them.
We've already said our goodbyes.
They're looking for their, their dragon, Donnie, and it just wouldn't be right.
I don't know many others.
I have Perseus, of course.
I'm not sure he is the best rat in the world, but not sure how good he is in a fight.
Um, and I did, I met someone on my travels with Flint and Thea.
She was, well, I mean, she's the one that gave me my name.
So I feel like we have a, a very special bond.
She was very wise and she did give me a way to communicate with her.
So I suppose I could ask.
Well, which way did she give to communicate with you?
She gave me this and then I rummage in my stuff and pull out a rock.
She called it a sending note.
So if I crush this, I don't know if I then speak to her or I summon her or
the details are a little hazy.
I did almost die just two weeks ago.
It's, uh, from the sounds of it, it's likely a message that you can send to, send to her.
So you would just have to tell her where to meet us, perhaps along the road
to the Paltryck Mountains.
So you're going to come with me then?
I thought that I was the first one being that I said we too could make the journey, but
if you did not want me.
I want nothing more than for you to come with me while I literally meet my maker.
All right.
Well, you know what?
But you work on your message.
You send your message and send Perseus here with me.
See what I can cook up.
Hey, how attached are you to the fact of Perseus being a rat?
Oh, well, huh.
What an interesting question you ask.
I love Perseus for his kindness and loyalty.
Um, I don't think his being a rat is of particular importance.
Great.
Enough said.
And he scoops up the rat and runs out of the room.
So I'll leave you to craft your sending, your sending message.
However you want to do that.
Which message is sent to Margaret?
Margaret, my name is Lex.
We met in the Misty Forest.
You named me.
Maybe you remember.
I'm going on an adventure to find my creator.
And if you're not busy, it would be great if you could come.
Meet me in Silvery Moon in one week.
XO, Lex.
You crush the stone and your message is sent to Margaret.
Who is where at this moment?
Right now she is outside pulling her mace out of a werewolf.
Margaret's such a badass.
So as you pull the bones crunch, the flesh and blood fly,
this message as if from nowhere enters your mind that you are needed in Silvery Moon.
Oh, hello.
Oh, interesting.
Well, I could go for a little walkabout.
We see Margaret in her Betty White fashion.
Tidy everything up, put away her weapons and head out on the road to Silvery Moon.
We cut through a series of montage-y type things.
We pick it back up with Arvid in his lab.
There's beakers bubbling.
There's fires going.
There's incense burning throughout.
Perseus the rat is in a confinement of sorts
and he's casting a very nondescript spell.
He waves his hands, smoke billows up and out
and before us we see a halfling in the place of Perseus.
Tom, if you could describe your character.
He is a kind of an olive-toned skin color halfling.
He's, you know, a little bit on the tall side for a halfling, but not super-duper.
He has like a long-ass ponytail in the back and a bit of a bald top of his head.
So he's really rocking like that aging hippie look.
We see Arvid standing before Perseus, just clapping his hands to himself as the probably confused
once-was-rat-now-halfling is getting used to his new body, I presume.
At that moment, Lex enters the room.
Hey, um, Arvid, I was just wondering if there was any more of a-
I did it!
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't realize you had company.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. This is your friend. This is your rat.
This is Perseus.
Perseus!
Lex, it's me, Perseus!
Perseus?
Yeah, it's me!
He made me into a person.
I did it!
Arvid!
Oh, Perseus!
I don't even...
How?
Can you probably can't even explain?
I have no idea.
Magic.
We live in a world of magic and fantasy.
We can do whatever we wish.
He just keeps saying magic over and over, so I guess we have to believe him.
That's all I know about magic, so sounds right to me.
How do you...
How do you feel?
Do you feel...
Okay?
I feel really tall.
You are so much taller than you were before.
I mean, he's still probably like half my height.
Things that looked really big before now look really small, and I'm here for it.
That's...
I'm so happy.
Could I...
Can I hug you?
Is that okay?
I'm so happy to be able to talk to you.
I mean, I've always talked to you, but to have you be able to talk back is really new
and wonderful.
Yeah, I mean, bring it in, big guy.
So I crouch over and give him a big hug.
Oh, it's like bringing family together.
This is just so exciting.
We are like family.
Perseus is my very best friend in the whole world.
Yeah, I mean, we were together a long time in rat years, so I don't know how long it
was in normal years, but it's a long time.
Now, one thing we must discuss here, Perseus, as he hands you clothes to put on...
Oh, thank you, thank you.
...is I've imbued you with some magics, and we'll discuss that on the road.
Don't worry about it, totally fine.
Might have had to make a pact with a fiend.
On our way!
That's what I mean.
We cut to the three of them on the road at the gates of Silvery Moon as we see the silhouette
of one Margaret Broadcloak standing there waiting, unknown how fast she ran.
It's that aged speed walking.
It is.
It's all those malls she walks around.
She's just got this really good technique, and she just really motors.
But you see Margaret standing ahead of you at the gates of Silvery Moon.
She came, Arvid, she came.
Margaret!
Lexington, how are you?
Well, it's been a busy few weeks.
We made it to Waterdeep.
My friends still haven't found their dragon friend.
I died.
My friend Arvid saved me.
My best friend Arad is now a halfling.
Well, that's me.
He means me.
Oh.
Yes, that's definitely a busy couple of weeks then.
And yourself?
Oh, not bad.
Just roaming around, doing what I can.
I thought I'd head on over here once I got your message.
This is a beautiful city.
I haven't been here for very long, but it's got some very nice eateries if you're
interested.
Yes, I think it's a very high class city.
Is there a lot of good cheese?
You know what?
There is.
That was the first thing I passed by.
Ooh, I'd like me some of that.
We'll stop and get some.
This episode of Dumbgeons and Dragons is brought to you by Hey It's Jolly Entertainment.
You can purchase their new novel The Veiled Monarch on Amazon, Kindle, and coming
soon to audible.com or visit heyitsjolly.com to get your copy today.
Humans always tell me they think it's easier to be non-human.
They don't know what it's like to be one of us.
How difficult it is to keep your head above water.
You wouldn't happen to know anything about that, would you?
Faulkner looked back over his shoulder.
Not a clue.
I believe you have a mole.
Vince flew at Faulkner, grabbing his shirt collar.
Yes, I'm angry.
I love them.
You love them too.
Constance was like a sister to you.
You call Robert your nephew.
Leo and I both struggled against Faulkner and Brian.
Our minds and emotions were in such a state that we didn't know what we were doing.
All we could think of was getting back inside that room and killing Jacob Stewart.
Dad, Brian, please!
Get The Veiled Monarch on Amazon, Kindle, and coming soon to audible.com or visit
heyitsjolly.com to get your copy.
Margaret, I'm so happy you came.
Thank you so much.
It's hard to explain in just this brief note, but I was created in the Baldrick Mountains,
I escaped, and now I want to go find the man that created me.
For some answers.
And maybe some vengeance?
Oh.
And cheese.
Well, I can definitely get behind the vengeance idea.
Wow, so you were created by someone.
Yes, so I'm usually quite tight-lipped about this, or I have been, because I do have
a bit of a monstrous appearance and people are quite frightened of me, often.
But my friend Arvid here, in the last couple weeks, we've been talking a bit
and he's helped me see that, you know, I can open up to people a little bit more.
So, the short answer is that I'm an amalgamation of the parts of other human and humanoid creatures,
and then I somehow got brought back to life as me, but with all of these various
components.
Interesting.
That's why I didn't know what my name was when we met, or I had that long list
of names.
Oh, that list was really long.
Well, before we set out, I do want to say that that's a whole lot of information to
take in, and I've spent a good chunk of my life hunting down monsters.
And I know I've only known you for a little while, Lex, but I saw how you defended
those people in the forest.
So, when we go out on this adventure, whatever it is that you learn, just
remember that you are who you've become, not whatever this person made you as.
I've hunted monsters and you're not one.
I think Lex is just like frozen.
This is like the nicest thing anyone's ever said to him.
Maybe if his tear ducts are attached, maybe a single tear comes down his face.
I don't know.
Yes, I made sure to reattach those after.
Arvid, you're so thoughtful.
You're so thoughtful.
Thank you, Margaret.
That really means a lot to me.
I was a little afraid of what I was going to discover about myself.
Yes, it could be a lot, but it doesn't change what you've done since you've left.
But on the other hand, it doesn't change the things we may do to this person if
we find them.
That can be kind of monstrous.
So to the cheese shop?
Oh, yes, please.
We cut through another series of montage scenes.
Tom, where is the first one that we see on this road towards the Baldrick Mountains?
We are crossing over a like a single file rope bridge over a river.
The river is crashing below and you're swaying back and forth.
There are apes, actual apes, not the weird baboon like apes that you fought
previously with Margaret, kind of standing, staring at you.
Some of them throwing small stones out towards you on the bridge, as if taunting
you and perhaps hoping that you fall into the water and you make it across
safely.
Rev, what's the next scene we see?
The next scene is everyone at a campfire and Perseus holding a
weapon and Lex and Margaret trying to teach him how to use it.
So I don't grab the pointy end.
Yes.
Does this feel natural to you?
Does this feel like what you want to handle or?
I mean, I like the size of it.
It fits nicely in my hand, so that's good.
Well, that's a start.
OK, so I'm going to come and get you out of the way.
So I'm going to come for you.
Do you feel ready?
Is it another hug?
No, we're going to do we're going to try some of the moves we've been talking
about.
OK, the moves.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
OK, I'm ready.
Here I come and I sort of like parry with a with a small rapier and just
see if he's how he's handling his weapon.
So, Lex, you're coming at Perseus.
Perseus is defending himself.
Yeah, that's that's sorry.
That's how the scene is playing out.
Yes.
Yeah.
OK, Lex attack role.
Perseus.
It's probably a dexterity check.
OK.
I mean, I'm coming in pretty soft because, you know, with with advantage.
Perseus.
OK.
I will go with the first one was much better.
OK, what do you get 14 for me?
And I'm doing a straight attack role, straight attack role 22.
OK, OK, describe to me how you take down or subdue the unawares Perseus.
Well, I feel like your kill.
How do you feel like I'm coming in
with my weapon and I see like I can tell that he is totally not
ready for this attack.
The training isn't going as well as I thought, maybe.
So I try and kind of pull it back, but then kind of trip and then land on him.
So I don't actually hit him with my weapon so much as my huge body
just lands on his small one.
Arvid sees this from across the campfire.
He's like, I told you that he's not going to be great with weapons.
That thing I mentioned about the dark magics and the fiend and stuff.
Yeah, let's let's maybe work on that.
Just try and think of something to conjure up there, Perseus.
OK, do you have any suggestions?
Oh, gosh, I don't know.
I haven't looked at your spells list.
It's a little inside baseball there.
I mean, if it helps, if you want to keep working with that
that sword, just think of it like a hug.
But then on the on the last part of the hug, just put the blade in their back.
That's right. Yes, do that.
But also maybe.
Lex, you come at Perseus again,
but this time, Perseus, instead of trying to touch, stand your ground
and say, just focus on pushing Lex away.
OK. OK, ready?
And then maybe say a word with it, something that's just whatever moves you.
OK, here it comes, buddy, here I come.
Oh, that was much gentler.
It's a 14.
I say, well, don't hurt me.
And I throw a beam of crackling energy towards Lex.
I missed, but I'm sure I missed it was 11, but I threw it anyway.
Did you do Eldritch Blast? Yeah, yeah, perfect.
So, I mean, what's your AC there, Tom? Oh, 14.
Meets and beats.
So, again, Lex comes in, but this crackling beam of energy
shoots out and strikes into a tree as Lex dodges around it
and then subdues you again.
Well, that was that was closer.
I was thinking more of like
I don't know, stunning them, but that's cool, too.
We'll work on it on the way.
I thought that was amazing.
How did you do that?
Could you do that while you were a rat?
I don't I don't think so.
Arvid, was that in me all along?
I said, yes, it was inside of you.
Oh, cool. Yeah, it just held within your rat form,
released by a dark one and never to be talked about
in this way again for a little while.
OK, moving on.
Carla, what's the next scene we see?
Maybe we are coming through like a very small village, so.
A provincial sort of town that maybe is a bit unaccustomed
to our ragtag kind of crew.
Or maybe not, I don't know their lives.
You've entered the the tiny village of Hammersforth.
And you're nearing the end of your journey.
You're aiming to get in the vicinity of the Baldrick Mountains.
And you're getting odd looks as you pass through.
You are, for lack of a better term, a unique adventuring group.
What with a Frankensteinish monster, a small halfling,
an old lady and Arvid, who need not describe himself.
He's just an otherworldly creature.
Otherworldly creature.
He's he's glancing at people as he walks by and says,
is he doing a good job here?
Never heard of this city before.
But am I doing good speaking with the regular folk?
Yes, Margaret, I don't feel like any of the rest of us
are qualified to answer that question.
He was a rat and I'm a creation, so.
What's a regular folk?
Exactly, exactly, my good friend.
Let's see if they will give us food and board for saving their village.
Do we need to do that?
You said that with a question mark.
Did we? Are we pretending?
Are we going to go? Do we have to go do something now?
No, I've got I've got money.
Oh, I mean, sure, we could spend money.
We could go out and adventure.
I think it might do
Perseus some good to get a few more blasts off before we get to the mountain.
You go and Arvid seems he seems OK with this.
And then you ask around the village and there is a
they do have a problem off and to the east.
Somebody roll me a D 100 presentile dice.
OK. 100.
Seriously? Yeah.
So one in two zeros.
This becomes the adventure today now, because
I mean, usually what you put at 100 doesn't know.
That's fine.
Usually what you put at 100, you'd never expect it to actually come to.
No, it's this is the this is two crazy rolls.
Makes no sense.
Sorry, guys, I'm going to be the Amy Roller tonight after that.
One good, amazing.
What creature are we going to defend Hammersmith from or Hammersforth from?
Used up all my mojo.
They tell you of a tale of a ghost haunting this town.
And they say
that the rumor is that it lives up in the coal mine
not too far from Hammersforth and frequently comes down and
well, not only terrifies villagers, but does so much
so that it it kills them, stops them in their tracks.
And it does this every third full moon, which happens to be tomorrow.
I have an idea. OK.
Because we must be near the Baldrick Mountains
or probably in the foothills or near the base of the absolutely.
What if we go and talk to the ghost?
OK. The one that scares people to death.
OK, perfect. I have an idea.
I'd like to. I feel a sort of kinship hearing about this ghost,
and I want to speak to him, but I understand
that he does frighten people to death.
So perhaps I should just go or I don't want to force you to do this.
But I feel like I might be able to help resolve this.
I think we should go with you, perhaps if we go today
before the full moon. I mean, you're right.
Sometimes monsters, creatures of the night.
They've got a curse.
They've got a connection here that they can't get rid of.
So it may be something that you can figure out and help with,
as opposed to us trying to destroy it.
Anywhere you go, Lex, I'm right there with you.
I mean, you are the reason that we're here.
So if we let you wander off by yourself to get yourself killed.
Well, we can just all go home.
But that would not be very satisfying.
I'd be super sad, too.
That too, very sad, because we have become so dear to each other.
Oh, that reminds me.
Do you happen to know the name of your creator just in case
something does happen to you?
I assume the rest of us would sure love to take vengeance for you.
I don't. I left in.
A hurry, let's say, so I know I can make my way back,
but I wasn't really in my right mind and able to figure out
who he was.
I'm hoping I can just find sort of reverse
the way I left and get back to where where he was.
No, that's fair.
The four of you head off to the coal mine, and it's a spooky coal mine.
There are cobwebs and overgrown.
It looks like it hasn't been hasn't been utilized in quite some time.
But you find your way through the overgrown path
to the mouth of the coal mine and you hear like a soft, breathy
emanating deep from within.
Granger, is that you?
Welcome to the middle.
Yeah. Yeah.
And now, Amy, with the breakdown.
We're here in the middle, and I want you to know that I love you so much.
Please don't ever go.
Wiggy wiggy.
That was really good.
Off the cuff, I swear to God.
There have been many times
we have one of us has attempted to rap in the middle.
And it's gone very bad.
And it's rhymed every time.
It hasn't gone great before.
And at that time, it rhymed and it was very throwbacky.
And it was from the heart, which I appreciated.
It was from the heart.
It was love motivated.
I like clean raps.
That's right. Will Smith.
It was a Will Smith rap for you.
I think it was so full of love because you're not in this episode
so that you have to inject yourself so immensely into this part.
Yes. Just to make it feel like you were there.
Was it weird listening without the dulcest tones of my voice in there?
Everybody's going to say yes.
But we did have Rev.
I mean, yes.
That's true. Rev was back as Margaret.
Rev is amazing.
So make sure you go listen to Rev, the Crit Show podcast.
He's great. They're great.
Tom and I had a chance to play with more of their crew.
They're all fantastic.
Yeah, it was super fun.
If you go support them on Patreon
or if you support us on Patreon, you can listen to the West,
the old West train heist that I got to run for them.
It was a heck of a good time.
Speaking of Patreon, we'd love for you to come join us over there
at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Why? Because we've got a super cool hangout coming up next week.
We do. We hang. We're so cool.
We just hang. Just hang.
We hang on the first Tuesday of every month.
We just hang.
And you know what we've been doing in those hangs,
which is different from previous hangs where we've been,
I mean, we still take questions and stuff,
but we've been playing those Jackbox games.
We sure have.
And people are loving it.
It's very fun. It's been super fun.
It is. Yeah.
It's really fun to get to play those kind of games
with people that we don't know that well
because some of our patrons have been with us for a while.
But still, we don't spend a lot of time interacting with them.
And then we get to hear them be silly
and make their own jokes and make their own jokes.
And falsely accuse me of being an alien.
How dare you?
Maybe we'll play that alien game.
It was fun. It was a fun game.
But that's what we're doing.
It's a tough time to get together with friends,
but we want to try and help facilitate some of that.
And you can come join us and be part of the community
and play some games and have an hour of just laughs
and good times and rust make terrible, terrible jokes.
Yeah, we all learned we're not good comedians,
which is- When put on the spot.
When we can kind of think it over a little bit, we're okay.
Yeah.
In the pretend you're a stand-up comedian genre?
Yeah. Not great.
Not good.
I have not yet played this game.
I've got a friend who is an actual stand-up comedian.
I'm going to go get some hot tips from him
before the next game.
Oh, there we go. Oh, do it.
I'm going to call him.
We're on your tight five.
I'm going to say, when you're doing real stand-up comedy,
they are not like, here's the start of your joke.
Finish it.
Finish it with something funny.
Finish it and make it good in 30 seconds or less.
Exactly. It's a lot of pressure.
Then you've got to hop on the phone
and we've got to play this game
until we've run through all of the questions that they have.
So I know I've got some good zingers.
Yep. But come join us.
That's what we're trying to get at Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast.
We'd love to see you there to play some games,
to have just a moment, to just take a breath
and have some fun.
So we hope that you're able to do that.
And if you're not, of course, that's totally okay.
Totally okay.
We love you anyway.
We love having you along for the ride.
My rap was still for you, patron or not.
Of course.
Link is down in the description for Patreon
and for Discord.
If you can't join us on Patreon,
please do join us on Discord
because we also have a great community there
that is open to the public.
So we'd love to see you in all the places.
But now let's get back to that episode
where Lex and Margaret and Perseus
are out doing stuff with Arvid.
It's the dream team.
Okay, bye.
Bye. Bye.
Granger, is that you?
It goes a second.
And you hear another breathy,
yes.
Granger, you don't know me, but perhaps you do.
Come here, look at me.
You feel a heavy wind kind of pushing.
You hear it first and then it's pushing
and dust is coming out.
And you see an incorporeal luminous form
coming out from the coal mine
and it rushes out and faces you.
And you see just a terrifying visage before you.
Everybody within 60 feet,
which is all of you, I do believe,
make a wisdom saving throw, please.
DC 13.
This plan's gonna go horribly awry
if I just get scared to death
and pee in my pants in front of him.
Okay.
Perseus is very much afraid.
18.
18, 17, and what did Perseus get?
12.
Okay, you didn't fail by that much, so you're okay.
I actually rolled a 13,
but I got a sweet minus one to that whiz, so.
Wah, wah.
Okay, Perseus, you are frightened for one minute,
but you did not fail by five or more,
so we don't have to deal with that.
Perfect.
Perseus, you're the only one who is afraid,
so you have to use any movement
to get away from this ghost
that you now see in front of you,
and it's right in front of you, Lex,
because you were the one talking to it
and it's kind of looking back and forth to everyone
and it says, who are you?
Granger, this will sound strange,
but part of me is you.
And I start to unbutton my shirt.
You hear from behind you, Arvid.
Oh my.
So I take my shirt off
and I am like this huge, broad-shouldered,
like strapping upper body.
Like a very strong man who spent maybe a decade or more
carrying very heavy things in a coal mine.
And you notice a small tattoo on my left shoulder
and I say, Granger, it's not my fault,
but maybe you can't rest
because part of you isn't at rest.
Part of you is with me.
And I turn to show him the tattoo,
because if it's him, then he'll know it's Bod.
He disperses into a cloud around you
and begins surrounding you and comes up
and is almost looking over your shoulder at this tattoo
and everybody else sees this as well.
Perseus, I believe you've run off
into the trees by this point.
Yeah, I know, long time.
You definitely don't see this for at least a minute.
And he, the ghost, kind of falls back down
and away from you and pauses for a moment
and then says, thank you.
And you see him kind of wisp and willow away
and there is a bit of luminescence
that follows out and it's dispersed along the ground
and then all at once, everything lifts up
and into a singular form and then explodes
in a giant light and then is sucked back in on itself.
I should say, I look pretty horrific.
So, because I'm all like sewn together
in like bits and pieces in Frankenstein-y,
so I don't know how Margaret reacts to that.
Perseus would know that's what I look like.
I'm not sure how did, I guess Arvid probably knows as well
because he was nursing me for weeks.
Yeah, I think there's a moment when the shirt comes off
and actually seeing all the connecting lines
and where all the pieces intersect.
That there's hesitation but it's not different enough
from some of the other things that she has encountered
that it really hits her in a bad way.
I think more so it's seeing it in that ghostly form
and also seeing it on you
is the thing that takes her more, I think.
The four of you, well the three of you
go find Perseus and then head back
towards Hammersforth and we see a scene of disbelief
followed by rejoice after the next day
the ghostly figure does not come to the village
and cheers echo through the valley
that surrounds this town.
And then we cut to another city.
The sign of the city says Glickfast
and this is at the base of the Baldrick Mountains.
You have seen it walking up to this town.
Lex, as you enter, you begin to get a feeling
that you remember being here.
More than just the flashing memories
that you've had of the pieces of you,
the people that make you.
But you, as in your current form, have been in this town.
My friends, we are so close.
I was here.
I came through this place
when I departed where I was created.
So, I don't know, I mean, it's possible
we could see my creator here
or at least he was very near to here.
And you hear a voice, Lex.
I mean, all of you hear it, the other three of you,
it kind of just blends in with the crowd.
But Lex, it stands out to you as a voice
that cuts through and anchors you in this place.
It's a higher pitched tone.
You look over and you see a familiar face
and you are reminded of a kobold
whose name is Marvin Dundalfoot.
He's passing between people
in this village of Glickfast saying,
hey, hey, I could get you a sweet deal.
Just look at this watch here.
I can get you any number of these things.
And as you kind of focus on him,
he has a feeling that somebody is watching him.
He looks over and he sees you
and then you see a look of panic in his eyes.
And he says,
I will, I'll say that later.
And he bolts down the street.
We've got to follow that kobold and I chase him.
Yeah, follow.
Everybody runs off chasing down the kobold
as we sweep up on the panoramic view of Glickfast
at the base of the Baldrick Mountains.
The music and sound effects from today's episode
can be found at epidemicsound.com.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Christian Brown, Creighton's Raven, Devin Michaels,
Gabriel Lynch, Jacob Madden, Joshua Dixon,
Cat Waterflame, and Stevie.
Find out more about becoming a patron
at www.epidemicsound.com.
And if you'd like to see more of our music
and sound effects from today's episode,
head over to www.epidemicsound.com.
You can find out more about becoming a patron
by visiting us at www.Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast,
where you can have access to exclusive bonus episodes,
including a Patreon exclusive podcast,
early access to our sister podcast, Facing Fate,
contributing in-game NPCs and magic items,
as well as joining us for live stream hangouts
throughout the month.
www.Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
Hope to see you over there.
Have a great week, be safe, and we'll talk soon.
Um, so message?
Ready for it?
I'm unprepared, so here it comes.
It's the best way to leave a very important,
send a very important message.
We can take it a couple times if you need to,
but you do you.
Is this thing on?
How does it work?
And that's the whole message.
Tap, tap, tap.
End of message.
Margaret?
Are we live?
Margaret.
Can you hear me?
And I start to.
Which part?
Wait, you're gonna tell us.
I'm gonna get there.
It's gonna get bad before it gets better.
I realize now when you just said which part.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.