Hey, real quick. This is the penultimate episode. We messed up the count in the last episode where we said there were more episodes coming. There's not. So there's, there's only one after this one. So, so the last, that last one was the thrultimate, thrultimate? Yes. Yeah, we've decided that was a word. Love it. That's how the thing goes. So there's only one more after today, which is, is wild and crazy. But that
that said, the way I phrased it made it sound like it's forever over. No, just this season. Just this season. And then we're going to be diving right in. Just this story arc. Yes. Yeah, I'm glad you caught that. Yeah. When it had some emails. Oh, yeah. You can send us your emails, but it's not over. I mean, the show's not over. Speaking of emails, we're looking for questions, right? For our Q&A. Yes, we need questions. Q&A in the, in the, what are they called? Summer
description. In the description, there's a link you can click. Yeah. In the episode description, just click on it and send us your questions. Cause we'll do a question episode after the next episode. That's right. Yes. And we're, we're going to record that with our patrons at our next gook hang. So maybe join us over there. Cause that'll be a lot of fun too, to have you over there. Okay. They're not going to keep you any longer. Get to the episode. Okay. Bye. Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons. I assume you're, you're screaming some sort of valiant battle cry. Can you just write
like some, or get a sound effect of a really angry, like pen scratching on paper? Okay. You charge forward. You're screaming your battle cry and Orcus turns and looks at you. He is actively trying to crawl as much as he can towards the portal right now. Yeah. He's trying. He moves as much as he can. And then like the tension in his leg where he's restrained is
holding him back. See him reach. He's trying to pull himself forward. And then everyone hears this booming voice throughout the room.
Orcus's voice booms throughout the lair and lands on one creature of Orcus's choice. And they're subject to power word kill. The buzzing sound from down the hall intensified and flying in on
backs of these winged creatures are thousands of Grancis that begin pouring out and down through the portal. You got him. Did you get him?
I mean, he doesn't have a dick anymore, so.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More. He, him also with me today is Tom Laird.
Hey, yeah, that's me. He, him. I am playing a moot who also goes with he, him.
And Carla Max dead.
She, her. That's me playing lip-synchy pip-digons and Glim. Both also she, her.
And Amy More.
Yeah, I'm here. And I can speak today. Huzzah. And I am my pro dancer she, her. And I'll be playing Thea Amastasia.
She, her. Sullivan Slyte. He, him. And Nighthunter Oglokanu. She, they.
And Kristen Flemmons.
Hi.
There she is.
Somehow unprepared. She, her. Playing Agath, Godlust, Kathua Lavi. Also she, her. And the horse Rax. He, him.
And Kyle Clasett.
Hey, hey, he, him. Gonna be playing Vorunax. Also he, him.
Lovely to have you all here. We're getting so very, I don't even, I can't even say we're getting close because who knows, who knows what's going to happen, right?
We could shenanigan for so many more episodes.
Maybe eight more years of this. Maybe not. Okay, maybe not eight years. But we are getting close and it is very exciting.
And then we just, I guess this is just a reminder that there will be a season three. We don't know what it is, but.
Could be anything.
You don't know where. You don't know when. But a season three will happen.
That's right.
It's behind you right now.
Yeah. Look out.
When you least suspect it.
It's in the backseat of your car.
You know what? We've already started it. It's in another feed. You have to go find it.
We've left Easter eggs throughout, is that what they're called? Easter eggs?
Easter eggs, yeah.
Throughout all these past episodes.
Those little things that you hide. Yep. Easter eggs.
Got it.
Shut up.
Where there are Easter eggs for, well, some characters that show up in this good season is over on Patreon.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragging cast.
Where we have a new, not a new, we have another podcast that is available for you.
It's called The Adventures Of.
It has crisscrossy applesaucey all over it.
Everybody's very confused looking, but that's what it is.
Yeah, I'm picking up what you're putting down.
We understand.
Yeah, it's all over there.
And when you're a patron, you get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Nathaniel Teeter.
Thank you.
Thanks Nathaniel.
You're awesome.
Thanks so much.
Nathaniel's a druid.
Aspiring.
I mean, I feel like he's there.
I feel like he's there too, because he's always posting like, here are the things I am growing, and druid.
His gardens are unreal.
Like we're middle of winter and eating fresh fruit out of the garden.
Yeah, it's actually kind of rude.
It's depressing and uplifting.
Both at the same time. I don't know how he manages it.
I think they call that necromancy.
Thank you Nathaniel for being a necr- I mean, a druid in our community.
And now, fuck it, let's play.
There's a stunned silence throughout the room.
This droning buzz of these massive demon creatures being ridden by Grancises.
Pouring through the portal before you.
Vorunax is helping Nighthunter back up through the portal.
Who's been holding this like, sick arm curl.
And looking really badass with nobody to see them.
Except the people down through the portal.
Waterdeep, who are being attacked, simultaneously attacked and saved by different demons.
Grancis, of course, being the savior of demons.
It's a confusing time.
I will say, Vorunax is definitely looking down, grabbing the chain with one arm.
Just looking at Nighthunter like, yeah, one arm lifting.
I can too.
She gives him a smile and a nod like, yeah, okay, you can do too.
As Nighthunter climbs back up in with Vorunax's help, we pan over to Agoth.
What does Agoth do?
I think after taking a quick pause at taking in the scene around,
Agoth is actually just going to drop the flail that is in her hand
and start like, pushing her way through all of these buzzing demons passing by
and just pushing through.
And just make her way over to Orcus's face where he has collapsed on the ground.
And I don't know, if there's any rubble, we need to like, clear that out of the way.
Maybe position him optimally.
And then just wind up and take the biggest sucker punch right into kisser.
Yeah, it takes a moment to get him propped up in a seated position.
I think we're all helping too because we want this for you.
We want to make sure that business continues as usual.
Everybody expecting Orcus to still be alive.
That kind of vibe of setting him up.
And then almost like Scott Pilgrim kind of fight scene winds up and just clocks him through.
His fist entails through his face and he blasts back and off of this chair that you have conveniently set him up on.
Might have to repeat that exercise a few times.
As you're going to set it up again, Grancis comes down off his flying demon creature and says,
So I did what we said.
I released all the Grancis.
They say they're helping.
But I also did what we said and I let go some help.
There's a loud thump from down the hall.
Oh, no.
Oh.
Oh, yeah.
So we don't actually need that.
Yeah, there was some...
I mean, your timing is great to get the other demons and get down there.
Amazing.
But we don't really need a big monster kind of backup.
Great point.
I don't know if this is one we can just turn off.
What do you know about Demogorgon?
I'm gonna do a check.
OK.
Who is that?
Nighthunter.
Nighthunter knows shit.
Me too.
Thea rolled a 19.
I rolled a nat 20.
I don't know.
Oh, plus nine.
So 29 total.
Just a 29.
Moot got an 11.
That's a 27 for me.
And Sullivan's Light actually did not do poorly.
Oh, minus one.
OK.
Yeah, OK.
So, OK.
Demogorgon, huge fiend.
Vorunax, you probably have a good sense of knowledge, being very attributed to Orcus.
Demogorgon and Orcus, not best friends.
In fact, arch enemies trying to take over the entire Abyss for a very long time,
Demogorgon was previously thought to be the step above Orcus.
But it appears that due to the fact that Demogorgon was in Orcus' prison,
Demogorgon now free, Demogorgon coming your way.
So we probably don't, I know there's a bit of a power vacuum,
and I didn't think someone would be trying to replace Orcus so quickly.
But we probably are going to need to step in here.
Either stop him here or stop the portal.
Close the portal somehow.
Is that something we can do?
Is that something you can do?
OK, I don't know.
Maybe?
I don't think I have the ability to.
No, I definitely, I have no portal magic, but...
I have like zero magic whatsoever, so...
Also, everybody else sees like the Million Grandsises, right?
Yes, yes.
There are old guys flying everywhere, what the hell's going on?
I don't think I can close that portal.
Yeah, no, I can open portals, and sometimes they close.
This is...I think...
I think we're stuck with the portal, everybody.
OK, cool, cool, cool.
OK.
OK, so what if we're just like, hey, Demogorgon, this is your area now.
Don't go through this portal, and you can keep this space,
because you are the one, the king now.
Do you think if we just rope it off, he'll respect the rope?
Is it like a red velvet rope?
I was going to say, if we put a red velvet rope, I mean, people are usually pretty...
Nobody crosses a red velvet room, not even here.
Oh, wow, I didn't know that was...I guess that's universal.
We take our cues very seriously.
The entire room shakes on this next thump.
We have no plan!
There's a half second, and then the door to Orcus' throne room,
the wall around it just is shrouded in shadow,
and then the entire wall bursts open and towards you.
Everybody make a dexterity saving throw.
OK, if you got below a 12,
you get 13 bludgeoning damage as rubble flies forth towards you.
You turn and you look, and you see this two-headed, gargantuan fiend,
skeletal jackal maws, one a jackal, one like this monkey.
It's got this long snake-like tail with pincers and barbs on it,
and its hands are tentacles,
like two tentacles coming off of each arm,
and it has these giant reptilian feet as it comes in.
I would just like to also say that when Night Hunter was pulled back up by Vorunax,
they are for sure just wrapping, they've just wrapped the chain around their hand,
because you don't want to waste that, I'm not going to let that fall into the real world.
What if it falls through the portal and hits someone,
an innocent person, at the bottom on the other side?
I don't know if Night Hunter's worried about that.
Casualties, it happens.
Okay, so everybody was kind of just chatting altogether,
so we're all assuming that we're going to start in a more central location.
Yes.
That's why we're not afeard.
Yeah, because that's why you're not afeard.
You're all clustered around Glim, the might.
Yeah, and also we had all just been moving Orcus' corpse around.
That's true.
Oh, that was a weird, yeah, that's kind of a like,
we're all going to talk about that later.
We're going to have some group therapy.
The way you puppeted him, Vorunax, was really awkward,
and I just think we should have said something at the time.
Would I guess I could have been able to just grab a souvenir
before the Demogorgon sounds like a tooth or something?
Sure, yeah.
You want an Orcus tooth?
I want a tooth, yeah.
Kyle, describe Orcus' teeth,
having been like prime on the benefits package for the Underdark.
Well, also, he got almost eaten.
True.
That's true, yeah.
I had some first-hand experience.
Well, one hand, you know.
Anyway, Orcus' teeth are surprisingly, they're large,
but they're like blunt.
It's one of those things where, like, it's not, they're not sharp,
but they're going to pierce you regardless,
and it's going to be more like a serrated kind of experience.
So yeah, like a large, like, blunt, spiky serration.
Okay, so Demogorgon's up first,
and he's going to swing his tentacles through the crowd.
He gets two tentacle attacks.
One is going to be towards Vorunax,
whom he probably recognizes just based on contextual clues.
Yeah, one's going to be towards Glim.
Okay, the one towards Vorunax is going to be a 32.
Probably not.
Yeah, hits.
The one towards Glim is going to be a 21.
Yep, that'll do it.
Oh, but we are very close together,
so I think I will, I cannot help a 32,
but I will use a warding maneuver for Glim.
So, I'm pretty sure you can see
with him five feet hit by an attack roll,
one D8 and add the number to your AC.
Yes, posted note.
Oh, bad roll, but a 22, so it'll work.
All right.
Okay, so Vorunax, you're going to take a 28 force damage,
and if the target is a creature,
I think you're a creature,
you must succeed on a DC 23 constitution saving throw.
Wow.
I mean, isn't everything in a creature in this game?
Basically, I mean, is it alive?
Yeah.
I think that's what it is.
23, 23.
Yeah, it happened, and that's 12.
Okay, cool, cool, cool.
So, your hit point maximum is reduced
by the amount equal to the damage taken.
Which is 28.
Which is 28, and happens until you finish a long rest.
The target dies if its hit point maximum is reduced to zero.
Holy shit.
What?
Nice knowing y'all.
No, I'll be good, I'll be all right.
It's if the maximum is reduced to zero.
So, there's like two levels you're playing with.
You're playing with, you know, you're active,
and then also your maximum is catching up behind you.
Yeah.
Right.
Okay.
Those two tentacle attacks happen,
and he lets out this grotesque scream into the room.
It's Grancis's turn.
Catnap.
He turns at you and he says,
it's time for the catnap.
No.
Yes.
Yes, Grancis, now is the time.
Look, look, look.
If not now, then when?
He's probably a little buffed for a catnap,
but we can try.
We can try anything.
There's a thousand of you guys.
There's a thousand of us.
We can all catnap.
But no, what I was going to say is,
if we kill him here, he just goes back home.
So, that gets him out of here if we can kill him.
And Orcus was like doing things to him down there,
like hurting him.
Not like weird things.
Thea, get your mind out of the gutter.
I wasn't thinking weird things.
It was like trying to make him weaker like the gods,
and he was probably going to try and take his power.
So, he's probably not full strength.
So, what I'm saying is,
if we just hit him as hard as we can,
as quickly as we can,
maybe he'll have a catnap.
I'm going to cast catnap.
Are you catnapping him?
Are you not catnapping him?
I'm very confused on the subject.
Why do we allow him to monologue?
I don't know.
You all just kind of let it happen.
He runs the game.
I can't tell him to shut up.
I'm married to him.
I think it's my right.
He just keeps talking.
You make a calling in chest.
I don't know.
Is this even going to fucking work?
Up to three willing creatures.
Nope.
If the target remains unconscious.
No.
So, that's not going to work.
How about we cast fireball?
Yeah.
That's probably better.
Oh, I enjoy the fire.
Bob may follow you depending on how this works out.
Okay.
Let's cast it high.
You know, go big or go home.
I think it's go big or die.
That is relevant.
So, he has to make a dex 19 saving throw.
Oh, that's a four on the die.
Let's see how dexterous.
I mean, surely he's not a plus 15.
Plus 10.
So, that's a 14.
So, he still misses it.
So, that's 14 D6.
Oh, yeah.
As this fireball erupts.
Can you roll them one at a time, please?
Google's going to roll.
Or seven.
Oh, no.
Three ones.
That's okay.
47 fire damage.
This massive ball erupts from Grancis
and out towards Demogorgon
and explodes in this fiery blaze around him.
You smell it before you see it
as the smoke begins to clear,
like the flesh blistering on his chest.
And it is Night Hunter's turn.
Well, old guy has some moves.
Handsome advice.
I think that is why we let you talk.
Night Hunter is going to grab corpse grinder
and try to grind some corpse.
That is a 24.
Yes, that will hit.
Ooh, 17.
Well, they're going to do it again.
Just going to keep hacking.
Ooh, that one's 21.
Does not hit.
No, does not hit.
Oh, she's mad.
I'm on a rage.
Fucking rage.
She's really mad that that last one didn't hit.
And that's a nat one.
I got too mad, you guys.
Love it.
Got too mad.
You've crossed over.
You hit him once,
and his tail swings around on the second one.
And that's a natural 20 plus 17.
Doesn't matter.
It's going to hit you for 40 bludgeoning damage
plus 22 necrotic damage.
OK.
So that's 40 plus 22 is 62 total damage.
All right.
That's OK.
I'm fine.
But I am going to do.
I'm going to.
I don't know.
I don't know how else to say it.
I'm going to do stones endurance.
I'm going to do it.
And reduce damage dealt by 1d12 plus 7.
To a goth.
I'm just going to look at the group.
So we are not talking then.
She like almost started pulling some hemp and rope out of the bag.
Puts that back in.
Yeah, no, I think we're just hitting.
I don't think he speaks the language of love.
No, no.
My god.
I wasn't even thinking about it.
Not even once.
Not even with the tentacle arms.
You look like you're into some freaky shit.
The look on the face is just pure like that.
We weren't afraid.
You didn't ask for this.
Demogorgon.
Not afraid.
Very afraid of this.
I will scoop the flail back up.
A goth is now going to go up there with Night Hunter.
And start wailing on it.
Perfect.
That is not amazing.
That is.
Oh, but it is a plus 12.
So that is still an 18.
18 does not hit.
Damn it.
All right.
Let's try again.
Three attacks.
Oh my god.
20.
That doesn't hit.
No.
Final attack.
Oh my god.
A three.
Encouragement.
I got a six and eight and a three.
Three.
Three attacks.
None of them hit.
I have a plus 12 on this weapon.
You're just tired from, you know, kicking Orcus's ass.
18.
I got a lot of propping him up with different, with different like hats and stuff.
Taking pictures.
The novelty sunglasses.
Yeah.
It's one minute duration.
Okay.
So yeah, you would have to.
I'll recast it because why the fuck not.
Does it get an attack right away?
It does.
So let's do that.
You have this.
Okay.
It's a 19.
So.
Does my you have this do anything?
It is motivational.
Oh, jeez.
If you are a bard.
That's right.
I guess so.
One, one character class we don't have.
A goth not feeling great, but.
Demogorgon is going to look down at you.
Down his nose.
Look down upon you.
Make a wisdom saving throw, please.
As he gazes forth upon you.
Okay.
This judgementalize.
I'm going to reroll that one.
Let's get a real dice out here.
Come on, buddy.
Okay.
Much better.
That's a 17 plus nine.
So 26.
There we go.
Okay.
That's good.
You have succeeded against his gaze ability.
Okay.
I don't know what it would have done, but you know it wouldn't have been great.
But you feel like this, this, this impending sense of doom that washes over you as he
looks down at you.
And it's more that you, I mean, you moved out of the frighten, frighten zone, but
we've kind of passed that.
So it's not quite frightening.
Like something bad would happen.
Let's just leave it there.
Let's just move on.
Great.
Moving on.
Flame of Kins.
Flame of Kins is stirred.
Okay.
That looked really cool.
Way to go with that.
Wow.
It's not really a time for sarcasm.
Seems kind of rude.
Yeah.
No, that's fair.
I apologize.
Um, I'm going to, uh, I'm tend to put them in a mental.
I can dominate monster.
Holy shit guys.
It's not even in a sexual way.
Isn't it?
Isn't it always?
It's a closed demogorgon's thing so he can't save anymore.
Okay.
How wise is he?
Hmm.
I'm pretty wise.
That's a 24 against a 19.
Well shit.
Um, okay.
I gazed back at him and it doesn't do anything.
Is it you dominated him right now?
Are you doing it?
Look at it.
Yeah.
I love Flamikin's meta knowledge.
Uh, does he get half damage during this time?
No.
Does he get a little bit, does he feel a little something from the eye contact though?
He feels a little, he feels a little dominated.
Yeah.
You know what's coming.
Uh, Glim.
Got all the heavy hitters up first, except for Flamikin's on the top.
Hit him.
Um, I'm going to use my fire breath.
I haven't done that in an age.
So he needs to make a dex save.
17.
Uh, that's an 18 on the die.
Plus 10.
Really?
Not a minus three.
Hmm.
Weird.
Um, okay.
Well he'll still take half damage.
So it's 24 on the die so he'll take 12 damage.
Which isn't a lot, but it looks pretty cool.
Looks badass.
Yeah, no, like a goth and, and night hunter run forward and, um, and neither are doing
exceptional.
Eye hit him.
I mean, there was contact.
A lot of people staring each other down and then a blast of fire comes out.
So there's a lot of things happening.
It's moving.
It's shaken.
Uh, anything else Glim would like to do.
Yeah.
He's got a couple heads so I really want to use the Vorpal Longsword.
Just in case it works out for me.
Just to see.
Just to see if it works out because it could be dope.
This time it didn't, but that is a 25.
25 will hit.
Great.
I can't remember what your Vorpal sword does.
Uh, if you hit a nat 20, I think it hits.
If I roll a 20, I cut off one of his heads.
Which is awesome.
So it could happen.
Yeah.
13 and then also seven radiant damage.
Love it.
Yeah.
Big cut in.
So now they're.
Oh.
And then I'll do more.
Do more.
Yes.
Okay.
As a bonus action, I'm going to do ensnaring strike because I hit him with my weapon
attack.
So writhing Mass of Thorny Vines appear at the point of impact and he needs to
make a strength savings throw.
I mean, you have advantage because you're large or larger, I assume.
So 25.
Yeah.
So, I mean, that'll, that'll, but it looked cool.
I shot fire.
I stabbed him.
I shot some vines.
You know, I'm just throwing it all at the wall, seeing what sticks.
Flavor of it.
Like he, he struggles a moment and then breaks free.
Uh, just to, you know, just to make that, that land.
Um, okay.
Like moot.
Have you closed the portal yet?
I don't, I don't think I know how, Grants.
Oh, just remember back to your teacher.
Gabriel.
He would have, he would have given you a lesson in closing portals.
I'm sure of it.
Are we having a flashback?
Off screen one.
Yeah.
Off screen lesson.
Oh, yeah.
You know, there was something about that, but like it only worked on small
portals.
Is that the one that when he used to use a portal to go from one bar to another bar
and then close up before the other barman got mad?
Yeah.
So no.
No, I mean, I'll need a little help.
I think.
What would you do if I sang out of tune?
No, keep going.
That's it.
That's a classic.
Has Grants ever sung in tune?
No, no, no.
All right, everybody.
Moot gets by with a little help from his friend.
Moot gets high with a little help from his friend.
All right, Russ, do I know how, like, do I know what to do here?
Like, seriously, though.
You want to try?
I mean, I'll give it a try.
Yeah.
Roll for portal.
Something maybe from your character sheet and then direct it at the portal and
see what happens.
Okay.
Because there's clearly a power source somewhere.
Maybe arcana.
You can try and judge where the power source is coming from.
Sure.
Let's give it a roll to start.
That is a 19.
Okay.
So yeah, you listening to the sweet dulcet tones of Grants is trying to
encourage everybody to sing to you.
He's running around like in everybody's faces as they're trying to fight
Demogorgon.
It's really just a wild scene.
But you get a good sense that the portal is drawing energy from the
floating now floating orbs of color that are moving through the space.
What color are these orbs and how many orbs are there?
They're like the god orbs that expelled from him when he.
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
Gotcha. Gotcha.
So there are many colors.
Like you could say the colors of the rainbow.
Okay.
Take a look around his lair.
What about the colors of the wind?
Yes.
They are blowing on the wind moving about and like there's like sparks
and little shots of energy being drawn to the portal itself.
I guess try and like take out a cluster of these things.
Okay.
Like I've got a firewall.
I've got lightning bolt.
Love it.
We can make some stuff happen here.
All right.
So you're aiming for the for the god presumed god aura.
Yeah.
I thought you were going to say the god balls.
The god balls.
Yeah.
I'll aim right for the god balls.
They need to make a deck saving throw.
Do they have that capability?
Since they are just orbs of energy, don't they just hang there?
I've rolled for something.
Well, you had to be an 18.
Love it.
You can you can continue with your spell.
Okay.
It is Fireball.
And if you didn't pass, then you're taking a bunch of damage.
Give me that damage, baby.
All right.
Fireball 10d6.
41.
Secondary Fireball goes off into the room towards these lights.
The lights themselves get struck by the Fireball and where the
previous Fireball exploded out into embers everywhere.
This one hits and then lingers and then gets sucked into the
balls themselves.
And they begin to now move closer to you.
They've where they were previously up in the air.
They've moved now 30 feet down and are we'll say probably another 30
feet away.
I feel I feel like you need a like a big butterfly net.
Yeah.
And is this going to go bad or good?
Like what are we thinking here?
Last we use some of those last time.
So I don't think they're inherently bad.
Okay.
Yeah.
So it's just like the you know, the spirits and powers of the
gods.
So maybe they're going to come and help help us.
Okay.
I said confidently.
Catch them.
Gotta catch them all.
God balls.
Anything else you want to do on your turn or just reflect on the
state of God balls.
I think just just soak it all in.
Okay.
Just give it a moment.
Perfect.
Love it.
Middle talk, middle talk.
It is time to middle talk.
It's the place where we ask you to fill out your questions and send
them to us because we're almost done the season.
That was so informative.
There's a link.
If I had to guess if Russ had to come up with a tune like on the
spot that he would base it off the Spiderman theme song.
Absolutely.
That would be my guess.
Yeah.
Just because he does a quick glance around the room and it's
like, what do I got for songs?
What shirt am I wearing?
Oh, it's a Marvel shirt.
All right.
Let's do something there.
I'm real on brand today.
I don't know what happened.
He's chilly.
I needed something to keep me warm.
There's only one episode left after this one in this season.
So like one and a half episodes left.
And that is wild and crazy and exciting.
And thank you for being here with us.
Couldn't have done it without you.
Couldn't have.
Wouldn't have.
Or could have, but just would have been like talking to no one.
Well, I mean,
maybe we would have just been playing a game if we weren't
releasing it,
but that wouldn't have been this fun because we wouldn't have
had you along for the adventure as well.
True.
As I said in the song,
we are taking questions for our end of, for our,
uh, regular end of season Q and a episode,
cause we did it after season one.
So now it's a regular thing if you do it twice.
Uh, so you can send us those questions.
We need to have shorter seasons.
So long ago that we did that.
One question per episode.
That would be unmanageable.
So what we're saying is there's a lot to draw from if you're
wondering about some stuff.
So questions, comments, concerns,
wonderments, you name it, send us, send them to us.
And we will record that after the finale drops, uh,
with our patrons.
Uh, so if you want to join us for that as well,
you can join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragging cast.
Uh, we'd love to see you over there.
Okay.
We'll let you get back to this episode,
this penultimate episode before we get to the season finale.
Have a great week.
We'll talk to you soon.
Okay. Bye.
Love you. Bye.
Bye.
Uh, Sully, you're up.
Oh no.
Uh, okay.
Speaking of God balls.
I think Sully would just feel like it would,
he would just be so tickled if his frightful sort of reflection
worked just once.
Uh, so he is going to like run up and slice at the
Demogorgon's like toe or whatever, wherever he can reach.
Um, oh, I bet it hurts.
It's, it's, I bet if he stubs that thing,
he's going to like let loose a string of swears.
Uh, oh, oh, 23.
23 will hit.
Oh, oh, Sully hits him with the, the, the,
the sword of a frightful sort of reflection.
And what happens is you get eight, eight damage,
also the pommel of the sword shimmer gloom has a name,
uh, gives the, gives the, uh, attacking and a sense of fear.
And so you need to make a constitution saving throw.
So how, how I, yeah.
Uh, so, uh, Demogorgon is immune to fright.
Oh, okay.
Well then that's fine.
I'm just down there poking his toe being like this thing doesn't work.
Here's what happens though.
So you go up and you hit his, you hit his ingrown toe and it feels really bad.
And he's like, he's hopping up and down now.
So they got to watch out for that.
Uh, but he's feeling really bad about it.
There was a demon right behind him who was, uh, sweeping, uh,
sweeping up some of the rubble and you,
you like show the sword to, to Demogorgon.
And by the whole, in one of these jump ups,
the demon behind him sees the frightful sword of reflection,
gets very scared and, and drops his broom and runs away.
I'll take it.
Is Demogorgon going to step on the broom and it's going to hit him in the face?
Yes.
Yeah.
Uh, the broom which magically grew 12 sizes that day,
uh, now is a rake and he lands on it.
You didn't say how big the demon was that was doing the sweeping.
Yeah.
I'm seeing this enormous demon just trying to scooch by, just being like,
Janitor here.
Don't mind me.
Yeah, it's fine.
Borinox.
Uh, seeing somebody attacking the orbs,
realizing that that's a, that's a solution.
Um, he's going to take note of it and he's going to do a real test.
He says, well, let's see if, uh, if that power is actually gone.
And I pull out the wand of Orcus.
And I am going to use three charges off the wand of Orcus to cast circle of death around the god orbs.
So, uh, I need all the orbs to give me a, uh, constitution saving throw, DC 18.
If this, if the, uh, spell actually works.
Okay. Yep. Great.
Borinox remembers what happened last time he destroyed one of these.
I think he liked it.
Okay. Cool.
Uh, okay.
Uh, so that happens.
So they rolled for something and, uh, did, did not beat your, your DC.
So 8d6 and that is 29 necrotic damage.
So this necrotic energy begins to swirl out and it like, uh, it acts,
is acting as like this river of air,
moving these orbs around this room and sparks begin to shoot off of them.
They get wrapped up in like this black, ichorish aura around them and then get dimmer and dimmer.
And the encircling space, um, tightens.
And at the same time, the portal tightens as well.
The god orbs themselves get closer to the position of everybody else on the ground.
Perfect.
Uh, and I'll use my movement to move up close to a goth
and hopefully give a little bit of a saving throw bonus now.
Thanks.
Uh, okay.
The, uh.
Um, Thea's gonna do something that, uh, she often forgets to do.
And she yells out, is everyone feeling okay?
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
Uh, feeling pretty good.
Uh, a little demoralized.
Yeah, I'm okay.
I thought we beat the big guy and then didn't.
It was a little unsettling, yeah.
Don't let that get you.
You guys are doing a great job.
Um, so she saw.
Thanks, Thea.
She saw, um, a goth go like, ehh, which was probably very hard for her to do.
Um, and so she's going to run up to a goth.
Uh, and cast Cure Wounds.
Oh, 12, sorry.
You get 12.
Thank you.
Which is, you know, not a lot, but, but better than, better than nothing.
It's something.
Uh, and then, uh, she's just gonna, uh, take both her daggers
and just, um, just like jam it in his calf.
And yell, Charlie Horse!
Is one of those daggers the dagger that you picked out of the hallway?
No.
Okay.
They're just my old regular old daggers.
Uh, that is, uh, 24.
Okay.
Are you still sticking with your two regular daggers?
Got it.
Yeah.
Cool. Love it.
I'm scared of that other dagger and I'm not sure why I have it.
Because you took it.
Yeah, those hit.
Five plus six, 11.
And then she, like, skips backwards and it's like, ah, ah.
Uh, you take an attack of opportunity.
What?
Because you, you skip backwards.
Do you really, do you, ah.
No, I tricked you.
Damn.
I said you could trick, I said you could walk away.
I was like, I shall never do that.
But then she did.
Damn my fucking touchdown dance.
Showboating.
Uh, 27.
I'm gonna get kicked.
I'm gonna do the same maneuver again since, uh,
this is for Agath's benefit that she came up.
So, so you get four to your AC, but if that doesn't,
if the attack still hits, you're resistant to it.
So you get half damage if it still hits.
Okay.
That only brings you up to a 23.
So it would still hit.
Yeah.
So you only take half the damage.
That's great.
Uh, 14 force damage.
Uh, and you have to make a constitution saving throw.
No attack.
Jesus, why is it so low?
Well.
Fuck.
How about a 10?
No.
So your hit point maximum is reduced by that much as well.
So you, uh, reduce your hit point maximum.
By 10.
Oh, by 14.
Yeah.
Oh.
Uh, okay.
Lipsinki.
Okay.
I am going to cast Psychic Scream at ninth level on the Demogorgon.
So he needs to make an intelligence saving throw.
Hell yeah.
Hopefully he's dumb as a sack of bricks.
That's right.
Is he a dummy?
Uh, 19.
Okay.
So that means he won't be stunned,
but he's still going to take half of the damage,
which is 14d6.
So that's 50 damage.
So he'll take 25 damage.
25.
And that's psychic damage.
That is psychic damage.
What does it look like when Lipsinki casts?
Um, you know, it's actually not that impressive because I just am like,
scrunch up my face and like give him a really mean face.
And I'm all fLexed up, scowling so hard.
So I mean, honestly, he doesn't even notice.
I'm so small.
He doesn't even see it coming.
Is she okay?
I don't know.
I am also going to hurl the Demogorgon through hell.
When you hit a creature with an attack,
you use this feature to instantly transport the target through the lower planes.
At the end of your next turn,
the target returns to the space it previously occupied or the nearest occupied space.
And it takes a whole schwack of damage when it comes back.
Okay.
So he's gone.
Cool.
He's gone. There's no save.
Nope.
She just punches you into hell.
Deal with it.
Love it.
Okay.
So there's a temper tantrum.
And then, I don't know.
I like, I think we've established that one as like the,
the hell scapes like open up underneath them because we did use that one in,
in a, in at least an episode.
Probably the episode that scared everybody and turned them off of our podcast.
Probably.
Yeah.
But now I'm using it for good.
Right?
Open, opens up beneath them.
Disappears.
It closes behind.
You're now in this space.
The necrotic energy swirling these god orbs around.
The portal had shrunk by half.
We are back up.
So it's Demogorgon's turn.
Demogorgon's not there right now.
He's not here, man.
Grants is his turn.
Okay.
What do you guys figure out about this portal business?
I just finished the third round of the song and I feel like we're really just bringing it home.
You sound really out of breath.
Well, it's, I've been in, I've been in the prison for a bit.
No, no moot.
You're not going to tell me?
Not going to tell me?
I mean, yeah, I haven't.
Warnocks, you got it?
We're working on it.
No.
I imagine we're going to be dealing with the orbs that are going on here.
No one over there seems to have a good idea of it.
So I figured I'd follow suit.
It looked like as orbs get closer, portal closed.
Okay.
So we should target that.
All right.
You want me to do that?
I mean, I know I sent him away, but he is coming back like pretty quick.
So if you want to.
I could get him to take attack, Katnip.
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
Cool.
He's going to cast.
What are you hitting it with?
You hit it with fire.
You hit it with some necrotic.
I'll try.
I'll try cold.
He does.
And it's going to take some damage.
Ninety eight.
Forty damage.
Wow.
Spicy.
Okay.
So this orb gets thrown into the stream of necrotic energy and explodes and it leaves
like this blizzarding effect that everything kind of casts through and they begin to close
even more down to like about five feet and everything is spinning so fast and
light is shooting off of this stream that is happening in the center.
So that's what I got.
And then it's night hunter's turn.
Night hunter is looking at all the orbs and all the magic and it's just like, and she
she backs up a few paces from where the Demogorgon was and is just with her chain
just ready to, I don't know, hit it once.
As soon as it comes back, she wants to like wail on that thing.
Okay.
So readying action for attack.
Yeah.
For return.
Agath.
Samesies.
Agath is also going to ready an action to do a hit.
Okay.
Readying action.
Flamikins is going to also try and hit the things with lightning bolt this time.
We've got fire, necrotic, we've got cold, we've got lightning blasts going out.
And it charges this spinning energy in the center and the shooting out, everybody feels
like the hairs on their body stand up and it's in this spinning ball in the center.
The portal is near closed.
You can still see light streaming up through it and hear the battle that's happening
on the other side.
We go to Glim.
I think that Glim's just going to also ready an action, I think, with the purple longsword.
Love this trio so far of badasses just standing waiting for this big monster to come back.
Lipsinki was like, he's coming back.
We're all like, good.
We weren't done yet.
Moot, back to you.
All right.
I'm going to cast Burning Hands, Russ.
And I'm going to make a break for the globes if someone can give me a boost.
Okay.
We've got next in turn Sully, Varunox, Thea, and Lipsinki.
I mean, I feel like Sully could give me the old double hand brace as I step up
and try and go for it.
I love that.
Okay.
Just like we practiced.
So Moot dashes from his location towards Sully.
Sully, what do you look like as you're preparing yourself for this jump?
Okay.
So you would assume that it would be your standard hands, you know, fingers linked, right?
Foot there.
It's not.
They've actually been practicing this for a while.
What he's going to do.
Moot's going to run up, then swan dive.
Love it.
And then, like, waist.
Sully's going to have him around the waist and propel him back behind him.
So much like Swayze.
I was going to say, we've got a real, like, dirty dancing.
Yes, except propulsion.
And we've had the time of our lives, so it totally tracks.
Sing it, Grantus.
And I have the time of my life.
Okay.
Propelling you forward.
You are soaring through the air.
That's how on point.
I'm not even going to make you roll because you practiced.
Everyone marvels.
The sheer mechanics of it are mind boggling.
Moot, burning hands, hands ablaze, reaches,
connects with this spinning sphere of god orbs and is sucked inside.
Oh, no.
Oh, guys.
This was his idea.
You saw that the whole time.
I was just support because my friend wanted to do something,
and I wanted to be there for him.
That's your action.
That's rude.
Should I not try to continue destroying the orbs?
They are spinning faster.
You can see as you watch them, you can see glimpses of like Moot's face,
and it changes every single time.
It's like panicked.
It's excited.
Throwing up.
It is all of the emotions that you could be going through.
He is going through right now inside of this churning laundry of god
or the classic emotion of throwing up.
So it's not like he's inside of an orb.
No.
He is not inside of an orb.
He appears to be him or his bodily state is inside of the vortex
that is being created.
Well, fuck.
That rules out AOE.
I mean, you don't know.
It's true.
That has crossed my mind.
I mean, you do what you got to do.
Moot's a tough boy.
He can handle it.
You might even get a hellish rebuke for your efforts.
Who knows?
Oh, that's cool.
I can cop to that.
Yeah, I'm going to throw a fifth level fireball at it.
That's what I was going to do anyway.
Nice.
Okay.
So, deck saved, 20.
Being as I'm spinning in a vortex, Russ, do I have the ability to?
I don't even think you have the consciousness, the state of mind
to know that a fireball is coming towards you at this point.
Love it.
Yep.
Give us that fireball.
32 fire damage.
It's fine.
Right, Moot?
Probably.
So, as this fireball goes, Thea and Lipsinki, what, before I say what happens,
what do you two do in your own internal preparation?
Because all of this is happening kind of like at the same time, right?
So, Thea?
Oh, the minute that Moot got sucked in there, she was trying to think of a,
like, does she have a spell where she can, like, yank somebody out of some place?
And so, she's just trying to think of, her mind is splitting.
Do I help Moot or, because the Demogorgon's going to be right back?
Or, so she's got like two different spells she's waffling between at the moment.
And she never failed this way before.
Okay.
So, your action is to choose inaction.
I'm choosing to waffle.
Once the Demogorgon comes back, I'm actually just going to hold my action
and then cast a spell when he comes back.
Okay.
Lipsinki?
Well, I know that guy's coming back right now.
So, I am going to ready my Eldritch Blast, marking the end of my turn,
at which point Demogorgon comes back and takes a bunch of damage from psychic damage.
Okay, what's the psychic damage?
So, he gets 10d10.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, imagine they're all 10s.
Imagine.
I'm imagining it.
Imagine all the damage.
So, he takes 53 psychic damage.
Jesus.
That's wonderful.
Hopefully, all those readied actions like, bam, bam, bam, bam.
Like, I want it to be overkill.
But he's been dead for a moment.
And we're all just still, yeah, blasting.
Okay.
A lot of things happen all at once.
Fireball hits the spinning ball, gets sucked into the ball and the sphere.
There's fire.
There's electricity.
There's necrotic damage.
There's Moot's face.
All spinning by all at the same time.
The ball itself sucks into, like, a tight, like, grapefruit side.
And then, as Demogorgon comes back with the hideous thud and scream, the ball itself explodes.
Lights go everywhere.
Portal wavers.
And it explodes.
Does everybody make a dexterity saving throw?
Great. Love that.
With advantage.
I'll tell you why later.
Okay.
Everybody, regardless of your roll, is, like, blasted away from this center sphere.
I believe it was just two of you that rolled real, real bad.
You're going to take 16 bludgeoning damage as you're blown to the sides.
But then, all of these orbs explode out and begin spinning back around the room.
The portal is closed.
There's a, like, rubble point in the center of this throne room now where the portal once was.
Everything around you quiets considerably because you can no longer hear the battle below you.
And we see all of you as being encircled by your own individual aura.
There's these lights that are now around you.
You all pick yourselves up and the readied actions can go.
You're going to add 20 additional radiant damage to every hit you do.
Oh, shit. Sick.
You roll with advantage.
So we'll start with Night Hunter.
That was the order of which we held actions.
Night Hunter is feeling energized and kind of weird.
They decide to hack at the legs of this demogorgon.
So let me see here.
There's 18 plus 13. I think it hit.
Yep.
19 plus 13. I think it hits.
15 plus 13. I think it hits.
Okay. So all three of them hit.
35. Damage.
Plus 60.
I got.
All right. Three attacks with the flail.
Nine plus 12. 21.
That's a no, right?
That's with advantage?
Yeah, it is.
Okay, better. 12 plus 12.
There we go. We finally have a hit.
I don't know what it's resistant to, but acid was working well before.
So let's go with acid.
So that's 20 points of acid.
And then the 20 radiant on top of it, I guess.
And there's one more attack.
Okay. Double 18s on that one.
Plus 12.
And that one is 19.
Acid plus the 20 radiant.
Okay. Glim.
Okay. I'm going to attack twice with the vorpal longsword.
Wow. That was really bad.
Because it's 21, isn't it? So that was 19 was my best roll.
But I'm going to try again.
And it's better because it's 25.
There you go.
15 slashing plus 23 radiant.
I added my extra radiant to that 20.
Okay. Thea.
Thea is going to let loose moonbeam at what level?
Seventh level.
Okay.
So they need to make a constitution saving throw.
They don't.
Oh, they don't?
Oh, okay.
My silvery beam of light blasts down upon this poor sucker.
35.
That was 20.
Yep.
And then she is also going to take her longbow out and shoot an arrow at it.
Just because she can.
Yes.
All right. That's a 25.
Give me damage.
Nice.
And it's going to be seven damage.
Plus 20.
Yep.
All right.
Lipsinki, final held action.
Perfect.
I'm going to eldritch blast with four beams right at my guy.
So that is 32 damage plus that 20 radiant.
It was a 20 for each beam.
Yeah, good question. Good question, Kyle.
It is a 20 for each beam?
Oh, it is.
Oh.
Yeah.
How many hit points does this thing have?
So that's 80 radiant then.
Okay.
Explosion, lights, everything's swirling, and Demogorgon comes back and is attacked by this onslaught of god-powered mayhem.
I guess it's probably a good description.
Everybody unleashing absolutely everything they have down into him.
And as this moonbeam and all of these attacks are hitting him, he's like shriveling up on the spot.
There is nothing that is left from him.
He's like this, what's the, you know, like the creatures in Little Mermaid, the seaweed creatures that everybody gets sucked down into.
That's what he looks like now.
Huge gargantuan hulking creature.
Now this little big bug-eyed nothing down in the center.
Who wants to step on it?
Oh, who doesn't want to step on it?
Neander wants to step on it.
Oh, could it be Rax?
Yeah, Rax has been quiet.
Oh, that's better.
He just comes over and like pony stomps him.
With Pegasus wings.
Fuck you.
Everybody allows Rax through and just stomps down on top.
The room is entirely quiet and you're all looking at each other.
Moot, you were blasted through the air but then suspended in place and you come down and you meet the group.
And all of a sudden you are, these lights begin to spin around you quicker again.
And they're spinning in this swirling vortex and everything's becoming blurry around you and you're all being lifted up.
And there is, you look and you see Bort and Flint's body also lifting up in place.
And you're all being propelled upward and there's this light above you and there's this snap.
You're all standing in this white room.
There's a basin in the center of this room that's rippling with water and you see like streams of light rushing through them.
Thea, you look over and you see Flint's body lying on the ground, scaleless.
But standing behind that body is this glowing aura of Flint as you knew him.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 2 Episode 154 starring Amy More as Thea, Nighthunter, and Sully.
Karla Maxted as Lipsinki and Glim. Tom Laird as Moot with Kyle Claset as Vorunax.
Kristen Flemmons as Agath, Godloss Catho Alavi, and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue Editing by Karla Maxted and Sound Design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and sound effects from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library, and Sound Ideas.
And a huge thank you to our supporting producers.
Do you like the stories that we're telling?
Season 2 only has one more episode, but that means that Season 3 is right around the corner.
So we're very excited for the next episode, the finale of Season 2, coming very soon.
How can you support us going into Season 3? Join us at Patreon, Patreon.com slash dumb dragoncast.
While you wait for Season 3, which shouldn't take too long to get to new episodes after we wrap up Season 2,
there's a whole slew of bonus content, including our Patreon exclusive game, The Adventures of,
DM'd by Tom, Amy, Karla, and I have a whole lot of fun.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragoncast. We hope to see you over there.
We can't wait for you to hear the finale for Season 2.
And don't forget to get your questions in.
If you're a patron, we'll be recording our Q&A episode at our next Goo Kang, which is October 3rd, 2023.
Sign up today to join us, but if you can't do that, submit your questions and we'll answer them for that episode.
The link is in the description where you can send them in.
Alright, that's it for me. Thank you so much for being here with us.
We hope you have a great week, and we'll talk to you soon.
Shoot a drop because it seemed like things went knock all the wood pretty good last time.
So what kind of mean thing is Russ planning?
That's my concern.
Like my characters aren't even mostly dead.
Exactly.
Not even mostly dead.
This portion of it might get cut out.
But I was talking to Tom after the game last week, and he was just, I guess I was like, I'm super nervous on how that went.
And then I have to remind myself that we've been playing this battle, this battle since the middle of September.
That's true.
It was like it seemed like it was just over too quickly.
It really wasn't though.
But it's not. It's not.
Carla, are you Sacred Oath?
Uh, yes.
Same.
What's up?
Two sides of the same coin here.
We've got Horcus on one side, bottom left on the other.
I mean, can't, yes.
Can't build pAlydins two different ways.
So six battle episodes with Horcus and then one goofy demogorgon episode to wrap it all up.
It's great. I love it.
Yep.
Anything else you want to do, Sully?
Or can do?
No.
Sully really at level 19 and still only has one attack.
I mean, usually rogues use their sneak attack, but you opted against that every time.
I forget that I haven't.
Also, okay, the whole thing about sneak attack is this is, okay, listeners, this is why I don't use it.
Because in Amy's brain, she thinks in order to sneak up on something, they need to not see you.
And every time we are in battle, it's like, boom, there's a demogorgon in front of you.
And I'm just not going to be like, um, like it can see me.
I don't, the mechanics of it I get because it's like, it's just the thing that happens.
But in Amy's story brain, you can't sneak up on something that's already looking at you.
You're in the shadows and you also have people distracting it at the same time.
That's why I've never, I never even think to use it.
Well, that's your good one.
So, you know, for next time.
I haven't been using my good one.
Moot back to you.
All right.
Are these orbs like within reach?
You want to grab with your hands?
Yeah.
If you want to.
So the portal we'll say is like two and a half feet across.
The balls themselves are spinning like just above it.
Like they're almost making a sphere in and of themselves as they're spinning in this matrix above them.
Yeah.
I mean, you'd have to maybe propel yourself or get some upsies, but you could reach them if somebody like assisted you in some way.
But I mean, is reaching them what I want to do.
Is that going to disrupt what's going on?
I mean, that was your, that was your go-to.
That was like you, that was the first thing you thought of.
So, you know, trust your gut.
What about your, what about your crab claw?
Haven't seen the crab claw in a while.
Don't touch it with your hand hand.
It's like permanently attached to me.
But yeah, I could, I could, I could send it on its way.
Just a thought.
No, no pressure.
I don't know if it's a good thing to hold those.
Nobody knows.
I mean, I don't know either.
Like, is that portal just going to open right back up?
It's working right now.
Right?
Okay, okay, okay.
Just looking through my spell list.
Oh shit, I do have portal closed.
Damn it.
Son of a bitch.
Turns out it's sixth level.
It's ninth level in everything.
That was a cantrip.
God.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.