previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
really bad dude named Orcus. And he shows up and starts taking all the gods out of the realm.
Is that Mademar? Oh! Oh! Oh shit! Oh no! Oh! Okay. He goes and stands out over
over the scene, which he hadn't really gone and looked at. Everybody else did,
and he sees like this this roiling blackness coming up the hill. Um...
Dots? I think we waited too long. Oh my god.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. I'm your dungeon master Russ More. He,
him, also with me today is Kristen Flammons. She, her. Playing Gath. She, her. So exciting
and unexpected and surprised. I love that. This look of sheer terror.
One of us. Didn't even have peanut butter in my mouth this time.
That's how I knew you were ready. Come on now. Also with me today is Tom Laird.
Yeah, that's me. I am also he, him. Nope. Wait. He, him. And I'm playing Moot,
who is also he, him. Got one half step ahead of myself.
There was an also in there. It's all thrown off now. Amy More.
Yes, she, her, and I will be playing Sullivan Slyte. He, him. And Karla Maxted.
She, her, playing Glim, also she, her. See, we got back on her course by the end
there. Couple panics and then he's back into it. What do we do on Patreon?
Well, that's where you don't have to pan. That's true.
You can hang out with us at various levels. There's like a hangout or a producer chat
where you come and talk about D&D or podcasts or technology or just like random bullshit.
Maybe not too long ago, we have like live shows, live streams, and you get to come and like,
ah, you know, participate in that. Give us some fun suggestions. There's a book club.
And I picked a book. Who else is there? Oh,
there's a whole other like podcast where we play D&D. There's that.
There's Dumptions Downtimes every Saturday where we talk about the episode we just
like released earlier that week. That's true.
Kristin, unobjectively, do we do too much for our patrons?
It seems like a pretty slick deal, personally. There we go. You heard it right from Kristin,
who is a regular cast member as well and will start to show up to all of these things
and more. No, no pressure on that. But also when you're a patron, you get an episode dedicated
to you like today's patron, Charlie Wharley. Thank you so much.
There's also a discord. That's great. You don't have to be a patron to be in that, but
but there's also a book club too, which is also great. You don't have to be a patron to
be that. No, you have to be a patron. Yes, you do have to be a patron to do that.
Yeah. I take it back. Yeah, just you dangled and then it was gone.
And it was gone. So quick. Just took it away.
But know that there is a book club and it's been great so far.
And we'd love for you to come join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
So many things that happen over there, but really our eternal love and gratitude is
is number one. Absolutely. And specifically this episode to Charlie, because I don't feel like
we said it enough. We didn't really get like enough like whoop whoop whoop whoop whoop
about, you know, about Charlie. Who's awesome about Charlie Warley specifically.
So you to bomb and now let's fuck it. Wait, no, that's it. That's our saying.
Yes, let's fuck it. This is how we're.
Let's start this. I'm playing flammie kids tonight.
Well, let's fuck it. Let's play. OK, I was going to be like, I'm doing Russ's thing.
And then you've got to handle the responsibility ever one of.
Yeah, no, you set the bar too high. Yeah. Thank you for doing that.
Screams, explosions, blood, guts.
And the smell that we described in this episode. It's so bad here.
It's hair. And why is it burning? Yeah, fish, all the fish. Yeah, it's it's very fish.
All of this is mayhem is climbing up Mount Celestia and it's being met by the pAlydins
and clerics who Bahamut who wasn't in like just in the mindset to really take in any
of this information and therefore was a real wiener, as was pointed out in the downtime.
Another patron thing you can go get if we didn't mention it already.
And we see Bahamut looking down at all of this as the group of you is
readying yourselves, preparing yourselves for making a move, for hopping on the back of a dragon,
for blinking and pretending to be somewhere else. You know, any way you want to present
teleportation as a means, you can close your eyes and take a step and then you've teleported.
We hear just like this inner monologue of Bahamut. Bahamut's log.
Uh, I don't know what day it is. I had a bit to drink before these folks showed up.
I was sleeping it off and they said that the world was going to end and I
I mean, you dime a dozen, you hear the world's going to end.
So I took them down to the bar, you know, just ease them up. You know,
sometimes it just takes a few and then maybe they just remember that they're in the really
cool kids club and that it's all going to be OK. But then they started presenting some
interesting facts that could not be true because they were from the future.
So they're not true for like the time that we're in now, but they're true for future sense.
And it all led and culminated to me taking them on a museum tour,
which I really thought was, you know, kind of the highlight.
All those items that they got, they look real cool, but I don't think they're going to help
them in any way. I'm not going to tell them that specifically and just going to just going
to let them just revel in the moment of having something of Bahamuts that's that's now in their
possession. They could take it. They could, you know, use it. They could sell it. Maybe it
actually does something really cool. I don't know. I forgot to ask. It's had a real kind
of vibe. But then Glim, one of my favorites Glim, a destiny to save the world. Destiny to
save the world. Oh, shit. Well, I guess that one's me. Egg on my face.
All right. Guess we're going to have to deal with this now. Captain's log out.
He's been standing there completely silent. We've been talking to him. Nothing.
I think he's in a coma, like waving my hand in front of his eyes.
Can they kidnap his mind without his body? Oh, oh, that's pretty dangerous.
Well, they did. I mean, if you're a zombie, is that not like kidnapping your mind and leave,
you know, your body's being taken over? They can do that.
Well, you think he's a zombie now? I don't think so. No, he doesn't look like it's not.
It's not got a lot of things falling off like zombies do. Yeah, it doesn't really
doesn't smell undead. There's only one way to see. And I want to wind up and
slap him on the face. I will have to hop. I do believe. Okay.
Hop, slap. Get on Rex's back. Good old hop, slap. You can get on Rex.
And then I just keep riding. Ride by slapping.
I'm just snapping him out of it. I'm not trying to hurt him.
It's like a cool breeze. All right, we got to do something here, everybody.
I don't know why we've been sitting around talking so much. We've got to get up and get
going. Okay. Yeah, I mean, you're definitely right, but we okay. Turn into a dragon.
Fly us out of here. Okay. Yeah, done.
He sneezes and it turns into a dragon. Oh, God, that seems like
that seems like a really awkward thing to happen every time you sneeze.
Did I not do that in the future? I don't know. We met you when you were
comatose and stuff. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So where are we going? Hop on.
Question. Can he just like carry Rex and his dragon hands?
He takes the net that you were carrying Matamar in.
Nope. This is the episode now. Oh, God, not again.
Yeah. He takes the net that you were carrying Matamar in and wraps it around
Rex and is carrying it in like two of his dragon feet. And so you've got a horse
dangling below a dragon. Great. Yes. And okay, good. That's what we're doing.
Everybody climbs on the back of Bahamut. Does this include Matamar?
I don't want to stay here. Fair enough. Come on.
Okay. I'm coming too. Matamar also hops on.
Dragon takes off below you. You see skeletons and zombies all clamoring up the hill.
You see this purple, blackish, like ribboning aura that's cracking up and out of the stone
of the mountain. Flying up out of it are these like dripping like ichor-ridden black dragons,
multiple of them. They emerge from the ground, climbing up with their claws and their wings,
and they burst up into the air and are now flying quickly towards you.
That seems bad. All right, everybody.
We got to get Bahamut to a safe place. Looks like those dragons are going to try
and bring us down. All right. I'm going to go take care of the lead one.
Flamikins hops off and down towards the dragon, lands on top of its head. That was an
18 on the dive and releases this chaos bolt into the head of this dragon. That is lightning
that shoots out of her hands and into it for 25 lightning damage into its skull.
You see the skeleton of it light up as she releases it in there, and it drops down into
the sky, still flying, trying to now bat her off as she's holding on.
How close is the closest dragon? They're flying up from beneath you.
Probably closest one Flamikins would have landed on would have been about 30 feet,
so the next one is probably like 40, 45 feet. Like a drop, though, not like out.
Yeah, OK, I'm going to take this spear from Bahamut that seems like maybe a piece of garbage,
but we'll see. I'm just going to chuck it down at the dragon below us. Screw it.
All right, make a ranged attack, please.
With advantage, because you're in an aura of Bahamut.
Nice. He is good for something. 27.
Find an actual random cool spear that this could be because he doesn't know what it does.
Yeah, in hindsight, he was not a good docent at the museum.
No, he really wasn't. Roll a D8 and we'll see which one this is.
You got it.
If it's a one, we reroll.
It's a seven.
You have the Spear of Bahamut, so it'd be D6 plus three plus two D8.
So 13.
The spear hits and like this glowing light emits from its back and the dragon lets out this
shriek as you see Ichor like bubbling up from inside of it.
It is loosely hanging onto the back as it takes a few big wing pumps.
What do you want to call those? What do we call those wing?
Flaps?
Flaps.
Beats?
Beats. Thank you. Either of those better than wing pumps.
That's what they do when they did something really cool with each other.
They wing pump.
Yeah, wing pumps. Either that or it pumps air into them, much like the sneakers of the 90s.
Seeing that the spear is cool,
Agath is going to follow Flamekin's lead and just jump down to get it.
And then if she gets there, just smack it two more times with her other attack actions.
Okay. Love it.
Roll athletics or acrobatics with advantage while you remain in Bahamut's aura.
Oh, that's definitely going to be an athletics roll.
19.
Throw it. You see the light and you leap off behind it.
Nobody's stopping anybody else from leaping off at any point.
No, still good.
Okay. You fly.
You're going to stop her from doing what she wants to do.
People can do what they want.
That's right.
Soar down and almost like you have a wingsuit.
You soar down and land on top and you grab hold of the spear,
which anchors you as you kind of slip just a fraction of an amount.
Can I actually try for my second attack
to just like land grabbing the spear hard enough that it's like sinking in even deeper?
Bah, I love it.
Sure. Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, we've already said you've grabbed it.
So just the force that you're driving it in, just give me damage.
12. 12 more.
Can Rex just like poop on that one underneath?
I mean, I don't mean to be gross,
but he probably can't really help us fight right now.
And he has a breath weapon if it gets close enough.
Right. Well, I guess that's better.
It just squeezes it every once in a while and it's just like poop bombs.
And I'll do a third, like rip it out and slam it down again.
It's a 16.
All good. Give me some damage.
18 plus 3. 21.
Yeah, this dragon that you've landed on is letting out like this gargling,
hideous call as it loses altitude.
And you begin dipping down closer to this like purplish cloud below you.
It's just going to rip the spear.
I'll keep this.
It is pretty cool.
Moot.
OK, let me just have a quick little peek at my spells list.
Yeah, I'll cast lightning bolt for us.
100 feet long, five feet wide stroke of lightning blasts out.
Creatures must make a deck saving throw.
If I can target more than one, I will.
But if not, I'll just target one.
Sorry, what was the range on it?
A hundred feet long, five feet wide.
Yeah, we can say you can get a couple of them.
There are now four dragons, flamingons on one,
a goth on the other and two more coming up that we can say that you can hit there.
Dexterity saving throw.
That's me.
Three on the die and 16.
They both fail.
OK.
All right.
So you are going to take 8d6 lightning damage.
Well, Moot's rolling those.
Can I say I realize I have unwavering mark.
Can I have marked this nasty dragon so it has disadvantage on attacks?
That's not me.
On the one that you hit?
Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
OK, that's my dragon now.
OK, so yeah, if it doesn't, if it tries to attack somebody else, it's got disadvantage.
OK, a nine and 11 and a seven.
So 27.
27 lightning damage to both of them.
That lightning calls down from the sky and rips through both of these.
Huge tears come into their wings as they as they drop down about 20 feet each.
Errol the 15 on my wild magic table.
Thank you.
The one that flamingons is on his turn, it's going to with its fly movement of 80 feet,
try and fly up and ram into Bahamut.
And it's going to miss.
But everybody else must make a dexterity saving throw as it beats its wings moving past him.
50.
18.
Is that also us not on Bahamut?
No, no, you're fine.
And flamingons is fine.
11 for Matamar.
So everybody who is on Bahamut is going to take 15 bludgeoning damage and be knocked prone,
which is not great because you're on the back of a flying dragon.
I feel like we weren't standing to be better to begin with.
Could be.
Likely we're not standing.
Yeah, fair enough.
OK, it's the one that a goths.
Wait, is this my dragon that's doing this?
That was flamingons dragon.
Now it's now it's your dragon and it hit you with its tail.
It's going to try 28, 33.
Oh, my God.
That's a big number.
I guess.
But like barely.
Yeah.
So 17 bludgeoning damage and a dexterity saving throw.
A cut, a cut.
It's not good.
Oh, that'd be that'd be a whole five.
So you get like hit hard with this tail and you soar off of this dragon's back.
You are now free falling towards just just the purple cloud.
I don't know what's below that.
That was 17 bludgeoning damage.
17 bludgeoning damage.
Yeah, not much.
Seen as it's played.
Dragon that flamingons is on comes up and tries to hit Bahamut veers,
but there's a wing blast and kind of knocks you all prone.
You're kind of laying on it, sitting on its back.
Anyways, that's fine.
You see over the edge that a goth is like tennis balled off of the back of a dragon
is now free falling down towards the earth below.
What do you do?
I think that.
Unfortunately, I can do I think nothing to help a goth right now.
But that one that just hit Bahamut, how far away would you say it is from us now?
Fly speed of 80.
So it's probably like 30 feet above.
Perfect.
That's exactly the number I wanted you to say.
Because that's how far my fire breath.
I mean, 35, right?
30.1 damage.
So I am a dex save.
With disadvantage because I'm going to say I can't see you.
That's a 14.
Great.
So it's going to take 5d6 fire damage, which was a bad rolls.
13 fire damage from that.
And then I think, yeah, I guess I'll just maybe throw my javelin.
Who even remembered I have it?
I don't use it.
So let's let's give that a shot at that same one.
No, it's right.
No, sure.
I'm a real athlete.
I'll throw it straight up above.
It's fine.
That way you could catch it when it's falling back down.
That's right.
That's a 25.
That hits.
So that is going to that's 13 piercing damage plus 8 radiant damage.
Glenn, don't kill it.
Kill it.
It'll crush us.
Does my javelin stab it and fall back down?
I think it's I think that that damage it embeds into.
Yeah.
So yeah, you hit like the underbelly of it and it's stuck in stuck in down there.
Sully.
A goth falling flamicons up high.
Glim huffing stuff up into the air just lobbing it and connecting.
Ikker dripping back down.
Two more dragons lightning hit from the bottom.
I am not equipped to fight in this type of situation.
Fly, you fool.
I can't.
What he is going to do though while he is laying prone
is he is going to scratch like he's going to get out his tattoo absorbing tattoo needle
and scratch a crude picture.
Looks a little like a dick, just not meant to just, you know,
it's on the back of a moving dragon.
You have to roll a D10 that's going to determine the color
and what that gives me defense against
or damage resistance against.
Seven.
Against poison damage.
Neat.
Okay.
Well, then I can't be poisoned.
And unless I want to start stabbing at Bob and the dragon that I'm on.
I mean, two people have jumped off so far.
It's going great.
50-50 right now on your.
If only I was a monk right now, I would level 20.
I'd just be flying.
Just do whatever I want.
I mean, I don't want to wait.
Does that count as my action though?
I think it does pretty sure that's okay.
Then then he will consider it for the next time,
but at least now he can't be poisoned.
I mean, there is some Icar dripping.
Maybe that purple stuff is poisonous.
I don't know.
Black dragons are known for their poison.
So, you know.
Are they?
I think it's acid.
Which is really just like really poisonous poison.
I mean, yeah.
Okay.
High rolls.
Matamar can do something.
Okay.
Matamar, who was on the back of Bahama,
like almost like blown off by the wings,
looks down and sees a goth.
It's like, I got this.
And he leaps off.
No, no.
Oh, Matamar.
Oh, buddy.
And the skin between his arms and his legs like spreads out
and he begins soaring down towards a goth
with wings that extend out.
And he's moving faster than a goth.
He's not going to make it there this turn.
So he's going to be able to catch you probably
on the next turn unless something stops you.
Okay.
Like the ground.
Exactly.
How did you worry about that when you worry about that?
I think it's Bahama's turn.
What do you want Bahama to do?
He really is.
He's this.
He can't make his own decisions to this extent.
Yeah.
He's this helpless.
Okay.
Bahama, fucking do something.
Like, I don't know, like bite one of the other dragons
or like, do you have a court breast?
Or go get a goth.
Like, yeah, save her.
She's fallen.
And then now we know we got that guy going down down.
He sends himself into a dive, says, hold on,
and is spiraling down towards a goth.
He passes Matamar who gets scooped up on his back
and makes it to a goth.
A goth make an athletics check to see if you can grapple.
Usually pretty good at those.
I just need a new dice.
Again, with advantage because Bahama's back in your range.
Okay, cool.
26.
You are in this free fall and Bahama catches up to you
and you grab onto like this fin on his back.
You're now on the back of Bahama again.
And as he feels you grab him,
he releases out of this spiral and shoots up
towards the dragons.
He's beneath them and releases a lightning breath
up and through three of them.
They're going to make a deck save.
One is going to save, the others are not,
and they are going to take 108 damage.
It is good having a god dragon on your side
when he like does something.
Yeah, exactly.
I mean, maybe he roasts some meat we need to, but.
We're back to Flamikins.
She's still on the back of this one
and is going to release another chaos bolt
into the head of this dragon.
It's going to be force damage.
So you see like this pulse that echoes out
up high in the sky and this,
the dragon that she's on the back of,
you see just stop, its wings stop flapping
and it begins to free fall upside down
and you just hear this.
Ah, as it catches its wing and throws itself back over
into a glide back out.
It's another middle and the dog rings the bell.
That's how we know it's the middle.
That's how we know that it's time to start the middle.
That how we know Amy's not going to be
in this middle anymore.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Amy.
And Amy is leaving.
Okay, Amy's gone.
We didn't say goodbye, we're leaving.
We didn't say goodbye, Amy.
Well, I can't say goodbye.
It was a little bit strange to see.
But we're not going to fight,
because we're going to save our lives.
It is so scary.
We talked the last time, which I want to say was last week, so it probably was, because
that's how we release episodes is weekly, where we reached a goal and we hit 100 patrons
and we did a live show and it was amazing.
It was so fun.
But what happened when we did that is we ran out of goals.
Right.
And you can't live life without goals.
No, we always need something to work towards.
Happiness is setting and achieving attainable goals.
Exactly.
So what we did was we collectively sat down and we're like, what are great things that
we could put up there?
And then Amy, Carla and I stared at each other blankly for a while.
And then Tom piped in with some really great ideas.
It wasn't even that we stared blankly at each other.
It's like that we spewed just a ton of nonsense, just nonsense, nonsense, nonsense.
And then Tom would just dip in and be like, hey, what about this fantastic idea?
So Tom.
Then I would drop my mic and I would disappear back into the shadows.
Like Homer into the shrub.
Great idea.
See you later.
Yup, I'm out.
So we've set a few goals over there.
The next one, when we reach a community goal of one hundred and fifteen patrons,
we will release four patrons in character positive affirmations.
Oh yeah, I forgot.
This is a good one.
So yeah, if you need a little pick me up, maybe Flamikins will be telling you
how great you are in no time.
Maybe.
I would tell you how great you are, but I have to save it for the goal.
So we'll release those as bonus audio for our patrons and maybe as tick tock content
because people keep asking us about all that tick tock content.
And it seems like a good fit.
People or person?
I'm not trying to point fingers, Tom.
He's the shush.
Many people. It's Paisley.
She's saying Paisley wants more talk that changes everything.
That's what she's screaming about right now.
So 115 patrons will start releasing in character positive affirmations
and then 125 improv live show again, because everybody loves them and we love them.
And then at 150, we're going to bring back something that we had for a while.
And then we turned it into a new show called Facing Fate, which is monthly
one shots and in small arcs will be coming back to our Patreon feed
where we play different games and play different characters in different worlds
and all that sort of thing.
And it won't just be for Facing Fate or Dumbgeons and Dragons.
It'll be its own thing that will probably turn into another podcast.
If you wanted to kind of prognosticate two years into the future,
this will probably be just a whole nother podcast we have.
But for now, in addition to like regular feed, Dungeons
and then Patreon feed, Tom show.
This will be Patreon feed, whole other thing.
Whole other thing.
So you can help us get there.
That's a ways out.
We've got little baby goals in between, and they're going to be lots of fun.
Like those positive affirmations.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Come join us.
Join the club.
One of us, one of us, one of us.
I really look forward to seeing who can determine whether it's Flint
reading the affirmation or Tallgear.
There's subtle differences.
I've played them both side by side.
There is a variation.
It's so subtle, though.
Our listeners will be able to listen if they're in the same content will make sense.
Exactly.
OK, listen to the rest of the episode that you're listening to right now.
Thanks, friends.
Bye.
OK, I love you.
A goth, you're on the back of Bahamut.
What do you want to do?
There's three above you that were blasted.
They have dropped back down towards you.
So all are within most 30 feet from you.
So it's all getting pretty cramped in this airspace that you're swarming around.
Well, maybe I will fire off some crossbow bolts.
Why not have a ranged weapon?
Yeah, let's do it.
Is it at advantage with Bahamut's aura?
Sweet.
Twenty seven to hit.
Yeah.
On the first one for I think it's just a regular old crossbow.
So that's an eight damage on that.
Oh, 19 plus seven.
Yeah, is.
Yeah.
Another eight damage.
And then last one.
Shooting the same one each time.
Dirty 20.
Yeah, there's like this is not big damage.
So let's just punch it into the eight plus one.
So nine damage on that one.
Agath does not like the crossbow.
It feels small and puny and unsatisfying in her hands.
But that's what you got.
You know, I can't fly.
What you got to do.
I can't.
You tried, though.
I tried.
You tried.
Didn't go great.
Could have gone worse, but love it.
Oh, are any of them in Brax's like breathing distance?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
OK, cool.
When he gets a moment, when one like swings by,
he will belch a horrible, horrible horse breath at them.
Let's say one of them passes beneath and he
takes an opportunity.
Constitution saving throw?
Plus 14.
It's a 21, 21.
Oh, yeah, that hits.
So it's going to be half of 66.
OK.
24, half of 24, 12.
Horse makes better hits than me.
12 poison damage, which probably
isn't going to do nothing to them
because they're black dragons.
No, wait.
We already established that that's not poison.
I mean, I think it's acid.
I think it's acid.
Yeah.
Moot.
How many more black dragons are flying around?
There are four total.
None have been made unalive yet.
I mean, they appear unalive.
They are undead.
So none have been made more dead.
Perfect.
So the two I hit with lightning
are still kicking around?
Yes.
The three that are surrounding are the two
that hit with lightning and the one that Agath
was on the back of.
The one that Flamikinskins was on the back of
was on a free fall, so it's farther away right now.
Are the two that I hit before still relatively close
to one another?
Yeah, everything's kind of swirling around you.
So there probably would be a point of which
if you're trying to hit two at the same time.
OK, yeah, I will do that.
And I will cast Synaptic Static.
Oh, I don't know if we've seen this one before.
No, I know.
I don't think I've heard about this one.
Each creature in a 20-foot radius sphere centered
on a point must make an intelligence saving throw.
And otherwise, they're going to take some psychic energy
damage.
Because they're undead, they don't
have the intelligence buffer that they usually have.
So that's a three and a two.
OK.
A creature with an intelligence score of two or lower
can't be affected by this spell.
But that's the score, not a roll.
Oh, yeah.
But hilarious that you rolled the two.
No, yeah.
OK, you're going to take 19 psychic damage.
And after a failed save, your target
has muddled thoughts for one minute.
During that time, it rolls a d6 and subtracts the number
rolled from all its attack rolls and ability checks,
as well as its constitution saving throws
to maintain concentration.
You can make an intelligence roll at the end of each turn
to see if you can break free.
And I rolled an eight on my Wild Magic Surge table,
Russ.
Well, the percentage dice.
Or the d20, not the percentage dice.
What were we at?
I think we're about six or seven.
So it's right about there.
OK, so we'll say we're at a seven now.
So if you roll seven next time, you'll get something.
I've written it down.
Will it be good?
Will it be bad?
Nobody knows.
That's the joy of Wild Magic.
Dragon's turns.
The two that were hit with the synaptic thing
basically can't do anything.
Yes, is that what I understood?
After a failed save, they have muddled thoughts for one minute.
During that time, you can roll a d6
and subtract the number rolled from all your attack rolls
and ability checks.
So you can still do things.
It's just penalized.
One of them is going to do acid breath
towards Bahamut and crew.
So everybody needs to make a dexterity saving throw.
We'll remedy that by subtract six from the saving throw.
So what was a 22 now is only a 16.
I am resistant.
So does that mean I get to roll a second time?
Resistant means half damage.
So 13.
Sorry, everybody with advantage because you're
in Bahamut's sphere.
That's 13 again.
Natural 20.
OK, 20 is good.
23.
3 is good.
17.
17 is also good.
So Glim and Matamar also grabbed on.
So Matamar is going to go.
Matamar doesn't do well.
So that's 15 d8 acid damage.
I have a thing where I can use my reaction to not,
if I succeed on a saving throw,
I can just not take the half damage.
So I'm going to do that.
OK, you're not going to take the half damage.
So Glim and Matamar are going to take 60 acid damage.
Oh, I might have a thing for that.
But I take half because I'm resistant, right?
And you're going to take half because you're resistant.
So I take 30.
Mut's going to take half.
Sully's going to take half.
Agatha's going to take nothing.
Rax is going to take nothing.
Because Rax is an acid thing, I think, right?
This isn't like being hit by an attack.
Yeah, because. Yeah.
Stupid dragon.
Cool stuff is for player characters.
Yeah, that's right.
OK, that acid breath brings out and everybody's just covered in this.
It burns your skin and it gets in your eyes and your lungs.
And even though, Agatha, you don't take any damage,
you still feel it like this cloud, this plume around you.
Bahamut surges forward and is like
sideswiped by another one of these dragons.
Everybody make a dexterity saving throw.
I'll get.
With advantage again?
With advantage?
Oh, well, I desperately needed the advantage.
Twenty.
Seventeen.
Nineteen.
OK, he's hit hard and you all managed to hold on.
You see Matamar, who was hit hard by this, get like bumped off.
He's basically non-reactive at this point.
He begins falling.
Bahamut tries to dip down to try and grab him.
Another one of these dragons comes down from the top
and goes for a Gotham Glim.
With an attack, a bite claw.
So the two bite or one bite is going to go towards Glim.
That's a 28.
One bite towards a Goth, a 30.
And a claw towards Glim.
That's a 34.
This wouldn't happen to be the dragon that I marked.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it is.
Because then it would have disadvantage against Glim.
Disadvantage on Glim.
OK, so two more rolls.
Well, that one is a 21.
So close, but they will still get me.
And that one is a 20.
That, oh, I am 20.
So it will also get me.
But just so it doesn't barely.
So that's going to be 19 piercing damage
and 15 slashing damage to Glim
and 19 piercing damage to a Goth.
I don't like that I have my calculator over here.
Tally-a-ball is too dangerous.
Below you, you see this crackling whirlpool of energy.
You look back and you see the entirety of Mount Celestia
being overrun.
And Bahamut calls back and he's like,
Glim, what did I write in the book?
The next entry.
It said not to come to Celestia.
You see him take this big claw and just scratching it
hard into the book itself.
In your book, it's being overwritten again.
It's just like a deeper cut into the page that you see.
It was already there.
And then he slams it shut and begins to dive down
towards this portal.
I give you a reaction before he
does whatever he's going to do.
I mean, I guess I'm just going to hold on
because I'm not jumping off.
I mean, I'm with him in whatever he's doing,
even though he's been a bit of a doofus.
So I'm just going to try and have an arm out to maybe
snag Matamar as we go by.
Oh, that's a great idea.
I see a Goth do that and also do the same
because our poor little buddy is having a hard time.
I summon my crab claw, Mayshant, to also try it.
It detaches from my hand and heads over there.
Bahamut falling in this spiral with these dragons closing
in quickly on you, crab claws zipping out.
And you manage to snag Matamar and pull him in
and hold on to him as you hit this portal.
And everything behind you, you
see all of these demons coming up from what you can presume
is a portal from the abyss.
You see this, you hear this thunderous echoing laughter
coming from closer to the mountain.
And as you hit the portal, Bahamut transforms back
into himself and is suspended in the portal
as you all fall through it.
You see him above as you turn back to look at him.
And he's pulling the, with all of his power,
pulling the portal closed behind you.
Somebody roll me percentile dice, please.
OK, remind me how these work.
I have a zero, zero, and an eight.
Is that 80 or is that eight?
That's eight.
Which could be great or terrible.
You never know with a percentile dice.
All of the numbers.
All of the numbers could be great or terrible.
Colors and light zip past you until all of these images
of Toriel and of all these fantastical, mystical places
and of this dark, terrible place.
And then you land hard.
All of you.
The wind is knocked out of you
and there's this radiating heat around you.
You're in this dim, red lit cave, it feels like.
You get up and you look around
and you see all of your travel companions.
And Goth, you're huddled close.
You have Mademar huddled close,
Rax is off into the side and standing up
and pawing at the dirt.
Do we see, sorry, did the portal close above us?
So we saw him close it above it.
I will be pumping a quick Spare the Dying
into Mademar, just in case.
Sure, yeah.
What does Spare the Dying look like
and remind me what it does?
You touch a living creature that has zero hit points.
The creature becomes stable.
The spell has no effect on undead or constructs.
OK, yeah.
So I'm assuming since he was.
You can stabilize him, yeah.
Yeah, he kind of coughs back to life.
Does anybody know where we are?
It's hot.
I mean, it is so hot in here.
But I mean, Bahamut must have had a plan that we would.
What, meet up later?
I don't know.
Well, we can't stay here.
We got to figure out where we are, right?
Flammikins gets up and starts to stumble off
towards a cave opening.
Well, hold on.
I think we should probably stay together.
Well, I thought you were going to follow me.
Wow, it's fucking like leadership.
Or are you giving off here?
OK, I'll follow you into a dark cave.
You all carry forward down this corridor
and you hear this rumble.
It's like low growl coming from up ahead.
That's like resonating the walls.
And you round a corner into this wide chamber.
There's this huge throne across the other side.
And in this chamber, there are
six chromatic dragons around the outside.
And in the throne is Tiamat.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season two, episode 130,
starring Amy More as Sully, Carla Maxdead as Glim,
Tom Laird as Moot, with Kristen Flemmons as Agath,
and Rust Moore as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing by Newt Shannelcott
and sound design by Rust Moore.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound, Artlist,
and Kavin MacLeod and sound effects from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library, and Sound Ideas.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Cat Waterfly,
Jacob Madden, Christian Brown, Craig Zeiss,
Erin Stevens, Daryl, Perry Matey,
L.A. Branton, Kayla Littlejohn,
Nathaniel Teeter, and Nicholas Cooper.
Help us reach our next goal of 115 patrons
where we'll release in-character positive
affirmations directly to our patrons
as well as on our TikTok.
Yeah, we're on TikTok too.
Join us today at Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast
and find us on Facebook and Twitter and TikTok.
Link is in the description.
Thank you for listening.
Have a great week.
We'll talk again soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.