Previously, on Dumpshens and Dragons.
I'll watch this, whatever you have coming up, see how you perform.
And if I think it's worth Orcus's time to actually have you draw attention to yourself
as to draw attention away from us, then we'll move forward with the plan.
Just so matter of fact, it sounds like they're on their way.
Fireball erupts, blasting you back and into the surrounding undead.
I'm just gonna try and do whatever damage I can.
Yeah, Margaret will start swinging her Mace of Disruption.
Armin, you got any plans here?
Just a moment, I can summon perhaps some help.
These four are proving an issue for you.
I'm gonna look up at the dais and then at Lex and then just fly forward and scoop my arms.
Not ready for this yet.
And he casts Dimension Door beneath you.
You know, he can see where Thelonious is, so he puts it like, just above him.
Oh please, dear boy.
And he casts Counterspell, which is not just going to shut your door, but rather redirect
your door.
And it's going to open at the top of the cavern.
Squirming black tentacles fill a 20 foot square, and they begin reaching up
and clubbing you.
I will use my reaction to cast Hellish Rebuke.
That I'm gonna fly down and do a shield strike and try to move him five feet and tumble him
down the stairs.
Arvid has to make a strength saving throw, which he does not make.
Things aren't going the way Lex wanted.
Now his boyfriend's half dead and his best friend's just fell from the ceiling.
It's very bad.
And then we hear this crack.
Margaret, you see Thea and what you recognize as Flint.
Going with a small, red-haired, pigtailed gnome.
The undead are quickly rushing back to them and there's another crack off into the distance
and a tall goliath falls down.
What the?
What is happening?
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More.
He, him.
Also with me today is Amy More.
I can barely hear anything.
What?
Your clap was so loud.
Uh, she, her.
And I'm playing today, guys.
I'm playing today and I'm playing, um, and I'm playing Thea Amastasia, she, her, and
I'm playing, uh, Gael Nighthunter, Ogla Kahnu, um, she, they.
Uh, yeah.
What I didn't realize in the last one is that Amy listed so many character names.
I was like, Oh, one of them's gotta be in it.
I didn't list any.
I said, I don't know.
Oh, okay.
Good.
Yeah.
I was like, I just knew Amy played so many characters, like one of them will
be in it at some point.
At the very, very end.
Nope.
Sorry.
I kept, I kept trying to be like, and what's Flank's up to at this moment?
And you're like, he's not, you're not in this one, Amy.
So if you heard heavy breathing in the back of that episode, that's just Amy hanging
out.
Uh, also with us, Rev Deshaime.
Hey, he, him, and I am Margaret Broadcloak, she, her.
And Tom Laird.
He, him, and I'm playing a very hurt Perseus and Flint.
And Kyle Claset.
Hey, he, him.
I will be playing Vorunax, he, him, and, uh, I'm excited to do this.
Let's go.
And Carla Maxted.
She, her, and I'll be playing Lex, he, him, and Lipsinki, she, her.
So many characters back.
We did it.
Everybody.
We, we, some people played no characters for one's show and, uh, and, and one
character.
How did it feel to play one individual character for a brief moment?
I mean, good until you, until you screwed over my idea.
Tom's holding on to some great stuff.
Tom's like, if it was my game, I totally would have let you Pac-Man his head.
Well, for the amount of times that you cried when I wouldn't let you use cloud
of daggers.
Lasset's a bit of a baby about it.
If you'd like to hear that, you can go to our Patreon, listen to the game that
Tom D.M.'s where he is the kindest D.M.
The kindest, gentlest D.M. who just handholds us through so many, lets us do
whatever we want.
Handholds and railroads at the same time.
It's quite weird.
Can the audience slip?
You just said kind-less.
You sure did.
And I was like.
But you also get an episode dedicated to you, like today's patron, Trent
Ash.
Hey Trent.
Thank you.
So much.
Nice, you Trent.
And you can join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
It would be the kind-less thing you could do.
And now fuck it, let's play.
Okay.
Ah.
Boom.
Crash.
The sound of my heart, the beat goes on and on and on and on.
Is that our entrance music?
I think so.
It's pretty good.
Yeah, I did feel good about that I think.
Yeah, I think that's pretty good.
A crack rings out and a thud as your body hits the ground, Nighthunter.
Tell me what you were doing before you ended up here on the beach back in the future.
Well, Nighthunter was ready to make a stand next to their beloved wife and like just ready
to essentially just die on the front lines I think.
Like her, Elia, I mean Opal was somewhere there too and just kind of ready to hold
down the fort or die trying.
Yeah, that's the last thing that she remembers.
As you stared down Orcus' forces, this crack rang out from the tent that blew it apart
that signified that the travelers with the intent to go to the abyss had left.
And you feel yourself as you rush forward being whipped up into this hurricane of energy.
You look to your side and you see Elia leaping off of these undead who looks back at you
and you lock eyes as you disappear from that scene.
You now lie prone on the stone floor of this cavern that you're in.
You hear groans of undead and swift moving behind you.
What do you do?
Can I use an action to spring up?
It would be half your movement.
It doesn't need to be an action.
You can use an action if you want to.
No, it's fine.
If you wanted to do that cool thing where people like jump to their feet from on their back.
Yeah, I want to do that.
But I'm not using an action for it.
I'm just going to do it.
I feel like that's just how Nighthunter gets up.
So run to the mill for her.
So she's like really big and bulky.
So I don't think that that she probably fell like forward in a crouching kind of like splayed
and then like slowly, you know, when people get up cool.
I don't know.
You know, people not springing up, but like stepping up and they're lifting their
head in the last moment.
Like the fuck is going on here?
And without even thinking, she just starts swing.
She's got her weapons, right?
Yeah, you have everything that was on you.
Just didn't lose it in the whipping tornado she got whisked away in.
Yeah, no, you had it in your hand, so likely it fell to the ground.
So you picked it up as you stood.
So as they get up during the last straightening moment, she whips her arm out
and slices to the side and behind her as she becomes aware that she is surrounded by the undead.
Because this is exactly the way she left things.
So she's just wheeled a corpse grinder around.
In a hurricane, undead are being dispelled
and the black ichor from their bodies is being plastered across the wall.
As everybody else sees this Goliath enter from who knows where
and begin clearing the spot around themselves.
Thea, Flint and Lipsinki.
You land, you see Night Hunter or the what presumably is Night Hunter
crash down a distance from you.
You've made Lex and Margaret off into the back
and Thea, you specifically see Thelonious at the top of the dais
with another figure who looks familiar kind of off into the shadows behind him.
Insert cool thing she says here.
Just cut it back in, Russ?
Yeah, we'll just do a couple takes later.
I don't know how it's going to be like.
I want to loose an arrow.
I don't want to waste any time.
Thea raises her head, sees Prim's bane,
grabs her oath bow and fucking just shoots an arrow at him.
And just does some whispering.
Swift death to you who have wronged me.
That's the sound an arrow makes.
I didn't know if you knew that.
All right, oh, please.
Fuck off.
Oh, no.
She's taking off her headphones.
She took off her headphones.
It's a bad sign.
It's fine.
What happened, Amy?
I don't want to talk about it.
You haven't said it in so long.
There's too much of a buildup.
It was too.
There's too much pressure.
I didn't make the right sound.
I didn't make the right sound effect.
Fuck.
OK, so Thea does what Thea does.
Just as she's even notching the arrow in the bow,
it's like Swift, and she's seething mad.
She's like, Swift death to you who have wronged me.
And she's like, can't get it.
And the performance, and there's things around.
And I don't even think she gets it off
and kind of it like boing.
And then she's like toothy in front of her.
That was fucking embarrassing.
God damn it.
Isn't that one, in case?
In case you can't tell.
I just wanted to say that out loud.
A lot of Verrocta, Nicktoe moment there.
I'm mad.
Well, I have another attack.
Can I fucking just try to?
Or is it like, is it done?
I think you're good.
You came back.
You said your sweet catchphrase.
You did what you usually do.
Roll a one.
So the fans are getting just everything they want.
This is a lot of fanservice going on.
This is the Endgame fanservice episode.
Thea, OK.
I just want to listen.
No, you know what?
Thea will just like contemplate her life choices
at this moment.
And I'll just like play Nighthunter for a while.
Flint and Lipsinki.
I'll throw my Dwarven Hammer at this asshole.
Thelonious is the asshole you're throwing at?
No, at Thea for fucking that up.
Get it together, asshole.
All right.
That's enough out of you.
That is a dirty 20 on the first one.
Nice.
The juxtaposition of our characters is just fantastic.
25 on the second one, Russ.
You loose your hammer, flies through the air,
goes out and it strikes him.
And then on the recoil, hits him again on the way back.
Give me some damage, please.
I can definitely do that.
12 on the first one.
And 12 on the second one.
Thea leans over and goes,
hey, thanks.
Thanks for stepping in there.
Yeah, you know I got your back.
Do you think they saw it?
Oh yeah, everybody saw it.
Especially that cool Goliath over there.
Lipsinki, you are looking around.
You see the chaos that's happening around you.
You hear just this,
before you met Vorunax,
how the messages you got from your patron
were echoing and distant and sporadic
and like there were multiple voices
coming from everywhere all at once.
Whereas after you met Vorunax,
things became a little more clearer.
Things are now back to that chaotic mind state
that you have been out of for 10 years.
You look up to the dais and you see the hammer fly
and it hits this dark elf
who falls from this flying position
down to the top of this dais.
And in that you see a figure
kind of move in and out of a shadow.
You get a distinct feeling
that this individual looks very much like Vorunax
who you left deceased back
in the timeline who was crushed by Orcus.
Y'all, y'all, he's here.
They landed us right here.
He's, I think, alright, you guys,
I'm just gonna go.
I gotta, Vorunax is up there,
so I'm just going to start making my way
to the front towards my friend.
Undead all in front of you.
Yep, yep, yep.
Okay, cool, cool, cool, cool.
I mean, I'll do something about that.
Yeah, no, I know that's what you were looking for.
I'm just laying the scene
so you're not just like, I'm gonna walk up.
I'm just gonna stroll on over.
Maybe bow as she passes.
That's right.
We all have questions.
Well, that's cool, but I'm not gonna do that.
Alright, don't.
Save that one for later.
I mean, don't save them all for later.
Russ might totally drop you from 250 feet in the air.
I think that I will just, like,
my bracers will turn into, like,
Sharpie's coming out,
and I'm swinging Sharpie the shovel back and forth
just to, like, clear it, you know?
Just to raise the undead in front of you.
Exactly, because now I've got a mission,
and yeah, I don't know Thelonious, so like,
he doesn't care about that at all.
Love that.
We see you break off from the group
and just begin cutting down people in front of you.
We go back to Lex and Margaret,
who have kind of, who have huddled down
behind a spot of rubble.
Margaret, you're holding off undead
as Lex, you are greatly injured
being torn at and crushed by the onslaught of undead.
We obviously, like, from our vantage point
have seen these people arrive.
Yeah, there's bright light.
If we determined that Lex and Lipsinki
do know each other from the prison,
we would not establish that.
They would have both been in there at the same time.
So they should for sure have a conversation.
I mean, certainly I feel like
Lipsinki knows Perseus in rat form.
Fuck yeah.
Right, because...
I forgot that thread, shit.
There's a never-ending,
there's a never-ending number of threads you've woven.
Yeah, this is on you.
I know, that's totally on me.
I forgot those two happened concurrent
or, like, right after each other,
like, because you played Lipsinki
and then we, on the escape, found Lex, right?
Yeah, yeah.
And Perseus.
Ah, son of a bitch.
All right, well,
Amy rolling out one, I forgot a storyline.
All right.
I don't know that that matters
other than Lex, like,
has a spark of recognition.
You would definitely recognize Thea and Flint.
Yeah.
Flint being much more Dragonborn-y looking
and then probably, yeah,
Perseus for sure would have recognized
Perseus as being attacked by Undead though.
He's a little preoccupied.
And I wouldn't recognize Perseus in this form
because I only knew him as a rat.
Yes, for Lipsinki.
If we are alive in a few minutes,
maybe they can reunite.
That'll be nice.
Yeah, cool.
Love it.
Great.
Yeah.
So, yeah, hint of recognition
maybe through an open door,
passing a window kind of thing
as you are being led to and from
different areas of the building.
Yeah.
Love it.
All that to say what I do has...
Margaret, what do we...
What do we do?
We came here, we found him
and he's...
They're very powerful,
those that just arrived,
but I feel like we failed.
Well, we're not going to do any good here.
We're going to make any kind of a chance.
We got to get to them.
You're right.
Let's go.
I start like schlogging my way forward,
not thinking of a good plan,
just like movement.
The two of you begin cutting your way forward
in this scene,
making your way to Flint and Thea
would be the first people that you approach.
Thelonious has fallen to the dais
and he turns and looks at Vorunax
and he says,
who are we even supposed to be distracting?
It's like you picked up in the middle of a conversation
from so long ago.
Well, at this point, Thelonious,
I don't think it really matters.
It seems like with the arrival of
some prestigious heroes,
you may actually find your end here
and if you really need to know,
well, water deep.
We were going for water deep.
Keep people in water deep
so we can set up a summoning pool
in Blackpool.
Something small,
something off the beaten path.
No one would think to look there.
But you'll take that secret with you to your grave
and if it's my turn,
I'll attack.
He's, for all intents and purposes,
prone at this point
so with advantage.
Oh, dope, dope, dope.
All right, that is going to be an 18.
Second attack is either a 25,
it's a 25.
Please make a wisdom saving throw
as you swing down towards Thelonious.
Okie dokie.
That wisdom saving throw is going to be a 32.
Wowza, wowza.
Give me some damage then.
All right, that's going to be
seven bludgeoning, 13 necrotic
and then the second attack,
it will be five bludgeoning damage,
20 necrotic.
Wow.
Wow, ouchie.
Forgot your wisdom was so fucking,
fucking good, hey?
Thelonious apparently didn't know who I was
but I knew who Thelonious was.
There you go.
You did your homework.
He was, for players,
he was trying to temporal shunt you
so basically you just disappear
to another point in time
and then return on your next action
at which point.
Very cool spell when it works.
Imagine all of us sitting there going like,
oh come on, the whole thing.
He was right there.
Another point in time,
that would have been great
and then probably dies like between
and then yeah, you never come back.
Yeah, oh.
But no, no, no, we got Jaypes.
Yeah, that's right.
Jaypes is in the wings.
Two huge blows go down into Thelonious
who crumples down to the ground.
He's not dead.
He's one powerful wizard.
Powerful wizard, hey?
Anybody playing the home game
keeping track of hit points, don't.
Meaty wizard.
That's right.
I'm just standing over
kind of like looking straight face down
and I'm like,
this is your end.
Not yet.
Ball you fucker.
And he casts Dimension Door beneath you.
Counterspell.
He casts Counterspell.
No, I don't think I can react
in a reaction, can I?
It's just an endless loop
of them counterspelling one another.
Now to be fair,
my Counterspell has to be cast
at a fifth level.
I have to be a role on that.
So Dimension Door is being cast
at a fourth level spell.
So you would,
so first you would need to
succeed on a,
what did we say?
A saving throw of something?
Wisdom, I think.
Wisdom.
When you cast a spell using a slot
of fourth or higher,
the interrupted spell has no effect
if the level is less than
or equal to the level
of the spell slot.
So I'm at fifth,
you're at fourth,
it would just cancel out
without a roll.
So it's canceled out.
Son of a bitch.
Okay, well then
then we're gonna do
what the internet says
and he's gonna try
and Counterspell you.
So you're casting it at fifth
so I gotta succeed on a
DC 10 plus the spells
level.
15.
Might work.
Okay, here we go.
Come on, big money,
big money, big money, big money.
It's a 16 on the die.
Ooh, nice.
Yeah.
So
the
the scene,
the portal is beginning
to appear beneath you
and you see Varanok's
casting Counterspell
which is
which is beginning to close
and then
Thelonious
says,
fuck no, not today
and wags his finger
up at Varanok's
that sends like this
reverberating
wave
that
just extinguishes
his Counterspell
and we see
Varanok's disappear
into the dimension door
and
we wanna drop you 250 feet
or do we wanna move you
somewhere else?
You do whatever you're feeling
what do you think
what do you think Thelonious
would do?
I think he'd drop you
250 feet.
Drop it like it's hot.
You go up
and you see Varanok's
begin to fall.
Lex and Margaret
you are beginning
to make your way
and you see
Lex specifically
you see over top of
these undead
and you see
Flint and Thea
beginning to walk away
from you
so like this point
in the middle
that would have helped you
is now moving
farther away.
I guess
I assumed
Rev, that Margaret
and I were also
gonna try and like
just dip in
and pick up Arvid
and Perseus
on the way
to where
you know, trying
you know, try and
get them out
I don't think
Lex is so focused
on vengeance
that he would be
forgetting
his
his one
true creepy love
and his best friend
so
I think
yeah
Thelonious is
a little bit
secondary
to Lex
than like
getting the hordes
off of his
Okay, you're making
your way to Arvid
he would have been
the closest at this point
you're clearing the way
Margaret
using her shield
and Mace
and you using
your sword
and you get to a point
where you
last saw Arvid
and as you get there
you
clear away
the undead
and
can you roll
roll me a dice please
what kind of dice?
a d20
a d20 dice
do I want to roll
low or high?
I want you to roll
it's for us
it's for a strength
saving throw
you get
to that point
and clear away
and you
see
the lifeless body
of Arvid
can
um
I don't
I don't know
if you want me
to describe him
but I'm going to
because
this is an audio
audio podcast
it's an audio
podcast
I guess
I do need you
to because
I need to know
like is he
dead dead
or like D&D dead
because
he can do if he's
just D&D dead
but if he's like
smushed
or something
yeah his body
has been picked
and torn apart
he is
spread
over a good distance
his belongings
no longer there
this isn't because of
the 12 I rolled
is it?
oh no
that's really rude
take responsibility
fuck
look I already rolled
and he died
I was trying to get you
to roll to save him
I think that
had
Lex been
built with tear ducts
there would be tears
but unfortunately
he does not have that way
of
expressing himself
but there probably is
even a further slowing
of
of his steps
like he is
quite
injured
himself
and already kind of
feeling like
I don't know if we can
win this day
yeah so like
it's a real bummer
I guess is what I'm
saying it's real
downer here
Margaret you
I mean you see the
scene ahead of you too
but you also see
the
the downturn
in Lex
and the slowing
of
what
they're doing
yeah I think that
you know this is
not a
sight that is
unfamiliar to
Margaret
of having
lost people
in a battle like this
especially something
this large
and
you know pushing
back at these
undead with the
shield
come on Lex
we gotta keep moving
don't let it be
for nothing
you
you're right
Perseus is
still
there and
I just
I want us to be
alive and
I want
Thelonious to be
dead but
I want us to be
alive more
two of you begin
pressing forward
again
Thea and
Flint
you
follow in behind
Lipsinki
you
had your eyes
set on
who you saw
as Vorunax
and were further confirmed
stepped out of the shadows
to
try and strike down
Thelonious
you now see
Vorunax dimension
doored up
and now falling
250 feet
down
towards
the earth below
think of that
what can I do
save my friend
does Thea
see it too
can
she help out
if
Lipsinki
is
at this point
Thea
Thea and Flint
you would have seen
Vorunax
step out
especially after
Lipsinki called
and said
he's here
that's where you were
making it too
so all three of you
see this scene
Vorunax falling
can I do something
cool
you gotta do it now
if you're gonna do it
Thea looks up
and sees
Vorunax
fall through
a portal
in the ceiling essentially
and she
runs forward
and
using her
wild shape
which she doesn't
get off into
because apparently
she forgets she's a druid
she will
she wild shapes
into a
clockwork
dragon
and flies
upward
to intercept
or to at least
at the very least
slow down
uh
Vorunax's fall
good timing
uh
yeah for everybody else
you see this
the cool foley
that's playing in the background
is really
really awesome
as this
as this mechanical
dragon
explodes from the ground
uh
and Vorunax
you see
one moment you're
on the ground
trying to counter spell Thelonious
next you're
falling
towards the ground
and you see this dragon
rushing up
beneath you
what do you do?
uh
just go
I didn't know he could
just summon
did okay
that's very different
I'm gonna try to
grab onto the dragon
because I definitely
don't want to fall
no take it from me
it's not great
no
you reach out to grab
the dragon
unbeknownst to you
is trying to save you
as well
so I feel like
this
this works
because you're both
trying to do the same thing
without knowing
that you're doing
the same thing
right
so Thea is going to
I assume
put yourself in a good position
to be able to be
have parts of you
grabbed by
yeah I'm hoping
he's gonna like
land kinda on my back
grab my tail
kinda situation
right
I mean I'm not like
a giant creature
but I
could at least
slow a fall
as the scene
plays out
I assume there's
a bit of uncertainty
not knowing
who the dragon
came from
but
clarity comes
at least in some
respect
when you're able
to grab onto the dragon
and it doesn't
just try and
chomp chomp you
from the feet up
you then said
you go
and try
and dragon
and breath
weapon
yeah as I'm sailing
forward
in the direction
of
Thelonious
I want to release
a fire breath
it's a 15 foot cone
must make a
dexterity saving throw
what happens is
his protective dome
comes up
of course it does
as he sees you
go to save Vorunax
and then fly
another 150 feet
towards him
time and perspective
works in his favor
in that moment
fine
as my breath weapon
doesn't
work
we
I slow us
to the ground
on the dais
I hover in the air
hey everybody
welcome to the middle
thought I'd come in nice
and quiet
just kind of like
sneak in here
because I have something
that I want to tell you
it's almost my birthday
and because it's
almost my birthday
I've decided to do
game time this month
and we've got two
amazing people
who are going to be
but
I'd really love
three
three's my favorite number
so
maybe even four
five would be great
so I'm getting a little
greedy
it is my birthday though
so consider it
because I would love
to play with you
you're doing so well
we weren't sure
if we wanted to
steal the shadow
or the thunder
I know
that was like
100% Amy
and 100%
great
and that's how Amy runs
game time
is 100% great
100% great
I know exactly
10 out of 10
greats agree
everybody always
has a great time
at Amy's table
and we can't wait
well Carla's playing
in it
because Carla never
gets to play with Amy
at game times
and it is always
shenanigans
always
always shenanigans
so
Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast
you can sign up
for any tier there
but if you want
to play in Amy's
game time
which is coming up
on
April
23rd
the year of right now
you can play with Amy
it's a morning game
for us
so it's like
a lunch hour
eastern-ish
game
but all the details
are at Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast
take it out Amy
I'd really love it
if you could come
play with me
for my birthday
make sure that
you put Baileys
or something
in your coffee
because you're gonna need it
it's gonna be crazy
did Amy mention
it's her birthday
guys
no pressure
birthday
but a little bit of pressure
because that's what
birthdays are for
so
so there you go
it's an important one
all right
love you bye
I mean do it
let's go back to flint
and Lipsinki
dragon
goes to save
Vorunax as both of you
are like flipping
through your Rolodex
of cool vines to do
and other doors to open
Bea's got this one
you see Thelonious
the protective shield
that
is put up
I want to cast
haste
on
Lipsinki
what does that give
target speed
is doubled
gains plus two bonus
to AC
has advantage on
deck saving throws
and gains additional
actions on each
of his turns
and additional action
nice
so that
that action can be used
to take the attack
dash disengage hide
or use an object action
Lipsinki is going to
now attack Thelonious
cause now
Thelonious did
some shit
to Vorunax so
she knows him now
so she's going to
eldritch blast him
normally only has
one attack but
I'm pretty sure
I just got another one
in case it
changes your mind
you did see
that protective barrier
go up as a flame
of dragon breath
didn't seem to
hit him
well god damn it
that's my coolest
thing I can do
why can't I
hurt him
what's your dig speed
my dig speed
great question
I think it's under sharpie
yep
it's very long
cause
it's a cool
it's a cool thing
someone made
thank you Devon
digging speed by
feet
cut through
stone
at one foot
per action
that's rough
I mean better
than a regular shovel
yeah absolutely
true
yeah so I can attack
that fucker
or I can
but it's just a waste
so I don't want to
do that
you have clocked
that there's another
group in the room
also making their way
towards
yeah
I mean
if Lipsinki was
a different person
I think that would matter
yep that's fine
no that's tough
yeah
so I'll just
I'll just keep
keep going
and going faster now
and
and attacking zombies
with sharpie
I guess
on the way to
Thelonious
cause now
I don't like him
Lipsinki
you take off
Flint
in hot pursuit
night hunter
how's night hunter doing?
how is night hunter?
probably loving it
probably killed like
2000 zombies
emotionally
not great
no
feeling
very at a place
like
just playing the
look on
Elia's face
as she was sucked away
over and over
and over again
which I just think
intensifying
the amount of slashing
and chopping
and slicing
that she is doing
in this group of undead
scene we see
with night hunter
is like these
like in the action movies
when
when like
John Wick is remembering
his dog
in that moment
with the quick
like flashes back
to the one you love
it sounded goofy
but the
the sentiment is there
absolutely
yes yes
she's feeling all the
John Wick feeling
has slowed down
and you're just
carving through
the things around you
taking the occasional
like claw
or bite
or
or like thud
against you
you get rushed on
and like blast them
apart
at one point
and it's
and it's really cool
yeah
cause I mean like
just leaving
a pile
of bodies
yeah
Lex and Margaret
you are slowly
making your way
towards where
Perseus
was last seen
Tom has
has rolled a strength
saving throw for me
Tom please
tell everybody
what that is
so it's not like
I'm just making shit up
it was an 18
ok
you're clearing away
and you get
you get over top
of where
Perseus was
and you see
his belongings
in the bag
in the clothes
and it looks like
he's
gone
I think
Lex
like falls to his knees
Perseus
are you
are you here
I
and maybe even
is sadly
kind of like
trying to look around
like
for parts
just to know
for sure
that he's gone
cause
it's definitely
not exactly
the same scene
that you saw with Arvid
and you
are moving through
his belongings
and
Margaret
you're holding back
the undead
the undead around you
and
you hear
a small squeak
and
Perseus the rat
makes his way
out of the
clothing
and
the satchel
and out of that
and scurries up
your arm
and into your pocket
oh
Perseus
thank god
we'll
we'll figure it out
or you can stay like that
if you want
that's fine too
I just
oh
and
still kind of on my knees
I think I just look at Margaret like
okay so
grateful
cause I've really just been counting on her to keep me safe
as I'm
doing this very ill advised thing
like crawling around on the floor
and
yeah
get up and feel
like
a bit renewed
I'm not
completely alone
again
this is the moment Lex
we could leave
we could fly out that door right now
do you want to keep going
or are we
are we staying
well like you said
we can't
we can't make it all for nothing
Arvid's
gone and we've made it all the way here so
I think
I think we keep trying
if
if you're willing
I think in response
I scoop him up now that he has found
now that we know about the two other party members
and
actually fly us to
the center group
part of the scene
Margaret scoops Lex and Perseus
is
inside of Lex's shoulder
Flint and Lipsinki
are making their way towards the dais
the
the clockwork dragon and Vorunax
are hovering just above the dais
setting down behind Thelonious
who is
who is standing up
before everyone
making their way towards him
and Margaret and Lex
you are the first
to
make your way to the top of this dais
as you get over top of it
Margaret
how do you
release Lex
yeah I think I
I just land us both down
the two of you land down in front
of Thelonious who looks at you
and
Lex it was supposed to be
so much better with the two of us
it wasn't supposed to be this messy
right Vorunax
it wasn't supposed to be this messy okay
you can still
you're strong
you you can
you can still come
help me
help
you
I would never
help you
and I guess I'm going to try and attack him
I know he's in his little bubble
because he's a big wiener
as as he's
as he's just
softening quote unquote
trying to
in in
get your mind out of a gutter
you can't call him a big wiener
and then you talk about him
fair enough
my bad
as he's trying to relay
this emotion towards you
Rev belongs here
yeah
he
and you
grab your weapon
and begin to charge towards him
his face shifts
and
Margaret you feel
the same heat
as
when he last cast fireball
and you see it welling up
in his hands in front of him
and he releases it
towards Lex
as Lex is charging towards him
I'm going to use Vigilant Guardian
which lets me switch places with someone
like seeing that this
I know that we are both in bad shape and seeing
this fireball coming at
Lex
I switch places with him
the fireball erupts
towards Lex
and Lex you see this light
rushing towards you
and in a flash you are
back and off to the side
and you see Margaret
taking the brunt of this
fireball
engulfed in this flame as it passes
over her
further back into this cavern
exploding on the wall
describe the stance
describe the scene that
Lex sees of Margaret
there is this moment
where they
switch places
that it's like this shield
kind of breaks in front
of Lex and
moves him back
into the side
and as the fire
runs over the shield
and starts to engulf Margaret
she
is bracing against it and looks
back at Lex
and there's just a little bit of a smile
and with her free hand she casts back
her mace to
Lex's feet
and then the smile
and Margaret are both
gone
there's a look of
satisfaction in Thelonious's
eyes then a look of confusion
as he sees not Lex before
him but Margaret
and he looks over to
Lex with this
almost relieved
sensation washing over his
face
ah well I guess I pick up that dope mace
don't want that
to be for nothing
as you pick up the mace you see that
in the leather
around it it has a
something etched in it and it says
we watch out for those
who others overlook
and as I read
that I think I'm gonna quickly reach
into my pocket and pull
Perseus out and give him a little smooch on his
cute little furry head
say you take care of yourself buddy
and put him down cause I'm gonna run
at Thelonious again and I don't
wanna carry him there
with me
Thelonious is stunned
for all intents
and purposes and is not moving as you
run towards him
as sort of fast as I
can with my
shambling body
I go towards him
with that mace
sort of in my last
stand against him
because
I'm not doing so great either
you rush across and you swing
down hard into
Thelonious
Margaret's mace
crushes down into his body
you hit him hard once and he falls
to the ground
in disbelief and anger
and fear
you reach back to hit him
a second time and as the mace
hits this black
pool
extends out from beneath you
and splashes up and
around the two of you
and crashes
down and we hear crushing
crushing
and as this wave roils
out the two of them
are gone
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 2
Episode 120
Jamie Moore as Thea and Nighthunter
Carla Maxted as Lex and Lipsynke
Tom Laird as Perseus and Flint
with Kyle Claset as
Vorunax, Rev DeShane
as Margaret Broadcloak, and Russ More
as your dungeon master
A huge thank you to our good friend Rev
who joined us consistently
over the last three years to bring
Margaret to life as a part of Team
Lex. What started as
a fun side arc one shot
turned into a story of dedication
to the heart while bringing workers
rights to the forefront across the realms
Thank you, Rev
Hear more from Rev on his
show, The Crit Show, available
anywhere you listen to podcasts
Production and sound design of this episode
is by Russ More
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound, Boom
Library, and Sound Ideas
A huge thank you to our supporting producers
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok
Kat Waterflame, Jacob Madden
Christian Brown, Devin Michaels
Craig Zeiss, Aaron Stevens,
Daryleth, Lulahan, Charlie Warley
L.A. Branton, and Nathaniel Teeter
You can support us and the shows we
create directly by visiting Patreon.com
slash dumbdragoncast. Join us today
to help us reach 100 patrons and when
we do, we'll host another hilarious
and amazing exclusive live
show for each and every one of our patrons
Thank you for listening. Have a
great week. We'll talk again soon
Guys, I'm like
98 degrees
which is absolutely true
But like in like centigrade
No, in like Kelvin, I'm not sure
I feel very warm right now. I'm really mad
But what happened?
I feel like I've been waiting
such a long time to play
and to like
fight this character
I've never been on an
episode where you have gotten to play
so I think
Is it living up to
To all the hype
Rev has been coming back year
after year after year
Just waiting to play with me
Yeah, it's everything that you thought it would be
and more, right? Yeah
You know, if someone was going to roll one die
in my presence
Why not that one? It's going to be that one
Can I do my
cool thing or do you want time
to look something up? I guess
I guess, do you want to talk amongst
What's going to be the coolest thing to do?
Okay, here's my
thing. I want to
shape shift into a clockwork
dragon. I want to fly
and catch him on my
back and as I'm soaring toward
Thelonious, I want to let out
fire breath, Adam
Well, I mean, I don't know what I could do
that would be cooler than that, so
I feel like
I feel like that's a pretty fucking
good one
I was going to summon a vine out of the wall to try
to catch him
You know, I was like, I can open a different
door, but that's just going to send him
somewhere bad
I'm trying to get this guy
to like us, so
I love that plan
I switch places with him
Counterspell on Margaret
Just to be a dick
You're not getting your Obi-Wan Kenobi moment hurt
If Russ had just
described that and I was like, oh man, that's too
bad
That's awesome
Dumbgeons and Dragons
is a Dumb Dragons production