previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
vision goes black you were supposed to wait in the library you'd have now entered the masters house
his home and his place hmm this isn't going to be good this isn't going to be good i'm
gonna have to try and clean this up you just you just wait right where you are i will come
find you later see an image of yourself in this first mirror but something about it is
very different as you kind of address Mannix they reach their hand up and touch the mirror
Mannix i'm i'm sorry i i know what it means to lose a loved one and i can't imagine how you
feel seeing them again but we i don't think we can stop here memories flood back of Mannix
talking about Leona and going on these adventures and going to visit Leona's father you forget why
you ask that question welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons we're a D&D fifth edition actual play
podcast and i'm your dungeon master Russ More and with me today is Amy More oh you caught
me like in the middle of a yard i was trying to drag it out a little bit there see if i
could get by it you didn't i'm Amy More i play Thea Amastasia a high elf druid and Carla
Maxtead that is me bright-eyed and bushy-tailed i play Yen Bull Nury a Kalishtar cleric and Tom
Laird also here and i play Flint Firebeard and he is a champion dwarf fighter hey everybody
did you know that today's season two episode 50 what that feels like a halfway there mark but
since we don't have an end episode goal like we do in facing fate it's like it's just nothing
it's just a number it's it is it's just a number that one day we'll look back at and
be like remember when we'd only done 50 episodes of this season we were so young and
naive back then we were so young then 14 years from now season two is still happening exactly
Russ hasn't booked us into 2021 yet so you know all right i gotta do that by the end of
the week anyways oh god uh where we have even more content that you can go listen to is
Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast we have an entire other show over there
exclusive to patrons called the adventures of which was a tentative name that just kind of
stuck for the last four seasons yeah yeah we're just fine um i blame the dm yeah that guy yeah
when you ask the dm hey give me a title to your thing and he's like ah whatever i'll get it to
you next week and then you gotta post it now in my defense russ i named the damn thing the
side scrollers so yeah but then we did other things that kind of fell under side scroller
umbrella i gave you a name it's not my fault you threw it away yeah it's true yeah it is my fault
oh no it's russ's fault again yeah tom really turned that around on you yeah you did you
you were like oh just mention it i've been waiting yeah he's been falling into my trap
this one's been canned for a while um but when you are a patron you get an episode
dedicated to you like today's patron angela hoppner thank you you guys know what i heard
what's that angela hoppner's pretty fucking rad i heard the same thing weird rumors are vicious
around i hadn't heard that yet but i'm really glad i have now because i feel like i'm finally
in the loop yeah you know i i saw it scrawled on a bathroom wall wow angela fucking rocks
that's what i saw Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast you can have your name scrawled
no i won't do that no it wasn't like for a good time now fuck it let's play dnd no no
i'm not done talking about this angela that's not what i meant i just meant you fucking rock
you're looking down at manic's as they turn to face you and say
what do you mean you're sorry for the loss of my daughter um i don't i don't know why
it's it's okay i'm sorry it's okay we have to keep going the longer we spend here the more
shangalar will play with our minds manic's turns and begins walking down the hall in the
direction you were heading i also follow i mean i'm still kind of looking in the mirrors as we
as we pass because how could you not i'm definitely having a glance as well
yeah you see those same images play over and over of thea in this more monk attire
thea in back in the university older than she was when she was there but like she never had left
flint working hand in hand with his his family his father his sister down in the mines at
mithral hall and yen bull leading this charge of the calum port army across the land against
an unknown entity across the way you follow manic's and you leave the hall of mirrors and it
it's this as you were walking through it's this carved out hollowed out as if you're
walking through a tree and as you leave the mirrors the tree begins to fade and morph
into more of a rock facade
and you see moisture begin to build up and the further you go
moss and algae begin to sprawl across the ground and up the walls manic's is walking
straight ahead and you see up ahead that light but it's getting nearer now
wow and it's glowing brighter into the opening at the end of this hallway
and it looks like it opens into a room should we slow down we should
so i i agree we must approach the light but let's not yes yes of course
guys it's the weirdest fucking pyramid i've ever been in
yes it's been i thought it would all be stone but instead tree mirrors and tree and the most
beautiful bathroom i've ever seen i know it was that's really gonna stick with me it's
haunting it's a hauntingly beautiful i shall never see another one it's like ever again
are you feeling that kind of like feeling of loss and grief like there i suspect i will never
see it again yeah i guess we'll just have to see what is at the end of this rock hallway
oh my god maybe it's another bathroom oh okay no but it's probably not so it's probably
not it's probably a monster we should be ready we should be ready does it feel like fluorescent
lighting like are we gonna look terrible in there i mean it looks like a dim uh like
almost like a dancing light that shimmers with like this rainbow irradiance oh everyone's gonna
look in there never i thought maybe it'd be worry gone i thought maybe it might be like
the waiting room from beetle juice um yes uh i mean we didn't know what we were walking into
but shangular is prepared for many individuals and clearly wallace has taken some design
liberties the man's a fucking genius though i mean this is the trick of of shangular it has not
been frightening yet it has not been it it makes me more scared than if we had seen
many fearsome creatures that's true i can kill a monster can't kill a creepy room filled with
mirrors you okay am i okay yes why i don't know you just touched one so immediately i'm
suspicious feeling energized as ever and ready to find our way to this lich okay
can i like ready in action if we open the door and something comes at us can i like
oh there's no door is gonna end oh it's an open okay well if something attacks us through
the archway can i like ready if like a fireball in my hand sure yeah okay cool i want to do that
okay yeah we can say that you have that kind of prepped and ready to go is yeah
i can just hold fire no big deal sure yeah why not why not we live in a magical world
fucking amistacia okay yeah you are decimators of dragons baby
baby anybody else want to say that they ready any particular item well i think i have my mace
of terror out but i think we just kind of have as we have been i don't i don't remember if i
said it before but as we're walking through the scary lich's flying pyramid sure probably
yeah i'd assume you were like the sweetest and you have like
like your freaking terror stick i assume i have my moist tongue longsword out but not
moistened yet yeah you don't want to pre-moisten it it's just a bit much yeah makes the floor
all slippery we're all slipping and sliding on it also slippery floor signs everywhere
me right it goes against his aesthetic so
um okay you've all readied your or you know you're ready to go as if something were to jump
out at you um and you walk slowly towards this room and it's kind of takes a bend and and
goes into this like open uh more cavernous looking chamber and dim light dances in the air
and it shimmering through the colors of the rainbow and gently lighting the walls of this
cavern you see a few piles of bones and scraps of gear litter the floor throughout here but do
i see your true colors shining through do i see your true colors and that's why i love you
please don't say us
to let them show uh russ do i see anything in the pile of gear and
bones and anything that looks of interest and also to clarify are these piles of human bones
or like rib bones from the dining hall oh good good clarifying yeah um they do this is just
the bone room uh they they do look like um perhaps human or humanoid bones um everybody
i am assuming we've moved past the front entryway uh yeah carefully peeking around
the corners being all sorts of careful i'm not losing all my hit points in the first
fucking interaction stupid flying pyramid it's not happening i mean with the smile on russ's
face you might be so we will i know big shitty grunt over here i don't know what you're talking
about everybody make a wisdom saving throw as you enter you just finished singing true colors
to us i know he's really lulling us uh sorry what was that and wisdom saving throw wisdom
saving throw fuck you yeah 25 bitch wow i have a plus 10 wisdom saving throw i have a plus
nine and i only got a 14 so thank god i got that plus nine i'm probably still gonna die
i'm just gonna fire up in the character sheet which i realize i did not have open
you fire up your character you know what we've been doing this for a long time folks
and tom over here big guy thought he could do it without his character you know what it's
what kind of plus do you have on your saving throw so you don't know those off my heart
you've been playing this character for 85 years i mean i should know it second skin now
this he is you all right so we're just doing a oof we're doing a wisdom save
yeah got it right minus one on a 15 is a 14 oh okay wait so thea's got a 10
Yenbul's got a nine yep manix has a 10 and you got a minus one that's awesome your head
band doesn't help with wisdom only intelligence that's intellect yeah damn that's good that's just
well you know what good you have to have some fries somewhere i was gonna say he's very very
strong and good at fighting you can't be good at everything no it's awesome this character
can't do anything only magic now we're in a fucking flying ledge fortress so sorry tom what
what did you get 14 14 okay uh which like is still pretty good it's fine i was delighted
with my 14 but only because i rolled a five you should be proud of your 14
no because i got a 14 too i was like don't you bash that 14 that's right i'm like motherfuckers
25 in your face feel bad for all the 14s out there that's right wow amy's color does not
look good on amy jeez um they all of you save uh so you walk into this room and yeah
the colors are shining through the rainbow colors the colors are Glimering are the color
shining through the rainbow colors i don't know i've lost the description here this fucking
lights everywhere kind of like rainbow connection into the room yes yeah yeah yeah that's exactly
what you feel um you go and examine does it shine bright like a diamond like a diamond
we're in all the songs today you know what i feel like we've been missing out on certain
parts of this from our podcast lately you know we've been getting really and sometimes
you just need to add inject a little bit of silly back into it um you go into this
room and round this corner and the lights seem like they're coming from no particular
location they're coming from everywhere like a disco ball somewhere yeah but you can't trace
it back to anything you go look closer at the gear and at the remains that are in this
room and they do appear um human or humanoid as previously described and the gear is old
and rusted you look through and there's um there's broken up shields there's blades
that seem to have been bent snapped bow um one of the figures is wearing um
um like full plate armor and has like this amulet around their um around their neck
nobody touch the amulet yes i think it seems like a bad idea to take from the dead in this
place oh well that and i like you know those things nine out of ten usually cursed so oh
but yeah yours is much more moral what what makes you say it would be cursed thea the
dude's dead didn't he well obviously wasn't lucky looks like a stab wound that killed them
how can you tell that he is but bones there is a blade sticking okay bones
fine well i mean you're you guys are good at magic is there a way to tell if it's
cursed or anything like that before we touch it i can tell if it's magical but i can't tell
if it's cursed so i'm just gonna leave it but manic's if you want to pick it up um
i'll kill you if you go crazy if you want me to perfect love it uh let's see just offering
that that you know it's it's a friendship thing right i mean flint you know well if
you can detect if it is magical i can dispel the source of magic can you yes oh well hold on
and then it will just be pretty and then it will just be pretty yeah it's kind of like this
this design that's like it loops around the corners on the outside and like feeds into itself
does seem pretty yeah um i don't know yen bull doesn't seem comfortable with
sorry robbing the dead is that it's just this is a warrior i assume who came here to fight the
lich that we are trying to fight and if there was weapons i would feel like we could take
those but just to take a piece of jewelry for no reason yes could be a family heirloom
um could have been and you would find the family and track them down oh god i wish man
our list is so long and the steps we got to do that'd be so far down i'd be afraid that
it would get lost but if you want to track the family down like well i don't know if you
need a little side adventure after all this is over see how optimistic i am that this is
gonna go our way i feel like one i love your optimism two i'm a little worried about
my whole city being destroyed i might be busy well what if this is something that could help
us i just i just bend down and i go hey amulet magic and i cast detect magic it glows it glows
with a because you get the source of magic right i do believe it's a an abjuration school
of abjuration you can get a sense that it is perhaps a warding spell of some sort that has
been cast on the amulet at the same time as you ask hey you magic you get a strong glow
coming from further into this room this room kind of wraps around a corner and the
the lights that are all the colors of you know rotating through the colors of the rainbow
as you ask as you cast detect magic the source of whatever this light is becomes apparent to you
it's further and around this bend and it's like emanating brightly from the center or
leading further into this room so only i can see this yeah um i say kind of absently
yeah that that thing's like magic and i say but the light over here
and i start to wander toward the the bright light uh good good good magic uh like take it
magic or uh uh warding warding spell i mean that's
that's good that's good magic usually unless it's warding against you um this light is
coming from over here manix reaches down and grabs it and no ill effect and picks it up
puts it in their satchel um i think i'm kind of following thea because the group follows
further into this room it opens up into a wider chamber that immediately you see
thea you see the source of whatever is casting this this light throughout the room but around
it are several other creatures you see six zombies kind of shambling around the center where
you see the center of this light everybody else just sees the colors throughout the room
um but you see six zombies you see two uh zombified warriors they have like full plate
armor head uh gear they carry swords with them and there are two like flashing floating lights
also like just mindlessly shambling for lack of a better term around the center of this
wider chamber that you walk into and as you enter and see them it doesn't look like they
acknowledge you is there six normal zombies and then in plus two warrior zombies plus two
unknown kind of floating right luminescent things so a total of 10 10 bogies things
okay um i whisper to my friends um there's something in the middle of the room creating
like what does it look like to me just a big bright light there's just a big bright light
in the middle of the room and i think it's you know how moths are drawn to a flame
i have i think that might be what's happening here considering we're standing here and
nothing's attacked us yet the school because you're gonna get the school on that one
at least i'm not gonna get schooled that's right um but we don't see the creatures or
we see the creatures but not the light yeah you all see the creatures but not like the
but not the light source magic stuff yeah um and the school of magic is enchantment
for you detect magic
oh maybe i'll tell yen but well no i was just like usually i'm surrounded by people who don't
do magic so it's like it doesn't really matter yeah i mean manic says too like i could be like
yo flint it's enchantment and he'll be like cool i don't care um it looks like it's an
enchantment maybe somebody else has been here before us and we are
you know reaping the benefits of their trap that is still set perhaps i can't imagine shangla
would have zombies and undead here and then not have them ready to attack us yeah they
definitely look preoccupied is there enough room to like skate around these circling moth-like
zombies um yeah yeah you could walk by them yes i would like to do that um i would recommend
nobody touch them when you charm somebody it's just best you don't touch them flint don't touch
okay as you're as everybody's walking by let's do either an acrobatics or a stealth
as while there is room to walk by like they are kind of shambling around
you need to maneuver dodge and weave
um you softly begin to move closer to them and intermingle with them and beyond where they
are walking you see through the light comes clear that there is another opening to another chamber
as the three of you move past you hear a clang of armor and you look back over your shoulder
and manix has bumped into one of the armored zombies who takes a stumble closer to the light
and then back and as manix tries to just kind of softly step away it turns and looks
towards you and begins to shamble with its sword raised towards manix roll for initiative
is it just this one that has been disturbed just the one guys we try to try to kill that
one but but don't touch anything else nat 20 i wasted it plus two 22 uh 11 hear my sadness
17 all right thea you are up first okay maybe we can get manix to like lure it
over to where we are so it separates from the group
that'd be great um
can i be like manix to like closer to the wall to get it closer to the wall so you are
saving your action until manix moves them because manix is next in the order but um i would like
god i'm gonna you know what i'm just gonna do it um i whisper i bring out my oath bow
and i whisper swift death to those who have wronged me uh and i aim it at the head of this
fucking zombie and what i'm trying to do is i'm trying to hit it um as it's shambling
so that it's not going to fall like i'm gonna make sure there's no zombie directly behind it
you know like i'm not i'm trying to avoid a domino effect right so that's what i'm gonna do
so i'm gonna i'm gonna roll
as she says confidently i'm gonna roll um that's a 17 17 glances off the chainmail that this
creature is wearing and goes into the back of one of the other zombies
and it turns and begins to shambles towards you as well um i have another turn okay
how can amy make it work oh wait no i'm sorry oh god i just i just finished reading the paragraph
i have advantage on that role okay sorry because i knew my oath bow did something
can we back it up just a moment is it if you name it as your enemy though yeah and how
often can you do that uh if it dies i can name another enemy so it's like a hunter's mark
essentially yeah yeah um when i make the attack against my sworn enemy i have advantage on the
role and my target gains no benefit from cover well that doesn't make any sense um
and if it takes a hit it's an extra 3d6 piercing damage
damage okay that's better that's a 19 plus 7 so 26 that will hit so okay we rewind
the glancing blow doesn't actually happen and then the arrow strikes true into this creature
roll damage okay it gets 1d8 plus 2 and then 3d6 17 damage of the piercing variety
does it die no oh but at least it didn't hit the other one so you know that's does it fall
or does it just no it just yeah it kind of goes into its chest breaks through the chain mail you
hear the crunch of bones beneath it um and it continues forward it's manic oh no sorry i get
another turn all right because that was the advantage oh my god amy taking up all the turns
what is happening is this what it's like when i play yes okay that was a 9 plus 7 which
doesn't hit but i get advantage oh my gosh 19 plus 7 again oh my rolls are great uh so that hits
and it is 20 piercing damage tell me how you kill this uh this one goes straight through the
eye the skull crunches inside of its helmet and you hear it like like break apart and fracture
as it falls to the ground and i yell manic's catch it manic's reaches out and catches it why
am i catching it drag it away because if one trips on it that could stop their right thing
yeah sure it begins to drag it away not sure why i caught it and just dragged it but okay
yeah yeah so it didn't fall into something damn it manic's just doing it doing it he drags
it off to the side okay let's i was close and you leave the room i don't know does manic's
make it across without bumping into anything else he was like on the other side okay then
yes then yes okay you walk through the rest of this room you hear the zombies just rock back
and forth as you enter this new chamber it's a dark kind of 30 foot hallway that narrows
to a 10 foot um like 30 foot wide hallway that narrows to a 10 foot wide exit into
this room that you can see water lapping up in the center of um as you are about to enter
sorry the water is in the center of the hallway the water is in the center of the
room that you are about to enter okay so through the hallway into the next room you can see that
there is a lake or a pond or some or a pool of some sort that is in the center of this darker
room that you are entering and from the light that you were seeing in the last one
it takes a minute for your eyes to kind of focus and adjust as you enter into this darker
chamber is there like edges around is there an exit on the other side like what can we see
we just walk in and there's like water in the middle have you walked into you've walked
completely into the room or are you still in the hallway i think we're just like peeking
in okay um yeah you peek in and it it's more cavernous looking like dark rock black walls
um you see the the the water in the center um and it is just in the center there is a perimeter
around um and there are like jut outs in along the side of the walls and within you see
a shimmer of water kind of floating in place in each of these different jut outs that you
can see um from your vantage point you don't see an egress you do see a wider opening
often to the right but you don't know if it leads anywhere from where you're standing
um so on like the so like there's tidal pools on the fjords into the water is that what's
happening like the in each of the the jet outs yeah um so um not really i might not have
described that well so around the cavalry statues not not really more spheres um so these
alcoves hold these enormous globes oh i see so yeah they're suspended in in the air of each
of these each of these alcoves that you see around from your vantage point you can see
three of those spheres and the spheres seem like they're made of water i see so can you
guys swim pretty good or seems like there's definitely a monster in there right oh yeah
why else why else have a pool what's up with the water circles you can never trust a lich
to just have a pool because it is relaxing or a nice feature to have in your flow in your
flying pyramid just seems like only to keep a monster right so we don't want to disturb
this monster then i don't want to disturb the monster should we try to sneak around to the
right where the it seems like perhaps there is an exit sure i mean we've already been detected
but i mean the least if we can just avoid some some combat water stuff is tricky it's wet
oh and then you're wet for the rest of the adventure you're wet for the rest of the day
you are just soaking wet it's exhausting i i know shangalar knows we are here
yes but we don't know that all the creatures know we are here still a good idea to sneak
i think okay yeah i think that's a good call all right everybody as you enter roll a stealth
check i'm so stealthy
i'm not though because i only rolled to 12 so what i'm gonna do is i'm going to
use one of my luck points i'm gonna roll again for disadvantage i rolled quite well
hmm you have disadvantage yeah i wear heavy
17 for me russ nice 20 for me oh god only 13 for me that's got a 12
okay you enter and you see the pool a little more clearly it has sheer sides that like drop
off the water within 10 feet when you get there is lightly obscured it's kind of hazy
as you walk up to it you can't really see down into it you pass by which direction were you
going around the pool sorry there was a right yeah bigger opening off into the right as you
enter further into the room you turn and you see before you get to this clearing there's one
of these large globes that is suspended in this alcove you see them more clearly now
the water's swirling around inside of it there's nothing in it that you can see
it's just suspended there and as you get about 30 or 40 feet into this you hear a ripple
in the water oh shit i don't think we're sneaky enough you guys can we sneak faster
um sure yeah you can certainly try um everybody make a dexterity saving throw
guys my holes are on it 22 damn amy
who am i it's been a while since i've rolled sorry 16 carla
it was 12 for me i wasn't much better might have to retire this d20 it's doing me real dirty
as you begin to move faster through this room all of the surfaces beneath you and the walls
begin to glisten they become slimy and wet um yen bull you slip and fall and begin sliding
towards the open pool in the middle mannix does as well thea you see uh yen bull and mannix
or you hear rather because you were quite stealthy and agile you feel like the ground
begin to get slick beneath you and you hear them slip and fall and begin to move like their bodies
are moving with momentum towards the pool oh god oh um hold on and i wild shape
into i don't fucking know a crocodile
so i dive and mid-dive down i wild shape into a crocodile all of my possessions um doing that
whole absorbs into my body thing um and i i belly slide which i assume will be much faster
than how they're sliding and i go to kind of stop like not stop them there's no stopping
from getting into the water but i try to create a barrier between them and the water so that
nothing can get them so you're like a surfboard sure yeah so yeah so you're you're
trying to stop them essentially from yeah make a dexterity check
well that was a nat one so maybe i crush you to death not sure so sorry um okay so you
best intentions yada yada yada the the scales really tipped the other way my roles were
ballin i'm just i don't know what happened carla changed her dice and now it's affecting
you shit carla bring back your crappy dice i'm sorry with a nat one i think you run into
rather than stop one of them odds it's mannex evens it's yen bull odds it's mannex so you
rush into mannex pushing them further and into the pool with a loud splash sorry i think you
you probably have enough momentum to follow them down in i do but we'll say that's the end
of your turn and it's mannex's turn and mannex sees these white tentacles almost
move through the water towards them and one of them grabs hold of mannex uh thea you're
able to see this as a crocodile it like wraps around their waist and two of them
bludgeon mannex jesus and mannex is going to take some damage nobody sees really how bad it is
and they have to make a constitution saving throw which they do not do well at hopefully
they have a big plus
we're here in the middle nice to see you it's always nice to see you it's nice to just be
like right in your ears oh yeah i feel so close to you right now this is such a
are we all just gonna whisper yeah should i crinkle a bag are we in asmr podcast now
just kind of laundry while we talk you guys i'm gonna stir a coffee okay now it's gonna be
so loud when we come back and just talk in our normal voices so we'll just slowly ramp it up
hey we had a we had a super fun time last month playing uh our game time with one of our
patrons uh gabe thank you for coming out with us but we want to play with you too and we'd like
you to come join us over on Patreon for our game time this month which is july 15th it'd be super
fun if you could be there it's real fun last time i got to have psychic weapons not like
like physical weapons that i could manifest psychically not like i could i'm making a face
like it looks like i'm psychically damaging you like you can punish me with your mind
yeah yeah um and i just had a bitch and tried it so yeah you did i didn't get to participate
but i will in the next one well you can actually go listen to that one it's available
to the public over on our Patreon page um just go it's uh Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
and just to be clear by the public for us means like you don't need to be a patron
to listen you can just go and listen and be like oh those crazy dumb idiots these dummies
is probably what you'll say i mean it's the most accurate reaction indeed yeah except for gabe
who's lovely oh and i don't want to call him a crazy dumb idiot he's so much better than us
that's really why we do these is so that we learn how to play dnd from people who know
how to like solve problems in a logical way yeah like use items in the room and take
direction you know just from the description that's given all the things that we don't do
right we don't do any of that it was a very big learning experience and we'd like you to be a
part of that for us please please make us better please Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast we have
that lovely game time that we have uh every month uh so if this month doesn't work for
you come join us in one of the future months love to have you there but we also
have tons of great bonus content for all of our patrons including episodes and one shots
and hangouts down times too where we talk about the episodes we just recorded this episode that
you're listening to right now we keep recording after that and that episode goes up to Patreon
we do a little debrief yell at russ realize we didn't understand anything that was happening
in the middle it's pretty fun you can in real time listen to us realize all the dumb things
we did yeah and now can't go back and change because time travel is nothing for us that's
not how editing works oh it's totally fine and we don't get to edit it Patreon.com slash
dumb dragon cast we'd love to see you over there and now i think that's all we've got for you
today so we'll get you back to the episode with these lovely folks who are stuck in a
pyramid you have a great week we'll talk to you soon in post mirror touching mannex has
like a plus eight to con that's right if his daughter's alive he's so strong so much better
where is your constitution higher if your daughter dies because you've had to live with that and
grow like stronger as a person okay uh okay can i have my second turn now does hardship make
us stronger let's have a philosophical conversation why here what doesn't kill
you makes you stronger stand a little taller um doesn't mean i'm lonely when i'm alone
so you're right kelly clarkson has taught me anything and she has so many things so sorry
could i have my second action we got all we got all hard up on me hitting mannex and i
didn't get to take my action is wild shape not an action it was i have two actions y'all
you moved to to try to stop them from falling and that was i figured that was part of the dive
okay i concede i yield the floor i do you know what i've only had one action for like the
past four years so i'm really not gonna get your fill well i'm not gonna like
be all hard up on it now flint you're up next so you see uh mannex and thea as
crocodile go under the water and then it begins to like
like waves begin to undulate across the surface of this across the surface of this pool
all right do i see any more of these weird tentacle things uh you don't see the tentacle
things at all because they were seen under the water so mannex and thea were the only ones
that saw that yeah all right it's just getting stormy for no reason i made a big splash
that is fair uh yeah i guess i'm going to uh turn my rod of lordly might into a ladder
and attempt to like throw it on over to yen bull okay by throw it you mean hold on to it on
one end and lower it down so she can like shift it on over okay um
i'm just gonna fuck you down the hill into the water i gave you a ladder
okay is that all you're doing for your turn uh yeah i mean okay that seems like the most
pressing thing yeah okay you and uh yen bull it's yen bull's turn now so i guess you can
coordinate what you're doing from above um i'm going to cast water walk on myself and my
friends okay so they can walk on the water now as if it was harmless solid ground and um
do you have to be able to see or touch the person or is it just
um six people within 10 willing creatures i can see are they fully submerged fully submerged
and we had established that it was obscured that doesn't i don't think that matters i
think i'm still going to cast it on flint and i so that we can now go in the water yes sounds
good well i mean amy turned into a crocodile she's doing all right i'm okay that's true
and i guess for my movement i am going to move um towards that ladder i don't know how
near it is to me or or what the deal is with it it can be up to 50 feet long
so it depends how far down you've slid i guess you said it was like a 14 foot drop
oh yeah because you slid towards so you hadn't fallen into the water yet but yeah about 10 feet
down but yeah you're like moving have moved towards the edge so i yeah he's moving it
towards you so you could reach it yeah okay yep then i'm gonna scramble up that ladder
sounds good um at the end of your turn um the uh a tail comes out of the darkness in the water
towards you that's a 15 to hit your crocodile yep um and you're gonna take 15 bludgeoning
damage a lot of 15s going on here um and it's back to thea so you see this tail coming
through the the murky water below you see these tentacles wrapped around mannax as they're
um like panicking um you see like this dark silhouette of this creature huh i just want to
chomp chomp on the tentacle that's holding mannax okay so that we can get the fuck out
of here because now i'm down to four hit points because crocodile ain't too into buff
apparently okay uh so i'm going to use a bite action oh god amy's back you guys that was a six
guess who's back do back again okay um do i still have my second action because i'm still thea
and technically the amulet is still on me yeah okay cool oh there's a nat 20 all right oh damn
much better okay so um it is one d10 plus two so that's essentially two d10 plus two
and then the target is grappled or does it crap i rolled a fucking one
and a nine so that's 10 11 12 piercing damage and the target is grappled you need to do a
dc of 12 on its turn on its turn uh sounds good yeah and until this grapple ends the target is
restrained i mean the the tentacle is restrained the tentacle is restrained we'll say that the
tentacle comes loose uh from mannax um and mannax begins to swim ferociously towards
the surface um he's gonna try and make another tail swipe at you neat uh that's gonna be a 16
yep that'll do it 15 yeah that'll do it too so you turn back into thea i sure do
i'm thea and you got this tentacle in your in between your teeth i bite down harder
um okay then um okay mannix manages to swim up and break the surface you hear a gasp
from the water and the surface you see them kind of trying to swim towards uh the edge
you're thinking go you bastard go it's the creature's turn okay flint make a wisdom saving
throw i would love to russ that is 15 okay you feel like a twinge in your in your psyche like
someone's trying to like knock at the door but they just can't quite get in like you're
familiar with this kind of feeling having borton there i think sure like you know there's
too many people in there also with the dream assault that he forwent
mm-hmm yep in they um yeah they are unsuccessful but you feel someone trying to break in there
um and it is fucking psychic squid uh it's flint's turn uh perfect did yen bull manage
to scurry up the ladder uh yes yen bull would have made it to the ladder and
scramble back up all right uh so maybe i'll leave the ladder out and i'll swing it on over to uh to
mannix see if they can climb on up okay we'll say that they are able to make it on their next
turn okay um thea underneath as you kind of come back to your your own form um you
see this creature clearly as it swims past you and i'd like you to kind of
well i'll show you what you see and then um if you get up before they see it then you can
describe it oh fuck no get out of the water get out of the water what is that such a big mouth
it's not okay nobody else sees it yet what do you do uh i i bled out a silent scream oh sorry
it's not it's not your turn but this is what you see um so flint you've moved your ladder
yen bull it's your turn uh well i still haven't seen the creature so i don't even know what's
going on and i can't see my friends down there i guess i can see mannix they're thrashing
to try and get to the ladder flint flint hold the top of the ladder and i'm gonna go back down
the ladder to try and help grab mannix okay um make a dexterity acrobatics check maybe
go down a ladder well it's slippery sure yeah i mean climb down the ladder maybe a
maybe a dexterity check to try and grab them and then maybe oh okay i didn't think
he was that close i see what you're saying yeah i mean they're within you know reachable
distance if they were to reach for you stretch we're all just we're all just stretching and
reaching uh it's not no no we're not doing a great job though because it's only a 12
johnson and joanne mcleod if you want to come on to this podcast that'd be great
absolutely yeah with the zumba episode um so yeah you just kind of brush fingertips and they
kind of dip back under um and then pop back up taking a big breath and it's anything else you
want to do uh i don't think so i don't want to shoot any magic into that pool where my
friends are all right back to thea add a thing i can't see um thea you see a tail swinging
through the water towards you that's only a 10 to hit though so don't i have a turn before
they have a turn oh shit okay well that doesn't yeah it kind of doesn't hit me anyways it blows
by you and kind of sucks you up into this swirl of water and you get kind of tossed
and turned now it's your turn cool well um it looks like i'm like in the middle of the
water essentially um does it can i see anything below my feet like is it just
no it just keeps going it's a cavern okay cool i'm going to alter self
as one of my actions i am going to adapt my body to an aquatic environment spreading gills
and growing webbing between my fingers i can breathe underwater and gain a swimming speed
equal to my walking speed sweet so i'm going to do that sounds like a good strategy you
know so i don't drown because i feel like you'd be like you're going to take some stress also
you haven't breathed in two rounds so i mean the crocodile yeah the crocodile had like extra
breath holding capacity i don't think thea does she's a pot smoker i don't think that makes
you have extra great lung capacity i don't think it hurts but i don't know if it helps
so she's gonna do that so she um and this is the first time so she's kind of like
looking at her fingers and like taking deep breaths and it's like then you see the face
of this monster moving towards you and then things get real uh under underwater this thing
is not taking any damage correct no it has i bit it okay you bit it i bit it fair enough
yeah it took don't you dare forget about that bite ross don't you dare forget about
that bite because i'm gonna cast toll the dead no i'm not this is a serious situation i'm not
gonna get out of here i'm gonna cast blight on this dick on its dick no on this dick
i don't know if it has a dick i haven't seen all that much of it right now just a lot of teeth
and some tentacles and a tail apparently uh okay so necromantic energy washes over this
creature of my choice as i put my hands out into the water i say a little prayer to a god
that i don't know i don't think the is super religious but she's just like i've never cast
a spell under the water let's see how this works and from her fingertips come a black inky
cloud because normally it's like a black cloud that comes but it's a black you know when
you're playing mario kart and someone gets the little squid it's like that fuck you up with
exactly it's just like that except cloud here and and wraps itself around the squid and or thing
whatever it is and the target must make a constitution saving throw before it drains
the moisture and vitality from it oh neat okay cool okay so the target takes 8d8 necrotic
damage 30 okay it didn't kill a good thing you rolled it well i didn't think it would
it's taken like practically no damage as you said and this thing all that bite damage though
like connects with its flesh and you see it like recede and turn black and it lets out
this hideous scream that sends shock waves through the water above you see like waves
breach up and across the the top of the edge around the pool
that's the end of your turn um yes because i turned myself into something and i did a spell
okay manic swims it's like propelled with it and towards you yin bowl and you two begin
to scramble up and as you reach the top of this ladder where flint is standing you see
behind him one of these globes moving towards him
the intro song nowhere land is by Kavin mcleod of incompetech.filmmusic.io
all other music and sound effects can be found at epidemicsound.com a huge thank you to our
supporting producers christian brown devin michaels gabriel lynch jacob madden joshua dixon
cat Waterflame and stevie to find out more how you can support dumbs and the dragons
visit Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast thank you for listening have a great week we'll talk
soon sorry one second my levels are just uh your bathroom design app is um yep exactly
russ is an autocad quickly designing yeah he's got hgtv up there for just some you know little
design tips something about shiplap i don't know it's great in shiplap yes always with
the shiplap always with the shiplap and amy you've always wanted to do the all musical
episode so i have yeah i don't know how we'll make that work but maybe we can get uh get there
bombarded in to help us yeah we could do maybe Patreon could pay for some singing lessons for
me it's a little pitchy dog enjoy that randy jackson reference yes no i liked it very topical
i loved it oh that would be i say i say i say i do believe boy i do
yo sam andy sam that's more of a foghorn leghorn but sure
oh yes yes Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production