previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
I'm, I feel anxious to get going.
I take the bird in my hands, close my eyes like I did when we were praying.
The warmth begins to come back.
You open your hands and you look down at the bird
and it begins flapping its wings, slow at first and then quicker, and it takes flight.
I pack up, you know, I throw my pack back on my shoulders and pick up my stuff and I'm
I'm ready.
Seem like a good kid.
I want to do you a favor.
I'm going to need something in return.
But I need to know that you can use these tools that are laid out here
as you say they are your possessions.
I'm verily proficient in the tools you seek.
There is a certain higher up who carries a ledger.
Hey listen, you want out of here?
No.
What's your mission?
I steal something from Dinglehopper Never Never.
Lord Dagglet Never Ember.
That's what I said.
I'm looking for Mr. Gabriel.
I'm sure you're of the highest character.
If you were to find him, perhaps the Fallen Tower.
I'm too drunk to teach you right now.
Can I find you somewhere tomorrow?
I'll probably be here.
Okay.
Maybe come by a little earlier in the day.
I've never seen anything like you before.
I'm a dragonborn.
My name's Glim.
It's very nice to meet you Glim.
I'm Moot.
Nice to meet you, Moot.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We're a D&D 5th edition actual play podcast.
And I'm your dungeon master, Russ More.
And with me today is Carla Johnson.
That is me.
I play Norixious Akra, better known as Glim.
And Tom Laird.
Hey, that's me.
I play Moot.
He's a half-orc wild magic sorcerer.
And Amy More.
Indeed I am.
I play Sullivan Slyte or Sully, a lightfoot halfling rogue.
How's everybody doing?
Great.
I'm a dragonborn pAlydin.
I didn't say that.
You didn't.
You have to say it because it's all new.
It's new.
I have to say it.
New things.
New things are happening.
Where new things are always happening is over on Patreon where you can come and join us.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And if you're a patron of ours, you get an episode dedicated to you.
And today's episode is dedicated to Setzer Orion.
Setzer.
Thanks, Setzer.
Setzer, you rock.
You rock.
Thank you.
If you want to join us over on Patreon, that's Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
We'd really love to see you.
Let's just jump right in.
Fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
Previously, Glim, you have made it to Neverwinter.
And you just met an interesting half-orc who just ran the other direction.
So now it's night-time-ish, early night-time dusk.
What you doing?
I think I will probably grab a snack and then like wander.
Just to like, like Glim hasn't been anywhere, right?
She's so sheltered.
So just to, yeah, like check out this new city.
Sure.
So you've come into kind of the northeastern entry to Neverwinter.
There is a large outcropping where caravans can kind of pull in,
offload everything that they need to and then ride back out.
In the vicinity, you see a few different shops, most of which are closed at this point.
There's a bustle of noise going on down the street
in the direction that the half-orc ran.
There is a dimly lit information center.
Which calls to you?
It does.
For some reason that calls to me.
But I need my snack first.
As far as people kind of in the street,
there are mostly the people that you were on the caravan with.
But yeah, that's what you see.
Dude, you need your snack first.
I thought you'd have like literally a baggie of like, I don't know, granola.
Oh, I'm sure I do.
I'm sure I have snacks.
Trail mix.
Totally.
No, no, that's like so on brand for Glim.
You pull out a snack pack, like that's how.
No, what is something like granola?
Like that's like some gorp.
Like that seems right.
Maybe I'll ask my good friend from the caravan.
I want to ask them where I should go get some food.
She's kind of busy offloading some of her stuff from one of the caravans.
Ain't a lull?
Yes.
You've been here before, right?
A few times, yeah.
Where would I go to find some sort of delicacy on a budget from a street vendor?
A delicacy on a budget from a street vendor.
Well, I mean, if you walk down, you hear the noise going on down off to the east there?
I do.
So if you keep going down that way, you'll eventually run into the Fallen Tower,
which is a very well-known tavern in the area.
They've got some pretty good food and a little bit of a shady clientele from time to time.
But also on the way, I mean, sometimes there are street vendors kind of just milling about
getting that sweet drunk coin, you know, how they do outside of taverns.
Awesome.
Thank you so much.
It was so great to travel with you.
I love you very much.
And I can't wait until I see you again.
That love word again.
Every time.
It just really gets me.
I am fond of you as well.
Glam, it's a pleasure riding with you.
I hope to see you again soon.
See you soon.
God, I love it.
She's a delight.
I love you.
I love you very much.
She just has had, like, that's her whole life has been that, right?
Um, so she is going to go towards the fallen tower because shady character sounds pretty fun.
The thing that I think is fun about Glam is like, she's very big and strong.
So she's very innocent, but not like helpless, fearful and not helpless.
Exactly.
So so why not?
Sure.
Why not?
There are varying degrees of inebriated people.
I don't know how much drinking went on in your your village.
I think it would have been a thing, probably.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, there are some people who are pretty far in as far as that goes.
Coming from the direction that you are walking.
Specifically, there's a human and a dwarf bustling about telling stories as they kind of
come up to and walk past you.
And you continue on down the way and you make it to a pretty well lit for what you've seen so far.
Most of the stores have all their lights are are snuffed and you make it to a literal fallen tower.
It looks like it's been broken or sheared off and it's fallen into the street.
There's a loud jovial goings on inside.
Great.
Okay.
I'm going to go in there.
Is there a performer or anything?
It does sound like there's a bar playing.
Yep.
As you as you get closer to go in and like go up to the bar and order probably like a pint of beer.
No, I think like Glenn would drink.
I think like she's not a child and it's like again big and strong.
So probably has like a very good tolerance for alcohol because she's like big.
Yeah.
So you walk in and it's as far as like the outside goes is it looks like a destroyed tower inside.
It looks very well kept all things considered.
There's warm woods.
Most of the tables are pretty much full.
Some of them have a couple people passed out on them.
Others look like they're kind of finishing up their drinks and moving out.
Given the later hour.
May you walk up to the bar.
There is a dwarven woman behind the bar and she's busy serving some people who are
more or less taking up most of her attention.
But she kind of catches you out of the corner of her eye.
Walk up and she kind of hushes them for a little while.
Slams a couple of tankards down in front of them and walks over to you and says,
What can I do for you there miss?
Hi, could I get a pint of your finest ale?
And can I still get something to eat?
Is it too late?
Yeah, no, well, I mean, it's getting a little bit late,
but we can certainly give you some food here.
Is there anything in particular you're looking for?
Let me get you that that that ale here.
And you didn't even try for a woman's voice, do you?
Just a dwarven woman's very mouthful.
Dwarven woman.
Very, very deep.
Yeah, well, all types.
She's a very sexy voice.
All types.
And she comes back and she's like,
Well, the menu's been pretty picked clean.
We've still got some of the special tonight.
It's roasted tarantula with hairs carefully singed off
and their fangs used for toothpicks later.
Tarantula.
There's a lovely sauce that goes with it too.
No, I mean, tarantula is my number two favorite spider to eat.
So perfect.
What's your number one?
You know that big one that like eats birds?
It's like really big, so it's like quite meaty
because, you know, I've got a big appetite.
I haven't eaten any of those.
They're like didn't even know there were spider eating birds.
They're enormous.
Wow, you must have traveled.
You must have traveled all over the place to see spiders like that.
Oh, I haven't been anywhere.
Those are local to where I'm from.
That's terrifying.
I like you, though.
I like you.
I'm going to go get you some tarantulas.
Extra sauce because I feel like it.
Hey, thanks.
I like you too.
She puts down the ale in front of you there.
Perfect.
She goes off into the back.
I'm going to like scan around, see who I see.
Who was it was like a group of people
that she was dealing with before that are also sitting at the bar?
Yes.
Yeah, there looks to be two human males,
a female half-elf and a dwarven male.
And they're kind of they've turned into themselves,
or not turned into themselves,
but like turned and are talking to themselves loudly.
Some of them are talking about joining the mercenary force
to go off and fight against the cult of the dragon.
Oh, yeah, I'm definitely going to want to talk to them.
So I'll approach with my pint in my hand and say,
excuse me.
One of the males turns and says,
what can I do for their dragon friend?
Hi, I'm Glim.
I'm so sorry to interrupt.
I couldn't help but overhear
that you're talking about fighting the cult of the dragon.
Yeah, well, I mean, they're terrible.
Well, so I just left my home to maybe help
that fight I just got here.
And I thought, these seem like experts.
Maybe they can tell me the best way to help fight
and the main sources of conflict
and who the major players are
and all the socio geopolitical situations
that are happening here.
Can you guys fill me in on that?
They kind of look to each other and they start to laugh.
I'm having trouble taking you seriously there, my dear.
So what you're saying is
you have no idea what's happening?
Well, I wouldn't say no idea.
A bard did come to my village and tell us that,
you know, this cult of the dragon's trying to rise Tiamat
and obviously I don't want that.
I follow Bahamut, so that's, you know.
Oh, Bahamut, a dragon god.
But the very best believer in truth
and justice and peace, dragon god.
Yes, yeah, absolutely.
You know what you can probably do is
we need lots of people.
You know what?
I'm a recruiter.
I could get you right into the battle
if that's what you're looking for.
Where's the battle happening?
I've only just arrived in town.
Would I have to ship out tonight or?
Well, not tonight.
We're leaving in a couple of days.
We're actually probably leaving tomorrow morning
and heading down south.
Down to the Well of Dragons
where the cult has their little setup going on down there.
Oh, so the main headquarters, that's where.
Yeah, we're getting all the people
who want to just fight and do good.
And you sound like you want to do that.
You must be very high ranking.
Pretty, pretty high ranking
and he gets an elbow into the side.
I mean, I know some people.
Okay, and what are your names?
My name's Lop, Lop Kim.
And this is my friend, Ken Rat.
Is this the two humans?
Microphone.
Those are the two humans.
My dwarven friend here is Eugenie.
And your elven friend is Gene Genie.
Her name is Uchu.
And they all kind of tip their head to you
as a couple of them turn back to their drinks
and just allow Lop to continue talking to you.
And so how long have you been fighting
the cult of the dragon?
Ever since basically day one.
No hands for hire here.
We've been with the forces
since they've been starting to make their way
into little towns and villages.
See, I'm a little bit confused
because what I did over here,
I was eavesdropping, I apologize,
but it sounded like you were just thinking
about maybe joining up.
So I feel like one of these stories
isn't maybe quite the truth.
So you're eavesdropper.
So you're pulling my leg.
That's what you're saying.
I like her.
You're funny.
You guys are funny.
That's funny.
So you're not fighting yet then?
No, but I mean, I do know people
who could probably sign you up
if that's what you're interested in.
And the bartender comes back with your plate
and she says, oh, here,
I'll just bring it down here to your drink.
You might want to eat up.
Thank you so much.
Hey guys, if you, I love a laugh.
So I'll be back after I eat my dinner.
You can tell me some more stories maybe.
Oh, so many, so many stories.
I'm going to have to think of them.
You can't believe it.
And I walk away kind of laughing.
I got a good sense of humor about the whole thing.
We would pull pranks where I was from too
on new people passing through.
It's fine.
And then I'm going to just like dig
into that delicious tarantula dish
that I'm eating apparently.
Well, at least, you know,
the hair has been removed.
Carefully singed off.
The fangs have been placed
like toothpicks on the side of the plate.
Delicious.
Probably say that you kind of spend
some more of your evening there.
Do you go and find lodging somewhere else
or do you try and find something there?
If there's rooms there,
I probably would just stay there.
Like I really like the bartender.
She is really great.
And I mean, you know, I'm happy wherever
I ate that delicious meal.
So if I can find a room there,
I'll just stay there.
Sounds good.
We'll say you get a room there
and we'll cut to the next morning.
Sully, you are.
You just kind of wake up
with the sunlight coming
through your bars.
You hear a bird song outside
and you hear your good friend
Merv down the way,
kind of coughing and stirring
as he usually does
waking when he wakes up.
Hi, you're sounding old today, buddy.
Well, I mean, I kind of am old.
It's worse in the morning.
Well, you know, you lay down,
everything settles.
Yeah, everything kind of settles
and everything's got to work itself back out.
Work on the sea.
You know, there's a lot of things
that get in there.
What?
Sea science.
That doesn't sound like real science.
Are you ready, buddy?
Are you ready?
Today's the day.
What are we doing today?
Well, today we go in
and I get real close to the bars
and I go, we're going to steal
Lord Never Ember's ledger.
Yeah, that sounds like a terrible idea.
You sure you want to do this?
Well, OK, I guess you could stay here.
No, I mean, I'm going to come
because, you know,
if we get out of here.
But I mean, it still sounds like a terrible.
Do you know who Lord Never Ember is?
A Lord?
Like the Lord of Neverwinter.
OK, cool.
Oh, my God.
Do you think he has more than one ledger?
I mean, did you not get a description of the ledger?
Yeah, I'm sure I did at some point.
I have total faith that this plan is going to work.
I love that the biggest concern
is that there might be more than one ledger.
I'm just going to walk into a vast, like, ledger room.
It's just like wall to wall, Florida ceiling, ledger.
It's like a ledger Rolodex.
Like, oh, shit, I don't even know.
I can't wait for this.
Hopefully, they give us a bag of holding or something
for all the ledgers we're going to find up in here.
Yeah, well, I was lucky to get some of the items
that I did manage to not leave with her, so that's fine.
That's good.
It's fine.
So, yeah, you sound ready.
Totally ready, totally ready.
Let's do this.
Door opens to the jails.
As soon as I say, let's do this.
And one of the guards walks in with the tray of bread.
I'm like, OK, I'm going to do this.
And one of the guards walks in with the tray of breakfast.
More slop.
Slides it under Merv's, and then slides it down to yours,
and then turns to Leif.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
What?
Are we getting out?
Why would you get out?
You're prisoners.
Well, we've got a secret mission.
Yeah, that's what all prisoners say.
Do they really?
Yeah.
They all say they have a secret mission?
All of them.
They say they're here on a secret mission,
and they've been wrongfully accused,
and they shouldn't be hanged or have their head chopped off.
Yeah, I bet anyone in that situation would say that.
But no, I just had a meeting with Miss Fuck.
I've never met Miss Fuck.
Well, then you're missing out, my friend.
Sounds like it.
Miss Mam Meow Meow.
Miss Madame Meow Meow.
I have mam down here.
Miss Mam Meow Meow.
All right, Miss Mam Meow Meow Meow.
Wait, hold on.
Are there three meows?
Meow?
Say that again, meow.
Like meow?
So, wait.
Are you super drooping?
Eat your slap right meow,
and then I'll come back with Miss Madame Meow Meow and meow.
Miss Mam Meow Meow is not going to come down here and talk to me,
but I just went up there and talked to her,
and I'm not going to tell you the secret plan.
You look like a lackey.
You got me right.
Cool, but like, could you just tell her?
Yeah, I'll go tell her.
Okay, thanks.
Yeah, I got her direct line right here.
He walks out and he flips the bird as he walks.
I flip him back.
Both of them, my teeny tiny fingers through the bars.
As the door shuts, Merv says, are you sure?
No.
There's a secret mission?
Yes.
I didn't just make up that whole conversation.
Make a persuasion shit.
Oh my god.
All right, all right.
Well, hopefully they come for us soon
because we're getting out on our own here.
Well, you know what?
We're just fueling up.
They just want us to fuel up before we go.
That's all that is.
He picks up his slop tray and sits back down
and starts eating away at it.
I kind of push mine around a little bit.
I'm picky.
Where are you?
You're probably waking up at this point.
Sure, back at Nogwoods.
Yeah, so you went back to Nogwoods.
You ran back after meeting this dragonborn
who helped you up in the street.
So you're waking up.
You had made it back.
There was a key and a note left on the main door
or main kind of desk at the entrance way there
because everybody had gone to sleep by that point
with some directions to your dorm.
You had made it safe and sound
and now you're waking up the next morning.
Lovely bird song and lights coming in
through the shade.
What time of the morning is it?
How late does Moot sleep?
I guess should be the better question.
Well, he's still a youngster
so he takes as much opportunity
to get all the sleep that he can.
So I'll say until, yeah, 1030?
Sure, knowing your appointment
isn't until the lunch hour.
You sleep the better part of the morning away
and are waking up.
Sun's a little higher in the sky
than had previously mentioned.
Maybe you woke up a little bit
and you just close your eyes again
and then woke up at 1030.
I'm going to put on the best clothes that I brought
because it's the first day of school.
Got to look sharp.
And I'm going to head back over.
I'm assuming Gabriel's back at the inn again
or am I eating him somewhere else?
I think he told you to meet him there
at the Fallen Tower.
Okay, yeah.
So one final spot check in the mirror before I go
and I make my way back to the Fallen Tower.
You make your way back down
and you pass by Shilso who calls to you
and says, you found everything okay?
Everything was great.
The note and the key, it was all perfect.
Ah, good.
Yes, yes.
Well, good.
Well, you're off for your day then?
Are you going to go do what people
who don't go to this school but stay here do?
Yeah, I'm going to go talk to this Gabriel guy
and see if he can teach me a thing or two.
And I had a question.
Is there like a laundry service here at the school as well?
Because I mean, I only brought a couple of outfits
and one is pretty dirty after some travel.
So I wonder if I can maybe get it cleaned.
Yep, we could probably do that for you.
You're staying here.
We can just, if you just, you know, here's a bag.
Just leave it outside your door.
It'll be cleaned up for you by the time you get back.
Oh, oh, perfect.
That's awesome.
So I run back to my room and throw those clothes in a bag.
You head back out and down and out to the Fallen Tower
unless you're stopping anywhere else on the way.
No, I figured I'd probably go right there nice and early.
You know, apt pupil, et cetera.
You make it there, I'd say you'd probably make it there
early-ish, like probably quarter two, 1130 quarter two.
That seem fair?
Sure.
You stroll in and there's a, it's a very thin crowd
compared to the scene that you walked into last night.
There's one bartender who's kind of cleaning up,
cleaning up the glasses and the tables
and just rearranging after a night of frivolity
that the city had underwent.
Is there the bartender that was working yesterday in there?
Is there a different one this time?
There is a different one.
Perfect.
I'll stroll over to the bar and I'll say,
Bartender, have you seen Gabriel?
Has he been in yet?
Gabriel, no.
He usually gets in later.
I'm supposed to meet him here at noon.
Okay, well, hopefully he's keeping his appointments today.
The way you said that makes it seem like maybe
that's not what happens every day.
Is that not what happens every day?
You don't know Gabriel very well, do you?
Uh, no, no.
Okay, well, sometimes he does.
Sometimes he's really good.
Sometimes he's punctual and sometimes he's not.
So, okay, so just, I'll get, I'll get what I get, I guess, huh?
That's what I'm getting at.
Can I get you anything while you wait?
Do you have any, like, decks of cards or anything
I can maybe borrow or kill some time before he shows up?
He kind of looks around.
I think we used to have something here.
He lifts up a bunch of stuff underneath one of the tables
or behind the bar and then pulls out a deck of cards
and tosses it across to you.
So yeah, there you go.
I'll just go.
Nothing to eat or drink?
Yeah, do you have something like a lighter beer?
Something in that neighborhood?
It's a little early for me to start with the heavy stuff.
I mean, we got water.
I'll take one of those, sure.
What's the lightest beer you have?
Water.
Some places do not look kindly on those who order just water.
That's fair.
You seem like a nice kid and you're going to be waiting on Gabriel a while.
I'm not going to steal your money.
I'll give you some water.
He slides a glass across the bar to you.
Perfect, yeah, thanks.
I'll just, I'll be over there.
If you see Gabriel, send him my way.
I'm sure you'll see him before anybody else does.
Well, I'm just going to be looking at the door nonstop, so yes, probably.
If he sneaks in through the back way, there's no back way.
Just keep an eye out.
Perfect, will do.
He goes back to shining up the glasses there.
So you sit down at one of the tables
and you hear some footsteps coming down the stairs
and you see the dragonborn that you saw last night as Glim enters the room.
Glim, what do you do?
I mean, I was just making the stupidest big smile
and that's probably, was actually, I, Carla, was doing it.
But really, it's probably what Glim would do too
because she would recognize him.
She'd be excited.
So I'm going to walk down the stairs and...
Tell him you love him.
Not yet.
I barely know him.
I just really like him.
We did not ride on a caravan together for days on end.
I really like him quite a bit.
He was so clumsy.
What's falling down?
So yeah, I'm going to walk up and say,
good morning.
Oh, oh, it's you again.
Hi.
It's you again.
How are you?
I'm great.
I had a great night's sleep last night.
I'm excited for, I guess it's my first day of school to an extent.
Oh, that's an exciting day.
I can't remember if I gave you my name.
I'm Glim and I hold my hand out.
Yeah, yeah, Glim, it's Moot.
Moot, it is so great to see you again.
Where are you going to go to school?
What are you going to go to school for?
Tell me everything.
Okay, to answer the first question, I think it's here.
Is it like a bartending school?
No, no.
Second question will cover that.
I'm trying to learn magic.
Oh.
There was a guy here last night that the school,
the Nogwood School of Wizcraft and Witchery
sent me over here to talk to this Gabriel fellow.
So I'm hoping he'll be able to help me out.
What kind of magic?
I see you've got cards.
Are you going to do like card tricks?
Sleight of hand?
What kind of magic are you going to learn?
If only.
We had a magician, quote unquote,
that came to our village one time and he was really good with that stuff.
But he wouldn't tell me how any of them were done.
I love a magician.
I guess it's in their code or something that they don't want to tell you.
I asked so many questions and they wouldn't tell me any of the secrets.
Yeah, it's the worst.
But no, so I don't think it's going to be that type of magic.
I seem to have what the lady at the school called was wild magic.
Oh, that sounds exciting and kind of dangerous.
Is it dangerous?
It was scary.
Yeah, I can't really control it.
So I'm hoping that's what Gabriel can help me out with.
Wow.
You know what?
It sounds like we have a lot in common because I also have a very special gift.
Really?
I'm like, I mean, this sounds conceited,
but I think I'm like maybe going to help save the world.
I have a calling.
Wow.
Yeah, I mean, no, I shot like this freezing ray out of my hands one time.
Yours is way cooler.
I don't know if it is.
A freezing ray sounds pretty cool.
But like saving the world, that's awesome.
Well, I mean, if I'm going to be honest, and we're friends now,
so I feel like I can be honest, I don't exactly know how I'm going to do that.
Okay.
But I think that I can.
I'm looking for, hey, I'm looking for some people to help me.
And I...
To help you save the world?
This sounds kind of crazy, but I think you might be one of them.
What makes you say that?
I'm like, I don't even know how to do this magic stuff.
I just have a feeling.
I don't know.
I don't know, Moot.
I just have a feeling about you.
Okay, that's cool.
The door opens with a loud bang and then heavy footsteps and Moot,
you see Gabriel kind of, he's got a hat that's low on his face.
Sunglasses are on.
Tucked into himself.
And he goes over and up to the bar and just holds up a finger
and the bartender slides him a drink as he kind of just sits there for a moment
while you're still conversing.
Have I noticed Gabriel come in or am I...?
Yeah, I mean, I figure you've kind of got at least half an eye on the door
the whole time even while you're talking with Glim.
So yeah, you definitely see him.
I kind of excitedly tap Glim on the hand.
I say, oh, that's him.
That's Gabriel.
That's the guy who's going to teach me.
That guy.
Yeah, that's who the school told me to find.
Glim, you definitely see someone who is...
He looks pretty rough.
If not half in the bag, he's rough.
He's probably still drunk and hungover at the same time.
Yeah, like I can probably smell him.
Oh, yeah, there's an odor.
Roll for smell.
Roll for odor.
It's a good one.
Yeah.
Pungent.
Huh.
Well, and he's a teacher?
Well, I guess he studied wild magic at the school
because he thought there was something that he could tap into with it.
But I guess they kind of also kicked him out of the school for...
I mean, the lady at the school said
she didn't say he wasted his time, but I think that's kind of what she felt.
Hmm.
Well, you can't judge a magician by their smell, I always say.
So I guess I should leave you to school.
It was really good to see you again.
Are you going to...
Maybe I'll see you back here.
I'm staying here.
Oh, you're staying here?
Cool.
I'm staying here.
I'm just over at the school,
but I imagine because I think this is like Gabriel's base of operations.
I think we're going to be here a while.
Okay.
Well, I'm going to, you know, go about my day, but you're my friend now.
I'm going to see you again, Moot.
Good luck with school.
That sounds like a great plan.
I'll see you later.
So I'm going to like go out and like,
I don't know, go look at shit or whatever.
There's like floating things.
It's amazing, right?
Yep.
Absolutely.
We'll catch back up with you in a moment.
I can't wait to hear what Gabriel's got going on.
Moot, you, so Glim says goodbye, you split ways, you...
Yeah.
Has he moved yet from his...
He's taken a couple of drinks,
but more or less he's been very stationary.
Not really.
It doesn't appear that he's looking for you particularly
or anything else in the room.
Okay.
Yeah.
Is he just at the bar?
I'll head over, sidle up next to him at the bar and say,
Gabriel, I'm so glad you made it.
You hear a low rumble, almost like a snore.
And I kind of tap him on the shoulder
and shake him a little bit and say,
Gabriel?
It's just the rest of my eyes.
Who are you, what?
Well, we met last night.
My name's Moot.
Were you the one who stole all my money?
Nope.
Definitely, definitely wasn't me.
Were you the one who switched my shoes?
Over at the school, told me to find you.
We chatted last night about Wild Magic.
You're the kid who wants to learn things.
You came back.
Yeah, you told me to come back.
I did.
You said meet here at noon.
I've sent a lot of people to meet here at noon and they...
I don't know, they don't come back.
I mean, at least four.
Anyways, so you came back.
Great.
You got magic in you.
I mean, yeah, that's what Savoy seemed to think.
And I mean, that's, I mean, yeah, I just, I don't know.
Like, do you think you're going to be able to help me?
Yeah.
Have you had a drink yet?
I had some water.
Had some water.
Well, I asked for a lighter beer and then he suggested water.
So I just went with that.
Okay.
You could have had some special stuff.
I hear that's really good in the first thing in the morning.
Oh, yeah.
You seemed to really like that last night when I got you a couple of rounds of that.
Yeah, it's very good.
Very good.
Okay, so we got to learn magic.
Out of curiosity, is that like a two-day process?
How many days do you want to do it in?
I mean, did we talk rates last night?
No, you just kind of sunk back into your drink and said you'd do it for free.
I said I'd do it for free?
Yeah.
You said that you were just so excited someone had wild magic that you were just so into it.
Make a deception check with advantage.
Because he's drunk?
His senses aren't really keen right now.
So the first one was a 16.
The second roll was an 11.
So I'll go with the 16.
Well, I was a philanthropist at one point.
So I'm probably good to teach you for free, I guess.
Well, that's awesome.
Well, I mean, I'll gladly buy a few rounds of that special stuff every now and then as a thank you.
Great, great.
Okay, so you said you had fire magic.
Well, the one that manifested was like ice.
It was like I froze people.
Ice is like fire of the north.
So is winter coming?
Well, maybe sometime there's seasons.
Do you need to teach you about seasons too?
No, I think I can handle that.
Okay, so can you show me what you got?
Are you sure that's safe?
I don't really know what I'm doing at all.
I mean, this place has been wrecked harder times than...
Well, I mean, it is literally a fallen over tower, so...
Right?
So what's the worst you could do?
We can't fall it over twice.
Well, I mean, I froze some...
Yeah, okay, I'll try.
Give me your beer.
What are you going to do with my beer, boy?
Well, I'm going to try and make it colder.
All right, he slides his beer.
So let's make a...
I don't want to do this.
Make a charisma check with disadvantage.
Okay.
Okay, first was a nat 20.
Shucks.
Second one is an 18.
Oh, so 21.
Shit, all right.
So describe this.
This is going to work really well.
Okay.
So probably better than what you're trying to do.
So describe to me what happens when this spell incurs.
I take the beer that has some condensation on it
because it's been sitting there for a few seconds
while he's been drinking it.
And as I touch the glass,
all of a sudden kind of frost starts forming around the edges
and the bits of condensation start freezing to the glass.
And I kind of like look at him like I'm doing it.
I'm doing it.
And then the glass like shatters because I'm doing it too well.
You see kind of a look of hope and joy in his eyes
as he sees the glass begin to frost.
And then it shatters and like his entire body just slumps.
I see.
Bartender, can you pour him another one real quick?
Well, you got the magic in you, boy.
You need to control it
so that you don't waste any more goddamn drinks.
Yeah, I mean that's why I want to learn from you.
I want to be able to control this.
Okay, good.
I'm going to finish this drink
and then we're going to go somewhere safer away from drinks.
I can't believe that you did this in this
this zone of safety for drinks.
This hallowed ground.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry about that.
This hallowed ground for beverages.
You wanted me to show you what I tried my best.
Don't listen to me.
I mean, do listen to me because I'm going to teach you.
But yeah, it's a lot of conflicting messages here.
Don't touch my drink.
He takes another drink and begins to finish it.
Well, hey there, welcome to the middle part.
Had a little something hanky go on with our interlude recording.
So you just got me, which is okay,
because I'm here to tell you how to enter the contest.
You got a few days left until June 30th
when you can win a copy of Ghosts of Saltmarsh,
the latest adventure module from Wizards of the Coast.
And how do you do that?
Well, all you have to do is share a link to this episode
or another episode that you like.
You can do so on Twitter with the hashtag DumbDragonCast
or down in the description of this episode,
there's a Facebook link
or you can go right to our Facebook page,
share the post to your personal page,
telling people how much you like us
and make a little comment on the post
to let us know that you did so.
And away you go.
You're entered to win Ghosts of Saltmarsh.
We'll make the draw on July 1st.
Contest closes June 30th.
We'll let the winner know via social media first
and then we'll make the announcement on next week's episode.
And speaking of next week's episode,
we're gonna be giving you the game
that Amy and I played at D&D Live 2019, The Descent.
It was such a fun game and such a fun setting
that I'm really looking forward to
with Baldur's Gate The Descent to Avernus or Avernus,
however you wanna say it.
But we played with Saloni from Plot Hunters,
Ted from Nerd Immersion,
Kyle from Bombarded,
and Renee from Fate and the Fable Maidens.
That's coming up next week.
Make sure you enter the contest before June 30th.
Otherwise, let's get back to the episode.
You have a great week and we'll talk soon.
Let's be honest.
Featuring special guests, the Venture Maidens,
D&D is for nerds, and more.
Plus, we're in Wizards of the Coast's podcast of series.
He just said his hopes and dreams.
He didn't cast a spell.
You gotta get down deep and lift from the knees.
But that's the only big organ he has.
Damn.
Taking initiative.
Look us up on Twitter at ti-underscore-pod
and on our website, takinginitiativepodcast.com.
You've been sitting in your cell all day now.
Merv calls over.
He's like, are you sure you're sure?
That's what she said.
You hear...
Guard!
Make a perception check.
What about my secret mission?
Yeah, right?
Seventeen.
You hear footsteps and like he's jingling coming from down the hall.
Hello!
They stop outside the door and the door opens.
And you see the same guard you saw the night...
Yesterday, I guess.
Officer Tangrin.
And he's standing there and he comes into the room and says...
Ah, tattie boy, tattie boy.
Is it time for my secret mission?
You talk very loud about your secret mission.
There's two of us in here, for god's sakes.
I've been hearing complaints of somebody yelling out into the street.
I told Merv not to do that.
You hear him scoff.
He goes to unlock your cell.
Opens it up and then goes to unlock Merv's cell as well.
He's like, well, are you coming?
Totally.
The two of you follow Officer Tangrin back to Miss Mammyowmyow's office.
He opens the door and lets you in.
And Miss Mammyowmyow is sitting at her desk with all of your
things and Merv, what you can presume, are Merv's things out on the table.
Hey, Merv, are those your things?
Yeah.
You want to trade some things later?
No.
Look at my things.
There's nothing to mine you want.
You wouldn't do any sort of trade things.
I've seen you put things up your butt.
You saw nothing.
Things fell out of what I can only presume was your butt.
I don't want to touch any of your things.
Miss Mammyowmyow pipes in.
Look, you want to do this or what?
Oh, yeah, for sure.
Yes, Miss Mammyowmyow.
All right.
So here's what you're going to do.
You're going to take your things.
You're going to go to Castle Never.
You're going to sneak on in there to Dangle Never Embers.
You're going to grab a ledger.
Hey, does he have more than one?
Yes.
What color?
Good of you to ask.
It should be a red ledger.
Is there any writing on it just in case he has two red ledgers?
There's going to be a symbol on it.
No, there's not going to be symbols on it.
It's the symbol of the Never Embers.
Oh, yes.
And they say a picture says a thousand words.
You know what the symbol for the Never Embers is, don't you?
Of course it's it's not embers.
That's for sure.
Never would they put embers.
No, ma'am, I don't know.
I don't know.
I don't know what the symbol is.
Okay, it's it's a like an oculus singular.
Like a like a looky-loo.
What's a looky-loo?
Like something you look through.
Well, it's no, it's just like one glass.
Yes, like the one glass.
Ah, the one like a monocle.
Sure, if that's what you call it here.
Anyways, it's got that a chain that wraps around it some fires from below.
Well, it's really pretentious.
Right?
Yeah.
This is why we need this ledger.
Very pretentious.
We have to bring down the pretension.
I'm ready.
Hold on.
I'm going to write this symbol down.
Have you been to Castle Never?
Do you know how you're going to get in there?
No, but I get invited to many places.
Merv speaks up.
He's like, I've seen it.
I know kind of whereabouts his office is.
See, and this is why we need Merv.
Can't believe you didn't want me to bring Merv.
Well, good.
I mean, at least one of you is worth something.
So you bring the ledger back to me and then...
Hug it out and you set me free.
Us free.
Is that what we agreed on?
That is, yeah.
So, okay, you go free.
Don't worry about it.
Well, hold on a second.
If I come back, are you going to let me go?
Yeah, absolutely.
Well, it certainly doesn't sound like that.
I am a cat of my word.
I don't believe you, but I'm searching for some excitement in my life.
That those three walls and one bar just can't offer me.
I'll take my chances at Castle Ember.
Well, good.
Off you go then.
Okay, thank you.
I start to gather up my shit.
I hop her desk.
She watches you.
I have a bag.
Does anybody have a bag?
Didn't you have this all on you when you came in here?
Yeah, you took my bag.
She holds up the bag on the desk.
Yeah, that one.
Start to fill it.
Come on, Murph.
Yeah, I'm already.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah, Castle Ember waits for no person.
You are led back out into the street.
Murph, I don't fully trust this.
I mispronounced the castle name twice and nobody corrected me.
I don't think anybody knows what's happening here.
Pretty sure they're aware that you probably don't know what's happening.
Fair enough, yeah.
Um, but if all we have to do is go in, get a ledger and get out,
then we might be able to hedge our bets.
All right.
Lead the way, trusty steed.
Yah!
What a thing to say to your new partner.
You follow Murph through the streets.
It's getting to be about dusk now.
And he leads you to a large gate that surrounds
Castle Never.
And he says, look, there it is.
All right.
Now it's your job.
How are we getting in there?
We knock.
You're going to knock on cat?
What are you going to say when you knock on the door?
They'll come to me.
I love this plan.
Do you want me to hang back or do you want me to come in?
Oh, no, no, we're partners.
Great.
You're right in this.
Yeah.
Just don't look.
Don't have that look.
What look?
Fix your face.
You're still doing it.
No, that's also weird.
Can you look like you have a purpose?
A little different.
No, don't do weird things with your arms.
Put your hands down.
You look like you're hiding something.
Oh, God.
Okay, let's go.
Okay.
So you walk up to the gate and there's two guards standing at the gate to Castle Never.
Good sirs or ma'am.
Are they fully arbored?
Yes.
Well, that's why I can't tell.
What do you want?
I am here on behalf of Lord Neverember.
You're here on behalf of Lord Neverember?
Yes.
He said I have to come in.
For what purpose?
I can't believe you have.
My name is Sullivan's Light.
Great.
Are you saying you've never heard of me?
No.
I make only the best linens for all of the kings and queens and lords and ladies of the lands.
Okay.
My linen services have been requested here.
Deception.
Eighteen.
And nobody keeps a linenery waiting.
Lord Neverember didn't say anything about linens.
I'm sorry.
Does he talk to you about his underwear as well?
Do you know how personal a man's linens are, sir or ma'am?
He goes over to a booth and he says usually he tells me if he's expecting
particularly individuals.
Right here he's got his shoemaker.
Right here he's got his favorite cook.
Right here he's got his underwear maker.
And it's not Sullivan's Light.
Who does he have making his underwear, sir?
Because I have been called in for linens, which I assumed included underwear as well.
And if there is someone else encroaching in on my underwear game,
I need to talk to Lord Neverember to tell him how much of a mistake
he is making going with these other people.
Lord Neverember's not here.
He's off to fight the battle of the linens.
Battle against the cult of the dragon.
And when he comes back and does not have a smooth set of soft, cool silk sheets
to crawl into at night after he is done battling for your freedom,
you can tell him.
Can I like roll intimidation?
Yeah, what are you trying to do here?
Are you trying to intimidate or persuade?
I'm trying to like, I don't know, both.
I'm trying to-
Yeah, well pick which one's the best for you.
Is there a convince roll?
They're the same.
17.
He looks quite taken aback.
Sure, tell me.
I don't want to disappoint.
How do you feel when you, after a hard day's work,
crawl into a freshly made bed?
I mean, my bed's very rarely made, but I mean, I assume it's very good.
Right?
Yeah.
Best feeling in the world.
You want to take that away from your lord?
Yeah, no.
He looks over to his friend and his friend's like,
I'm getting involved in this, man.
It's kind of luck you're getting from him.
So, okay, so do you have like a card or something,
some sort of writ that says that who you are, who you say you are?
I have slight of hand.
Can that just mean to work like instead of stealing,
but like to show something really fast,
like how FBI show their badges?
Like, sorry, sorry, how do they do it?
So you're trying to show them a badge to say you're a linen maker.
You're an underwear maker.
Yeah.
It's a very strong guild.
Yeah, sure.
I get it.
We take our job very seriously.
Okay, yeah.
Um, perhaps let's say you can use slight of hand,
but you use it to quickly.
Can I like quickly backwards behind,
write something official sounding?
Okay, okay.
It's a nat 20 plus six, 26.
No problem.
Like Merv sees you do it because he's standing behind you.
But otherwise, there's like fucking blown away by my penmanship.
Blown away by this behind the back,
like upside down penmanship that you're doing.
But you managed to write whatever you want to write on this page.
And you go to hand it to him.
And what does it say?
It says,
Linenary Guild of Faerun, Sir Sullivan Sleight,
Esquire, Linenary Extraordinaire,
um, to see Lord Neverember's bedroom chambers
in order to outfit with new linens upon his arrival.
He looks this over and it's,
I mean, there's even like,
So now I got a stamp on it.
There's like a sealed something on it.
It's official as fuck.
To him, it looks completely official.
Oh, all right.
I'm sorry, Mr. Sir Sullivan Sleight.
He opens the gates and here's your visitor's badge.
Thank you.
One for my associate, please.
He looks to Merv and so are you a linen, linen?
Do you do linens too?
Yeah, I do the best linens.
Untrue.
He is but a apprentice.
That's the one.
I am an apprentice of linens.
All right.
Hence you both your badges and
ushers you towards the front gate of the Castle Neverember.
Thank you.
Of course.
I won't mention it to Lord Neverember.
Thank you.
Thank you for, thank you for that, Sir Sullivan Sleight.
And we walk up to the-
You walk up a long path to the front entrance,
um, and the doors open for you as you get to the top there.
And you find yourself in Castle Neverember and Merv says,
well, uh, I didn't think we'd get past that.
But, um, uh, yeah, his, his office is on the top,
top of the castle.
So I guess we head up there.
Okay.
Are you trying to just go straight up or are you going sneakily?
What are you trying to do?
Let's sneak.
We're like, we don't want to draw attention to ourselves,
but if we're there, we obviously have a 16.
You stealthily, um, make your way through.
There's, there aren't too many people kind of milling about.
It is kind of later hours.
So there are a few guards that you kind of stop and make your way past
without them noticing you, uh, Merv as well.
And you make your way up to the top of the castle
and there's a single door up at the top of the flight of stairs.
Um, it's a large carved, uh, entryway, big, huge wooden door,
massive silver and brass handle.
As far as it goes, I'm pretty sure this is where his office is.
Well, I go up and I touch it.
I go, Ooh, this is fancy.
Have you never seen a door?
No, but this one's super nice.
I try the handle.
It's locked.
I take out my thieves tools and I pick it.
Is that?
It's light of hand.
Okay.
25.
Damn.
Frank, these big dice.
Big dice, it's crushing it.
So it takes you a minute, um, before you kind of feel where,
where the mechanism is, but-
I'm a very romantic tune as I do it.
Merv's kind of just standing watch.
But it takes you a minute to kind of find it.
But once you do, it's like butter thing opens up
and you feel the door open and swing open and into the room.
And inside there's a large wooden desk.
There's lots of tapestries hung by the walls
and two huge bookshelves filled with different writings and scrolls.
Hey, do you think if we pull on enough books,
we're going to find that one of these bookshelves swings open
and there's going to be a secret passageway down inside?
Uh, I mean, maybe,
but we should probably just find the ledger and get out of here.
Sure, but yeah, if we have a few extra minutes,
I think we should totally look for a secret passage.
Okay, okay.
Maybe we should just kind of look around.
Yeah, no, for sure.
I go to the desk.
Make an investigation check.
13.
You rifle through some of the papers on the desk
and you don't find anything on top.
There are four drawers along the side.
I would like to go through the drawers starting at the bottom.
You pull on them and they are locked.
Oh, I have to pick these too.
You see Merv kind of going through the books on the shelves.
13.
It takes you a little longer with each lock as you go through,
but you manage to get them.
And you pull open the first three locked drawers.
Yeah, you don't find the ledger.
You find lots of different papers and official looking documents,
but nothing from as far as the ledger that you're looking for.
I scroll a couple smiley faces on the corners of some of the papers.
The more important looking ones.
Okay, good.
Noted.
Do you sign your name to them too?
I do not.
Sully's no dumb.
No dummy.
Okay, yeah, the third one you get to,
you manage to open up and inside underneath a few pieces of paper
is a ledger matching the description that Ms. Ma'am Meow Meow gave you.
I take it out and I open it.
You see written in a language that you do not recognize.
It looks like there could be different subjects or names
followed by a colon and a list of different things.
You can't read it though.
I have no idea what the language is.
No idea.
It's not something you've ever seen before.
Merv!
You look up and you see Merv, he's got a few books in his hand as well.
What?
He's got a few books in his hand.
What you got?
Just some things.
You stealing.
Some things I wanted to learn and catch up on.
What you stealing?
There's a book on fishery practices and taxes
and the best trade routes through the canals.
So just workbooks.
It's workbooks.
You said there were three.
You only told me two.
Two of them are tax related.
Oh, yeah, that sounds about right.
Wow, those are boring as all get out.
I mean, that's why I'm in jail is I got caught on like taxes and goods and stuff.
There you go.
You learn at you.
Yeah.
You don't make the same mistake twice.
I appreciate that.
Slip them into his bag and he comes over and looks.
You understand any of this?
I mean, no.
It looks like an old language.
I'm kind of limited in the languages I know.
I know.
But you're old.
I'm not that old.
How old are you?
That's an awfully personal question.
I'm like 32.
Shit.
Really?
Yeah.
Dude.
Dude hasn't aged very well.
The sea has not been kind to you, my friend.
No, apparently not.
With that, you hear a noise, a loud crack coming from outside a window in the room.
You see a bright purple and black light come and it shines and illuminates in the window.
And three figures come through.
They're robed.
Uh, Murph.
They see you and Murph's like, um, what's this?
They see you, they turn to you, and they draw weapons.
Oh, shit.
What are you doing here?
Who are you?
They pull their arrows tighter and said, we are asking the questions.
I, can I make a sleight of hand to sneakily slip the book, the ledger into my bag?
Yep.
Fuck.
It's now good.
Nine.
What's that?
What do you have there?
Oh, here?
Can I make another sleight of hand roll to take something different off of the
desk to show them?
One of them looses an arrow and it clipped Murph's shoulder.
Rude.
He kind of stumbles back.
You can make a sleight of hand if you want to.
Oh, good.
That's a 19.
So 25.
Um, I mean, he, he sees that you slipped something into your bag
and now have something different in your hand.
Yeah.
Um, it's like, no.
And they move towards you and Murph.
I pick up a heavy bottle of ink from the desk
and I throw it in their eyes to blind them so we can escape.
Okay.
I make a straight dex check.
Oh, fuck these dice.
I gave you one compliment.
14.
Yeah, you hit one of them in the face, but there's one who's talking
and appears to be the leader and then another one is moving towards Murph
and he moves to grab him.
But he doesn't cause Murph is like, real slippery person.
Murph rolled a nat one.
So he grabs Murph and begins pulling him back towards
as the other one's trying to wipe the ink from his eyes.
Well, I should do something about this.
They're moving back towards the portal.
Oh, it was a portal.
You could presume.
It was a light.
You're several stories up in the air.
I'm going to acrobatic, like, parkour, like,
foot on the desk, foot on the chair,
hop to grab Murph and like pull him to the side
and away from the backing up to the portal.
Make an acrobatics check.
13.
You do that.
It looks super cool.
Nice.
However, as you're jumping and leaping towards Murph,
the one with the ink in his eyes kind of clears it just in time to see you
and jumps and tackles you to the ground.
You see Murph and the other one and the person or thing
who took him go through the portal
and the other one follows and calls to him saying,
bring him to.
I'm tackled on the floor right now?
Yeah.
I'm going to intimidate, I think.
So Murph is basically already through the portal.
Yeah, Murph is gone.
I'm just working on not going through the portal myself.
I'm going to intimidate in a very strange way.
I'm going to like, as he's got me around the waist,
I'm going to like hook my legs around him and like cuddle his face
and be like, I haven't been held in so long
and just like make him like super uncomfortable
and like really nuzzle into his neck.
I don't know if there's a proper thing for that.
Sure, go intimidate.
Trying to like.
Make him feel uncomfortable.
Yeah.
Nine.
You know, I think you make him feel uncomfortable enough
to try and like pry you off
and give some space between you and him
before he starts to move back towards you.
No, but it was so nice.
So you have space between him.
The door's behind you.
The portal is off to the other side of the room.
Both the other assailants have walked through with Murph.
If I turn to run, will he get any sort of, okay.
No, we're in a skills check, not a combat.
Okay, I'm going to make an athletics check then to run.
Sure.
I guess.
Fuck me.
Three.
Have I forgotten how to run?
Well, we'll say it's an acrobatics
because athletics is strength.
Acrobatics is for, yeah.
So yeah, you turn to run
and you feel this guy has jumped
and has grabbed your ankle and you fall to the ground
and he is now trying to pull at your legs.
I, as I'm being pulled, so we're like midway to the door.
Yeah, you're kind of almost at the door.
Like you could, in theory, you were like a few feet from it.
He's now got you.
He's laying on the ground as well
and he's like pulling at your legs.
Okay, I think I might have to attack this poor guy.
However.
He's not a poor guy.
Yeah, that poor guy.
You're a level one character.
Will be when I'm done with them.
I have acrobar.
Yeah, you do.
What kind of attack?
Like obviously whacking him.
And I'm gonna.
Gonna be plus your strength modifier.
Which is huge because you're half length, so it's low.
Yeah, it's minus one.
Go down.
What kind of weapons proficiencies you have?
Weapon.
Simple weapons.
Yeah, that would count as a simple weapon.
So you plus proficiency.
So it would be plus one to attack.
Okay.
Twelve.
Yeah, you clock him in the head.
Good.
Hard enough to kind of stun him.
But you have a straight shot to the door now.
I run.
You make your way down the door.
You don't hear him kind of calling.
You see, you look up as you're kind of rounding these stairs.
You see the purple and black light go out.
And you make it down to the bottom and then you hear a bell ringing.
Loud and echoing down through the chamber as you leave the front door.
And you see the two guards turn to you withdrawing their weapons.
And they say, what's going on in there?
I, I stop running and I casually stroll over to them.
And I say, are you aware that there are people
portaling in to the castle and stealing lininaries?
I don't really care about the lininaries.
But if there's portals, like we saw it,
one of them begins to run in.
The other one goes back to the gate to stand watch, stand guard.
And you hear a commotion inside.
But you, as of right now, are free to carry on.
Okay. I carry on out of there.
You make your way out into the main street.
You're walking down the street back towards wherever you're going.
I'm headed to the first bar I see.
Okay.
That was very stressful.
Sully hasn't had a drink in, I don't know how long he's been in that prison.
You make it to a building where there looks to be a lot of people gathering.
There's no real sign outside.
But as you're walking in, you come face to face with a rather tall
and imposing Dragonborn.
For the love of Pete, you're big.
I am pretty big.
You are a little bit smaller than me, though.
Yes. Yes.
That is, that was implied.
That was implied.
Make a perception check, Lynn.
Well, I mean, I have a plus one, so that's a problem.
Wait, am I perceiving that he's smaller than me?
Just some spatial awareness.
Eyes at 18.
So you hear bells ringing off in the castle off,
which you, throughout your travels and speaking with people in the city,
have come to know as Castle Never.
You notice that Sully may have a tinge of panic behind the eyes,
but you also see a very, like the bag that Sully is carrying.
You don't know Sully, but the bag that this halfling is carrying
is kind of half open and there's a very impressive looking book inside.
Well, we've been staring at each other for a little bit,
so I feel inclined to ask you your name.
Okay.
That socially thing.
That's a social thing.
What's your name?
I'm Glim.
Who are you?
The name's Sullivan Sleight.
You can call me Sully.
Oh, thanks, Sully.
Looks like I'm hearing a lot of noise and commotion.
Sounds like they might be looking for something important
and I like make a significant glance down toward his bag.
Really?
Because I thought those were party bells.
See, I'm new here in the city.
I literally just got out of prison.
Wrongfully accused, mind you.
And I was just looking to,
do you know where there's like a good place we can sit down and have a beer?
I assume we're at the Fallen Tower, are we?
Or like near the Fallen Tower?
Was that where the people were gathering?
You're on another side of the city,
so you're at a different tavern to be named.
Oh, okay.
Well, you know, I'm staying at a nice place,
but it's a long way away.
Why don't we should just...
Do you want to maybe have a drink?
Sure, you're from here?
I just got here, just last night.
Whoa, well, tell me about your travels.
Um, maybe I'll ask my good friend...
Melania.
No, just kidding.
Do you want to make up a name for us?
That I thought, because that is not what it's going to be.
Too political.
Guys, it's easy.
Moot is just Tom backwards.
Which I didn't even put together when I named the character that.
Then I was like, oh, all right.
I saw it on like the screen and I was like,
oh, yep, yep.
Sure did that.
I'm changing my character name to Al Rack.
And that's a good character name.
That's awesome.
Yeah, Al Rack is totally...
Yeah, see, these are all D&D names.
These are great.
I got to write these down here.
These will be key characters later, so...
Definitely, big players.
Well, they might...
You never know.
You never know with us.
That's also a really good point, Tom.
Giant dice.
Roll to 16.
Add my bonus.
Spider-Man.
It was a really good bonus, you guys.
All of a sudden, I'm Spider-Man.
What time of the morning is it?
It's probably fairly early.
We'd say, you know, seven-ish.
OK, well, I'm supposed to meet What's-his-nuts-at-noon, correct?
What's-his-nuts-at-noon, correct?
You're inspiring, mentor?
Yeah, that's the one.
Oh, what's-his-nuts?
Oh, what's-his-nuts.
Old drunk McGee.
Calls to you and says, you found everything OK.
I can't remember if that was her voice, but it is now.
Oh, she had a lot of Irish going on.
Yeah, they sometimes do.
You guys are so fucking sweet.
And I feel like Sully is going to come in and just like fuck this shit up.
It's going to be adorable, adorable, adorable, friendship, love.
Keyster.
And I'm just going to suck all that adorableness like right up my bum.
Right up your keys.
This is why we need this ledger.
Very pretentious.
We have to bring down the pretension.
I'm ready.
Hold on.
I'm going to write this symbol down.
I mean, you've heard of toppling the patriarchy.
Wait till you try to topple the pretension.
The songs Nowhere Land, Loopster, Marty Gotza Plan,
Virtutes, Instrumenti, and Anguish are by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
Licensed under Creative Commons by attribution.
Visit creativecommons.org slash licenses slash buy slash 4.0.
Songs Lowly Tavern Bard and Lowly Tavern Bard III are by Technoaxe, royalty-free music.
Visit technoaxe.com.
Licensed under Creative Commons by attribution.
Creativecommons.org slash licenses slash buy slash 3.0.