previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
as you slow your pace where there's a slab of jet black stone that sits at the center of this
cavern alcove its sides show relief carvings of familiar old faces you look at them a little
more closely and they're your own faces i uh don't remember sitting for this but like they
did a really good job with us in a flash you're in a stone walled hallway another hallway how
refreshing are we all here we look around are we all there i'm here hurry hurry you gotta go
gotta go fast gotta go gotta go really quick okay boys ah ah shh and then down at the end
of the hallway you see a pseudo dragon zip by and then come back and looks down towards you
holy fucking shit donnie welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons i am your dungeon master Russ More and
with me today is carla max dead that is me i play yen bolnuri a kalashtar cleric and amy
more that's me i play thea amistacia a high elf druid and tom laird hey that's me i play
flint Firebeard a champion dwarf phyta welcome everybody that's you we are having us oh that's
us oh okay yeah no yeah you you too but also you but also you thank you for being here
yes thank you i got confused yeah yeah sometimes i talk to you guys sometimes i don't you know
it's all up to what i've written down previously he's shaking his head vigorous head shaking
you can hear that in the audio recording can't you yeah his hair swishes back versus actually
just panning the audio from left to right right i'm so good like that anyways um way
back a long time ago we started something called Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
yes okay we did yes and since we started it we have loaded well over
50 plus hours of amazing audio bonus content that we would love for you to hear by coming
and joining us at that at that web address Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and part
of that is an entire series of great adventures yes with your on keep going with your more
heroes uh-huh from another story opal elia and knight hunter who are they well the only
way to find out is to come visit us and when you are a patron you get an episode dedicated
to you like today's patron lee wilson yay thanks lee thanks lee thank you for not
jumping in and saving me everybody no that was sometimes we just like to watch you drown a
little it's like you were you were going somewhere and just were building in pregnant pauses
for effect i thought maybe you put yourself in a word maze and you were trying to get out
i feel like sometimes we have to be those mama birds that are just like okay time to fly
and they either fly or they don't yeah well i got so lee if you stopped listening before
you heard your if you showed out i'm so sorry so sorry but it's there so just skip back 15
seconds it'll be perfect i mean probably 30 at this point and now let's play
the four of you find yourselves having just seen your friend donnie flying soaring speedily
careening towards you holy fuck guys i thought i'd never see you again oh my god donnie is it
really you and i bend down and i and i gather him in my arms and i start checking him over
you save you have you been are you okay is anyone hurt you no well i mean it's malnutrition uh
a little starvation uh mental uh terror you take your pick but otherwise great other than that how
was the play mrs lincoln where have who holy how many days has it i hello i am donnie who are your
friends hello i'm uh yen bull it is so nice to meet you i have i've heard about you uh
hey thea you see this person that is talking to me the yeah is it's real
mm-hmm okay yeah she's real and this other one oh mannex yes yes mannex oh cool good
so you acknowledge their presence i've even seen people well um you've been alone
well except for when i'm being chased who took you uh well see there was a flash yeah i
remember the flash yeah we all got thrown you was you was all gone i didn't see anybody
i was i was out of the forest it was it was cold and dark and i heard i heard this laughter
kind of kind of sounded like real not like fun laughter like they're watching the play
you know that remember that one cat play that came through town everybody was really laughing at
it because it was so gosh darn good oh yeah yeah that was that was great yeah little little
knoll on the prairie i think is what it was anyways uh no this was like evil laughter but
it sounded familiar it sounded like you know that uh the guy we met down in the in the crazy
with the brains and the pieces and bits uh-huh it's kind of sounded like him like thelonious
primsbane oh that's the name that's the name yeah you know yeah brains and jars and stuff yeah
shit anyway he he started into this diatribe that ended with like run run as fast as you
can don't get caught or you'll be dead in a flash at i i i called him out on his rhyming
scheme and then he sent some undead after me uh so he didn't seem to like that um but real
uh i ran like he said and every once in a while i'll see a flash of lightning and then laughter
again and it's been like this for a while i don't know how long exactly i've been here
oh you poor thing how long have have you we i how long um i mean it's been it's been a while
well we looked for you pretty hard at the start but there was just no sign
but we never gave up hope we actually had people working to try to find you mystically
using magic i i had no idea we'd find you in a floating pyramid i would have i would have
brought your collar yeah yeah because you're just itty bitty now hey um it's just a little tired
come here and i open up my bag my satchel he uh flies in and like collapses inside of your
bed oh there are snacks in there he's unconscious yeah seemingly you must be so happy to have
found your friend i know you have missed him so much you have mentioned it and he has been
missing for so long it's a little bittersweet though i mean how is this all gonna go down
if if i mean yes i'm happy to have him back of course but we are in just the most dangerous
place we could possibly be and now if primsbane has his hand in this if he's working with
the lich oh i i'm not like i'm not giving up hope or anything obviously super positive
that everything's gonna be fine um so the genus are that you talked to did they give you
like a timeline or just kind of can't remember don't know how long we've been in here you
know time seems to be just a construct at this point yes i don't know can you tell me about this
primsbane he said brains in jars and undead and the undead part makes it seem like
perhaps he and the lich would be friends
let's let us hope not yeah no he's a really bad dude super handsome though gotta give it
to him um he is an um he's an elf wizard and that guy's got some crazy power and he's just
like fucking crazy so but we know his one weakness he is very bad at rhymes
that's right we could maybe taunt him i'm not sure how that could help us but perhaps
uh maybe thea could challenge him to a rap battle
that's right i'll start thinking up some some sick rhymes really fool that a-hole
i will write a rap later
ahead of you down this hallway there's nothing behind you uh it is a torch lit
hallway that looks like it tees off at the end which is where you saw donnie zipping across
as you're talking the uh out of the corner of your eye you see a flash of a figure
down at the end of the hallway running down the top of the t
uh not back where we came not running down towards the top of the t but not running
it's uh floating and orb-like you see a glinting eye staring back at you
and that clicking that you heard echoes down the hallway is it like a baby beholder or a big
beholder big beholder the big beholder um oh hey hi you you're still here you you are here
to help for buxy doesn't say anything and they turn and move to the right of the t and disappear
um perhaps that is the way we should go i think so yeah something seems wrong though
why why wouldn't they say anything i want to slowly peek around the corner
i just want to run around the corner and slowly peek around the corner you walk down the hallway
and approach the corner is it just you peeking around or are you three stooges in it oh three
stooges obviously i mean four stooges there's four of us manix is down there is very small
sure yeah um okay the four of you peek your head around the corner
and you see the torch lit hallway which continues uh but before you you see a dead end
about 25 feet down you look to the left and another dead end
but we don't see for buxy you don't see for buxy i like whisper into the dead end
for buxy it just echoes back off the stone in front of you my whisper echoes back dang
yeah it's too loud it's echoey got crazy acoustics in this dead end do you think maybe
there's um like a secret brick we can touch a passageway uh maybe this isn't actually a
dead end maybe it's just a an illusion yes this must be true i have heard about
mazes where along the walls if you feel your way you will find a hole in the maze that you
cannot see that could have been the way out all along but instead you are actually just
trying to get out by using logic yes i have heard of such a place
well um we don't have anything to lose i mean donnie came from down here yes
have come from somewhere i'd ask him but he's totally snoozing he needs to sleep
keep can i roll a perception check to see if i can perceive anything
probably investigation for anybody wanting to investigate their current situation
investigate the current situation i would love to not investigate my current situation with my
four seven hmm all right let's no it's dead ends guys there's nowhere to go
the crit fail so mannex mannex rolled an 18 this is why we keep an NPC around with
just in case you need to find a plot point tom get your own roles well sorry amy
okay i'll let it go this time um okay crit fail tom okay yep got it uh okay the three
of you are like patting the walls trying to find a brick or stone or something to depress or turn
or whatever uh so focused on the dead end ahead of you um you mannex walks back down the hallway
and is looking for other things and gets to the t and calls you three over hey uh
uh come come take a look at this yes what do you see it looks like a map you walk over
and you see very faint and worn etched into the stone right at the end of the
hallway that you walk down to get to this t is a worn down map and it looks like the pathway
of the tunnels that you are in uh there is a star at the end of a long straight hallway
teeing off to dead ends on either side so it's like a you are here this is our mall
map the you are here can i take out a couple pieces of parchment or scroll or whatever i have
and a piece of charcoal and rub this making itching yes sure rub this out can i can i rub
one out episode title can i rub this out see you in the middle of this wants to just rub
one out guys it's stressful just need a moment look away don't look at me
no keep direct eye contact it's going to be extreme yeah fair enough okay um yeah absolutely
so you pull out a a piece of paper and charcoal or something as you touch the wall
Yenbul flint and mannex you see thea disappear
thea you touch the wall and immediately have an orgasm sure and immediately have an orgasm but
also uh you rub the the chalk or charcoal along the paper turn around and see that your friends
are gone however above you where there was stone it is open you see elongated versions of your
friends looking down at you almost like i'm seeing them through a glass ceiling that's also
a funhouse mirror and they're very huge um Yenbul flint and mannex uh you see on the map
there is now beside the star a tiny image of thea oh she has she has been pulled into the map
but how how would that even work i don't know what is a magical flying
castle what are you talking about how would that work oh you know what fair point
how does any of this work after a moment you hear stone movement down towards either end of
the hallway and two doorways open up and on the map you see passageways start to form
on the etched in map do passageways form in my version of this weird hallway yes they do
you see you hear the stone grinding and then look down both sides where there was a dead end
when you looked but did not see your friends now you see two open passageways
okay beyond it on the map the passageways extend but then fade off i i yell up at them
uh hey you don't hear thea
yeah i look at my bag do i still have donnie yep you have all of your content still with
you including donnie okay well i think thea disappeared when she touched the wall
i think we should all stay together yes yeah i mean that's it's probably good idea for this
weird pyramid castle flying magic place we're in so yeah let's let's go find her
yes let's touch the wall as well i'm going to touch the map okay uh everybody touches the map
yeah you all touch the map and the instant you do uh you are standing beside thea
you see um the same illusion of like outstretched uh structures outside and
you see your friends as you each one like yeah i assume Yenbul goes first you see flint and
manix flint goes you see manix and manix uh touches it and follows him behind oh you guys
found me i feel like i'm tiny or are you guys really big no it was likely me i'm i'm
tiny but now we're tiny you think we have shrunk well i don't know and i gesture with
my head up to the glass ceiling of giantness but doorways huh and i point to the left and the
right did this happen in big world yes the stone moved yes okay well um maybe we go down
one of them and we should go right where if a boxy went i think so sounds as good as any choice
let's do it okay let's go wait hold on is this where we want to be or should we try touching
the map again and getting back up to normal land i mean i don't know i don't know i also
don't know i don't want to get i don't want to get to a certain part and it'd be like
oh this is as far as you can go shadow land mirror world person um i'm gonna touch the map
again i want to see what happens if i just go back to the other side okay so what are you
doing to try and get back to the other side just gonna touch the touch the map again uh you
touch the map that's on the wall and nothing happens all right well that answers that question
um let's go to the right yes it appears we have made our decision um you did describe
it as a glass ceiling but there is no actual glass above oh yes no it is just you can see
that there is a mirror image almost of what's down here yeah sorry folks no glass
um okay so you're heading down to the right yeah yes for if you begin to walk
down to the right in the direction uh where you saw for buxy go um and as you take a few steps
from your current location the stone walls begin to close in on either side that's not good
like we're in a trash compactor on a spaceship sorry no just like they're just like they're
resealing actively moving they're just getting smaller not moving but like closing up the
doors that just opened i see yeah okay oh can we run for it
make a text or athletics or acrobatics are you running just just by yourself okay
cool no no let's go i'm like let's go if the door is closing i want to try and get
through the door athletics he said 19 okay i'm so fast so fast uh 15 22 oh wow well i have a plus
10 so really it wasn't that great uh the faster you run the faster they close and by the time
you get to them they are closed are we just trapped in a passageway with no
no exits cool um maybe we go stand by the map again yes perhaps it goes um three two one on the
timer maybe i mean it was just open for the whole time we had this conversation and then just
started to close so i walked back over to the map yeah me too uh the four of you walk back
the four of you walk back over to the map uh and they remain closed i touch the map
nothing happens i knock on the map nothing i take a piece of paper out and i etch another
you have another etching up the map cool but i'm on this one this time
yeah we're on this one now right you can see up and out you look around you can see up
and out and into the big world uh but there are no egresses can i make an investigation check to
see what the frick is around me i will also 19 oh investigating the shit out of this place
you are mine's only a 12 uh okay yeah with a 19 you get the feeling that you could climb up
the walls oh i just get i just get a feeling okay well you're not actively climbing you're
investigating right no but i mean okay so i'm looking and i see like there are like
notches that'd be good for hand holds or do i put my hand on and i'm like yes like spider
man no you could you could climb up to the open ceiling okay um hey you guys uh i think
we might be able to get back up there if we and i put my foot on one foot hold and grab a hand
up and start to scale the wall you climb up um by yourself everybody's just watching thea at
the moment maybe what's this crazy girl doing i was like ready to catch her if she fell sure
thanks when spotting thea you climb up and as you reach up and pull yourself up to the top
of this wall um you are shot out and back you're now looking back at the map and you see
three figures on the map oh and i can't see my friends anymore uh no you see them tiny figures
drawn on the wall right but not around me as you exit the map the doorways begin to open back
up should we just go for the doorway or should we wait for her to come back oh because the
doorway opened down in tiny world also it did yes or do we all head up and then go for the doorway
i don't like the idea of us separating no i don't either so but we need to
we either need to get her back or all go up there because we need to be together
i i don't think i hear this conversation you don't do i i was like what's thea doing
thea's like waiting and looking and being like you're not they're not fucking coming
oh my oh my god you just see three uh images of your friends kind of just roughly scared i
figure like like mario the original mario characters like moving big arms and legs um
just kind of flipping back and forth as if they're discussing something with each other
um well we know if we are all down here we cannot go to door i suppose we could all go up
there and see if we can get the door or maybe we just waited too long last time before we went
but yeah let's go up and we'll see if we're waiting if we're able to go over there then
let's go quickly damn it we did it again i spider-man like thea did up the wall yes me too
everybody follows and is sucked out into the big world the real world um and as uh the the four
of you set foot into this you hear the stones closing again ah no no run run no no no run
faster you run the faster i think it's a little late what took you guys so long up here like
an asshole just like standing by myself i go back to the map and i touch it again russ
uh flint is back inside the map i also run and touch it
goes back inside the map well i mean did it open the doors again when i did that or when flint
goes back inside the map the doors do open again okay yeah then yeah i'll follow too and then i
immediately start walking in an leisurely pace toward the door not waiting just being like
okay so flint and yen bull are inside manix and thea are out or no no i've also touched the map
and then as soon as i get down there i'm walking to the start heading for that door manix
follows lead and follows behind the three of you and as the fourth one of you gets back
into the map the doors begin to close again faster you run the faster they uh all right
one of us has to not be we have we have solved the problem a little bit
okay who wants should we just split two and two should we i don't think there should just be
one person all alone that seems rather shitty also not it i mean i can do it if need be
but i'm happy to go with someone too yes i see what you're saying yes it makes sense two and
two and we will both in in large world and timey world go towards the right as teams of two
okay and if we are if we are if we find ourselves faced with a choice again
choose to go right okay how about that and then hopefully we will be going in the same
direction the whole time
all right manix uh you and me up top and we'll we'll leave these two here all right so we are in
tiny world you folks are going back up yep okay um then i i hope we will see you soon
i give i give flint a hug oh sure yeah hug hug as well i guess i reciprocate you return the
hug you know just stand there i returned sir let me roll for hug here oh failed failed miserably
it's oh cool you just did you just like wiggled back and forth just not completely
unresponsive flint and manix you climb back up and out you see the two images of yen bull
and thea thea and yen bull you see elongated outstretched flint and manix the tallest flint
is ever gonna look hey you're damn right manix too well as we start to make our way
towards the door rust does anything happen this time the door remains open all right
nonchAlydintly yen bull let's not scare it closed yes we won't run then it goes quicker
let's just walk at a normal pace flint and manix as you two begin to walk towards the
door you see the map begin to follow along with you inside you see your friends big arms big legs
moving alongside following with you does our map follow us yes your map follows along with
okay somebody roll me a d8 no it's not gonna be me okay i don't want to be responsible
straight up refusal i don't want to be responsible for what happens because of this
that is a three oh that's my favorite number you're walking for a while taking always rights
yeah so just in circles it's not a right it's a wrong okay that's how we remember it
you're walking for a while and taking always rights any chance you get the map continually
following beside flint and manix all four of you you hear like a is a long dark hallway
ahead of you and as you as you walk down the hallways the darkness fades the closer you get
and torches illuminate like this map or this these tunnels are bringing themselves into view
it feels like just beyond this darkness you hear like this low groaning and like soft
patted feet strike the stone just outside of you uh yen bull do you hear that yes i do it sounds
like a large creature do we are so small what if it is just a normal size creature
doesn't matter does it flint and manix you hear this too up up in your own area okay flint
and manix you see yen bull and thea stop for a moment turn to each other big arms
what if we use this and i take out a potion
and it is passed without a trace sure it's happening it's not invisibility so you remember
oh right it's not never mind i mean you can use it if you want to but it's not it's just a hallway
with no like things
your call though um
well maybe we can befriend it like we like we did the beholder yes perhaps just because it
is a creature it does not mean it is evil perhaps it is also being held here against
its will okay um well let's go forward carefully um with friendship in our hearts yes
up with flint and manix i wonder what they're talking about do you hear that sound too yeah i'm
i'm not really sure what it is but we we better get ready i think okay meanwhile we're
like friendship in our hearts and flint is like get your weapons ready all four of you
see the others begin to move again on the map and you move forward and as you walk forward
the the groaning gets louder and begins to echo off the walls and ahead of you illuminated
by torches you see first you see like a long cloak that extends down to the ground the light
moves up and it's a deep hooded figure with hands that are dark like gray mottled gray
they don't look quite human yeah you can't quite place them like they're not reptilian
they're not human they're not mammalian they begin to raise their hands to their hood
hello if we can see them i assume they can see us yeah i mean yeah i assume that we're facing
the front not the back yeah yeah you see like the deep recessed hood so you don't see a face
or anything beyond it um it's just shadow as they're raising their hands to their hood you
say hello they go to raise their hood make a constitution saving throw as their face becomes
clear and it's gaunt and you see dark deep recessed eyes and a long jaw that extends down
and opens a long slithering tongue rolls out of their mouth slime sloughs down their skin
it's a 22 for my con roll 17 for mine which is okay don't feel like it's good enough
uh 17 for mine as well as this creature uses its withering gaze on the four of you you each
take 11 necrotic damage dang son roll for initiative i say it's like the stare my mother
would give to me when i when i told her i didn't want to take over the family business
uh 10 19 12 keski's pass flint
uh the creature ahead of you do i know this creature make a you can you
druidic wise you can tell it it's undead well yeah i mean pretty much everything you run
into this thing ain't alive guys um but roll nature or or arcana would probably
whichever you prefer 18 you recognize it you've maybe heard stories or read broken passages of
an undead creature named the bodak bodak horseman um and it's uh it has a
um a gaze that if looked upon can instantly kill a creature oh
welcome to the middle hey it's me just me yeah well you know when you edit late and
everybody else goes to bed uh it's it's just me that's okay i just wanted to talk to you i
just wanted to have you to myself in this moment and uh you know just get to know how
how things are going with you hopefully you're doing well i really wish the best for you right
now hopefully you're safe and happy and healthy and that's what i want to get across here right
now is that we appreciate you we do we love that you're here with us loving the story that
we were creating for and with you it's amazing so that's all that's all i got right now there
may be an ad right after this but i hope you're well be safe be kind to yourself be kind to
others and yeah what else can i tell you we've got some fun cool things coming up in this
storyline and in the mooclum and sully storyline that we're really excited about
and we hope you are too there's some great guests coming your way before the end of the year
and beyond the story there's so much to be thankful for and a large part of it is thanks
to you so i hope you have a great day i hope you have a great week i hope you have a great
rest of your year uh take time for yourself be it listening to podcasts reading books
playing video games going for a run whatever you do find time for it because it's very easy
as we are all super busy and super consumed with media and twitter and facebook and all
of that sort of stuff to forget to take time for you so here's here's here's here's the
challenge take 10 minutes today any 10 minutes at any point in the day do something for
enjoyment i mean you're listening to a podcast right now hopefully that's the case
but unplug put your phone away read a book go for a walk tomorrow maybe do 15 minutes
a day after that try for 20 until you get to a point when maybe you can do an hour that'd be
pretty cool maybe you're already doing this and then fantastic but if if you need a little
encouragement hopefully that's what this is know that you are loved and that you are
appreciated now let's get you back to the story have a great week we'll talk soon
again well don't don't look at it
i drop my gaze to the ground okay i also do if you if you look at it it can kill you
it's a boat it's a bodak i i read about it in the libraries um ditch uh don't like we're
gonna have to not look at this and fight it because i don't i don't think that i think this
thing wants to be here if you want to figure out what this is flint you can roll uh i said
nature or arcana all right or see if you know about it i mean neither one of those are super
great but i still have some bonuses so i mean it would make sense if you didn't but uh
yeah 15 you you would have heard tales of a creature that reminds you of this
but they were all like children's stories of creatures with a gaze that could injure
or harm you thea you're up first oh i am neat okay uh okay uh let's see what kind of spells
i have where i don't need to actually look at anything if it doesn't say a creature you can see
if it just says within range is it a spell attack yeah you roll with disadvantage if you're
not looking oh i'm gonna eldritch blast at disadvantage yeah 14 it goes wide and cracks
into the stone beside it damn it uh okay fine uh what if i try to hit it with my oath bow
at disadvantage because i'm not looking yeah i whisper with death to those who have wronged me
and oh 14 the arrow goes wide flint and manox you see cracks form as out of the corner of
your eye you see like sparks shoot from what you presume to be thea's character in this and
cracks begin to form on the stone where these things hit is manox's turn they
at the beginning of their turn don't look away uh so they have to make a constitution saving
throw we haven't had an NPC die in a long time flint you see manox stumbles and holds their head
tight and like corrects themselves and uh holds their mace and slams it down into the ground
trying to turn undead uh which doesn't work so a beam of light ripples through the hallway
and you see a faint aura Yenbul and thea within your hallway move towards this creature and like
wind gusts at its cloak and nothing happens to it flint um how visible were those cracks ross
you mentioned uh it's like something just struck into so not like it's something's cracking or
damaging but like something struck into it and like chipped off part of the stone
oh okay well now i'm very curious about that yeah happened at the same time you saw it or your
periphery sparks come from thea's character on the map okay um but if you don't intentionally
look away from this creature i need you to make a constitution saving throw okay uh yeah
i probably noticed what happened to manox but didn't really understand why or how
so i will roll a constitution saving throw uh that is a 19 you take no damage as you do
what you want to do the creature locks eyes with you and i point at my two eyes and i say i'm the
captain now as i stroll forward with my axe in hand okay go for it all right first attack
21 that will hit second attack 24 yep third attack 17 uh also will hit oh uh as you as you
step forward uh this is unrelated to the constitution saving throw um but you're going
to take five necrotic damage as you step in you feel like this withering effect okay all
right so all three attacks hit you got it roll some damage all right let's do this
uh 16 and 11 is 27 followed by another 12 so 39 magic slashing damage three huge strikes
uh crush into this creature um and
yen bull and thea you see gashes show up across its cloak and cut into its flesh
mirror world flint is there anything else you want to do uh nope no that'll be
that'll be about it for me okay thea has a strange urge to nickname flint captain now and
she's just not sure why uh Yenbul is your uh i am going to channel divinity turn undead
i'm going to speak a prayer centering the undead needs to make a wisdom saving throw
the problem this thing is dumb as shit right uh 13 that is good for me uh if the creature
fails its saving throw it is turned for one minute until it takes any damage a turn creature
must spend its turn trying to move as far away from you as it can and it can't willingly move
to a space within 30 feet of you it also can't take reactions for its action it can only use
dash or try to escape an effect that prevents it from moving there's nowhere to move the
creature can use dodge okay so it's got a turn on its turn and get away there's more okay
but wait um if you order now in the next 10 minutes when an undead fails its
saving throw against your turn undead feature the creature is instantly destroyed if its
challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold which this almost certainly isn't
but what if it is what if it is what is the threshold what is my level 16 so challenge
rating of three or lower oh it's higher than that would have been super cool totally imagine
okay that's uh all for your turn yes neither of you yen bull or thea took any step towards it
you just cast from no yeah okay we are spell casters we do not go near the creatures
okay flint you take these three strikes in and then there's this like
aura that washes over the area and the creature in front of you turns and begins to walk away
allowing you an opportunity attack oh all right let's do that oh we're gonna fuck it up don't
smile you bitch do i i just roll damage it automatically hits uh you have to roll to it
okay yeah because you could get so excited that you miss just be like trap or something
sure i could yeah yeah yeah um it was an 18 before bonuses so i'm sure it's fine
you know what it hits i guess it's really 31 just for you this time yeah the nice nice dm
doing yes solid all right and that is 17 damage all right describe what everyone sees when you
destroy this creature well thank god because otherwise it would have come at us um i guess
i just as it's like turning to walk away from me i take like one big step and just like plant
my axe and like it's back do you yell don't you walk away from me or anything like that
yeah give us a cool line oh geez now i'm on the spot for a cool line i can cut amy's
you can have don't you walk away from me or i wasn't finished with you
i'm the captain now just keep saying that we're not done here i like it yeah so the creature
another huge gash latches into its back that yimbal and thea see and it falls to the ground
and for you two it fades into the stone for flint and manix it remains in front of you
you this mysterious i thought theirs would have faded into the stone and ours would
have stayed yeah we're not in a real world uh can i go over to the wall where those like
cracks maybe showed up sure and just like feel around and see if i can like determine whether
or not that was like an optical illusion or a real thing sure yeah i mean yeah give me an
investigation role at advantage because there's no pressing i mean guys it's real nice when there's
no pressing issues the first one was a 21 second one was a nine so we'll go with the 21
21 yeah you go over and um there's they're definitely real cracks like it
like something caused real damage to it and it even has like this bit of like residue on
there which is reminiscent of thea's eldritch blast smells like my perfume
you're like chanel number five i ask manix if i can borrow their mace for a quick sec
they yeah yeah yeah here and i don't want to wreck your own weapons strike the wall with it
well i mean a mace is a pretty good crushing tool and axe not as much okay yeah you hit
the wall and strike into it the stone crumbles a little bit below
Yenbul and thea you see stone like crack and like drop to the ground
i've been fighting with him for a long time i know what his flashes look like
i think it's flint i mean you can see him flint what do you do oh right we can see
him doing this oh yes oh i don't see any like visual representation of them of them of my little
tiny friends with big arms and big legs do you know what do you think we're like pumping our
fists so like you don't see them like in the hallway with you yeah like i don't i like there's
no hole for me to look through and like see them down there i am sorry i understand what
you're asking yes uh no you don't see you know you don't see through the stone like it's just
deeper the stone just goes deeper um but yeah no you don't see them except for the tiny
images of them on the map on the wall Yenbul do you have a dagger or anything
oh actually you know what here and i grab my uh i grab an arrow and i go over to the wall
where the smash happened um and i carve in high flint all right 20 minutes later i did it fast
okay you carve in high flint and you hear the sound of like hooves hitting the stone ahead
of you and snarling and grunting and you turn and you see glowing eyes all four of you down
your respective hallways glowing eyes and like smoke billowing from these nostrils that are
flaring as a skeleton minotaur charges out towards you
the song long road ahead is by Kavin mcleod of incompetech.filmmusic.io all other music
and sound effects can be found at epidemicsound.com or boomlibrary.com a huge thank you to our
supporting producers christian brown darylith devan michaels gabriel lynch jacob madden
jessica Babyok cat water flame mark heartless and stevie to find out more about how you
can support Dumbgeons and dragons visit us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where you
can have exclusive access to 50 plus hours of bonus audio content create in-game NPCs and
items as well as play games with the cast Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast have a great week
and we'll talk soon Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production