previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
As you step through and your eyes are trying to adjust and you're seeing this before you,
this wave of energy blasts out towards all of you and you're all going to take
32 psychic damage and be stunned for one minute.
Oh, okay.
Welcome to tonight's game.
I feel like it just ended.
Well, you feel these tentacles wrap around your face and there's like this alien like teeth,
mouth beginning to take a chomp out of your face and for everybody they hear like this
this like suction this and moot's gone.
Pleasure to see you again, Moot.
It's been a while.
Have you come to make good?
Kind of in a bit of a pickle here being here and all my friends
being back wherever we were in that weird moist cave.
Oh, oh, so you've so you've come for another favor.
There's this brilliant flash of like electric light and moot.
You're hovering above the brain in the center of this room blast of energy
that ripples out around the room briefly stunning the creatures in the room
while at the same time releasing your friends from their paralysis
that's been holding them for the last 18 seconds.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More.
He him also with me today is Tom Laird.
Yeah, he him and I'm playing Moot who also goes with he him.
And Carla Maxted.
She her playing Glim also she her.
And Amy More, so kind of you.
She her and I'll be playing Sullivan slight.
He him.
Was it enough time, Chris?
Hold on.
And I will be playing Sullivan slight.
The lightfoot halfling rogue level 20 who has taken quite a few hits,
but not enough to get him down.
Never going to get him down.
Not going to keep them down.
Can't do things like that.
He him.
Joining us again today is Kristen Flemmons.
Oh, hi, it's me, Kristen Flemmons, who definitely doesn't have a mouthful of peanut butter.
She her playing Agath who also doesn't have a mouthful of peanut butter,
just a mouthful of cave floor and mind flayer hatred.
She her.
Yeah, I realized now that I was like, is everybody ready?
And then I didn't stop and wait for a response.
No, she had a mouthful of peanut butter.
I realized that after I introduced Thomas looking over and like.
I'm pointing at her just like, panic, panic, panic.
She's got a mouthful of peanut butter.
Either choose her first.
That's all right.
Amy's a pro.
She know how to drag that out.
That's right.
I handled it.
It was fine.
Oh, yes.
So much fun.
Where there's also a lot of fun is over on Patreon.
Patreon.com.
So I'm Dragoncast where you join.
You become part of the part of the community.
You can come chat with us in Discord and on Patreon,
and we answer your questions and hang out and Amy post garden pictures
and Tom and I post all the bread things and Carla posts.
Carla, sometimes I don't post anything.
I just creepily look at everything.
Everyone else.
Yeah, just yeah.
I'm just always there in the background.
And she's reading everything.
There's been like three dog photos you've posted over the course of it.
Yeah, fair enough.
If my dog was able to take a photo of my dog where he wasn't moving,
I'd post pictures every day.
But every picture is just a blur.
The flash running through the screen.
That's right.
But when you are a patron, you also get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Darylith.
Darylith, thank you.
That is a name that I definitely recommend.
No, I recommend that name.
I recommend Darylith as well.
Five out of five would say that name again.
Would say that name again.
So many things that they've posted.
That's what I was going to say.
I totally recognize from Discord.
Darylith's very active in the community.
Great contributor.
Thanks, Darylith.
Also fun to say.
Five out of five would say again.
Absolutely.
Like Darylith, you can join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And now, fuck it, let's play.
Or die.
Either or.
I mean, it's still up in the air.
Yes, and?
Have you been to the improv classes?
We left our friends in a perilous scene
where everybody except Sullivan Sleight and Glim were...
Taking naps, slaggers.
Taking naps on the job.
Being controlled by this elder brain.
Surrounded by mind flares and troglodytes.
And these other weird things that started coming in.
Grells, these bird-beaked brains with tentacles.
Coming in, moving upon our adventures.
As Moot makes an electric appearance high above the brain.
And there's this blast of energy
that comes out from him and from the location where he arrives.
And everybody who's incapacitated.
And everybody who's mind controlled.
There's this static shock that runs through you.
And you feel movement come back to you.
As everybody is able to get up of their own accord.
What?
Nothing!
No, I'm imagining him coming down, floating down.
But he's got a harness on.
There's pressure wires.
And he's got a microphone.
He's wearing leather pants.
And he's all like, get up!
Get on up.
And everyone is doing that.
So that's what my big smile is.
I mean, I'm super into it.
And it's like, where do you get the leather pants?
That was the old search boot.
Yep, that's right.
Yep.
It was the pants.
Everybody wakes up and you get assless chaps.
100%.
Moot, it is your turn in rotation.
You are electrified with wild magic energy as well as the...
I mean, we'll play with this great old one situation for a little while.
As long as we need to here.
You are hovering in the space above the brain.
Which its tentacles are now with this energy that's in the room.
Flailing around, as I said, you can hear its calls.
You can't make sense of them.
Hear its calls competing with the great old one's calls
as it's screaming to all of the other creatures,
which have amassed more since you left the space.
Which really was instance ago, but for you feels like a little bit longer.
Like a few minutes, as you were discussing.
The goings on with Athabasca getting caught up in the void space.
Can you give me a rundown of where everything is in relation to this giant brain?
Okay, so you got the giant brain.
We'll say you're facing your friends and the entrance which you came in.
Glim and Sully appear to be fighting or have...
They appear to be fighting as you enter.
Everybody else is kind of laid out in the space around them.
All of these soft clawed creatures, the troglodytes,
are moving quickly around the walls.
Some of them leaping in the air down towards your friends.
There are the grells, the bird-beaked brains coming in from behind.
And you look behind and there is this cavern that goes deeper into this tunnel system
where they appear to be coming out of.
And then tentacles splashing around in this giant lake pool that the brain is suspended in.
Mind flayers hovering.
I was like, what about the mind flayers?
But I didn't want to be like, what about the homework teacher?
Yeah, that's right.
What about the quiz we're supposed to have?
How far away are Moot and Sully and Agath and Rex?
From the brain, you're right over top of it.
Everybody else is probably tentacles coming out like 60 to 75 feet.
So they've got some distance but you are within any proximity.
Yeah, if I can hit the brain with a fireball, that's what's going to happen here.
It's like the downtime didn't even happen, you guys.
Well, Ice Storm is like a big cylinder that I will be inside of.
Aren't you immune to your own shit?
That's what I wonder.
I mean, maybe when I'm all supercharged.
I don't know, Russ, how are you feeling about it?
Nah, we'll say that you've got a level of protection.
Okay, then we are changing to Ice Storm.
Cut it up.
Hate this brain.
Well, it does bludgeoning damage and brains are soft, so.
Absolutely.
That will hopefully be a good thing.
Russ, you need to make a dexterity saving throw.
The humidity in here is really making Glim's hair look pretty hilarious though,
so we'll probably all laugh about it once we're out of this situation.
I'm imagining you are like Monica in Jamaica.
Does three succeed?
Three is very close.
Okay, I just wanted to be part of the team here, just like with low rolls.
This hailstorm just starts to like absolutely pound this giant brain,
and you're going to take a bunch of bludgeoning and cold damage.
Here we go.
No immunities to any of those.
Okay.
Oh, do you have immunities to fire?
I'm not telling you what I have immunities to.
I have no immunities to none of those.
That's 17 bludgeoning and a bunch of colds coming your way too.
Well, from the zero damage I've taken so far.
26 cold on top of that.
26, 17, 33, 43.
And the hailstorms will turn the area of effect into difficult terrain until the next turn.
Okay, so we're going to say like the pool beneath it begins to freeze,
so the tentacles have problems, difficulty moving.
It's going to try to hit you with one of those tentacles before they're completely locked in.
That's going to be an 18 to hit.
18 will hit.
Okay, you're going to take 20 bludgeoning damage,
and you are make a strength saving throw, please.
I are make a strength saving throw.
Coming up.
You are make a strength saving throw.
Oh, that's a 20.
You are not grappled, so you're going to take that bludgeoning damage, but not be grappled.
Is there anything else you can do on your turn, sir?
No, no, that is all we are doing this time.
Okay, well, I mean, that's pretty good.
It's pretty good coming back and saving the fucking day.
What would the mind flayers do in this situation?
They haven't specifically taken damage.
Dodge just like this is going south, man.
We're out of here.
We're not paid enough.
It's going to I don't think this one has recharged.
So I'm going to try it recharges.
It's going to try and try and mind blast you moot.
Make an intelligence saving throw, please.
Also, Russ, I did have a bonus action that I would like to retcon into the end of my last turn.
Go for it.
Where I cast mage armor on myself, which I can do at will without expending any spell slots or components.
OK, we'll say the boon for you is you also get advantage on your saving throws and ability checks.
Oh, OK, that's dope.
First one is a 17.
17 saves.
So yeah, the 18 was for the brain.
It's been much it's much more intelligent.
By one hit point.
So 17 does succeed.
So you don't need that.
Awesome.
Well, 17 was my best one.
OK, so you got this blast comes out.
It doesn't work on you.
You do take 11 psychic damage, however, half damage.
Agatha, you have motion motion.
You are prone to stand up as half your movement, but there are the troglodytes
bearing down on you in the air.
So even if you were to stand up and have half movement,
like you're going to be able to hit something several things if you want to.
I would love to hit several things.
But is there a mind flair within
whacking a distance in melee?
No, within range.
Yes.
OK, could I move to make it?
I do have a reach weapon.
So if I moved and then I had a long weapon.
Can it reach 15 feet in the air?
I want I want.
What if he lands?
It says reach.
I don't know.
I can look up reach five feet.
No, it's 15.
Totally 15.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Holy 50.
They're just carrying around a 15 foot stick.
OK, no, hold on.
Wait, is there one of those stupid brain birds
she could step on and jump into the air and hit it?
Yeah, let's do that.
That sounds like that.
Yeah, describe that to me if that's what you want.
Brain birds one stone.
Yeah, exactly.
All right, Agatha gets up and is royally pissed off.
She does not like being incapacitated one bit.
And locks eyes with one of these horrific googly face tentacle bros.
And just like, you know, I don't know what this gesture is called.
The the point net your eyes point net their eyes gesture.
I'm the captain now.
Yeah, like I'm a very different movie.
Yeah, I don't know.
But that's what she does.
And she just takes off.
And like with those big thunderous Goliath steps
and leaps and like, you know, air runs.
Crushing brain, crushing bird brain birds under her feet
and then like comes down stabbing with this giant lance.
Awesome.
Yeah, come on.
Come on, dice.
Oh, my God.
OK, OK, OK, OK.
That's not a natural 20, but a 20.
Yeah, that'll hit.
All right.
Vicious lance.
Get vicious.
That is 12 points of vicious lance damage.
I get three attacks.
Can I do like, am I like spend it in the air?
I can just whale on this guy midair or am I hitting somebody on my way down?
Yeah, like you get three per action.
Yeah.
So I imagine like you're coming in like flailing.
You're falling as you're going.
So maybe you hit the head on the first one chest and the knees on the third.
But yeah, like that is not nearly as good.
What is seven plus nine, 16, 16 will hit.
That is 11 more points of vicious lance damage.
I'm assuming it's like piercing or slashing.
But I mean, a lance certainly sounds like a piercing weapon.
Yeah, I'm just imagining lance from NSYNC.
Just that is who am I wielding vicious now.
Bye bye bye.
And then 24.
Yes.
Oh, yes.
14 points of bye bye bye.
You're going to NSYNC this lance into him.
Sorry, continue.
I'm going to do another thing.
I'm going to mark him.
Unwavering mark.
There it is.
When you hit with a melee attack, I can mark the creature until the end of my next turn.
It has disadvantage on any attack that doesn't target me.
So it's the like you and me, bro.
You guys can't see it.
Kristin's got crazy eyes.
Yeah, such good eyes.
Boom, boom, boom.
Falling down, crazy eyes are happening.
It looks stunned in the air as it's kind of blasted back from these three hits.
Matamar, who quickly, let's see if they.
Realizes that he's way in over his head.
He's way out of his depth.
But quickly stands up, knows far and beyond that he's way out of his steps
and rushes and hides in like this little alcove.
It's the right thing to do.
Yeah, it really is.
What if he died?
How bad would we feel?
Roll a 24 stealth so he manages to kind of sneak through and around and away.
He is rock now.
Unless called upon, we'll say that he is out of rotation for now.
Rocks.
Who can roll for his acid?
Nope.
Who can he trample with his bad ass hoops?
Every stupid bird brain.
Got lots of lots of troglodytes, bird brains coming in.
Troglodytes would probably be the easiest, easiest hit.
The troglodytes are the soft clawed creatures, soft claws.
All right, baby babies.
Oh, that's a one.
So no, he trips on a stone.
He trips, kind of getting up and the troglodytes rush on top of him.
Sorry, they are rushing on top of him.
The brain's turn, it senses.
Like you can, you can hear, again, don't understand what it's saying specifically,
but you sense there's a tone shift in the in the directions that it's giving.
It is more panicked and frantic.
And below you, below this ice storm that it continues to get pummeled and like the lake
is freezing, it blinks out of existence beneath you.
Get your own thing, brain.
And it is gone.
If you roll arcana, you might know what it did.
Sure, I'm into it.
A dirty 20.
You get a distinct feeling that it cast plane shift.
So it has left this plane, no longer sense it or its location or its voice.
Okay.
You sense the voice of the mind flares who are like second in command now,
who are also increasing in panic and and ferocity.
And one of them is next.
And it is also going to plane shift out.
Glim, as the brain is gone and as the great old one's power
has released you from the control of the brain over you, it is your turn.
Great.
Moot is still above like that pool where the brain was.
Yes.
Okay, but there's still a bunch of other creatures.
Should we have a moment since you did just try to like whack at me?
I rolled like a one and a two.
I mean, realistically, do you even know that I tried to attack you?
I don't know.
Because it was pretty bad.
Came up behind, you heard like the swing of the sword.
Whoa, you tried, almost hit me.
Easy does it there.
But maybe.
I don't know.
You tell me.
Do you even know that you were mind controlled?
Oh, you do.
Well, then I assume you'd be apologetic regardless of whether or not
I knew you were trying to hit me.
Oh, Sully, I'm so sorry.
It was like I had my brain and I did a bad job, so I didn't hit you.
But I'm so I'm so sorry.
Oh, that's all right.
Maybe you can make it up to me by like squishing some of these real gross things.
And Sully like shakes his leg because there's like one of those little
gross brain bird things beside him.
I think that what I will do is what's like the biggest bad within reach of me?
It's me.
Two mind players up in the air will say that a goth maybe knocked one down.
So it is like five feet above the ground right now.
Perfect.
Um, so I'm going to attack it with the vorpal longsword, but then I'm also
I hit it, which hopefully I will put some some extra special divine smite on that.
So he'll get a whole bunch of extra radiant damage.
That is a 23.
She's back.
Yeah.
So then 31 stabby damage.
Okay, describe what it looks like when you kill this mind flayer.
I feel like I really did not like having something in my brain.
So I'm really going for head.
So if that means a decapitation, maybe, or it could be just a real gross stab into the face.
Like they've got, yeah, like big bulbous skulls and then like long octopus tentacles
coming off of their like chin area.
And I mean, it did have its face tentacles all over your face.
I forgot about that too.
I'm really having a bad day.
Glim's having a rough one.
So yeah, maybe just like direct stab into the face and then a pull down.
Just kind of kind of flay it a little.
Yeah.
You're flaying its mind.
Love it.
That's fun.
Moot, in your mind, you sense like it get a little quieter as far as like the
different voices that you're hearing as you see now Glim flay as one mind flayer.
You still have two.
I have one more attack.
Troglodytes or...
Yeah.
I'll go for a Troglodyte.
That's a 26.
Yes.
And that is 24.
Describe the death.
I can't even smite anything.
I'm just killing them all straight up.
All right.
Yeah.
Glim has hit upon a theme here and the theme is get out of my head
or I will remove yours from you.
So I think it's all just going to be head stuff today.
All right.
Going for heads.
Just swinging around the brain down and then swinging wide.
Anything you can or would like to do to finish out your turn?
No, I don't think so.
Oh, it feels so much better being able to do something guys.
Troglodytes are going to continue to attack.
They're going to try as long as there's mind flayers around.
Several are going to rush you, Glim.
We're going to say...
Seems fair.
Four are going to try and attack you.
Two roll and get with their multi-attacks.
18 to hit.
Yep.
18 is my AC.
And then two rolled a nine.
So you're going to take 21 slashing damage.
One's going to come towards you, Sully.
Uh, with a bite for a nine and a claw for a 22.
Uncanny dodge.
All right.
So you just walked in and waited for someone to attack me.
So you take half damage on that one then?
I do believe I have the attacks damage against me.
Indeed.
Seven slashing damage then.
Moot, you're up in the air.
The Grells are going to try and come towards you.
Okay.
They get to make two attacks.
One with tentacles and one with their beaks.
There's quite a few of them.
Brace yourself.
I'll say four of them are coming at you.
So four tentacle attacks.
Okay.
Ooh.
So now one and a 13 and a 13 and an eight.
They didn't hit with their tentacles,
so they're not going to hit with their beaks.
I mean, yeah, that was not great.
He's like pushing them away by their faces.
I just looked up a Grell and in a way,
it actually is much funnier than I thought
because it really looks like a testicle.
Descriptions are the key.
Well, now I need to Google this.
It really looks more like a testicle with a beak
and some tendrils than a brain.
I mean, it also looks like a brain, I guess.
But I don't know.
Just in case you want that.
Just in case you want that in your brain.
Oh, yeah.
Yep.
It's still much more,
the beak itself is much more comical
than the beak that I had given it in my mind.
It was much more sinister.
This looks like a Muppet beak.
See, that's the beautiful thing about the mind palace.
The thing you're going to come up with
is way worse than whatever the artist did.
It was much scarier than I thought.
Good, then we succeeded there.
Listeners, don't go ahead and Google these.
Yeah, don't look at it.
Just picture something scary.
Everything is panicking.
There's no, there's nothing landing anywhere.
Flamikins is up.
Oh my God, she's still here.
Stretching, feeling good.
Verbal somatic, baby.
She's doing lunges in the corner,
just waiting for her turn.
I like what you're doing, moot.
Let's cast lightning bolt.
Fuck yeah, bud.
Everything has to make a dexterity saving throw,
a stroke of lightning 100 feet long
and five feet wide blasts out
in a direction you choose.
Each creature.
Is that everybody?
Well, she's not going to point it towards you.
Are we scattered?
It's only five feet wide.
Yeah, but she's a professional.
Of course she is.
That's something that people say about Flamikins.
If there's anything that anyone's ever said
about Flamikins when describing her in one word,
it is professional.
Do you want her to roll 11d6
and kill a whole bunch of shit or not?
Hell yeah.
Obviously, yes we do, Russ.
But we're going to make fun at the same time.
That's what we do, Russ.
Fair enough.
Russ has had it up to here with our shit.
That's right.
Hey, we got to put up with him
just beating on us the whole last episode.
The whole last episode, it was rough.
36.
A line of these creatures,
just like the lightning burns through them
as the other ones on the perimeter of this scatter.
So many of them drop.
Yes.
Question, are these troglodytes and growls,
look at me using the real words,
coming out of the tunnel continuously
or had they all arrived?
There are no new ones coming.
Like the troglodytes looked like they were the ones.
The growls, there were several of them that came out,
but there's not like an endless stream of things
coming out of this cavern.
I was just wondering.
Sully was going to do something cool,
but so much has happened in between
that has now made that impossible.
You can still do cool things.
Now I'm going to do something like-
It's going to be mediocre, guys.
Prepare yourself.
I think what he's going to do
is he's just going to like, I don't know,
run through some of these growls
or whatever is closest to him
with both daggers in each hand
and just whoosh.
Go for it.
Like that.
In his right hand, he has rolled a 19.
Yep.
Thank God for that bonus to hit.
And in his left hand, it is a 28.
Also good.
Nice.
One D4 plus six.
Not going to be a lot here.
And in one hand, oh, nine damage.
And in the next, seven damage.
Did I get like a sneak attack or anything like that?
I mean, you're around friends and stuff.
I am, but my-
Sneak attack gives you 10 D6.
Okay.
Well, I guess, you know what?
I think I have like a disconnect between
what I believe to be sneak attack
and what it says sneak attack is.
To me, if I'm in the middle of a group of things
that are currently fighting,
I'm not sneaky.
Everybody knows I'm there.
But this is just like-
Well, there's where you're wrong though, Amy.
Right?
Like, obviously that's not what sneak attack means.
If you sneak up and have advantage on something,
then yes, absolutely.
But there's also the caveat of
if you have an ally within five feet
of another creature, you also get sneak attack
because their attention is split, right?
Yeah, they're distracted.
So you're sneaking over-
Let's see Daisy.
Let's roll 10 D6 and see what happens.
33.
33, all right.
How about that?
The growls.
There's one mind flayer left.
There's some growls, the voices in your head,
great old one who's still giving you
this boon that you have here.
And then the troglodytes, which are
quite, fewer in numbers than they were previously.
We'll say that, but there's still several
surrounding your friends down on the ground.
Am I getting any like tips and tricks from my
great one whispering in my ear?
What kind of tips and tricks do you want?
Duck.
Cheat code.
Slash.
Up, up, down, down, back, back, back, back.
I mean, is it like an up, up, down, down,
left, right, left, right, B, A, select, start situation?
It's the middle and I've got to sing a song by myself
because we didn't record it last night
because we were so tired.
Hey, it's me in the middle by myself.
Happy to have you here.
Just curious.
Have you been thinking about joining us on Patreon?
We would love to have you.
In fact, if we get four more patrons,
we are going to reach another goal that we have going on
when we reach 100 patrons.
It's a huge goal for us.
Love these community goals because that means
we're 100 people strong in our Patreon community
that are supporting us here,
creating the shows that you love,
including this one, Dumbgeons and Dragons.
But when we reach that goal,
we're going to do another improv live show
exclusively for our patrons.
Try and get as many people out there as we can
because the bigger we make those shows,
the more suggestions fly in,
the more wildness happens.
And we're going to wrangle some past guests of the show
to see how many people we can get to come join us
for a night of fun and laughs and just all out good times.
So like I said, if you've been on the fence,
now's a great time to help us reach the next goal
to support the show that you love here
with Dumbgeons and Dragons
and get to partake in an exclusive live show.
You get your invite automatically coming right to you.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
We hope to see you over there.
Let's get back to the episode here
and see what magic is in store for everybody
as they battle their way through
all of these yucky, yucky monsters
who comes up with these things.
All right.
Bye now.
No, it's more like relationship
with your great old one.
Just a solid cheer section.
That relationship's good.
Good.
He took my hand.
He gave me some power like in marriage.
Okay.
After that, though, like between then and now,
like what historically,
because we haven't really delved into it.
Like this is the first time we've actually been able
in this new timeline to be like,
what?
What up?
Great old one.
Um, what normally between the last seven years
or whatever it's been,
have they done for you?
Well, the ability to use magic on an ongoing basis,
pretty big one for moot
and really gives a leg up
over like a lot of other situations
because there's not a lot of people out in the world
over those last years that have that access.
All right.
So he's actually been pretty stoked with his deal.
I've got such some questions though
about your great old ones.
Are they gods?
Are they immune to the goings on of what's happening?
We can't answer these questions right now.
We can answer these questions in the downtime.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Oh, all right.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
If you want to get the downtime that we do
after the episode and like chit chat
about like what we learned on our character sheets,
what great old ones are, you know,
cool stuff like that.
I'm going to have to go sign up
for our own Patreon apparently to gain access to.
Well, I was thinking like here like if he's like,
you know, if there's an obvious game plan
of like we should kill the last mind flayer
and the rest of this will dissolve quickly,
like maybe he's whispering that in my ear
or maybe he's just like, yes,
wreak havoc upon everyone.
No, probably more the second,
like the vibe you're getting.
Like they have their own kind of vibe and motivations
and while you are a pawn in that,
they don't really care too much if anybody lives or dies
so long as you succeed in what you're doing.
Okay.
So kill everything.
Yeah.
I mean, let's do that.
I will.
Okay.
In that case, I will cast Eldrick Blast again.
And I'll focus three of them on the mind flayer
and then one on, I don't know, Grel.
This really blasts the shit out of this crew.
Hey, Larry, Larry, listen up.
Grel with the limp.
Get out of here.
Okay.
Give me some rolls.
All right.
First one's a 27.
Second one's a 26.
Third one is a 17 and fourth one's a 27.
All will hit.
Jesus.
Regardless of which ones are being hit.
Perfect.
All right.
I'll roll some D10s here.
Give me, based on your wild magic connection state right now,
just give me max damage.
Oh, well, okay.
Then the mind flayer takes 30 force damage
and the Grel takes 10 force damage.
All right.
Maybe describe the death of the mind flayer and the grip.
It's not great
because the balls of energy keep slamming him into the wall
and eventually he just kind of like gufies
under the third and final one.
And then it's like a real slow slide down the wall.
Gross.
That was disgusting.
It was fantastic.
It was disgusting.
Well, there's just a lot going on right now.
I might have been overkill, but you know what?
Let's just do it.
Let's do it.
Let's have a little fun.
Okay.
There are many, many creepy...
Sully looks worriedly over at Glim.
Like, oh, I don't know how to process that.
Okay.
So there are no more mind flayers.
There's no more brain.
There are troglodytes that are attacking.
Some confusion enters their kind of scape
as the last mind flayer dies
and the Grel's are there too.
Let's go one more round around, starting with a goth.
Describe the scene and what cool thing
that could lean into the next individual.
Feel free to work together
and describe cool, awesome shit that's happening
if you need an assist on anything.
Let's just be really awesome
killing all these troglodytes
because they're low levels and they won't kill you.
What kind of weapon do you have?
Because Sully could toss you a few Grel.
You could play some baseball.
Yeah, yeah.
Or we could do some skeet shooting.
What kind of weapon do you have?
Because I think a goth would want to go
get these troglodytes off racks, right?
Because he was kind of being swarmed.
So I don't know if she can
whack some of them up in the air
if anybody has some spell action perhaps.
I just got a short bow.
Okay, sweet.
Target practice?
Yeah, target practice time.
Mood's got spells.
Karla or Glim's got spells.
Everybody.
It's just a fun game that we're going to be playing now
inside the game we're already playing.
I'm going to run over and grab the mace
and just batter up,
start whacking them off into the air off of racks.
And I think imagine as there's fewer laying them down,
he can sort of assist as well
and bucking them up into the sky.
What if I cast Moonbeam
and then you hit them into the Moonbeam
and then they just went in radiant damage
as they enter the area?
I love this.
Little like a firework show.
Sully's just yelling things like
Paul, because, you know.
Not doing anything after that.
No, no, because I mean the Moonbeam's there
so he's not going to waste arrows on this business.
He's just showing encouragement.
Awesome.
Yeah, Troglodytes and Grel are flying through this Moonbeam.
Moot, what do you, what kind of, you got a jazzed vibe.
What are you doing?
Yeah.
Okay, let's look through this spell list again
and find something fun.
Hang on.
I love and I'm scared of this version of Moot
and I am here for it.
This is a bloodthirsty mood.
Okay.
Let's have some fun.
Like the fuck is wrong with this guy?
Yes.
Okay.
Got a little spell here called Sickening Radiance.
Oh, yeah.
If we're working with some radiant damage
over on one end,
well, we'll put some radiant light on another.
As well.
Light this place up.
So dim greenish light spreads within a 30-foot radius sphere
centered on a point I choose,
which I'll put like right next to the Moonbeam.
Catch any stragglers?
Yeah.
Yeah, you can't always be accurate on all of them.
When a creature moves into the spell's area
for the first time or starts its turn there,
that creature must succeed on a con saving throw
or take 4d10 radiant damage,
suffer one level of exhaustion,
and emit a dim greenish light in a 5-foot radius.
It just happens.
Everything that as these creatures are being batted around
and the Sickening Radiance is being spread around,
they begin to try and flee as they're being caught up in it.
So he's trying to catch the ones that are trying to get away
and like throw them into the Moonbeam or the Sickening Sphere.
I don't think it works that well.
I think he's like grabbing tentacles because it's probably similar size to him.
He's just kind of like grappling off to the side.
You guys are doing cool shit.
He's like, get over here, you fucking bud.
Brain stupid.
Hey, Charlie, toss one over here.
Toss it.
I can barely.
Chaos bolt flies towards you.
It explodes in your face.
There's brain goop all over you.
Ah, that warning would have been nice.
Thank you so much.
I gave you the warning.
I said toss them over here.
You weren't throwing them.
That's not a warning.
That's a direction.
As the scene fades down,
you're covered in the death of all of these creatures.
You settle yourselves, moot you,
kind of the sound in your head lightens.
It's not gone, but it's kind of just in the back there.
As you bring yourself down
and you have a moment now to collectively breathe,
you all recollect yourselves
and you notice the further tunnel
where the grells were seen coming in.
You see Matamar moving off too.
He has snuck off
and you see him just kind of disappear down that cape.
Do we all have that moment
where we look at each other and laugh?
Because we all just almost die.
But there's like nothing else you can do, right?
But moves laughing like a little too much.
Yeah.
Sounds a little manic.
We should follow Matamar.
He's just going.
Right?
And it's so humid in here.
You guys look at my hair.
I wasn't going to say anything, but that's nuts.
That moonbeam didn't scare things off.
That dew would have.
You begin to move further back
and you hear like the sliding sound
of the black ichor that you walk through to get in here.
You see it falling and sliding down to the ground
and dispersing like within the pool.
And you see light coming in from outside of this cave
as you're moving back to follow Matamar.
You go down this tunnel and it winds around for a little bit.
You're calling out to Matamar as you enter into this new area,
this new cavern and there are these alcoves
where there are our bodies lined up in.
And you see Matamar like at the center of this room
there is this, for lack of a better term,
what looks like a large bird bath.
This thing's really bird centric.
Right, but within it is a very similar substance
to what the pool was made out of,
this kind of suspension fluid.
And in this suspension fluid are these large tadpole-like creatures
like with long tails.
And he's looking into this and has this glazed over look to him.
Hey, Matamar.
Buddy.
Snaps out.
Yeah, yeah.
You okay?
There was a lot of gore back there
and you seemed really scared.
You disappeared for a little bit.
Great job at hiding.
But then you just kind of took off without saying anything.
I mean, we did laugh for a really long time back there.
Some of us more than others, but...
No, I heard you.
I just felt compelled to come back here.
I don't know why.
That's not good.
You look around to the...
They're all similar creatures.
Some are more human.
Some are mostly what a Matamar appears to be.
And a lot of them appear to be in this stasis state.
They're not awake.
They are...
Are they in vats?
Are they just standing there?
No, they're standing up,
but there's this substance that seems to be binding them to the wall.
Kakuni?
Kakuni-esque.
Yep.
The more you go around,
some of them appear to have giant holes in their head.
Oh, Buddy, don't look too closely at some of these guys.
They look like they may be your friends.
Or they were your friends.
No, I see that.
Don't look.
He said don't.
I was here before you.
I saw...
And then...
These things in this pool...
I remember now.
I remember they put them in...
If you walk through and then you'd...
They put them in your head.
Excuse me?
Who say?
Those things with the tentacles off their face.
That's where my friends went.
That's where I went.
So you...
You have...
Do you have one of these in your...
Inside your head right now?
I think so.
So you're like incubating like a frog or something?
I don't think they're frogs.
I think they're more of them.
These little guys are those tentacle bearded bastards?
Once they come out...
I wonder...
Can you be healed of this?
Maybe not healed right now.
Obviously you're okay for the moment.
These ones seem not to be okay
because some of them have the holes in the heads
and that seems like they've hatched, right?
One of these tadpole looking creatures
trying to climb up and out.
I'm going to mace it.
Like falls to the ground.
Yes, I was going to say.
My higher breath recharges and I take my staff.
Yeah, no, that thing is getting squashed.
There's like four of us.
Four of us just all of a sudden are like,
oh God, and then start hitting it.
And Rex is like stomp, stomp, stomp.
Wow.
That was not an overreaction.
I don't know if you can be healed.
Well, I mean if anybody knows Bahamut probably knows,
so like we're maybe just like,
you know, we're going to ask him
like share some big information,
but maybe he could just do like one other little thing.
Maybe this can't be okay for the people,
the gods who live here in Celestia, right?
You can come be like some evidence for us
of the bad thing that's happening.
I'm going to take Madame Mars hand and.
Crush his skull.
You see like a guy kind of grits her teeth a little bit
and she's going to try and cast lesser restoration on him
and see if that does anything.
Tell me what lesser restoration can heal.
I mean, I'm thinking it's probably not high enough level,
but she's going to try.
It says you touch a creature
and can end either one disease or one condition affecting it.
Condition can be blinded, deafened, paralyzed or poisoned.
Is not necessarily that so you can definitely use it,
but yeah, like there's a radiant glow
that moves from you to him
and I don't know if it did anything.
It was worth an attempt,
but this is beyond my abilities.
I am much more adept at the crushing side of things these days.
Oh, oh, what if we lure it out like a tapeworm?
What if we try to find someone more adept?
Okay, I guess that's true.
I don't want to be cruel or anything though,
but it seems like there's a bigger problem than just Madame Mars.
No offense, Madame Mars.
No, that's fine.
Because I mean, they're just going to keep taking your people
to incubate the weird bits, right?
Well, are there any more of them other than he looks around at the 12 bodies?
Oh, we should probably kill all these people.
Yeah, I mean not even kill
because they're definitely already dead and gone.
So they are no longer your friends and loved ones
and we're just going to really quickly just maybe take care of.
I'm going to maybe you should just go back down the tunnel.
He walks out and you see him kind of just put his hands in his ears.
This is the worst timeline ever.
We cut ahead as you're being led out of the cavern that you are in
and you pass by various pictograms on the walls showing images
that look very similar to the mind flares coming up
from what looks like some under dark region
with a figure hovering around and above them.
It looks very reminiscent.
That looks very reminiscent of Orcus.
And his goat like hideous face.
And these figures are depicted as rising to these other worldly God like planes
with what can be determined as hatcheries
being created or implanted in these worlds
with a final image or goal of them working alongside
an undead army.
It leads you out of the cavern.
You are on a hill that overlooks the forest where you came from.
You've moved beyond whatever or broken whatever void that you were trapped in
from this elder brain or these mind flares or whatever power that was trapping you
was trapping you within this loop.
And you see the mountain before you a little bit closer than it was before.
And Matamar sullen and broken leads you down and towards Mount Celestia.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 2 Episode 122
Starring Amy More as Sullivan Slyte
Carla Maxted as Glimp Tom Laird as Moot
Kristen Flemmons as a Goth and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Editing, Production and Sound Design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and sound effects from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Christian Brown, Devin Michaels,
Craig Zeiss, Aaron Stevens, Darylith, Lulahan, L.A. Branton and Nathaniel Teeter
to support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many other productions
and get access to an exclusive podcast called The Adventures Of,
bonus episodes and much more.
Please join our Patreon at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast.
You can also follow us at facebook.com slash Dumb Dragon Podcast
and on Instagram and Twitter at Dumb Dragon Cast.
Thank you for listening.
Have a great week.
We'll talk again soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.