previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
I can fly over oh also I can fly so now it's left to uh the two fighter types and a ghost horse
Rax and I are both perhaps too heavy for this now I also have a tome of thunderstep do you think
it could open a book say some words close the book and then teleport itself to a place it can
see um guys I can get from one place to another but you need hands to make it happen
Rax work with me work with me Rax I didn't think the bridge was going to be the point
you turn and you look up these steps towards this castle looming before you
and you see carved into the wall above the door is a giant raven's head
it
welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons I'm your dungeon master Russ More he him also with me today is
Kristen Fleming hi again welcome back thanks I'm never leaving no that's it that's that's our
goal I love it first intro so you're like a main cast member now yeah you're just in
rotation now you're not a guest star if you were in our home you'd have to go get your
own plates and stuff right you could rifle through our fridge that's right I'm fine with that I make
good leftover snacks and I don't have any problem with loading the dishwasher perfect amazing we
don't have a dishwasher so I know she doesn't want to be on the podcast one more day just
one more day Kristen just one more day stick it out this one time you're gonna get one
the next time a new patron signs up so it's fine mild heart arrhythmia at that point right
I know every morning I wake up I'm like I had a better life 200 200 patron we get a new dishwasher
oh that's yeah that's a good goal yeah uh who do you play Kristen thank you for the prompt
because I didn't remember what I was supposed to do now I play Agath god-lost cathalo alavi
whose name I may have gotten right for the first time um she her goliath cleric fighter
person got it all check the boxes also with me today is Amy More I am here so happy to
be here uh and I play the amistacia a high elf druid uh she her for both of us
guys I'm gonna nail this Amy's very tired very tired I feel Amy's pain and Carla Max dead
she her I play Yen Bolnuri a Kalishtar cleric and Tom Laird too he him and I am playing
Telgear tonight who also goes by he him hello everybody and welcome back Kristen uh you know
I just like to start it with with some good energy there throw everybody off we're in a
different place who knows what's gonna happen I'm into it bring the chaos where we have some
fun things happening like we're gonna get some new character art for this adventures of game
that we've been playing for almost the same amount of time as our regular show um and it's
it's so far looking very good so hopefully by the time that this comes out we have samples of
that to show our patrons and you could be one of them too at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
where you also get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron Ray Serbeck
hey thanks Ray thank you so much yes thank you Ray and now fuck it let's play
well that rhymes that's a good start it felt good
previously we crossed a bridge oh did we though eight hours later that's right it was real
rough you all find yourself standing at the base of this castle that you had seen off in the
distance this this giant angular stone castle and going up the main staircase to the entry
doors you see this large symbol of a raven's head above the door everybody roll a history
check please could it be a religion check could be religion would also qualify so either or
i'm not good at either of them oddly enough yeah no they're both bad i have a really great
bonus in history but i rolled a three natural 20 oh yes thank god i knew we kept christin
around for a reason way to spend it on the stuff that counts and that's why i introduced
christin first that's right not like hitting things um i know exactly what that is for us
you know that's the symbol of the raven queen without a doubt and i point to it
that is the symbol of the raven queen a little on the nose so don't you think
you know it's a raven does it have a crown on it oh does it have a crown yeah i'm curious
uh no no it doesn't the only thing it needs is a crown on it i also had a good role i had a 25
so what is what do i know other than just that the raven is the raven queen which seems like
probably not what christin earned with her nat 20 no that's that's exactly what you're
hands down that i deserve yeah you know that the raven queen is a queen a queen okay obviously
she likes a raven motif yeah a lesser deity who uh controls the shadow fell and all of its
denizens you know that the raven queen was i mean still is an elven being who tried to become a
god and through the ritual of becoming that god um was split and brought into the shadow
fell where she now controls or you know where she controlled we don't know what the current
status um what what her tinder bio says where she controls the the this plane trying to accrue
her power again to come into godhood of sorts okay so it kind of be maybe great if she's here
if she's feeling in a good mood yeah and is still functioning as a god
that'd be good if if that if she if she made it to that far then yes that would be good so
is the raven queen someone we got to be worried about or is this well i don't think she is
normally
a good guy i don't think but if a god is a god still functioning as a god that is
that is good news right at this point any god will do yeah well yeah i guess we that's what
beggars can't be choosers
uh no uh yeah no beggars can't be choosers uh so just go up do we do we just go knock on the
door or should we bring a gift is there like some sort of social etiquette in the situation
that we should be aware of i might have a gift on me though it's always nice to arrive
with something we all look through our inventory we've never really dealt with hostess gifts
before but let's see who has the cheese platter who has the cheese relatively new character here
i'm not sure what bonus stuff he's got i'm still trying to figure out how to use the
ring gates so like maybe i'll just give those to her first person you see are you the raven
queen here have these here you go i have some fishing tackle okay the pretty ones
more colorful no fly fishing no just okay rod uh i also have teleportation diamond i mean raven
queen pretty shiny sparkly thing right yeah i mean could work again we just knock is there just
like a big door are they yeah i mean i had i had set you up at the bottom of the stairs so
you know there there is just a big door uh you know big double wipe massive place to tie off
the horse do you want to bring the horse rex will accompany me of course of course why did i even
ask all right uh okay i skip up the steps jaunty russ if you could dub in a real cool guy knock
for amy at this point i think that would be great yeah you got it
as the knock happens everybody make a wisdom saving throw
it turns out it's more of a just let yourself in kind of establishment
jesus 30 what 22 wow guys something special just happened 19 also 19 okay that was with
plus nine y'all i have a plus 11 to my wisdom what is going on i have plus 10 i guess it's
because these high level characters it's really like stuff going on here i know well it's still my
little baby characters are like i'm a minus one my dex is still like only plus three and so is
my charisma but wisdom and intelligence like fuck yeah i've been through some shit obviously
well i now control right whoever just tried to control me no a 30s got to give me something
a 30 does get you something cool okay um but it's a butt as you knock oh no the door swings open
a goth and Yenbul and tulge the doors open wide and you feel like this warmth wash over you
and it's not like a weird warmth like you know like someone peed in the pool kind of
warmth like i guess a warm summer morning there's a bit of a dew in the air and it opens
into this green field like rolling hills trees off in the distance you see wildlife running across
us and you feel drawn into this
yeah i just re-rolled a wisdom saving throw for racks because i realized he hadn't saved
and he got a natural one so racks he's ready really stoked about this he's going i didn't
roll for well do i have to if if donnie's in my pouch i'm sleeping yeah covered it good
so just to clarify because i did cut out a little bit but with 19s and a 22 we see a beautiful
okay wow live place okay sounds great let's go this is it's like when we fought Tiamat
and it's like oh yeah deck save well i need to net or i fail cool
yeah you see your friends rush forward happily joyfully gleefully almost
oh it's awkward to watch as you watch them rush into this dark cold and dusty hallway
as the air is settling around you it's eerily quiet you see cobwebs like large
cobwebs hanging down from the ceiling and they're running and like grabbing these things
and like sniffing all of this oh my goodness it's so beautiful here it's the most beautiful
i mean the colors are just amazing oh the air is the perfect mix of it must rain so often in here
here you don't see anything else alive or undead for that matter in this location but you don't
you don't understand what is happening to you so it's just like a dank musty dark cobweb filled
foyer it's like it was this grand entryway like at one point it probably looked fantastic
it probably looked marvelous but right now it looks like it's been torn apart and like a
battle has happened here there are doorways like off to the side derelict just that have been
like yeah blown open and like hanging off their hinges some of them like barred up
on like you can see furniture on the on the inside of them are you guys did you guys all
have a conversation prior to us coming in here like is this a joke this is a weird
the three of you you don't hear thea it's a weird time to joke you see collectively
coming down towards you like over this hill you see a small satyr he's well about three feet
tall he's got like tussled brown hair brown eyes he's got a denim vest on
okay tell me more does it have a bedazzled unicorn on the back of it
it has a bedazzled unicorn on the back of it and he comes over to you and says oh my gosh
friends it's been so long since i've seen anybody come come with me where where where
have you been who what is happening you recognize this man as benjamin someone you
grew up with benjamin it is so fun they're all to see you i thought everyone was gone
no no we've all been here it's an uncanny coincidence isn't it it's so lovely isn't it
did you see the unicorns frolicking on the field not the ones just on my back
but the ones frolicking in the field over there i didn't i i didn't see them i didn't
show me where venny come follow me tell gear i i want to reach out and i want to shake
shake who are you shaking now i don't know if i want to shake somebody you've come into
the bit you've tried to shake somebody who are you shaking i reach out and i and i touch
yen bull's shoulder gently yamble as thea touches you like these thorny vines wrap
around your shoulder a goth and tell gear you see this plant shoot up and out of the ground
and grab hold of yen bull and begin pulling her back and down to the ground ow Benjamin help me
what is happening this place is so beautiful before and now it is hurting me is there
any chance that any of this seems strange to me i mean make an insight roll oh that's pretty
good um 28 all of the imagery and everything you see and smell and hear all maintains but
just kind of like in in the periphery like just out of sight you see shadows moving like
figures quickly zipping in and out and whenever you look at them they're not there and this
but you you do see this creature this thing pulling yen bull like yamble you're being
pulled to the ground now it appears yamble i think i'm trying to think what i would do i
mean i'd probably do something that's what i'm hoping for something i mean i think agath like
went to pull a weapon as the the thorns came out but as the shadows sort of appear the sides
of her vision i think she's gonna sort of spin and like maybe try and catch one not in the
periphery and still have her her weapon out and just say like something is not quite right
yeah something isn't right something isn't right i i i go to shake agath agath off of the same
creature that is attacking yamble like this cloud of spores shoots out into your face
uh make a constitution saving throw i would love to oh not one oh is a five although i can
technically reroll a saving throw once if i use one of my sticky notes that i think is
um stones endurance no it's one of them is it it's a are you a fighter indomitable
yeah yeah that's the one if you would like to reroll it you can sure yeah i'll reroll it just
so that i can make sure i use all the sticky notes um 15 it plumes up into your face and
you begin coughing and like batting at it um you have a weapon in your hand like if you
were to like bat at the cloud would you how how would you do that i probably like put it up
defensively like i mean it's a cloud of spores so that isn't you're not gonna swing
at it probably not gonna say put it up defensively and and uh and like raise the shield kind of thing
as you go up to agatha her shield comes up and her her weapon comes up in front of you what
do you do oh i back up and go whoa whoa whoa whoa hey it's me it's the agatha you see like a
shutter in this cloud of spores in your face and you see beyond it this darkened hallway just
for a brief second and thea almost ghostly coming in and out of image whoa whoa whoa whoa
i i see i see thea she is here but not here come with me come on it's me it's benjamin let's
go everybody's waiting for you i'm gonna attack benjamin okay uh roll to hit agatha no she doesn't
have any old friends that's right i was never a child definitely no not anyone with that much
uh charisma and cool vests yeah definitely not that was a different friend group yeah
yeah for sure 24 swing down with your scimitar hard into where benjamin is standing uh tulgear
and Yenbul make a constitution saving throw as agatha is double-bladed scimitaring your long
lost best friend 27 okay so you don't care about benjamin Yenbul cares about benjamin
scimitar is coming down into benjamin tulgear you have this moment of clarity like same kind
of thing as i described for agatha where's this there's this shutter and you're back in this
dark cobwebbed dusty hallway and then you're back and agatha is cutting down through
benjamin Yenbul you see the same thing you don't have the shutter what do you do as you
see agatha's blade coming down uh well i think i'm sort of kind of on the ground right
because i've been pulled down by this vine definitely at least to knees yeah um so i'm
gonna fight against that i mean sorry friend but i don't know i mean i'm gonna probably like
stab at that vine that's attached to me okay i mean i'm just down there so probably just
with like a dagger or something okay nothing nothing crazy it uh it was a nat one
one that's the one today that's the third just so far what's happening waving a dagger kind
of above my shoulder in a random pattern you go to stab at these vines Yenbul agatha you're
swiping through benjamin you don't really see what's happening with tulgear or Yenbul behind
you tulgear you see Yenbul begins stabbing but at the same time screaming as she's stabbing
these vines and thea you see Yenbul stabbing into her own shoulder oh oh my god uh i i want
to run at her and i want to wrench the the blade out of her hand uh okay uh make a maybe
just a straight dex roll actually or strength because you're trying to overpower her 14 um make
it a contested strength there Yenbul because so the vine is trying to pull your dagger away
from you at this point 17 the vines are trying to wrap themselves like around your blade to
try and knock the blade from your hand but you overpower them i feel like i rolled a one
on that attack roll so if the negative consequence i guess is that i am stabbing
myself then i guess i just have to accept that i'm stabbing myself because i did roll a one Yenbul
is screaming and maintains her hold on it as you are trying to wrestle it free from her
i go to chop her hand off no i'm totally kidding wow way out of control what would you
do your three friends are clueless and doing weird shit stabbing themselves back to agatha
you strike down into benjamin who at the last second turns and has like these puppy dog eyes
as you cut down hard into him and he explodes into butterflies
and just kind of surround you and they're flying all around you right now gonna swing
at a few of the butterflies agoth begins swinging wildly in this room i back the
fuck up right now you have a friend who's stabbing themselves on the ground you have
one swinging a double bladed scimitar through the air tolgear what are you doing yes tolgear
great question what are you doing join the fun i need to round out this uh this house of
horrors do something terrible don't just enjoy the beautiful scenery and breathe the fresh air
do something weird and gross all right um so i see yen bull stabbing at the vines correct
and now i see swinging at butterflies yeah yeah benjamin would have like
i don't know if you would have seen like the blade connect and like your brain connect those
two like benjamin was there one moment for you and then he's gone the next and now agoth
is swinging trying to catch butterflies sure um do i have a butterfly net in my possessions
right you look down into your bag and you pull out a butterfly net perfect yeah i'm gonna i'm
gonna try and like gently swing it towards some butterflies not the more aggressive one
that the cats do what's something dangerous in your bag that you would be carrying
oh i probably have lots of things like that uh let's go with uh my plus three battle axe
it's a bad day to be thea i'm just saying the uh make a dexterity saving throw i am not happy
that i saved on this got that 30 imagine how just peaceful this could have been okay this
is why i don't roll well because when they do it turns out nothing happens uh what kind of
this is a dex 18 yeah you see tel gear just kind of at the last moment coming
dangerously close to you swinging down his battle axe so you're now knocked back
he's swinging it weird though he's not using like the the sharp edge it's like the flat
spread out edge big smile on your face yeah totally have a good time happiness to get
out of the way you knock yourself back prone and you're just seeing this Yenbul
just like wrenching this blade into her shoulder agoth doesn't look happy i don't think
no no but yeah like agoth has has some clues as to what's happening tel gear also had like
just this shimmer of clarity but has gone back to trying to catch butterflies with a battle
there your friends are running around doing this what do you want to do uh i'd like to shout out
into the building okay hello hi uh um uh oh shit what was her name queen queen of the ravens
queen of the ravens if you're doing this uh we are here uh in peace and if you could stop
this we we really need your help your friends are still running around and the scene is playing
out in front of you everybody else as you're doing what you think you're doing there are these
just quick little shots of of clarity that come through and you see thea on the ground
screaming up and you hear just little glimpses of the pleads she's yelling out into this
room and then it goes back Yenbul as you get one of these you see the blood is like pouring down
your front and then it snaps back and the vine is trying to wrap itself around agoth and
tel gear you're chasing down and then you see your weapons come out as you're like running
towards each other trying to get these butterflies make dexterity saving throws please all right
well right away it's not great nine eighteen you see them tel gear a little bit too late agoth
you're able to move to the side but you're the momentum of your blade comes down and strikes
into tel gear uh roll damage please nine damage and as you take that damage uh make
another wisdom saving throw as you feel this sharp i mean you see it but then it goes back
to what you you see as a butterfly net sure uh that'll be a 24 and as it hits in everything
melts away like in this wave of death and decay like the entire green hills like like immediately
browns up and the trees shrivel up you see benjamin come back and he like quickly emaciates
himself and becomes a skeleton who falls to the ground and you're back like clear you're
bleeding but you're back and you see agoth continuing to cautiously run around and
strategically Yenbul grappling with herself and thea behind you screaming up into the building
all right uh yeah i guess i'll go um attempt to remove said dagger from Yenbul's shoulder
seems to be the order of the day let's do a straight strength contest thea you see
tel gear stand up and begin moving towards Yenbul and moving towards her dagger 12 19
tel gear and he grasps hold of it hard and like you describe how you take it from Yenbul
who's putting up a fight yeah um i picture it like you know when over the top i do know in over
the top so essentially tel gear goes over the top on this day i'm gonna need a little bit of
an explanation because i don't know over the top don't know over the top no and maybe some
of our listeners won't either can i have a little more so uh over the top which i have
seen one time only once based on register recommendation because he owned it
is a movie uh basically about arm wrestling it is and fathers and fathers and sons and the
bond that brings them together to cross generational gap basically sliced alone is like this crazy
arm wrestler dad guy who's a truck driver and his his signature move is to go over the top
when they're arm wrestling which means the fingers come over the top i've heard enough
yeah hey you asked i am sorry yeah i go over the top and i like slowly
get this dagger like a way a out of her shoulder and then b out of her hand tel gear
tel gear can you hear me
it's the middle
and we're here to say that amy's not here so we're gonna say all of her secrets
what tune did you go with you know i don't know i was an original it was very you came
in with like a very sort of plaintive energy that i was not expecting yeah i was like
expecting something kind of like upbeat robust and it was more like okay i'm just gonna test
the waters here well sometimes sometimes when i say i'm gonna try and find a tune my mind
blanks on all songs in the world and then it's like well i'll start one and i'll find it
halfway through but it but then it's just in a ridge and how i can sell that uh and get
all the royalties on it now you're rich just like that take that imagine dragons
i was gonna do thunder but not anymore i had a thing like that the other day for work uh they
were asked like what are your some of your favorite like ads that you remember and i was
like i don't think i've ever seen an ad before i can't i can't think of a single
tide pods yeah they did something didn't they like those delicious tide
pods we're in the middle now and we're um well amy's not here because she had to go put our
put our daughter to bed so what kind of secrets what kind of dirt do we have on amy i mean
nothing i don't think she's kind of an open book which is one of the best things about
her yeah let's just talk about all the things we like about amy she's very funny
very funny very funny yeah she's very very nice person very nice very smart and very smart
very like to the point but in a good way some people are like blunt but no she is like
oh there's no pointed but politely so yeah one thing i admire about amy is that she really
likes the things that she likes and just like goes for it owns it yeah and like champions
them too i like gardening get on board everybody else this is what is happening and i think it's
great also she's a total fox absolutely i don't want to like demean her but no
but we gotta say you gotta she's got the whole package you gotta call it yeah she just walked
back in so we're gonna stop talking about her now that's right amy's back now we're in the
middle of a of a middle so just bring it home here amy yep you got this amy and go you
guys are friggin awesome come visit us over at Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
see so good isn't she just nailed it yeah what are we talking about you we were just
said about her we're accurate yeah i think i think we brought it home all right thanks everybody have
a great rest of the episode i know yeah yeah right right here a little busy thank god
oh holy crap okay um what the fuck is going on don't know uh got stabbed woke up you're
welcome i'm on the case now agoth as you're running around make a dexterity saving throw
please gladly 11 few things happen because you took the blade so Yenbul the the vines to you
have ripped your blade and are now constricting themselves hard around your arm like you feel
like you're losing circulation in your arm you see it and it's turning like black and blue
quickly before your eyes agoth do you continue to chase the butterflies what's what you're
just kind of observing walking looking yeah i think at this point like get out a little bit
of aggression on the butterflies but that's that's not you know that's bloodless stated
with tilgar i guess i think right now just sort of defensive position because something
is clearly messed up but i don't seem to have a way to stop i've been through my
spell list like 17 times how can i stop this come on post it notes you see racks bolt off
yeah still within that one uh you see racks bolt off into the like going into the horizon
basically like following these green hills everybody else um tolgier and thea you see
racks bolt down this hallway oh shit i think yeah at that point uh i guess we sort of hang
her head and go shit and uh head after racks and then agath follows quickly behind racks
and you see agath break stride a little bit but only because the floor depresses quickly
beneath her and this this blade swings out of the wall and down i imagine you have a long
stride so it like catches an arm as you're on like the backswing and you take 17 slashing
damage as this blade swings down through no big deal yeah it's fine you have like a
thousand hit points so uh make a wisdom saving throw as you take this heavy amount of damage
come on so this is where i should have uh waited to use
that saving throw ability because i just rolled a two which makes it an 11 okay now sometimes
with fighters do they get multiple uses of that thanks maybe i'll go look right like i
mean occasionally it's like hey at level seven you get this and you get another one at level
14 says once one time per long rest damn yeah worth a shot totally worth a shot okay then
as this hits you you see this huge black winged creature like it's hard to describe
it's not bat like it's got like these this long snout with these razor sharp teeth and it like
flies up and out of what you now see as this giant crevice that racks has jumped across
and it is bearing down on you right now i'm gonna take evasive maneuver i gotta get that
horse because if he gets too far ahead of me i ain't ever gonna catch him so you're getting
you're like shielding yourself with your shield and you're trying to move away from this and
as um so there's this now like ravine how do you traverse that i'm very athletic can i jump
across it you can certainly try yes i will make it uh make it athletics come on or acrobatics
either or um 18 take a few steps back and run out and try and leap over top of this
you fall one step short but your foot hits the ground regardless like it's you feel like
it's almost like falling and then you hit the ground hard and like almost buckle underneath
yourself and those little shots of clarity come back and you see them ripple down the hallway
as you see racks running further down this dark hallway it's like increasingly dark um as
he goes down you turn back and you see your friends particularly Yenbul who's been taking
damage from herself if he's making my arm go for quite a while like lose
should probably have you make a wisdom saving throw no like i'm taking damage can i take a
wisdom saving throw i just like keeping you in the dark here i stabbed myself now my my hand
hurts real bad or doesn't i feel nothing in it it's numb and i have pins and needles for
an hour oh that wasn't a great roll guys uh oh this is plus 10 17 you're still in lala land
okay well okay what are the what are tel gear and thea doing you see agoth and the horse run down
right the yen bull is still not with it i'm just wrestling i guess tel gear but i think
vines but i'm struggling um three out of four of you are collectively in this place
uh i'm going to put my hands on yen bull and and shake her a little bit and and say come on you can
get out of this as i cast guidance on her first time ever i've never heard of this i've had it
since the dawn of time everybody and was like when will i fucking ever use this you're just
waiting for this moment please save me from stabbing myself have one in the back pocket
the whole time you touch one willing creature and once before the spell ends the target can
roll a d4 and add the number rolled to one ability check of its choice oh no wait it's an
ability check fuck this this is why can we just say it's a save yeah it's got yeah sure can
we just yeah uh so yen bull uh you that's why i've never used thea goes to shake you and
you like see her come in and out of view come on you can get out of this make another wisdom
saving throw you know what we'll say with advantage rather than just the plus four uh
okay because i'm being helpful because you're being helpful okay sure so 19 or 21 so i made
21 obviously it's the one that i want because it's better but it's not good enough still not
i guess that was my original role i think shit i'm just like rolling around like just pulling
and wrestling with the this mean vine looking at what i still see that looks like a gorgeous
beautiful place and somehow i found the one asshole plant that's attacking me isn't that
always the way it works you see benjamin back standing over you just you just have to
you just have to swing harder you just have to swing harder and then you can get free
and you can come play i want to come play help me well what can you do how can you get free
oh i i'll help you he reaches his hand out for you yeah grab his hand i mean of course i do
i don't i don't know what's going on it's my old friend benny everyone from the place that
i live is gone you guys grasp benny's hand uh-huh and you feel that if you cast sacred flame
all will be better great they have to you have to do a deck save whoever i'm
rolling that at it has to be to 17 oh god it's me
is it me who is i think it's all gear all right it was like oh maybe it's both oh yeah
18 oh good good for you so that's like what half damage no i think it's nothing
it's a cantrip so when you guys it's all coming up amy today burst of light goes up
before you thea makes you jump back oh god Yenbul you you clasp benjamin's hand and sacred flame
goes off you hear thea's yell off in the distance it seems like but as you look back
to benjamin his arm is skeletal and the skin is like sloughing away from him and he says come
play come play it will be fine come on let's go and he's like pulling at you make a what's
your wisdom plus 10 oh fuck okay make a wisdom saving throw oh jesus well i haven't made it
yet i know you haven't yet 29 wow as you see like this the flesh falling away and it's
instilling this fear in you and then you suddenly steal yourself and it all just falls
like you with dust oh and you're all standing in this dark hallway rax has run off further i
don't know if a god can hear his hooves yeah echoing down some hallway dust covered cobwebs
like not fresh cobwebs but like dust covered cobwebs hang from the ceilings your hands and
face and bodies are covered in this decay and you look around thea you recognize that all of
your cohorts your friends are back to themselves Yenbul yes i gosh are you okay i'm bleeding
yeah you stabbed yourself multiple times in the shoulder yeah for some reason a real bunch
um but there were these vines attacking me and i no no there weren't oh you i don't know what
happened but you three were in some sort of fantasy world look like you were having a real
good time until you weren't that's the thing it was great until it was so beautiful green
fields and fresh air and it was wonderful uh do you need any help Yenbul how's your shoulder
no i it is fine okay we should probably go after a goth she she ran down that corridor
chasing rax who i'm pretty sure is still in that dreamland
hallucination i think as you're saying that i sort of just like come up behind you
oh oh you are here but rax is gone rax is somewhere down that direction um well
we have to go get him since we don't exactly know where to go anyway
and i mean we didn't put in all that time getting over that bridge to not go after him
okay let's let's go find him um can i look around the room is there i hadn't had a
chance what with all my friends being like psycho and whatnot yeah uh is there anything
in here any books any sigils you definitely see symbols of the raven queen all down this
hallway you see tapestries where it appears like something or someone has like scratched
or torn out the faces and bodies of whoever was in these images so there's nothing discernible
from any of them as you're walking by you see specifically different landscapes of
similarly to what you've seen out in the landscape that you were landscape that you
were walking through but also the occasional one of like silvery moon or high forests but
those ones are much fewer and farther between he's got to reach a dead end at some point right like
there's it's not just a big circle or maybe he'll just come up behind us at some point
yes we have to keep going until we find rax or something else he's like a like a like a
homing beacon on him you got like a low jack attached to rax fortunately given his size he is
generally very easy to track
do we still hear his hooves he doesn't have to have like a bell on him or anything
yeah i would say you definitely hear him down this hallway and i imagine like with all the dust
and cobwebs like there's probably a fairly easy way to track him through because big bodies
brushed up against a wall or something there's a clean spot narrow corridor giant horse you
continue down the hallway following the the nays and hoof steps that you hear the room is
getting much darker so anybody without dark vision so yimbo for sure maybe a goth
would be having difficulty seeing the farther you go i can cast well i guess i can try to cast
light hold on is that going to use up a spell slot for you or is that a cantrip
it's a cantrip okay i was just gonna say don't don't waste your spells we haven't
even gotten to the raven queen but we don't know if anything happened after that last
spell no no but i mean save it for the raven queen just in case there's a big battle
because i had but yeah no it's a cantrip so i can uh i can just like cast it on my mace
so your mace begins to light up and you're able to see 30 or 60 feet or whatever it is it
lights up the hallway far enough that you can see everybody make perception check as that
happens 24 17 8 13 i guess that shoulder is really bothering yeah and you're holding the
mace with that shoulder too you're not doing yourself any favors the with the 24 you like the
light comes on and even with the 17 like you see the walls themselves ripple for a moment
um and then they stop like almost like you toss a small rock into a into a pool it ripples and
then it's still again did anyone else see that see see what i didn't see the walls are
made out of water that sounds stupid i understand how that sounds
i want to reach out and touch one of the walls with uh a head of my arrow
mama didn't raise no fool yeah you reach out and poke the wall with it
poke it yeah uh you do so and it seems like it's a real i take it and i carve my blade
onto it and i just carved the tea was here that appears as you carve it out must have
just been a trick of the light i guess i'm trying to see i don't even have like
detect magic or like the most basic kind of like revealing spell that i could i have to
who needs to build a bAlydinced party i have to detect magic i have to detect magic talkier
should do a spell i mean there's probably magic everywhere but we got to try and figure
out what's going on in this joint all right yeah let's do it i'm gonna cast detect magic
tell me how to talk here detects magic he kind of just like he has that little amulet
on his neck and he kind of just grabs it and mutters under his breath and
goes to uh detect all that good good magic or bad magic hey you magic is that what you
whisper is that what everybody whispers you magic for you as you detect magic the entirety
of your surroundings come back with basically the walls and the floors and the ceiling like
everything lights up and it's giving um an enchantment school of magic uh guys
everything is magic like the walls are alive with the magic the sound of magic yes okay
everybody sees it now the walls begin to like wave out and you you hear them collapsing in
behind you like almost like doors shutting but the wall is like folding in on itself
coming down from the entrance that you now no longer see because it's collapsing in behind you
perhaps we should go yes quickly yep everybody begins running down the hallways and as you run
it gets faster and faster and there's a singular door down at the end of this hallway
let's go yeah is that or get crushed by walls so uh you burst through this door and into
this darkened room that is illuminated by the light and you see ahead of you come into
view you see racks standing in the center of this room the sound of the crushing walls
goes until it hits that doorway and then it's like this echoey stop
and as you take a second you see along the edges of this what you now see is like a circular
room that now has no doors in or out you see figures that look like darkened humanoid figures
standing in obscured almost painful looking positions almost as if they're in like a tableau
or a statue and racks is ears up panicked eyes looking at these creatures i'll go up to racks and
just like put my hand on his neck and try and calm down a little bit kind of startles at
your touch and then like sinks back towards you and you see standing right in front of him
like uh-huh almost like a wave out of these these humanoid creatures in like these anguished
like you see the look on their face and it's anguished and the the flesh of them
it looks decayed but like there's this first one right in front of racks like he snorts
out and like this plume of noxious gas comes out and this figure like cranes its neck
and begins the cracking its bones as if it begins to move i'm gonna turn undead
Dumbgeons and Dragons season two episode 92 starring Amy More as thea amastasia carla
max dead as yen bolnuri tom laird is talkeer heavyfoot with guest christin Flemmons as a
goth god las catho alavi and Russ More as your dungeon master editing production and
sound design by Russ More this episode featured music from epidemic sound and sound effects from
epidemic sound boom library and sound ideas a huge thank you to our supporting producers
gabriel lynch jessica Babyok stevie cat water flame jacob madden christian brown
devin michaels erin stevens and lulahan to support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many other
productions and get access to an exclusive podcast called the adventures of bonus episodes
and much more please join our Patreon at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where
when we reach 100 patrons we'll release an exclusive Grancis and Flamikins kens bonus episode
escaping the abyss you can also follow us at facebook.com slash dumb dragon podcast and on
instagram and twitter at dumb dragon cast thank you for listening have a great week
we'll talk again soon
you are trying to take tom out you guys are going to do a swapsies on podcasting aren't you
i see what's going on here finally my plan begins tricky tricky i say that because i don't
think Yenbul has darkvision rude what are you doing looking at my sheet and learning my
weaknesses i think he said it i do either oh yeah so dagger in shoulder is it
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production