previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Black-Rotten Guts maybe are probably starting to fall out.
Causes this dragon to recoil.
It pulls its neck and head back out and up street level.
You hear coming in behind it first this like droning, humming.
A hail of rock hard ice pounds to the ground at a 20-foot radius,
and I make it specifically on this zombie clot.
and you hear a blade cut hard into the dragon and the head droops for a second
and then falls down into the cavern and dropping down carrying a double bladed
glowing sword with like flame coming from her nostrils is this copper and bronze
and gold and platinum dragonborn who's quickly followed down by a halfling and half orc
welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons i'm your dungeon master rust more he him also with me today is
tom lair he him and tonight i am playing two characters playing uh telgir heavyfoot who is a
mountain dwarf pAlydin who also goes by he him and i'm also playing moot who is a half orc wild
magic sorcerer and maybe something else we'll get into that later excellent and also with us
tonight is carla max dead i like the tease she her i am playing Yenbul nuri a kalishtar cleric
also she her and glim a dragonborn pAlydin slash maybe something else this is what we're doing
secrets tom established also also she her tom established what we're doing so we gotta stick
to it all right right and Amy More yes i'm here too and i will also be playing two characters
thea amastasia a high elf druid she her and sullivan's light a lightfoot halfling rogue
all the way baby no secrets here sully's all on the table ironic usually sully's the one with
yes the rogue's got no secrets he's an open book ten years into the darkest timeline
you probably don't have a lot of secrets anyways hey it's our hundredth episode today
of season two what excuse me of season two of season two yeah we've done well over 200
episodes but of season two we've finally crossed the streams happy birthday happy birthday
let's just sit in that moment for a little while all right feels good
here celebrating instead of diving into the darkest time yeah i know we just want to
just want to feel good about it strap in for 47 minutes of patting ourselves on the back here
all right that's pretty much amazing it's really been a joy just recording with you
these past hundred episodes plus absolutely plus all that bonus content plus all that
bonus content where you can find that bonus content is over on Patreon Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast keep going oh okay and if you are a patron with us you get an episode
dedicated to you like today's patron lacy linn thanks lacy linn i love the alliteration
i know it's fun to say always fun to say yeah your 100th episode that's very special
i think so after like the sex one and the drugs one though so that's probably the best
one to be absolutely it's right up there with sex drugs and 100th episode that's how the song
goes yeah there might be some rock and roll in this we'll have to wait and see but now
you go to Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and join us over there we'd love it don't back
your chair oh okay he's finally laid down uh now that the dog has relaxed itself fuck it let's
play
this is the new theme music for it i don't like what you're doing with your hands for the cross
it's why do you always comment on my hand only i'm the one who has to see them it's like
sandstorm over here most of the time they're like at the very bottom of the screen so we
only ever see like the tips of your fingers it's true it's like little flames at the bottom
it's better than when you're like going to roll dice but you're talking and talking and talking
it just looks like you're jerking off underneath the camera it's my it's my secret pleasure
looking over watching you going well you look like a jackass right now
see all the truth comes out in the 100th episode it really does yeah okay
hmm fuck it let's play fuck it let's play fuck it let's play carla do you want to it's it's the
100th episode fuck it let's play now all together three two one fuck it let's play
hey
a hollow wind howls across the plains as moot glim and sully see in the dull purple aura of what's
left of the moon castle orcas ahead of them it's about fucking time yeah this was a hard one
i can't believe we actually found it but we did it so great two thumbs up
well like one thumb up anyway oh god i'm sorry oh my that's real insensitive i'm so sorry it's like
i try not to say it and then i just say it and it's i'm so sorry mood i mean it's been a long
time since i was down to the one thumb but like i got that cool crab claw now just full
time for the other one so uh-huh yeah that's real cool it's pretty good trade-off a good
trade-off i mean considering the option could have been just no hand at all oh come on there
was always hook uh there was always sword for hand there was always i feel like mace for hand
okay mace for hand would have been really cool i feel like hook not as good crab claw pretty
good it's got a bit of the hook ideal to it i can pinch things with it yeah you gotta stop
that that's just it's never the time nor the place i'm sure there will be a time and a place
where it is the exact thing we need at that moment glim in your bag you've been carrying
a book for years now that has remained quiet your bag begins to
vibrate something you haven't felt since before orcas took over
oh my oh my what what is that so embarrassing what's in there oh my goodness
oh and i pull out the book is that what i think it is it is it's been
oh my god years we pull out the tome of bahamut and crack it open to the last page that had
any writing on it then you see before you a new entry illuminating before your eyes
yes guys oh my what what is happening this is unbelievable so you got you got a destiny again
what's what i don't know let's see let's see what it says three words appear all it says
is get back now books all bossy there glim i feel like it's pretty obvious what we need
to do so maybe we should like get back the three of you bolt off towards the city
we cut to the sewer with a rotting undead dragon's head between moot glim and sully
and thea Yenbul and talgir Yenbul turns around having just put the killing blow into the zombie
clot and the six adventurers are staring each other down you called also what the
hell was that thing that's yuck that's gross well it's like all the undead get together into
big one big undead ah it's like a gross zombie orgy that's exactly what i thought uh hi i'm
thea uh talgir Yenbul sullivan's light glim moot uh your place looks like shit yeah it's
really super gross in here like even grosser than it was just when it was the sewer
yeah that's uh undead dragon and all the zombies didn't exactly make it like top notch in here
anyway everyone's making for a boat we got to get the hell out of here are you guys coming
with uh well we're looking for Leosin uh he's on his way to the boat yeah he's back there
he's he's trucking to the boat okay you hear from down further into the sewer the opposite
way that Leosin went the sound of quacking quickly coming towards you
and moaning undead following fastin behind them go go go we got to get going we got to get going
they're all coming and i think it's i think i think they're behind them and there's a whole
bunch of things and just bolting past you uh moot starts to move his hands around because
he's going to cast some sort of spell that i'm going to look through my list and find
right now and then from far in the distance you hear here ducky ducky ducky coming to get you
and i yell back lip-synchy that's so fucked up so yeah moot's gonna wait for the the ducks
to go by and he like motions everyone to go and follow them
um
in the like the opening that the suit that the sewer ducks came out of yeah he walks over there
and he claps his hands together and a loud thunderous boom happens
and moot's all of a sudden in front of everyone that's running the other way as he's teleported
himself with thunderstep he fucking left us i thought you were gonna do some really i thought
he was gonna do something against himself in character well no what what happened though is
his thunder clap has caused the tunnel that the sewer ducks came running out of to collapse
in on itself okay it's like you know he wasn't just abandoning you see you later yeah right peace
does that asshole not know he shouldn't be doing magic how's he doing magic
and thea looks around her to be like what's dying uh yeah i gotta i okay i gotta i'll explain
later but it kind of has something to do with this and he points at his crab claw hand
that you can tell is oh my god magically there
if he should go if he should go to the boat uh yeah let's let's run let's get out of here
everybody tears off and follows down the passageways yeah of course get on that eventually
come to a further underground cavern and before you you see a what looks like a fully closed
ship better than a fully clothed ship that's right just got a little bikini on at the front
standing in the doorway is flamey kens let's get this fucker moving all right climb aboard
we've been waiting for you but thought we'd be we'll give up on you it's like great a
headhug and then i was like okay well she's probably dead now okay climb aboard glad you
waited for us yeah thanks flamey kens uh we are here and there are others yeah yeah no i
know them too get on board jesus mclem and sully which it's about time we were about you were
gonna have to swim your way over to mastika what were you gonna do that well i mean mastika
that sounds like a made-up place i mean glim's a strong swimmer and it wouldn't be the first
time sully's ridden her back the whole way somewhere all right well everybody sounds like
a shot at me damn it oh no just i mean it's just more convenient she makes really good time
it's hard for your little legs to keep up also it helps my training
it's hard to swim but have weights at the same time so you're doing me a favor all right
everybody except glim on board no no it's too late all right everybody's on board we're close
oh i'm just kidding come on oh you yeah the door slams shut and flamey kens pushes past everyone
it's like packed um this metal tube for lack of a better term she's pushing past everybody
to get to the front okay everybody you have a seat there you grab the kids there all right
everybody just wrangle up and hold on tight we're gonna be moving pretty fast okay and she
moves up to what appears to be a cockpit and starts hitting levers and pushing buttons and
you hear like a propulsion system start up at the back and begin to lurch forward uh flamey
kens is there anything that we can do yeah just make sure the kids don't fall over
when we go down here we got to get out into the bay and then we're just going to be going
down pretty quick because there's some big things in the ocean that are going to want to grab us
really quick and we got to get out before that horde comes because i'm sure uh big v and uh
little sinky whatever the names are they're going to want to get on board and come find
you and probably take your skins yeah that collapsed tunnel won't hold them for long guys
all right let's go somebody let's go everybody grab a baby i'm not touching a baby i mean i
i can grab a couple they're slippery and and sticky at the same time if there's a baby that needs
help help don't just take random babies yeah don't take random babies leo sin make sure they don't
take random babies uh yeah i got it i got it the submersible moves forward and you feel it
pitched down and then it slows for a minute and then launches off like a rocket holy shit
um i'm not feeling too great you guys yes i am also unvel yeah now that i've i stopped running
i thank you for yes but uh i've got to can you take your baby back please i've got to yeah
yeah sorry yes thank you oh uh flamey kens do you have a mop or anything i'm
um what did you do did you throw up already no i'm just getting blood all over your ship oh
jesus thea sorry yeah there's a mop there beside you hold on hey leo sin check the back see if
we grab the potions leo sin comes forward uh to each of you with stoppered vile and hands them
to you and says i don't know if this will take care of all of your ales but hopefully
it stops the bleeding at the very least thank you and i and i take the stopper off and
i drink it and then i go oh this is vile and then you turn yellow gotcha
no sorry yeah give her the other one too he hands you another one i can't believe i'm
not okay with this i had to work through a lot of this yellow trauma flamey kens yeah
no well i thought it would be a good like welcome back joke oh you look yeah you're like
a bumblebee over there that's good hi high five yeah
and the next high five the next five minutes well executed high five russ and amy trying
to high five oh yeah felt good all right no you just you just go to the back there it's
fine we don't have to talk about this ever again yeah it's probably best we don't i take
the other one like this better fucking god damn it's it's good it's good right leo's it it's
good leo's and why did you give me the other one in the first place it's it felt good to laugh
again oh my fine fine i drink the other one yeah i'm sorry but it was a little bit funny
everybody can regain 84 plus eight whoa oh boy i'm just gonna take a swig of this and i'm
gonna take a potion of superior healing oh which is that yeah i gave you a real thing
you're gonna take another one yeah all right sounds good leo's and moves over to moot
clem and sully it's so good to see you back did you did you find the amulet oh yeah we
we found that moot you got it oh you mean this one right here so he holds it up you don't
look as badass as you think you do wearing that um speaking of cool things something crazy happened
you'll never believe it like if i gave you a thousand years to guess you would never
guess what happened oh we should we should have him guess though because i want to see
what he comes up okay something that's so important to me i think yes and like maybe
it's going to change the course of my life again i think all right but i don't know i want
to know what what you think what it what does it start with
okay um w or b w in b warner brothers
um okay well uh okay a w or or a b um and it could change your life is it is it bahamut's back
i mean that was a really good guess how did you well um right my my book there was writing
in my in my book with the tome of bahamut and there hasn't been writing in like
like seven eight was your clue words in book so many years what writing in book writing in
writing i mean that's the long way around for sure yeah yeah i mean he got it so it was
obviously a good guess uh yes because bahamut's back and he turns you around
and in the next room in like the they've set up a makeshift triage you see a few people
lying down asleep or in comas um and in the center of these people is an older man in like torn and
tattered robes eyes closed giving off this aura of light you immediately
uh and i run over there wait wait but that's him i i know it's just just you know just take a
moment to to breathe and to settle yourself and to remember that meeting your hero sometimes
isn't all that it is uh built up to be in your in your head because your whole life you've
been dedicated to this person and uh so just you know just i just don't want to see you
sad if it doesn't go like the perfect way most of our life yeah but i mean he was gone and now
he's back yes i'll just take a deep breath i think maybe oh my god maybe it's happening
maybe maybe we're saving the world he's back it has been a long time since you've talked
about that yeah i mean i kind of i kind of missed it oh i really did it was always such
like a rallying cry for us whenever things were were really dark we just looked towards
glam and she's always well guys we're saving the world and then oh right of course that's
what we're doing and you know you your your strike gets a little longer when you remember
that well it's hard to remember when the whole world gets overtaken by undead and there's no
magic and your god disappears and now you're going now he's back okay well go what are you
waiting for okay okay okay is he in a coma yeah okay that's what i thought like you can still
fawn over oh for sure give him a little tap upside the face just a few times just to make sure
it's me glam the chosen one i've missed you can i braid your hair let her have a moment
so i think i'm going to kind of perch on his bedside i think i am pretty like uh i'm assuming
there's not chairs beside the bedside we're not in the hospital so i'm just going to kind of
scooch on there my giant body and try to calmly
me kind of grab his hand pahamit i oh god i can't i can't believe it really here i gave up
i gave up so long ago and i'm we tried for so long and then just kept getting worse and worse
and i thought you were never coming back but now you're you're back and we can fix you and
then we can fix the world and then everything's gonna be totally fine again
and then looks over at her friends one missing hand one missing an eye like well maybe
everything won't be exactly the same as it was before but if you're back then everything's
gonna be okay right right as you moved closer to him and as you hold his hand and the longer
you do you feel re-energized abilities and skills that you've long forgotten about
start to flood back to you while he doesn't say anything you get
for the first time in a long time an overwhelming sense of calm
and peace
it's just it's so good to have you back
now we just got to get you woken up we cut ahead several hours the uh your you tell
me what the is doing is flint on the ship yeah flint flint is in that kind of triage
setup yeah uh i think she's probably sitting with him resting uh recanting the story of
the shit that just went down and then at a nowhere uh this dragonborn and this halfling
and this like half orc just like essentially like i don't know come out of the sky they
chopped this dragon's head off right and now they're here with us and we're all
relying on Flamikinskins if you can believe it to get us all to this island of
mastodonia masturbation tika mastika so could be the last remaining place that isn't completely
fucked up maybe you'll you'll wake up there that'd be uh that'd be really cool if the uh
if he was flint was back right now like i'm sure he would have chopped off the dragon's
head before before those other for those other folks got there who are you i'm don e
i am a dragon who sits in your bag eating your crackers it wasn't quite it wasn't quite
enough for me i've been with you for the last how many years solemn moment it wasn't uh yeah sorry
oh he would have had that dragon handled yeah yeah totally is it offensive to you when we
slay dragons uh no because i mean there's good dragons and there's bad dragons and the bad
dragons are you know uh undead right now so that's pretty cool and i mean they called
you the decimators of dragons but really you'd never killed a dragon until Tiamat
right yeah but we don't like more of them have almost killed you you should be called the
decimated by dragons wow a little salty in there donnie well i mean i'm just calling it
like i see it you know they wrote the history books one way but i was there you want a
cracker yeah it's like a cracker here's a cracker he takes a cracker and then the entire
vessel you're in begins to vibrate like a big impact just hit it to the side hold on to your
butts we're gonna need some people to go outside in the water yeah in the water that's what's
outside get to the back leo sano hook you up uh you want to go swimming donnie uh no i'll
check on flint here make sure he doesn't roll over in his stupor coma and hurt himself more
okay i'm just gonna prop myself right under his side here see he was kind of leaning to this
side so now i'm like a stopper okay uh you can leave the crackers though because those will get
wet outside yeah they will okay stay safe buddy who heads to the back uh i do i think
moot does glen was just bragging about how good she was at swimming so she better go
sully can't swim um and i think yen bull goes to yeah i'd assume tell your uh grabs his axe
and goes for him bull tug your moot guys i just had a total moment i'm looking for i've got
something to do with water breathing underwater alter self something that allows me to do
something in water and i look and i'm like water skin like
like a wetsuit and then it says adventuring gear and then hold water and then and then it
said to drink water from yeah so that's where i'm at because it was like container and i was
like container like to contain my body like a scoop i don't understand like a mini submarine
i'm not sure all right let's have so that's where i'm at let's have just little quick scenes
of each of the three okay solly i please can you watch over bahamut yeah okay yeah i can do
that i will watch this old guy like well like he's your most important person i mean yeah now
that we have him in our sights uh i'll hold his hand don't let him out oh he's got that
soft old person skin that's nice it's nice it's a little crepey this guy feels kind of
nice yeah solly's rubbing his the back of of bahamut's hand against his face against his
cheek well i mean look after don't be don't make it weird okay um i'll see you soon
thea stands up from flint's side leaving donnie behind turns and sees tolgir and
we all going out to the water what else would we do fair yeah that's where they need us that's
where we're gonna be if i were to cast a spell do you think i that would like hurt bahamut
maybe i don't know glim walks by at exactly that moment uh hey you know a lot about this guy
bahamut yes he's like the coolest guy ever he's back i can't believe it okay i have a
question for you okay if i were to cast a tiny spell to give myself the ability to breathe
underwater would that hurt him okay um i don't know if you do anything that will hurt him
i'm gonna have to hurt you whoa but before we get to that maybe let's just like find out
what they want us to do and what leo's me maybe just before we start casting magic and
killing my god that just came back from who knows where for years he's finally just right
over there i know i know glim yeah yeah let's let's just maybe we could just i'm one of
the ones who busted him out actually i i got him out um got a real got a real sweet sour
thing going on here i'm not looking to hurt your god very important i understand thank you
for whatever you did to find him let me start there let's just maybe
at least let's just flamey kens can explain what the plan is are we swimming are we
let's just let's just go okay yeah and i i apologize i mean if you hurt him listen i i
heard you the first time but i get it okay she's allowed to crunch around the vessel
as she's like aren't you all back there yet if we all die in here because i'm not able to cast
a spell your god's not gonna be much help anyway i don't do it i don't know the answer
i feel super awkward right now that we had that interaction girl
our characters are always best friends i loved it it's just like oh my god you know
i didn't like it oh this bitch up in here wants to fucking cast magic this bitch threatening
at the fountain of fucking magic on board and she's like let me just pull it
yeah just see everybody rushes to the back here as we leave in on flint and fade into a dream
sequence
well i don't know why i came here tonight i got a feeling it's something right i'm so scared i
think i'll fall off my chair and i'm wondering how i'll get down the stairs
clowns to the left of me jokers to the right here i am stuck in the middle with you
i didn't start any any later in that song i just wanted i'd like that song yeah hey we're
in the middle now and we're talking about it's the middle how this is season two episode 100
give us that horn tom
dave's back baby for the hundredth episode for the hundred episode dave's not actually
dave's not back dave no dave's not here he's not here man yep um but yeah what holy geez
holy geez hey holy geez is pretty accurate we're just gonna sit and revel in it just sit with
us of this season season yeah we didn't make it to a centennial last season i don't think we
were committed enough yeah that was yeah that's right it was too straightforward with a through
start middle and end yeah i blame those first a bunch of episodes that were all like two hours
up on yeah oh yeah we would have been over easy totally yeah one but yeah before we figured out
so that was like 30 we easily would have done 110 150 yeah there we go so really we
did it just condensed it yep you got it um but what what what else we're very excited about
is over on Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and we know that we've been talking about
it a lot but we've got this super exciting thing where you can save two months free
on an annual membership new and upgrading members over at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast uh
also some other really great things going on over there like a new thing like a new thing
i was yeah we're starting a new we're starting a new thing we are where we read a book
and maybe you read it too and then we get together and talk about it you're talking
like a book club carla dumpster's book so it's like a club but like the main thing we do
is like read a book and then talk about it so yeah i mean i guess you could call it like
a book club well i like that let's say what we like read a book and then like i don't
know every few months have a zoom call where our patrons can come and join us and like chat about
the book yeah yeah exactly and like low pressure i think we'll probably do it like four times a
year so let's say like quarterly generally so it gives you a lot of time to read the book
it's not homework it's fun no it's fun we'll talk about it as much as we do love to give
homework this isn't homework if you've ever been to one of our gook hangs you know that
to be a fact tom carla and i just really like to read and we want to read with you
exactly amy's gonna pick the first book i've already picked it oh here it is give me that
air horn again i was a little lackluster tom i'm not gonna lie there you make you
amp it up okay the book we're gonna be reading is realm breaker by victoria aviard so if you
want to read along with us what like we're gonna get going on this right away and that means
let me do some math november december january so like february no we're in the beginning of
october we're in october yeah so like january new year january yeah yeah we'll start a
discord channel on our discord and we'll have details and everything there but yeah it'd be
so fun if you read the book and wanted to come talk about it with us because we're
nerds right grab your popcorn grab your wine let's talk about rum breaker too exactly this is very
exciting um russ this is so exciting this no it legitimately is very exciting but what what uh
amy tom and carla have kind of alluded to is that this is open to all patrons any tier
so come join us anywhere if this is something that interests you you like reading books you
like hanging out with friends we want to do that with you and we're doing it over in the
discord i might just come hang out and you know just kind of watch and see what goes on in a
book club you can also be in the book club just all that like bookish knowledge get that
knowledge and i could just toss in i'll read five pages uh of the books that are there so
that i have some base knowledge of like random characters not even like real like the main
character but just like the random character they met but on page 271 yeah they say this
discuss won't read five pages in a row he will take random pages six eight hundred uh 30
this book is not 800 pages there's not gonna be 800 pages in the book it is not 800 pages no
it's no it's really not um long story short Patreon.com dumb dragon cast we've got a
book club going on air horn tom it's just one long air horn no it's good it's running out of
steam on that one it's good yep um Patreon.com dumb dragon cast two months free book club it's
happening it's where it's at we'd love to see you over there and if you're already a patron
you could be part of the book club too so look for the details in our discord and on
Patreon okay bye you don't know why you listened to Scyther when he said that the trip down the
river would be the easiest way to escape Papa Zoodle's wrath because it really hasn't
worked out very well you've been trying your best to speed down the river but it turns
out this bird is quite vengeful and he's able to really take some uh some running starts at you
dive bombing you as you float down the river water Scyther what ah geez the fish are jumping
up i can't even keep my mouth open the birds coming from above wouldn't it be better to stay
in the canopy i mean i don't know i thought the river was a good way to do it we'll just
keep paddling and we'll get away from him i swear just keep swimming just keep paddling
god just keep paddling all right yeah uh he continues to paddle do you want to just to
roll anything for this or uh yeah roll let's do like dex let's do a dex roll because i have a
board character sheet uh obviously uh he's a ranger i mean he's a ranger who specializes in
ranged attacks so i would assume his dexterity is reasonably high level so i mean 15 on the
so probably at least a plus four so we'll say 19 yeah so you manage to uh increase your
paddling speed and like go a little bit off course because you see papa's little coming
and he's kind of locked into a dive headed towards the canoe and you're able to kind of
shift course enough that he's he misses you and he swoops back up and cries out
because he's just done with your bullshit look sider you gotta way out of here i don't think
we're gonna be able to keep dodging here i'm gonna take i'm gonna take a shot at him if
you don't have anything better going on i mean i think maybe take a shot at him that's a good
idea maybe you can slow him up a little bit um okay well i mean we either we either veer off
to the side where i mean as you can see there's not exactly a lot of tree cover
we're kind of going to be sitting ducks in that one but not much worse than we are right
now uh what okay up ahead um you see there's there's like some some some mist and some spray
up yeah that looks promising yeah that's um well that's the twin falls twin falls two of them
is it's the twin falls i think um i think they're going to be our best bet to to
to get rid of this guy how much did i pay you for this i mean we were going to discuss
price after we were done but needless to say it's uh oh the price is going up all right
buckle up buttercup i'm gonna take one of these special arrows i may have stolen from him and
fire it at him call it a pretty decent bonus that's gonna be a 23 uh you managed to you
don't put it through his wing but you manage to like clip a few feathers and he kind of
pulls up out of the out of the beginning of a dive that he had started and kind of circles
back up and like has this real mean look on his face as he's gonna try another attack oh
shit all right let's paddle buddy i mean we're almost to the falls just like we're gonna get
there in a second i'm gonna roll a d20 here to see if sider's able to help you out in any way
shape or form okay uh not great but he he throws up a minor illusion
and it's it's of a of a net going upwards towards papa zotal from his hands like he's
got some sort of t-shirt cannon and you see papa zotal kind of flinch as this thing is
coming towards him uh there's one thing that that papa zotal can't stand and that's
being subservient to anyone i mean the the inscription in chult in omu for papa zotal is
papa zotal teaches us to bow before no one this is the last thing in the world papa zotal
wants is to be trapped under a net and he kind of flinches and as the net gets closer to
him he kind of shakes his head and realizes that it was an illusion all along and he lets out this
like furious war cry and he's trying to gain speed to get one last shot at you guys before
you tip over the falls roll me a d4 russ all right a d4 a two you're over the cliff you're
over the waterfall you're free falling over the twin falls hold on to your butt sire
and as you hit the water you hit the water in more ways than one
as you're soaked with water and you open your eyes and you're in a jail cell
oh sire what do you get what do we rise and shine what what where's where's sire
look i don't know who that is but you've been here for two days we got to get you
right okay look there's there's the small matter of the fine that you owe
sure yeah no i he reaches down to his pockets and say i don't i don't where's my
back where's my bag i don't know you didn't have a bag when he came in oh shit
okay maybe someone took it in lost and found style maybe yeah what's it look like
it's got this uh brown leather here it's got kind of like a engraving of of a dragon across
it uh it's a little worn was wet last time i saw it soaked down a river yeah i don't uh i don't
remember anything like that being upstairs but uh i'll look for in a minute is this are we in
chult no friend we are so far away from chult it's kind of just dumbfounded as he as he
stands tries to brush himself off but he's just soaked
i mean i didn't throw that much water on you how'd you get so wet
uh i don't know i was in a in a river and
then i was here are you some kind of like dreamwalker
yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
yambol tolgear moot thea and glim that's everybody who said they were going to go
sully's behind so he's the only one who stayed behind um he's got a creep on bomb
he's not being creepy he likes old people not in a weird way every once in a while we'll just
do a cut scene of him telling him a story so just have a story ready that we can continue
at various parts of it okay okay you've made it to the back and Leosin's given you like
these glass vessels that adhere over your head and it's through what seems like magic
adhere themselves to your neck and you go down into this this hold area
and he's looking down at you and says i'm going to close this and you're going to
turn that valve and it's going to flood with water well and then what
and then you're going to open the hatch below you will be able to breathe because of the
vessel on your head for how long 30 minutes oh i've given you each an amulet of speed it
will allow you to move with efficiency and take care of whatever is attached itself aquaman
style swim speed is generally half so it'll give you full speed um so you won't be
hindered in that way were we able to ask Leosin vis-a-vis casting spells uh we can do that
quickly he's about to close the hatch hey if i were to cast a spell would i kill bahamut
it probably wouldn't be good okay and he closes the hatch and you don't do that bye
if you could know what that'd be great uh who opens the valve uh mood does
move you turn the valve and try with your crab claw first and can't quite gain purchase
yeah i can't quite figure it out like properly but then i get the other one involved and
no problem between the two of them you're able to rattle that thing open
oh yeah as you do water begins to fill up from the bottom there's a moment there where
everybody's kind of looking around before it completely covers you this is weird yeah i hate
this i have to pee well you probably can once we're out of here oh yeah no not in here
don't be weird don't pee in here but once we're outside just be fish pee in the in the ocean
one of you reaches down and opens the hatch and you all begin to file out and as you do you
see this huge decaying tentacle wrapped around the vessel crushing it beneath its
hefty weight you back away from the the ship that has slowed its speed
so that you can keep up with it and so that it doesn't take on extra stress and you see
an undead kraken that continues to crush the ship as it turns and looks at you
and lets out this screech towards you release the ship
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 2 Episode 100 Starring Amy More as Thea Amastasia and Sullivan
Sleight Carla Maxted as Yimbel Nuri and Glim Tom Laird as Tulkier Heavyfoot Flint Firebeard
and Moot and Russ More as your Dungeon Master Editing Production and Sound Design by Russ More
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and sound effects from Epidemic Sound
Boom Library and Sound Ideas. A huge thank you to our supporting producers, Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babyok, Kat Waterflame, Stevie, Jacob Madden, Devin Michaels, Christian Brown,
Aaron Stevens, Lou Lehan and Charlie Warley. To support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many
other productions and get access to an exclusive podcast called The Adventures Of,
bonus episodes and much more please join our Patreon at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
You can also follow us at facebook.com slash dumb dragon podcast and on Instagram and Twitter
at dumb dragon cast. Thank you for listening. Have a great week. We'll talk again soon.
It's best to scream after the dog falls asleep. Oh guys, you think we know
this is the time for an accent change, right? A lot has happened.
If the words are I'm back, baby, I'll lose my mind. Eat shit, Orcus.
OK, you're on thin ice. I thought you were making the ducks be undead.
But they can be chased by undead. That's absolutely 100 percent.
Hold on. You're not near me, though. Well, I'm in front of you.
Yeah, he just went to the other side of everybody. I thought you went to like
the boat. The boat. Yeah, that's what I thought, too.
No, I just jumped in front of you guys. That was all.
We're going to figure this all out together, everybody.
Everything's fine. Yeah. Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production.