previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons
so I've got this beautiful amulet and then I've also got this scroll of
detect thoughts what we use that for glim well you know if we have to like
interrogate a bad guy or like we're on the road and somebody drinks my
special organic oat milk yeah yeah I mean I've noticed that it does go
missing for you quite often it wasn't me know so he puts his three
items up on the counter there's the notebook of holding there's the ten
stickers oh you got them scroll of hellish rebuke those Bahamut posters oh
you're right I knew it I knew that's what you were looking at and then I
thought a Roman Roman's like us like where am I gonna put that up so I
could got a bedroom wall or anything but I got some good ideas when I
finally do settle down well and now like as you drift off to sleep at
night you can just like picture each of those amazing images and kind of
like go through the clicky clacker in your brain you know just like
thinking through each of them as you drift off to sleep that's what I do
absolutely and the three of our heroes dream about Bahamut as we fade out on
this episode the weirdest wet dream I ever had
welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More he him
also with me today is Carla Max dead she her I am playing Narcissus Akra
better known as Glim who is also she her and a dragon-born pAlydin and Amy
More she her and I play Sullivan slight also known as Sully he him and
he is a lightfoot halfling rogue and Tom Laird he him and I'm playing moot who
also goes by he him and he is a half-orc wild magic sorcerer how's
everybody doing good we went shopping nice to go shopping I'm exhausted still
from that shopping little retail therapy always feels good I said I
said last week but that's two weeks ago yeah all these timelines are
messing me up shopping episodes darkest time what's happening time jumps
shopping is that Russ that's mine full stop mine and I'm okay with it where
I'm okay with a lot of other decisions is some of our goals over on Patreon
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cats where when we hit a hundred patrons we
do something really we're gonna do something really special super special
what is it Tom and Amy and Carla are gonna DM a game for me well it just
sounds like more work for us finally we're gonna take turns DMing a game
where Russ plays the two main characters one of which being
everyone's favorite pirate goblin flammacons that's me and the other
being everyone's least least favorite pancake chef most favorite
yourself I'm sorry was that Grant's is saying oh go fuck yourself that was
Francis yes I don't think those words are coming I don't think so either
he's been spending too much time with flammacons Francis has been spending a
lot of time down in the abyss their whole boy it's dark timeline down
there darker than what fucking flint and the end
oh boy wow I guess a little I'm here for this version of Grancis you know you're potty
moth Grancis we can expect if we hit that hundred patrons Grancis might be
like I got yeah dirty hairy Clint Eastwood kind of feel to him now
coming up yeah is he too old for this shit maybe he's Danny Glover
it's one week from retirement maybe this week goes on forever though because it
is the abyss but join us over on Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon
cast where when you are a patron you get an episode dedicated to you like
today's patron Dixie lovely like the funnest names lovely like oh that feels
my heart that makes me happy that's a good name thanks Dixie thanks Dixie join
us today Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and now fuck it let's play
glim it's been pretty quiet on most fronts specifically the destiny front
since you've arrived in Gerothamar you pledged your oath you made
contact with Bahama in some way shape or form but not much has happened for you
since it's been relaxing could be a word that you could describe I'm not
gonna say how that makes you feel but you're currently out for a stroll
with Ekef taking in the beautiful day that it is pondering life and what
comes next it's just you know when you're looking forward to something
for so long and then you do it and it's wonderful and it's like everything you
ever could have dreamed and then you can kind of just like just really sit
in that for a while and then you're kind of just ready like what's the
next thing like I have this destiny to save the world and I feel like
Bahamut gave me like two thumbs up and we're good and I'm ready and now
like I told my friends the new next adventure would present itself and you
know it would be obvious but I don't really know what to do like it's
really nice here but I need I guess I'm a goal-oriented person you know
like I train physically and I try and train Bahamut now I need like I need a
task right well yes we've talked at length about the tasks you require
you've cleaned so well you've organized all of the book I mean it was a bit
dusty in there and it's just like it looks yeah I don't want to brag or
anything but it looks you know like it seems like a more used temple now and
I mean it is by me but you know like some others might come I left those
pamphlets at the Zet Mart so I am assuming at any point more more
definitely had some interest which is which is new it's not that it's not
that the turnout has ever been poor but we just Bahamut themselves are one
who doesn't tend to draw too much attention not to say that you're
doing anything wrong I hear it now as I say it that this is what you you
have been doing you've been trying to draw attention to Bahamut which
gratefully appreciated he's just normally like a more chill kind of dude
he's a chill dude yeah chill dude real sit back and relax just let things
be and when when opportunity presents itself then and then it's time to
act as we have discussed many times since you've arrived the book it had
nothing beyond until you pledged your oath and then new writings appeared which
you still say you did not write no right no I mean I wasn't in there like
totally swearing an oath and just like writing I mean I wouldn't do that
religious writing samples too so you like know for sure I know that you
believe me but like just for my own peace of mind I wanted to prove like
that wasn't me no of course glim I totally you know what let's let's enjoy
the day let's spend some time talking about perhaps something something other
than other than your destiny yeah like what are you into you know what I'm
so rude I can't even I get so focused on my own stuff but like I
guess what it what's your story bead work really like necklaces or like
clothing or clothing tapestries weave wool and bead to create intricate
designs and I'd love to see some of that oh well I do have some are you
selling it in the market or just like for your own fun no I donate them oh
for charity work of course and they do tend to fetch quite high prices for
the charities who put them up so I guess that in and of itself raising money for
children and the needy and the star and the starving individuals has been
has been a little a little calling a little artsy calling yeah mine I guess
you could say I do have I could I could show you some of them throughout
throughout Gerard the Mar I am well I'm working on one right now it's it's of
it's of Bahamut's canaries right Wow I would I mean I would be honored if you
would show me some of your work I don't know that many artists let's go
take a look and after the day maybe we'll go we'll go take another
look through the book and and just see if we miss something the last 75
times we've been through it okay sounds great the two of you walk off back to
go peruse some of ekif's artwork throughout Gerard the Mar as you're
walking through the the merchants floor you pass by a new buffet and you
don't pay too much attention to it but the camera stops and inside is
moot he is one of the first people to sample this new buffet the sign
which is lit up with brilliant color lights and fireworks went off for the
grand opening moot was invited because of his his excellent reviews of all of
these buffets and he was invited personally by sir schlaps delicious sounds
appetizing I hope that's not the name of the restaurant is it or is that the owner I'm
gonna need you to spell out schlaps for me or s ch l o p s I want to know if I'm
right sh l o p s schlaps delicious kind of onomatopoeic yeah sir schlaps comes
out to your table and he comes up to you and he says so is everything to
so far I see that you're sampling the blub the blubber baked barnacles they are
what I was most excited about at first I was not intrigued by them when I when
I read the placard in front of the dish I will be honest with you but
yes after trying them they are much better than I thought they would be oh
good good to hear I can't that is from from you that is quite the review you
are a hard hard man to please in the buffet field well just some of them you
know you go and then half the dishes that were there last time that you
really enjoyed aren't there or they haven't got enough of them and they
go out so fast and then there's not enough plates because you want to go
up a few times and it's just it's a whole thing and but you know you're
doing it right here sir schlaps thank you so much you know you've sampled most
of the things on on on the table here you've got the celebratory goat stew for
our grand opening delicious the goat and quail egg omelette a little bit of
a goat theme going on here the roasted tarantula what did you think of
those very crispy very tasty where'd you get goat eggs goat and quail egg
that's what I said uh-huh where'd you get the goat egg goat and quail egg yeah
so like ham and egg I'm making it I'm making a joke Amy I don't know if you
understand how omelets work so let me break it down I know you need a lot of
eggs Carla I'm wonder where the goat eggs came from as someone who had
omelets daily when he was in Mexico for two weeks last year at this time
top-notch beautiful beautiful sorry the roasted tarantula what did you
think of those oh so crispy and you know I thought the the legs would be
off-putting but really just added to the crunch factor very tasty it was a
delicacy I came across I'm not certain the city name but they also sold
potatoes oh I've been there you have I have let me just flip through my
notebook to find out where that was oh well while you do that I'm just
gonna run back and get something really quick here if only I had a
service to transcribe my old notebooks into my new endless notebook that way
the information would be instantly where I wanted it do you not get the joy
though of rewriting your notes were you guys not those students no I hated
rewriting my notes it helped me learn but I hate them all shitty in class
yeah and I get my good colorful pens out and I'd make them perfect me
okay we're the same person because we're cool right totally cool I'm gonna go
back and get you something that's off off menu here I'm just I'm trying it
out it's the squeaver chili served with a
cool glass of the Holstein milk okay um that sounds like a thing that you
just said yeah I'm not even gonna just I'm just gonna I'm gonna wait
and you're just gonna love it you're gonna love it I will explain it once I
come back he runs off into the back I'm sorry Holstein milk be Holstein
we'll explain it when we come back I don't think okay
Sullivan slight you didn't quite realize exactly how on edge you've
been until you stop needing to worry about the cult finding you or just
being in the general vicinity of cult faces you've kept watch frequently on
the Church of Tiamat and no one save for a cleaning crew really has been
coming or going and mostly the cleaning crew is coming and going because of
the things that you keep writing on the door being the most carefree
you've been in a long time and having found some perhaps different or
new direction what has Sully been doing with his days because Sully has pretty
much been preoccupied with the cult of the dragon since forever and since he
doesn't have to look over his shoulder here I think he's he's taken
those pamphlets and he is going to these he is going to edumacate himself
and learn how to use the staff of the adder so looking staff it is it's a
delightful looking staff and it looks like it holds a lot of power now you
were handed you were handed pamphlets for different schools that you could go
or different people that you could see one was more of a religious path
taking you down a path of a cleric another led you towards a more earthy
druid and the other towards a warlock which on on surface doesn't seem quite
as upfront as the other two paths a little more of a dark flavor to it
it's very the the candles are lit that emit a black light as you walk in well
are the Sanderson sisters gonna come maybe I don't know I feel like I should
know the reference but I don't a virgin lights the black flame candle
from Sanderson sisters from Hocus Pocus thank you I saw you smile Carla
that was for you Hocus Pocus to coming to Disney Plus sometime in the near
future I know I'm I'm so torn about it we're not talking about it so I guess
you're looking at those pamphlets where does Sully go first or where has Sully
been and what is catching his eye I think Sully has already been to the
clerics so who is it that you're devout to well I'm you know I'm just I'm kind
of looking around and just kind of sussing out there's a very rotund dwarf
in front of you he's graying he's got the hair like the Picard hair but
it's like sticking straight out a little more Danny DeVito a little more
Danny yep there's a Danny DeVito with a long beard in front of you oh god hey
who you devout to oh I don't know I'm just kind of you know well I who you
devout to I devout to payload who's that payloads the god of Sun and
summer he's the keeper at time okay go on okay he supports those in need
opposes all that is evil his lord of the agriculture and the bound to
full harvest what more do you need to know have I not sold yet bada bing is
he like best friends with Bahamut ah there they I'm sure they go get a little
coffee here and there I mean they have very similar similar ideologies
that come across cool cool cool all right well I already have one of
those people who talks me about Bahamut all the time okay so I'm
gonna have to pass okay so you're looking for more of a general opposite
you're looking for like a god of something not good a god of pain like
a god of like war no I'm not I think I'm just not looking for a god at all
oh well what do you do okay well what how can I convince you so he starts to
slowly it looks like you're trying to work a few different angles here what
man I'm just looking to learn then I don't be gold in a party what are you
bribing me to join your cult go payload wouldn't do that this is
weird I'm leaving but I might bye he scurries out of there
energy was way too much for me I think he wants to go next to the druid you
enter into actually you have to leave the main pyramid you have to go into
the forest and you enter nope Sully doesn't want to do it Sully goes
wanted to get a description of it you know okay I don't think Sully would
leave the pyramid and go into a forest by himself okay he gets kidnapped in
forests and in town you know what in large public spaces feels pretty safe
going out there in the wide wide world just ain't gonna ain't gonna do
it so he's gonna go to the warlock because he's too scared to go into
okay the door opens and there is a woman she's how tall is Sully five nope no
that's how tall Amy is three foot five okay so we so we so we you enter and
like I said it's a it's a dark office and there's paintings on the walls not
of anything in particular just like abstract art is what it looks like just
surface value that's what it kind of looks like and there's like glowing
paints that you see kind of spread all around black light in here
somewhere yeah there's black candles lit I've already said that oh so we
skipped around yeah yeah but yeah there's black candles lit that
illuminate some of the the iridescent paintings during raving in the corner
there's nobody immediately as you walk in stepping out from a back room is an
older woman she's only probably about a foot foot and a half taller than you
are she's very very slim she has like red and yellow clothing there's
almost like this gray you could confuse it for smoke but it's like
around like her her figure and she says yes can I help you sir
oh yeah my name is Sullivan slight and and and you are Andresa it's it's it's
very nice to make your acquaintance I am searching for a kind of a mentor a
little bit to help me with some learning oh okay and you've come here
because you are called by unknown voices what no you have an affinity for
magic I wouldn't say it's an affinity kind of like any pulls out from
behind them the staff and was like why got this stick okay I just just since
we just said Sully's height I'm wondering is the staff on his back
always like four feet above his head yeah no one knows and Victoria didn't
didn't dispute it Victoria beautiful person let me get away with shit okay oh
yes yes so yeah I got this the staff of the Adda might I see it while you
explain sure yeah I know funny business now of course do you know what it can
do got one of those stickers on there if you put a sticker on it when it
automatically hurt her I was just thinking if she like tried to swipe
it but never mind well no it is only swiping stuff isn't it it's not if you
have something that has a stick yeah no it's okay well there's there's a
sticker on the very bottom she did serve she did succeed the check
though so she's yeah yeah no funny business though because I'm I have no
idea what this thing does I would really like to learn about she taps
it on the ground and suddenly the head is a black snake that is identical
to the head of the carved snake that you saw previously and it like jumps out
at you oh Sullivan like jumps back and falls on his ass and then does like
like a crab walk backwards Jesus you wanna guide first you look back and it
like moves to her and then moves back into position and then locks back
into place as a wooden staff that's terrifying this is a very powerful
piece of equipment you have I couldn't I now see that what a weird gift for
someone to give me and you say you wish to control it well yeah cuz I mean
otherwise I just have a giant stick I'm hitting people with it's just uh
do you find yourself constantly in search of the answers to secrets
looking deeper into unknown like like how I don't know how to use this staff
that could be thinking there might not be a deeper level this very surface
like what do you mean like you constantly are searching for the
knowledge of what makes our world turn well that that's like I mean that's a
real big question I don't think you get anything done in your day if you
if you if you if you have you thought about that all the time have you
thought about what is beyond what we can comprehend but you know what there's
a lot I don't comprehend sometimes so you seem like a clean slate you know
what that's uh that's probably the nicest way someone's ever put it if you
wish to control this staff Sully it was yes I yes we do have an opening
an opening for a student to specifically learn about this staff or
to search for all the mysteries in the world well one is hand-in-hand with the
other you must learn you must you must learn how to harness magic you can't
just create and she snaps the staff on the ground again and the snake comes
back it doesn't jump out at you or anything it just begins to move what do
you wish to gain from this I would like to use it in a in what in battle
okay I can do that for you I feel like though that you're asking for a lot
more because it's not just gonna be like where does your training lie you
seem some like someone who knows something about the world you seem like
someone who has certain level of knowledge I see behind your eyes there
is a a wanting for knowledge and escape from fear what what I mean doesn't
everybody want to escape from the fears maybe not everybody walks through
these doors though well I see you got I got this pamphlet here mm-hmm so of
course just you know it this seems real like religious to like you like
follow any specific kind of God not in and of itself no power comes from
beings or places beyond our comprehension those aren't necessarily
though it's like so heavy for Sully right now I'm debating between going to
the dark side and being like okay thanks you really gave me something to
think about taking the staff back bringing it over to Zed Martin being
like give me 20 bucks I mean maybe the maybe the dude at Zed Mart will
want to swap you for something straight up if you want to think on
it we can come back yeah let's come back there's a Sully's in a quandary
he's he doesn't know what to do
welcome to the middle this is the place where all the things are told oh
it's getting kind of spooky in here yeah it's a real like ghost of Christmas
present vibe going on here right yeah four told seven years ago
ghost of Abraham Lincoln I'm not sure what's I'm not sure what's happening
yeah all right ah whoo hey we have friends we do yeah and we
want you to go listen to them because they put on really amazing shows as
well one of those shows is from a good dear friend of ours Travis Van Grof and
Caitlin stats who we met yes in person when you could meet people in
person yeah back in the olden times a time loved it
Travis and his lovely wife Caitlin make this show called Dark Dice among
others but Dark Dice is a a highly edited Dumbgeons and Dragons actual play
audio drama and he takes a lot of time making sure that the soundscape is just
perfect not just me blowing into a microphone and edits down the the
combat section so it's it's succinct and action-filled and climactic and
it's dark like it's scary and not a show for Carla no I can't even listen cuz
it's too scary I'm sure it's very good though I've heard nothing but good
things I know someone guys I know someone who's on that show who really
who his name is Russ More he heard of him that loser oh god I will not
have you saying anything bad about rest do not disparage our friend
Russ More hey this is the one time it's going in my favor all right yes
yeah season two so they just wrapped season one and season two I'm a part of
it I don't know how much I'm allowed to say probably not what is just that
maybe that's too much already but I play character and then we get into
crazy and you got gonna believe what happens when we get to beep so look
forward to that in season two but catch up on season one before that happens do
that good call and then before or after you listen to that come join us
in the reckless play guild over on Facebook our link is down in the
description it's our Facebook group over there that we share with dark
dice the lucky die the end of time another bothers and it's a great
community where you can share and talk about the shows and we'd love to see
you over there after you listen to Dark Dice or before or at the same time
multitask do it phones are magic they can do all these things at once it's
true I didn't mean to explain how phones work to you I'm sorry it lets
you back to the episode there it was Russ phonesplaining again yeah you know
me big phonesplainer okay bye everybody
moot sir schlops comes back out with the dish that he now it's his name is sir
schlops not the restaurant is and he's not sir schlop and then it's an
apostrophe s but he is sir schlops sir schlops the restaurant is sir
schlops with an apostrophe after okay sir schlops is yep there's no
extra s but yes yeah he says this is the squeaver chili served with a cool
glass of beholstein milk have you had such a thing now I've had milk before
but usually cow sometimes almond what exactly is this milk again it was the
beholstein milk it's a truly a special prize of dairy farms across
the realms as its back half is separated from the useful bit so
fertilizer can go directly where it needs to walk me through this again the
beholstein is truly a special prize of dairy farms across the realm as its
back half is separated from the useful bit so I didn't just me again with
the same info I meant you know some more info about it oh well this is
what they told me at cook culinary school it's a it's supposed to be it's
very tasty okay I mean I'll give it a shot please do the squeaver do you
didn't even ask about the squeaver that wasn't the the concerning part of
the dish okay I think it should be no I give it a try you taste it let's let's
roll something sure we haven't rolled for taste before for flavor town for
flavor what are we thinking the way you like something is not gonna be
perceptions give it is gonna be fall under my insight or it could be I guess
just survival it could be survival it could be like a like persuasion well
you want yeah yeah it could be persuasion how based on how the
flavors come I said flavors if you're the chef in ratatouille or not the
chef the critic in ratatouille then you roll for history sure yeah but
that's quite specific yeah am I the critic from ratatouille are you that's
a personal question only you can answer we haven't clarified it yet hasn't come
up I think I am all right well whatever whatever we decide here it's
either I think we say persuasion or history okay yeah sure let's let's go
persuasion I'm good with that then any time we need to check flavor town
we're gonna go persuasion for future roles okay 12 for persuasion it's an
okay not great it feels like it's a dish that has a lot of potential it
has it's like one of those dishes that is like either grows on you or
it's one that you just like instantly it's not one that's bad but it's one
that I think this one's a grower instead of a shower exactly the
whole steam well sir sir schlaps it's um I think you're I think you're on the
right track here but I think it just needs a little fine-tuning in the long
run oh yes do you have any suggestions well I don't really know if the milk
goes with it too well to be perfectly honest with you yes and I was
concerned about that when they when the salesman gave me the description of it
he really sold it up the back half separated from its useful bits
fertilizer to us directly when it's just it's just a song and dance that
just swept me away sure and I get that a confusing song and dance yeah I
understand yeah I think just a little hmm little longer with the braising
time and not not the milk get get rid of the milk well the squeaver is a tough
meat so yes I could I could see that and then remove the milk give some
bring something different in perhaps not dairy perhaps some acidity that's
perhaps something there was a little bit of just a little bite to it might
cut through a little bit more could do well please help yourself to
anything else you desire we're going to be letting in the letting in the
general public now if you you know hopefully you've enjoyed most parts
this one of course not a regular menu item you're free to mention it if you
desire in your review but I look forward to seeing what you write for
us I look forward to seeing what I write for you too it's always nice to
go home and like think about this for a little while before you really
before you really jot down your thoughts all over the flavors that the
whole experience I hope the ambiance was quite right for you
oh delightful I love that everyone eats out of a trough that is just a
delightful twist on the buffet I thought that you know you know why
why with the formalities of plates and cutlery just go straight to it
exactly the useful bits are separated so that the fertilizer is closer to
where it needs I can't even remember what it was supposed to be but it's
just all well together like it really works with the merch that you're
selling with the schlopping it up I think it's perfect you've really tapped
into the essence of sir schlops I'm gonna think about this yeah I look
forward to your review have a good day of course the entire thing is is
covered we'll see you next time hopefully I would I would have to
think I would be back bring your friends it'll be great he clears some
of your dishes and walks back into the kitchen
moot raids the dessert table on his way out yes and he's like gets a hose and
just sprays out the trough everything about this I feel like up Holstein
because I'm like because at first I was like I'm pretty sure a Holstein
it's a bill Holstein be I know but listen where I'm going with this
this is downtime talk remind me yeah no it's fine yeah you hit up the
dessert table there's a pound cake with sugary lemon drizzle there's
chocolate zucchini cakes coated in powdered sugar and crowned of
strawberries there's a friend Japan style baked
custard and Japan and Japan there's a French a panty style baked custard that
uses flour from exotic faraway seeds mood just helps himself to the lemon
meringue pie and just takes the whole thing and then you you take the
thing and then you walk by and then you see the yurt and breath massive bowl of
dark rye bread enriched with bone meal resulting in a beefy slightly crunchy
bread catches your eye does it I'll be back for you next time bread bone meal
in it very hearty right helps plants it does helps moots grow too I guess
yeah well I need all the help I can get after shrinking six inches strange off
beat remedy yeah the door opens to the citadel and ekif and glim you enter it
says well that's all the pieces that I've throughout the pyramid the
entire I think you've seen most of the pyramid today you know what it
was seeing your work was unbelievable and then I felt like yeah I had this
guided tour of all these like fancy offices of people who have all this
money and like bought your pieces to as a tax write-off for charity or like
I don't really know how that works something we don't yeah we don't talk
about that something like that but oh my goodness the one of Tiamat like
nope that's a different guy was surprising and upsetting she was
cowering she was cowering in a corner next to the absolute might of her
brother Bahamut and then Bahamut over top and then there's a rainbow and
there was a cloud and lightning and it was just like you could you could
feel the force of the battle but the beauty of the peace afterwards with
the rainbow and just that you captured that in this like tapestry beadwork was
it I've never I mean I cried I've never it was so powerful it brings a
tear to my eye to hear you describe it in such a beautiful way thank you
thank you I've forgotten entirely what we're doing here oh the book right
we were gonna look at the book again and see if it gives like I've really
been looking for a like glim next you need to but you know we've looked a lot
of times and there isn't really anything that clear maybe so maybe you
could help with like some subtext in the new writing right it's a period and
like that would would help point me in my next direction right yes come
have a seat he you seat and he brings the book over and he begins flipping
through and says well we've been through of course the beginnings of the
world and everything we can skip over some of this because really it's
there's not much subtext in creation of things and beings and
other other deities and let's get more to the end here and he flips to
the page that you had seen written the inscription you know protect your
friends protect your people save the world or however it was phrased and
then he he flips a couple pages and again all blank right to the end there
and then he flips back and as he's flipping back into some of the text you
catch sight of a new inscription appearing as he's kind of quickly
flipping past ask if wait wait wait I think I I think I saw something in
there oh oh sorry sorry he flips back a few pages to the final page of entry
and I think I think you're right and by the time he gets back to that page
there's a full inscription there it is in larger printing than anything
proceeding it the first line states saviors missing realms tearing apart
seek your start in hard castle echo speaks up is a hard castle isn't our
castles 300 miles away give or take it's not in the big picture not as
far as you traveled to get here by any stretch what does that mean saviors
missing if you're destined to save the world you're right here how could that
what what could that mean well I mean I'm probably not the only one right I
know that my friends are gonna help me but I didn't think like
single-handedly I mean maybe I did a little bit like between you and me
I think I did kind of maybe think like maybe kind of single-handedly not
single-handedly but like me and my friends you know maybe but that's
probably that's I'm probably getting a bit big for my britches there right
yes no it's good good not to get too ahead of ourselves isn't Vahmet
amazing like I said I wanted clear instructions and here is at least a
start and now like I at least I we need to go to hard castle Wow every
day I've just reminded about his greatness you know it's truly amazing
nothing written until a few weeks ago when you showed up and then now he's
like sending us messages basically this appears to be a way that he he's
speaking with you he folds up the book waits a moment to see if anything
else appears but after nothing does he folds up the book and he props it
in his lap and then moves it over to your lap I think this is better served
with you especially if you're leaving do you but don't you need it for no I
mean it's the book it's the one book it's the one book I have read it
several times within the past week alone I have it entirely memorized I
will spend my days transcribing what I know from the first portion and then
hopefully when our paths cross again I will be to be able to expand upon it
with anything new that has appeared for you well wow I don't know what to
say I mean this is you're just you're just filling my heart to
bursting basically you are truly amazing well thanks thanks for
everything I know I can be a bit hard to take sometimes not at all you have a
massive heart well I guess I've got to talk to my friends first but we'll
probably head to Hardcastle now that we know where we need to go next so
um I hopefully I'll see you again before I go but if I don't thanks
thanks for everything thank you be safe as the book says
take care of yourself and your friends and I'm gonna give him a hug and then
probably doesn't really want it but I'm giving it except it this is a soft
pat with one arm and I'm gonna go tell my friends about stage two of our
destiny this time it's personal see a walk in back into his chamber which
is another room just off off the main room and he comes out with a large
blank book he sits it on the table and he begins writing
the song long road ahead is by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io all
other music and sound effects can be found at epidemicsound.com or
boomlibrary.com a huge thank you to our supporting producers Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babyok, Mark Hartless, Jack Green, Stevie, Kat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown, Darylith, Devin Michaels, Aaron Stevens, and Ray Surbeck to
find out more about how you can support Dumbgeons and Dragons visit us
at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where you can have exclusive access to
50 plus hours of bonus audio content create in-game NPCs and items as well
as play games with the cast Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast have a great
week and we'll talk soon.
it was it was around it was right before the Rick and Morty episodes yeah we
were doing odd jobs there I'll see if I can find it Tom because I'm sure I
probably have potatoes written in giant letters that's okay we can go on
that's what I was looking for too and I couldn't find it anywhere okay
we'll go on to Sully here well was it previous weekend at Strahd's or
after weekend at Strahd's after weekend at Strahd's okay that was that was last
Halloween like a year ago Halloween I don't know time man Sullivan's light
attending the night garden I'm getting closer pay lords the god of I think he's
the god of light it's on the tip of your tongue let's see if I wrote it down
it's always a fun game to play when you're DM something about bone meal
bread I'm not sure a lot of weird recipes in here but yeah um not the
inscription I was looking for Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons
production