previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons
We got a commandeer Karen's boat
And that's what we use so first thing
Defeating the ferryman of the dead right defeat or persuade or persuade and if we look like we're dead
Even more of a reason
Right sure Ron's not gonna be like I don't know about these dead guys. No, they're just dead guys go
Yeah, I mean I complain or shift but
Can only do that one or maybe
We save that
Yes, I just wonder what can I hit with my ex while I am down there is there anything special that I can prepare for
tons what lives under the ice in the moat lives under the ice I could hear it yeah, I
Could hear it down in the prison imagine a multi-eyed multi-tentacled monster that can speaks inside your head, but is undead
so does
But still maintains the power it had beforehand is there something in your book that might
Answer some of these questions grants. Oh, yeah books full of all this great stuff if you look at the map here
It's got this little pinging beacon looks like it's at the Museum of Greenest. I think we're gonna have to go get his book
Let's do it
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. I'm your dungeon master rust more he him also with me today's Tom Laird
Yeah, he him and I am playing a flint fire beard and Carla max day
She her playing lip-synchy pip Diggins also she her and Amy More
Yeah, she her playing guy. I'll night hunter ogla. Can you see they and the amistacia?
She her and Kyle class it. Hey, what's up? He him gonna be playing Vorunax also he him welcome everybody
We're here for a caper. We gotta get a book back. Uh-huh. I love capers love a caper
We went from all talking to all action in this episode. That's all planning to know planning
That's right
And that's what you can do when you head to Patreon.com
Slash dumb dragon cast is just jump into the action because we got episodes on episodes on episodes over there, right?
Yes, that's right. Yep. Love the positive affirmation. Yeah, you also get an episode dedicated to you dedicated
To you dedicated to you like today's patron Cory booth
Thank you, Cory and you can join us too and be like Cory and it could be you to Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
Fuck it. Let's play
We got the book back end of episode
Great caper guys. Yeah fantastic Russell just post he'll put the rest in in post
Chopped together all of our words here. Let me set the scene. We're all
sitting around a table at
an
nondescript
You know tavern. Yeah in
Greenest. Mm-hmm, and we just finished
Planning our
infiltration of
orcas's lair
at least in preliminary planning and
we realized that
Big part of it has to do with them with grants
This is a book because otherwise he's useless to have around so we should probably go get grants. This is book
Yep, and he said there's a beacon on it. It's at the greenest library. So god
do we have to walk around with this enormous map like
tourist losers
Through the streets of greenest just like we just hire a really good docent. Yeah, it is a museum. So we'll be good
That's about as far as we can get with it as far as we can go, but that's pretty far we're ready
yeah, I think we rolled up the map because the map was mostly of
orcas's lair with I guess like an inset of
The greenest yeah, yeah, yeah for some reason it's really just a bar napkin and I'm just drawing yeah
Well, Grancis says I can just summon my book
What a caper we did it yeah, I mean that saved a lot of time and effort we figured it out
Episode we've solved it twice. Mm-hmm
Grancis can actually summon his book. Yeah. Yeah
It turns it flew right to him. He he was all like
Could just like in hocus pocus and just flew right to him. Sure. Yeah. Okay. Well, you've solved my book
Or Amy really did set the scene we're in the pub we're in greenest we've rolled up our map
We're ready to head to the library and by library. I mean museum
We're gonna stop at the library on the way to the museum you arrive at the library realize you're not supposed to be there
Lipstick he got a bit confused his library book. I mean it kind of made sense, but that's right smart people places
It is just a book that he's gonna check out from the library
Like it's actually not his book specifically and the little slip in it is just Grancis over and over and over and over again
The real challenge is that he has an enormous fine to pay but no money
So we're going to have to figure out how to get the librarian to give him the book
Yeah, that'd be great or whatever Russ has planned
Yes
That's totally fine you find yourselves in the greenest museum there is a
What are they called
Exhibit is the word. There's an exhibit on the red dragon attack that was stopped by
via a new Lara
There are very smaller exhibits one put on by Julie's doilies and
Vorunax you see one off into the distance. What's that one?
It's an exhibit of the construction of this museum
Meant solely to house the heroic deeds that have gone on around the land
You see all of these and they're all very intricate and then the middle of this massive chain
You could call it a chamber or a ballroom or some sort of large
exhibit space
where there is
very bare floors just
Nondescript tapestries of greenest and their various insignias on the walls
But there is a pedestal and this green in this glass case that's surrounding the entire
Pedestal and hovering in on this pedestal is this old
rickety
Torn-up leather book dang it. I could have said it's an exhibit with the book instead of it being in this thing
I thought it was gonna be antique spoons. So that would have been good, too
And the seven of you have entered this chamber and are standing looking at this glass case with this book
Inside and grants this pipes up and says well
There it is
Show them your ID tell them to give them give your book back
Yeah, is your is your name in the front cover, can you just say actually that's mine
I donated it to the museum, but I'd like to take it back just for a short while. Oh, that's probably a good idea
Who is it?
Who do you think we should talk to about that? Is there a docent nearby?
Curators excuse me. Excuse me you you you there. Yes. Yes. Yes kinds kind sir
That is my book
Which book the oh, sorry
The book in the middle of the big chamber with the big spotlight on it the glass
I know the book you're referring to do not touch tablet. Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm
the the commemorative plaque that says this was a
Book by the leader of the decimator of dragons who perished on the way to the well of the dragons
Ah, yes that plaque that book, of course. Oh, well, I'm I'm him. Oh, well, we were told he died
several times several times right everybody
Nope, you're alive. This is the only you keep this guy down. Can't stop won't stop
Never stop never stop and I live live life all the way to the fullest
Let's it's interesting cuz we were given the book after you died
Yeah, and now you would like it back. Well, yeah, cuz I I am NOT dead anymore. Oh
Okay
What do you what do you need as proof? I could I could give you my name
Grancis
Thor
Thrandor Ashton, well my good friend that just sounds like you're making that up on the spot and and what is your name?
Hopefully, you don't make it up on the spot Mortimer Jones that sounds like a pretty pretty solid name
Like the name of someone that would work at a museum sounds like he knew his name
Well, so you've got a name I've got a name and that's my book what can we do I got
He pulls his pockets up. I don't have any money. Well, I don't think you have to purchase something that is yours
true
Okay, what do you need Mortimer? Well, we do have a
more of a
Finders Keepers rule here at the museum
Hmm, the Finders Keepers of the the the Royal Museums of Faerun. I get it. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I'm glad you're you're familiar
Hi, I guess a written
affidavit from
some sort of
Royalty or maybe the mayor of Greenest? Oh
the mayor of Greenest
Hey, you you you folks know the greenest folks, right? Vorunax looks at himself says yes. Yeah
What do you mean the greenest folk like everybody? Yeah, cuz you see you you were the you saved
With the dragon, right? Wait a minute Mortimer. Don't you recognize?
You know, it's all starting and he like points to a giant tapestry that's on the wall behind him says that's
That's you
You're thea
Yes, and Flint look he's got he's shiny now and and and Flint's here too and why they are
Heroes, I would not have recognized him. The beard is the same but the rest is all very different
So does that change your mind it actually yes, it does
If and he's the leader of the Decimator of Dragons
So I am the leader of the Decimator of Dragons Grancis Threnn Threnn door
I'm gonna go leave a note for my manager
Explain what has happened. And yes, you can you can have the book. Okay, great
But I will ask when you're done with it if you could please bring it back
mmm
Like when you die again, you know when I die again sure or just if you no longer need it for your adventures or whatever
You've got going on
Yeah, okay. Yeah, you go write your note. We'll just hang out here and wait for you to come back with the key
Oh, I won't be back. Here's the key. Oh, all right Grancis. Don't worry. Okay Mortimer
So instead of leaving the note
You go you get the key and if you don't the fiery hells of orcas will be upon your
Doorstep before you know it in the waves of undead that'll lash out upon you are going to end your life
Well, calm down man. He'll forget
That was that was a pretty good one though
Pay him the big bucks down there, isn't it? I
Kind of notice I'm grabbing onto Mortimer's
Shirt, and I'm just like, oh, sorry and kind of wipe it off and step back
That's quite. All right. Yeah, you got taken by some madness there for a moment. Quite. All right, friend
I'm gonna give the key to to Thea
Personal this no
Yeah, good choice, yeah, okay, I am I'm gonna go write that note and
Best of luck with whatever you're up to. Oh seems legit. Thank you. Thank you. So we're good to take it now
Yes. Yes. I don't see why not. Well, there's 16
There's looks like a school of children who are strolling through. Maybe I should go surprise them now. Hey, it's my book
I do not think getting children is a good idea. He's already
Thank you
What it's quite a little little sashay that grants. Yeah, he's like he's like sneaking
Oh
Kids Miss Hannigan, who's that old man? Don't worry. Why are you hiding behind? What are you doing?
Oh, I'm smell like cheese
Why do you sound like a ghost?
An old man old men smell like cheese and ghosts. My grandpa doesn't smell like an old man cheese ghost
I've never smelled a ghost smell. Well, you can smell me. You're smelling the ghost
I feel is inappropriate again. There's a ghost over here. I know it's not again appropriate
No, I'm stinky cheese man here. I'm I'm grants is I'm the book owner this book
You were learning about who cares because you love
Education cuz your children this big book looks boring. I'm here for the book and the world that book's so ugly
Why don't you take better care of your stuff? It's all wrecked and ruined and
Would have done it in really colorful inks when I would have dirt dotted all my eyes with hearts and
stars
Our stars I like making an s out of three lines and then some diagonal lines. It looks super cool
Yeah, well those all sound like great suggestions, but when you're living on an airship and only have only have grease pencils
to write with
This is what you end up with kid, are you stealing from the museum?
No, they gave my friend the key. Where did they go? I saw your friend threaten that guy with his life
Oh, he wasn't threatened by the shirt. No, that's scary. That's what adults do
sometimes as they grab each other by the collar and they
Grabbed anyone by the collar miss Hannigan has anybody grab you grabbed anybody by the collar? No, Sonny
I would never yeah, Miss Hannigan is a big fat liar. I'm gonna tell my dad is captain of the guard
Oh, that's gonna be awkward. Oh, yeah, my dad's a mayor. So we'll grab you by your shirt
Your dad's a mayor. Oh, well, you should tell them that the decimators the Dragons are back
The who the book look at the read the plaque miss Hannigan
We haven't gotten that in history yet. When do we talk about them? Oh not for a while yet
Sonny the plaque is really high. Okay, miss Hannigan read them the plaque
I won't be doing that
Okay, I will read them the plan. In fact, if you could please leave the children alone
No, well, I've come to comment here the book
But the plaque says this book was owned by the leader of the decimator of dragons
I mean everyone else has left the friend or Ashton
He was the bravest soul ever known
To have lived and the kindest one who made the best pancakes
Well, I do like pancakes, but that waffles bro, I want to see the fossils
Waffles ain't good shit on pancake. We're looking at a fossil. I said
fossils
Miss Hannigan, he said the f-word
He's saying swears. No, it's just that's just my old man voice. Everything's
inappropriate
It was really just uck. All right, dearie time to move along leave the kids alone. Oh, well, no, but okay
Hey everybody, I
Didn't get the book. I didn't actually have the key you had the key
Yes, you ran ahead and wanted to harass the school
I didn't want to harass, I was trying to educate
Did you know I was a teacher?
You set the effort in front of the children. Right to their faces. You slipped
I've been in the abyss for a long time. Even I wouldn't do that. That's messed up
They called you out for grabbing a shirt
Me I say one word. Well words can hit deeper than fists. That's the bone
Okay. Well round two, how about I just go up and I don't talk to anybody and I just take the book
Yeah, I mean you've got a key. So maybe just yeah
Fanfare about it though, if that's all right, I'm just gonna well, okay
I mean, I guess that's fine. I mean we sure we've been given a key told we can take it but
Who's to say it isn't guarded and other means and then we get made out as thieves by the person whose life
I just threatened which sorry about that again
Well, I mean he did go write a note
Which could be code for I'm going to get the city guard. So we should probably
It's let's let's speed this whole thing up something no one has ever said before good call grants us
All right, we'll go you got the key I see I runs up and
Unlocks
The case and waits for an alarm. Nothing comes with the key lifts the lid waits for an alarm
There is an alarm that sounds
Takes the book and just nonchAlydintly puts it under
Was that the gates wait around me or just to the room just to the room. Okay, cool
You guys go on without me someone will have to I'll hold the pages up
Someone else is gonna have to transcribe just we will just rewrite this book one page at a time. You hear
heavy armored footsteps coming into the building
Led by Mortimer Mortimer, what the fuck is this them?
They're Mortimer is this the ones that said they're gonna steal your book
They don't look like the decimators of dragons
Well now that that's the over there she's one. Oh, that's the other area. That's what they all say says
I'm a see you're a thea that's a flint that one's covered in scales. He doesn't even look like a dwarf
I've been decimated by them. Oh wait, you're talking about the other one in scales
Well, yeah what you've been decimated by them?
That seems like something a little personal something that you might not want to share with the city guard
But that's fine, too. So, you know, they're good people. I have ID and and she she looks exactly like
That I mean that's her. Do you see the blue hair?
Well, they got the guys yeah, they got them the body modifications they could explain that I lift out
Donnie I'm like Donnie wake up. Can you hey? Oh, yeah. Hey
Hey, why are we in a square box? Well?
mistakes were made again
Always ending up in a square box
What's the deal? Why do you need me? Well, I was dreaming of the crackers that we don't have
Listen, I'll get more. Sorry. We're in a thing right now
these people don't believe that we're the decimator two-thirds of the decimators of
For two three
fifths of the decimators of the dragons three
Well, if I'm counting you I'm also gonna count. Yeah. Oh, of course. Yeah, okay. Yeah, cool
Okay, so we want me to do I don't know tell them bite them. I'm not sure
They are the decimators of dragons. Oh, you think they're gonna listen to a little talking dragon there, do ya?
And would you say this one any points to grant sis is the leader of the decimators of dragons?
This one's the leader of the decimators of dragons. They described grant sis Ashton grant sis Trandor Ashton is someone of big muscle and higher
Personality. Oh god grant sis. Did you write that yourself? Well, I did have letters prepared with Leosin
before my death that all of my
Earthly belongings would be shrined and heralded
By everyone to the name of the last group that I was known to be with Wow
Just to cover my bases, so that's why the plaque with the book was so so
accurate and effusive about what an amazing man
Could you write it could because I had a hand. I mean he polished up the word the phrasing. I've got a question
Where in this stupid museum? Do you have something dedicated to new Lara? Hmm?
Well, that's a six bays over there closer to
Closer to the front of the building there. Yes. It's one of the ones that you just most people don't notice when they even walk in
You guys I'm mad she looks to her spell this I
Mean Johnny's mad too. All right, I bet Johnny's mad Johnny get no
Okay
Okay, here I go
This isn't this isn't Donnie's voice Donnie apothecary. Yeah, there we go. We found him again. All right. Yeah
Well, okay, I'm gonna go sting him. I haven't stung anybody in a little while. No, just bite him. All right, here it comes, sir
This is not this is more for them than it is for me. I
Sustained myself on crackers. It's also for new Lara. God rest her soul wherever she is captured
That's a 14. Oh
He's got hard arm
There was my teeth on his nothing not not him Donnie the the little guy called the cops on us
Oh fighting a guy with armor use your head. Excuse me, tiny sir. That's a natural one
I have shimmy through these bars only to disgrace myself in the face of you all it's really unacceptable
It's been a while hasn't it do I put the cuffs on me, sir?
We don't have any cuffs for tiny dragons. Just cut just come back Donnie. Okay
Listen, what could we do to prove that? We are the decimators of dragons. This is grants us
He is not the leader of the decimator of dragons. We are a
We are a collective
Okay, what can they do Russ? What can they do? Oh, what can they do their Mortimer? Well, they could tell us
Exactly how they arrived in water deep the very first time
Yes, they probably could do that
Well, you'd be wrong
Clip clop and buttercup. No definitely wrong found them later
Airship
No, was it by
portal boat went down a river
Nope, not not that either
Was it in the back of a wagon led by two horses and a young farmer leading them into town
Was that true? That's well, that's a very good story that has more details more color
more
Was it on a train Oh
Ding ding ding to the person who's not a part of the decimators of dragons. There you go. I know my history
Oh, that's right. I always forget the trains exist. I just know my decimators history. That's good. Okay, there's one
So you can go free
Not the rest of you
The book through the bars just really actually we all kind of need to go. It's a whole thing. We need to
Go to hell and save the world
Save the world. Yeah, I've heard that one before you have
Every week someone comes in to try and steal something saying I'm the ruler of the world trying to save the destiny of the many
And did they and the world is on its way
In these people's defense, so that's just that's just crazy George
Yeah, is it the same person that comes in crazy George does come in here a lot and
And he and his friend and his relations, yes, we could have him on our side another ally another ally we could get wait
Who are you talking to?
forgot which character I was
You're not our now
No, I'm back crazy George though. We got to find that guy, right?
I think crazy George probably is seeing something that the others aren't make sense probably get him
Oh
Okay, we're here in the middle
It's happening right now
I clapped there we go to
Yes, because I didn't want to be too we did it
You guys kind of have rows between like two and three. So I just took a shot at it
You're welcome Russ. We made this way easier. No, it's all good. Yeah, we did it everybody
We've we've not only started the middle, but now we've synced it. Yeah, so that it's it makes perfect sense
So this is how episodes always start. Mm-hmm. Normally we cut it out
We don't want to feel like we're inaccessible, you know, we're just a bunch of dobers sitting around
Microphones
B&A holes, which I mean if you want to see
What kind of goopers we are sitting around being a holes you can
Yeah, we hit at the end of last month a 100 patron goal
Thank you Tom that was good underscoring we told you that but what we didn't tell you was when the live show is
We were still waiting to vote in the Patreon community on them when it should be and the votes are in everybody July
22nd a Friday night
Improv night a Friday improv night. That's did it and there's gonna be some special guests including
Yeah, why not Kyle is a regular cast
Actually needs to be there
Yeah contractually obligated
We've let him out of the room for tonight so that he didn't have to do these but he'll be there for that night
That's right. Also Cicero
So fun we haven't seen him in so long
So many things in the world have happened since we've last seen Cicero and it's it's too bad
Really because we'd love hanging out with him so much and can't wait to do so at the end of the month
So it's not too late if you want to be there you can still join Patreon and then you can be there and you can
Make suggestions and watch us embarrass ourselves and it'll be good when you do join us
We have some new goals, which you can see at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
There's some pretty pretty pretty stellar ones as far as we're concerned because Tom had some great ideas
During our business meeting. He's so fucking good. It's about damn time in a minute time
I say this with some goals and then Patreon. I mean, yeah
Yeah, yeah, I see did it. So it's about damn time you get over there to Patreon
Where Russ will definitely be singing the entire song about damn time by Lizzo. That's how we're gonna start and
It'll be good. Yeah, I'm gonna practice from now until then. All right, everybody there's gonna be the tick-tock dance, too
I'm in need a sentimental man or woman to pump
Very well, all right, I'm gonna go practice everybody you get back to the episode
In a minute somebody there was about pump me up
Or perhaps he is just a little crazy although you must think how
Ridiculous would you feel if you are stopping someone from saving the world?
Yeah, I mean they are all going to end up as undead very soon. Anyway, yes
From what you've told me. Yes
So this is close to black pool
So therefore if it is spreading outward likely before and the whole 10-year timeline
So I mean
How's the ley lines in this in this position here Varnoaks feeling good in greenest not bad
I think it's definitely it's got potential. Yes
I mean why Tiamat attacked it too. So when you go back to orcas you can tell him
Greenest should probably be next on list. Yes
Especially since now it looks like our plan has been
thwarted by these
Guards and we will not be able to save everyone if we're not gonna get out of here
we'll be stuck in jail might as well make it a point of order and I pull out a piece of paper and I
Write through hub. I write through black pool and all right
Greenest fold it up stick it in my pocket while looking at the guard Mortimer
Are they threatening us with the end of the world? Didn't they say they want to save the world and now they're saying that they want
to destroy
Greenest that is what they said. It's hard to know with these hooligans. What's what?
It's not that hard to understand
Okay, him and I were evil and then we were gonna take over the world
But then we decided to not be evil. So then we were gonna stop
The destruction of the world that we started great. It's obvious what is happening here
Can we just go to hell your interference of us saving the world makes me want to end the world
We're back to ending the world again. See this seems like I'm just saying this is could we just look in the book grants?
Write your name in there something you wrote a two paragraphs about how buff you were to put on this
Informational tag here in front of the book. Do you just sign your name in the book?
Yes, this is one of the biggest plaques we have in the museum. Yeah. See there's my name grants
Grant's is Thrandor Ashton
the buffest
Wizard around pinmanship check. Yeah, we do a handwriting analysis. Can you just
Just write something
Okay, yeah
Just just just crossed out a black hole and your utensil yeah
Oh had your name underneath greenest. Okay. Wait what I'm gonna write it on my hand
I hold up the book so that they can see writing
He writes grants is
Okay, look make a persuasion check. Oh
It's pretty good
There's similarities there wouldn't you say Mortimer you're a chief
Is a handwriting specialist of the museum aren't you
Yes, when I'm not giving tours, that is what I tend to focus on
Authentication and whatnot and it dubbed. I mean the loop in the G here. You can see it's very similar
Yes, yes your lessons with that Terry. We're really paying off now. Oh, yes, terry bear. He's delightful
Yes, my god, you guys it's called graphology. Can we go? Well, I mean you've made a convincing argument
Putting Grant's is his name here
On his hand. It looks the same Mortimer checks that out. You have blue hair
You two have threatened the world twice in the same sentence
weren't you Irish I
Forgot I wish you'd just let us go
You're talking to us about our story. Who are you it drips in and out as the more excited I get
Dad of that kid over there. What's going on here?
My kids here. Oh shit. All right. Well, uh, don't tell him I said shit
He's a little bit of a brat when it comes to bad words
I'm gonna just open the gate here here
Grants is if you could help me lift it that would just be that would just be stellar cuz you're so
Buff look at me go. I am going to cast I think I have guidance
Please say I have guidance. Why would I not have guidance night hunter?
Just wants to come and like wrench it up with me
I don't have guidance right as grant says does night hunter does as well and in unison the gate is thrown up
Grants is you're such a strong buff wizard, aren't you? Oh so strong so buff
Well, thank you for your for your time here. Mr. Captain the guard and Mortimer
Screw you for letting them know. Yes, that was a real dick move
Why not say no
You cannot have book. You cannot have book. This is entrapment. That's what this is. It is illegal
Just saying I don't know if you've ever worked in a small town museum before but it's quite boring
All right, fair enough. Yeah, okay
Especially when our main display is some grants this dude's book
Yeah, um can I get out of this like is there like is this gonna?
Back up. Oh, no, I'll go I'll go release the lever release the lever. I thought you said lemur
The lever lemur
It's been a great ketchup
We got the book now well
Any good recommendations Mortimer of things to see in greenest while we're here. Well, I would say the museum but you're already here
Recommend the thing that we're in
The stag and pony in is pretty fun any chance. Oh cosmic bowling on Saturdays. That's delightful
Do you know an artificer? Oh
Yes, what is um
What is his name Irish guard, oh, yeah, then artificer we've got one of those in town here
He just moved in a couple weeks ago. His name is
Squeaky McLeemerson another Irishman another Irishman
Yeah, that's he lives down the block around two ways they're beside the cosmic boldathon and
He's he's he's he's taking he's taking clients does this have to do with the beginning or the end of the world
Well, they're fairly intertwined. It's true go before I have to arrest you
Museum clerk. Goodbye. I'm a city guard. Well, I don't know who I'm talking to
We also enjoy wild mood swings here at the museum. So go while you can
Yes, let's see this squeaky McLeemerson as I eye down Mortimer gives you the old like I'm watching you
We cut ahead to this small cart
It's got fruits and vegetables on one side and trinkets and odds and ends on the other
It has a sign that says
Produce and artificing
And sitting behind the cart tinkering away
an older gnome gray hair frizzling around the sides that has grown down a kind of chin
length a bit of a
scraggly bushy
Half beard. He's got one monocle on as he's as a fine
Mechanical working tool working with some sort of small trinket
It doesn't really see you approach as there are several people kind of passing
Picking up fruit and tossing him a coin every now and again
I think we all just stand in front of the cart. Just kind of like
And maybe I'll say hello in no mish
So he pays attention
It's not that many of us throw clear and then the hello and he looks up and also in no mish. He responds
I was an old an old Irishman sound
Well, hello there. What can I do for you apples oranges bananas?
They're all right there. Just take what you like and you can be on your way. We actually need to get to hell
We're hoping you could
Just adjust some coordinates for us you need to get to hell
Yeah, well, I mean this is a I mean I got fruits and vegetables
The bananas are divine
We're not looking for the divine some say some say that when the watermelon goes bad
Well, it's kind of like going to hell
but
I don't know what you mean. I
I pull a ring off of my finger and I say well see this item here kind of already does it we just need you to change
Oh where it does it to so he takes it from you. If you offer it freely
Yeah, I place it on the cart. He picks it up and begins examining it and then lifts up like this drawer
top
Folds it up and then he lifts it up and then he lifts it up and then he lifts it up and then he lifts it up
and this long extendable like
intricate mechanical arm gets kind of
Envelopes out and it it presents like these binocular like
device
But they have like this green aura glow to the lenses and he looks through them and he's holding up
He says well, this is a very interesting piece. Where did you say you came by a family heirloom?
interesting enough
Yes, I see it goes into the depths of the abyss that's not a great place to go and you want to take it to hell
instead
Well, yes, you know
Well, it comes at a pretty penny
You you all look like you could probably afford it though. He looks like you've been around a little bit
Do you have a very similar aesthetic to the to the giant statue in town square? There's
Dwarven
Lizard dragon
Are you flint?
Guilty as charged. Oh, all right. Well, you look like the the statue. That's what gave you away there
I mean I can see past all the shines and sparkles, but we'll uh, we can talk that another time
Ah, yeah, absolutely. I can send this to just about anywhere you like well, we don't want you to send it anywhere
We want it to be able to send us somewhere just to clarify in case I yeah, that's what I said not clear. Okay
I'll send it in. I'll send you and it anywhere you like. Well, I mean it's going with you. Is it not
It is the thing that sins
Okay, but it doesn't stay you guys. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes is the answer. Okay, you know by this
I mean I could explain the mechanics of it with you
But really it is going to the place and taking you along with it
Now normally does it take more than just one person or does it take?
multiple in multiple individuals
Typically no more than two people. So if we can modify that that would be
Juice crank it up
Hopefully we can hopefully can sustain a little bit of extra extra NASA's they say in the industry
Where did you know it drifts
As you get older you find a lot of dialects that run by and you just kind of pick the ones that you like for
The time that you like them is it just kind of drifts in and out. Sounds good. Yeah, it's easy
Easy keeps people on their toes. Yeah, I mean the price would be probably a good
750 gold
Shouldn't be a problem
It's the juice is the extra juice that's gonna get you I've got
Ten gold
Well, I have seven well
It looks like we're gonna have to go back to the days of the the early level
Sidequest in order to get you a little bit more gold there friends
Uh just so happens. I need a little job done in order to finish some of my trinkets and knickknacks
Okay, and
Well, you gotta venture out into the dead man's marsh
find me some
Sprinkles and such can you be more specific?
Yep, I can be
next time on Dumbgeons and Dragons
Dumbgeons and Dragons season 2 episode 128 starring Amy More as thea and knight hunter carla max dead as lip sync
Tom laird as flint with kyle Claset as Vorunax and russe moore as your dungeon master production and sound design by russe moore
This episode featured music from epidemic sound and Kavin mcleod of incompetech.filmmusic.io
And sound effects from epidemic sound boom library and sound ideas a huge. Thank you to our supporting producers
Gabriel lynch jessica Babyok cat water flame jacob madden christian brown craig zeiss aron stevens darrelleth
perry matey la branton nathaniel teeter and nicholas cooper join us today at Patreon.com
Dumb dragon cast where we've reached 100 patrons and we'll be hosting a live improv night
Exclusive for all of our patrons coming up in july details will be available soon on Patreon and in our discord
Plus we've just announced some new community goals and some amazing new bonus content coming along with them
Including in character positive affirmations and the return of monthly one-shot episodes where we're excited to try out new characters new games
And play a whole smattering of different great things that we hope you're gonna love. Thank you for listening. Have a great week
We'll talk again soon
Oh, I do not believe that's what that plaque says at all good, sir
Yes end
Oh, I wish I knew my episode history better so I could just ask you questions about your adventures
Like that
I feel like you know what you're right. I'm like actively trying to think of things that I can't though
So that's all right. Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production