previously, on Dumptions and Dragons.
bracing against it and looks back at Lex and there's just a little bit of a smile and
with her free hand she casts back her mace to Lex's feet and
then the smile and
Margaret are both gone.
Well, I guess I pick up that. And as you pick up the mace you see that in the leather around it
it has a
something etched in it and it says
We watch out for those who others overlook as sort of fast as I can
with my
Shambling body
I go towards him with that mace
sort of in my last stand against him because
I'm not doing so great either
You reach back to hit him a second time and as the mace hits this black pool
extends out from beneath you and splashes up and around the two of you and
crashes down and we hear crushing
And as this wave roils out the two of them are gone
Oh
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. I'm your dungeon master Russ More. He him also with me today is Amy More
I knew you would call on me
She her and not only because you call on every one of us
But we because I was mouthing along with the words and you try to do that to throw me off
But I'm never thrown off and I'm playing Thea Amastasia. She her and
Night hunter
She they also with me Tom layer. I knew you would herald my coming is second. Thank you, sir
I am playing flint. We're both he hems and that's the end of that sentence. Good day
Call over
Carla maxed it
Maybe this my favorite energy Tom has ever brought to this
All I need is some tech issues before we start
I'm out of panic
It's a frantic bubbling bubbling under the surface I am she her I'm playing lip-synchy pip Diggins
Also, she her and with us today. It's Kyle class it baby
Once more you have summoned me here and I appreciate you for it
He him and I'm gonna be playing Voronok's so is baby now just a part of your name Kyle class a baby
Baby baby
Baby, it's like how lawyers have like Esquire and shit after their name
Yeah, but you added a new one baby Kyle class it baby crime boy
crime boy
That's right. Oh, I sorry I need to blow up your spot. Maybe I shouldn't let the people know careful
I'll come to your town and do a crime
Years later this podcast was used
Kind of the next version of cereal give me the wink when you need me to take this out of the feed this
Huge podcast get Kyle
I did something very nefarious
And Russ is just in there like I'll cover for you man and just like take this out of here
Yeah, no one will know I'm gonna make myself an accomplice fuck my family. That's right. Yeah
You'll be fine
Over here like
If you want Kyle to do a crime come join us at Patreon.com
You can pick the crime
Yeah, like stealing a hubba bubba maybe but
Or you could just come join us for delicious bonus content and all of the other things that we do over there
like live shows and
book clubs and
Other things like dedicating an episode to our patrons
Took a while, but we did it
today's episode is dedicated to
Kelly throw
Thanks Kelly sorry about that
Your episode gets to be the one where Tom did that intro
Yeah
Tom did that intro and we found out how many crimes Kyle's into
Big episode already big episode we could cut it now and probably be the most
The most sought-after episode because of all the crimes Kyle committed. It's where I got my influence for Varnock
So, you know, I was just like what did I do in real life?
Let me play that in D&D real Jared Leto kind of method acting
Exactly, I didn't know I was preparing for this role, but I was your whole life. Oh
Thank you, Kelly. Join us today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and now fuck it. Let's play
Rumbling cave crumbling ambiance is happening in the background
Thelonious prims Bane and Lex were just crushed by this black
Icarus wave
Rolling down the dais to the remaining undead of Thelonious's army who at the crashing death of Thelonious
There's a brief pause
But now they are beginning to turn and move towards you
Scrambling up the dais towards you the five of you are up on top of the dais clockwork dragon is
overseeing the entire army and
Then a squeak squeak a rat
Having been let down
By Lex comes along and does he does like a really cool air guitar riff with his fingers and then like
shreds down the the dais off in the other direction like he's some sort of like
Power skateboard guy and it's like flipping you the cowabunga on his way out. Is he on a skateboard remains to be seen
It's a Stuart little is what it is
Yeah, we got it we got a we got a SL situation going on here. Love it. Okay
Perseus runs off through the feet of the undead
Nair to be seen again in this episode or ever don't say that to us. He'll find a way
Not if I delete the character sheet
It'll still be in the campaign. I'll been spacing time to do it too. Damn it. What do you do?
Can I cast a spell at the undead? Let me say yes, you can
There are still hundreds of undead
Well, what else am I gonna do there is a bridge and a blade and an exit
off the dais towards the back of the cave
So yes, you may cast a spell. I think I'm gonna cast a spell so that we can make our escape
Okay, the spell is called wall of light
So a huge wall of bright light. I'm gonna make sure that clockwork dragons on this side of it
We're all we're all close enough together
Yeah, huge wall. They need to
make a con save
Every creature in its area, which is 60 feet by 5 feet thick
Dang. Okay. So basically you're blocking off a whole thing with a dais. Yeah
okay, cool thick wall of
Radiant light so thick what happens when they don't make it. Okay. Well, they're gonna be
It's it really murder if they're already dead. Yeah, they're gonna be blinded for one minute
Okay, we go to our resident crime expert
12 plus 9 and take 21 radiant damage. Oh, yeah, baby
undead love just just just lighten them up even in it and if
We for some reason are still here and
They get another turn then they're just gonna keep having to keep eating that damage. Got it. Okay
lip-synchy cast wall of like
Huge wall is built quicker than any Trump administration could ever
Was possible Wow
Yeah
Like cool
Couple reference me
It's a little newer than that you're right I take it back it was very modern the the undead army comes up and crashes into it
they're
Incinerated by this radiant heat as they slow and are waiting on the other side as you
now I'm gonna now I'm gonna
Try and exit while they are blocked by a wall of radiant light lip-synchy turns and runs down
Oh my god, where's night hunter up with you is is she
Last I said all of you were up there
Okay, I did establish off the top that all of you were up there
So whether you were in the last episode or not
Maybe she made her way up because she realized that the undead look different than the people on top of the dais
Yeah, maybe you did some like Elia jumps and flips, I'm sure she taught me a thing or two
Sorry, I need to make connections gotta we should probably all go. Hmm
Come on. Oh, yeah. Come on. Y'all. What are you even doing back there?
I tried to do a hop on wanna hop on everybody hops on the back of the clockwork dragon
And then looks at big and then looks at the and then looks at the doorway and realizes the clockwork dragon is not
Gonna fit through the guys. I'm not gonna fit through this door. You got you got to get off
I mean I brought you over the bridge
Did I I mean it was it was a fun idea? Okay, I
See a wild shapes back into herself. What's the range on wall of light Carla?
120 feet okay. I think I can keep it going for for a bit. Okay, awesome you all
Vorunax I'm gonna point them to the way that I came in whatever way that was said
Take care of yourselves. I can stop these for a little while get out of here save yourselves
You are saviors upon the land some of you I recognize from art. Although you look a little bit older than your depictions. I
Won't think anything of it
But know that Vorunax can be trusted and I will save you this day even if it cost me my life
Oh, no, that that's not necessary
Holy unnecessary sir. No, it's my holy charge. It is
so not
We we've come from the feet. Is it too early to drop this bomb? Is this in an appropriate time?
You're all still in the army. Yeah, we know
Appropriate time and I'm gonna turn I'm gonna do channel divinity and pretty much any undead within 30 feet of me need
To make a wisdom saving throw or be frightened for a minute or
okay, any of them within 30 feet of me or frightened of me and also a part of a
The aura of conquest means that all frightened creatures within 10 feet of me have their speed reduced to zero
And take psychic damage if they if starting the turn within my aura dang
Okay, so you'll you'll get up. You'll get a perimeter of some 30 feet
Who are on the opposite side of the
The wall of light but you won't get that 10 foot thing because nobody's that quite that nobody's within right now
Okay, cool
Well, they can move forward if they want to but they can't cuz they're frightened as Vorunax is doing his like whole leg
I got this and night hunter walks up and goes does this guy we need to have him. Yes. Yeah. Yeah
me okay, we
Night hunter walks up and like scoops him
Like she wants to she wants to whisk you off your feet
I think Vorunax is like kind of just
Behind yeah, yeah, I know I'm not even gonna resist cuz I'm just like what did what is going first a dragon now this
I don't know understand what's happening. Just that is okay. You understand later. Okay this way
Yes, as long as you don't think we need to stay and then stop these nefarious creatures
It's fine. No, we should just go. Okay would go that way you all tear across the bridge and through this tunnel cave system
Vorunax giving
What directions he feels he has
Vorunax make a
Probably a survival check to know if you can navigate the cave. That's a 22
Okay, you could make your way back to Thelonious his office or
You could I mean you could pretty much make your way anywhere. You want to go. Where do you want to go?
I probably would take them just toward the surface like
Out
Okay, just away you were moving through these tunnels with Vorunax giving you direction as you hit kind of that 120 foot
area you hear
We're gonna say you hear like an audible like snap and were as the wall of light goes out
and then the sound of the undead pick up again and they are
120 feet but you hear them cramming their way through the tunnel system behind you it takes probably a good 10 or 15 minutes of
frantic running and
Making your way through these caves. I have to put you down now. We are going too slow
Okay, I can definitely walk but it has been five minutes. You are good. Yes. Yes
Thank you for the ride
before you make your way back out to the surface of
This
Underdark entrance you exit into this rocky
mountainous region and it's kind of this this foggy misty
Dampness to the air you hear echoing back from down the halls. It's gotten quieter
Like obviously some of them have split off down other passageways that you did not go down
But you still hear the echoing of the Thelonious army in the caves behind you
But you do have a moment to stop and take a breath
Okay, how big is the mouth of the cave that we came out? We'll say like the tunnel system itself was probably
15 feet across at the widest and then it as you exited it exited into this much larger
Cavern before you came out into the open. Do you guys think we should like
barricade off the
The exit of that cave or should just keep running into the distance for our knocks
You have a safe house around here anywhere like I know I found myself down in that situation
Realized I had trailed somebody that was a little bit more powerful than I than I had anticipated
He's a tricky bastard. I tried to stop them and
You know make sure that their undead wastes were not brought upon the land
Really?
Yes, he looks around at the others like
That seems a little
That's not what I expected you to say. All right, um, we're all full of surprises
What would you expect me to say?
You know, I don't know cuz I don't know you that well
But I think that maybe we can block up that entrance somehow and then find a place where we can all kind of chat
You know and kind of get to know each other and to talk about you know, what's up our
Destinies and stuff like that. I
Mean, she's not even around to hear it
I'll tell her later. Yeah
Yes, I guess let's block up this hole and keep those
Treacherous undead from reaching the surface and harming any people
Mm-hmm. Yeah
Okay
Oh
How do you want to block this game I know this is what I'm trying to can can I eldritch blast it and
Cause rubble to fall or maybe the whole cave system to class. I don't care
I was gonna ask the exact same question
Should we do it together just to wreak as much havoc on it as possible? You can certainly you can certainly give it a go
Okay, I'll give it an eldritch blast as well
Oh
You know what neither does night hunter so she'll just watch with Flynn
You know what just stand beside one person's hand and then it's like you have it's like you're wearing like the Iron Man glove
Flint you want to move my hands around make it really feel like you're into it. I would love to it's a cavern wall
Stationary large wall. All right roll to hit the side of a barn
Last
20 damage make that 20 37 Wow and 20 so 57
23 so it's a 60 80 80 damage. Look at you three rocking and rolling with your Eldritch blast
Man Flynn is just in in awe. They're all different colors too, right?
Yeah moving those hands around out. What color are yours the color of my scarf, which is like
light
effervescent bluish greenish cool cool cool cool chartreuse with a core of black
mmm, uh
I think like let's say like a Barbie pink. Not what I was gonna say
Okay, so we got like green chartreuse and a pink it's like 4th of July happening over here
There's bright colors everywhere Jubilee from the X-Men. That's it. Yeah
If the cave begins to crumble and boulders begin to fall and as you see coming down the hallway the faces of
Some of the undead with their weapons drawn and the this hideous groaning and screaming
They run out and get crushed by this massive boulder which stops completely covers the entrance
Well done
Wow felt good
Inspiration for everybody
Especially Flint really what?
Because of the good hand movements. That's right. Yeah, that's fair. It's like, you know the spell
I do not know what inspiration does it's been so long since have you that
Gives you at your choice a an advantage to a role. Okay, I thought it was I got to
Change a part of the story. No, that's the plot points. We got rid of those
Because you guys started to use it for garbage
Some sort of game story mechanic in our hands and having it go bad
It's a bold move
Armies stopped you're in the in the in the in this cab open cavern of this mountainous
Entrance to the underdark tunnels which you've now sealed off there. Do we go now?
I was just gonna ask that same question as my head. I was going to ask where you actually came from because
You were not there and then you were well, technically I am here by accident
I was not supposed to come with this crew. I am glad I did though
I feel like I took care of a lot of things down there
May not have seen but I was swinging my ex around like crazy, but the faster that we could wrap this up
Maybe we could find a way to get back home so I could see Elia who I did not get to say goodbye to
Where's home?
well, I
Mean, it's a it's it's really simple or very complicated
Shall we walk? I'll talk
Yeah, maybe we should walk and talk and kind of
Um
so and I'm kind of looking at the others like are we just we just diving into which is gonna
Uh
So, um, maybe we should start by introducing ourselves. I'm lips. Thank you. Ah
Lip-synchy, it's a pleasure to meet you. It is so great for the first time to see you. Yes
I'm Flint fire beard. Oh, I've heard the name heard the name your reputation precedes you and
Imagine thea correct, correct. Nice to meet you
Nice to meet you as well
What what brings you heroes?
To that kind of place out of nowhere
Still just doing your heroing thing, I guess well
Turns out you're not wrong turns out
By various different paths, we are all here being heroes. Yes
Yes, we are. We all have chance to be here. Oh
Yes, we do. I
like this energy
you
Where I'm like, where are we at match 20 I wasted it no, it's a good perception
Reception plus 1030. Oh, I didn't yeah, that's right. That's role of the night
With all the awkward pleasantries going on. Sorry. I'll let like Flynn. Give me his to 14. Perfect
With all the awkward pleasantries going on thea you're first to hear it, but then everybody else. Here's a to this loud
beating of
wings coming from high up above you
You
Thea you first to hear it you quickly turn and you look and you see the silhouette of what looks like a very
large dragon swooping down towards you as everybody else turns and looks and
Coming through the fog is an explosion of this dragon's breath weapon
Everybody make a dexterity saving throw dragon
I
Think the 20 would have been better rolled on the dexterity saving throw. No, the perception was perfect
Chlorine in the water more
20 22 23 with my plus three Vorunax and lip-synchy are
going to take
Six the dynamic do the dynamic duo are going to take 67 acid damage
Everybody else. Oh, I'm so sorry. I did not roll for Nighthunter. I'm playing two characters. Someone needs to remind me
Oh, well that that is not not that's not appropriate. Well, you got you got inspiration, right?
Oh, I forgot to give her inspiration. Yeah, then I'll use it. Oh
Well, it was worse. Okay, so she's gonna take sorry 60, huh?
67 for the full damage
30. Oh wait, Carla is technically within 10 feet of me and gets a plus four because of an aura
So okay
So Carla would say air lip-synchy would take half which would bring it to 30
33 for those who who saved as this dragon now swoops down behind you an acid begins bubbling at your skin as you
Disperse and run the role for initiative. Heck. Yeah, just a little dragon fight to start things off a Ross
See ya
Nineteen for night on there roll off against yourself roll off against me another not 20 you guys. Oh my god
I don't know. Okay, so it'll go see ya with the 20 and I hunter with the 19
Yeah, I guess 14 teen
14 teen 14 teen
We will go popcorn so so far it's looking like I
Got a six first. I got it. I got a six guys. So six
I have a plus six and I got eight. Wow, you guys are just right ready to go
I mean you're tired. You were running for 15 minutes straight
I just took all that acid damage for carrying other level 20 lip-synchy does not have very high HP
So I'm pretty hurt guys
Yeah, it's not doing great neither, it's okay. We have a healer with us. Oh fuck
It's me
You do have a healer. I do the heel. Oh
I can do a heel. I can do a heel
I know that you guys don't necessarily just like think of the as someone who can heal people because she just doesn't very often
But she can get to know effectively
Great great great I can do this cuz you know dragon
Yeah, and I don't know if we need this now or if I take one more hit if I'm gonna be dead
I'm not sure the it is up to you to start the storylines gonna end quick. I
Will remind you as I sometimes do running is an okay thing to do fuck running. Okay
Said it out loud it doesn't matter
Now we'll fight to the death right here right now like heroes
We had all that success with that rock, so I think we're pretty pumped
Yeah, all of you spent spells lots to defeat a rock
He's very charismatic I believe that okay, I wish the I wasn't going first
I'm like trying to just dodge out of the way. You've got acid boiling your skin
There's a dragon who's swooping down towards your crew. What do you want to turn into a giant octopus? No, I'm just
I don't know fucking just like what the fuck is happening. Do I know what kind of dragon it is just by?
It's it's an what would be classified as an ancient black dragon nothing with the word ancients good. No
That's not good
Okay, um
Well, okay
All right five. No, don't fucking don't
She's I hate this three. No, okay. Hold on. Wait. Hold on. She's gonna cast
one storm of vengeance
That's what's up. I don't know what this does. Let's see
I
Think it's like a multi-round spell where like each round like it does different damage. Yes, this is true
Okay, so a churning storm cloud form centered on a point
I can see and spreading out at a radius of 360 feet
Amplified because of the currently stormy conditions boom fantastic
lightning flashes in the area thunder booms and strong winds roar
each creature under the cloud
Sorry, all this is
Remember thea can heal you each
The worst timeline, okay each creature under the cloud no more than 5,000 feet beneath the cloud. Are we 5,000 feet? No
Okay
When it appears must make a Constitution saving throw. Oh, oh well
Okay, I've got I've got
No, this is not too bad if you're all within 10 feet of me you get a plus four on that
Okay, I feel like I am I feel like yeah
Yeah, when you scatter when you scatter from a dragon breath you scatter together
Yes, that's right. We did not learn
Numbers
Okay, cool. No, that's fine. I'll be I'll be far away from Kyle. Okay, Constitution saving throw go for it again
23 28 8 oh 22 for the direct night hunter. You forgot the first part Carla. Oh
Wait, I have inspiration. Can I roll it again? Yeah, you bet. I'm just a little gnome you guys
21 okay, so let's a 16 now, which is better
Great not sorry. I mean, that's it was an 18 to save
Okay, so each creature on a field how the dragon doing to well, of course, they fucking did
The creature takes 2d6 thunder damage on a failed save
Which is you Carl? I'm so sorry and becomes deafened for five minutes. So you're wandering around like what?
skin boiling
Fuck I'm so sorry, but that's it. That's it
For this round and each round I maintain concentration the storm produces different effects on my turn
So after I I did this and then I go I'm I'm just I panicked. I'm sorry and I and I
Run away from you. Stop concentrating
No
I like I just want to like get out of wherever the acid is and like just kind of back myself out of
Immediate line of sure fighty fighty. Love it. Okay, cool. I'm sorry the
Running now just wreaking havoc and then getting the fuck out of there you were running
straight down the path to get out or
I just want to be on the skirt so that I'm not a target standing in the middle going cloud storm
lipsay lipsy
Wallet think lipsy. I can't
And I gesture wildly and I and I and I point and then I pointed the dragon and then I take my fist and I
Smash it into my hand. Yeah
Let's do it. I'm just gonna can you dig it?
Middles are in the center of a place where
you find information
Middles are where we tell you about Patreon and book clubs
Join us on Patreon
To find out which book Tom picked
It'll
Be real great
You should join us at Patreon dot-com
Managed to block every attempt by one of us to speak these long pregnant pauses and then more singing
If he can if you can edit it just the right way you could probably pick up the individual
Right before we're gonna say something but then but then
Anyway, I look forward to the remix
Patreon.com
Slash dumb dragon cast is where you can join us for all those great book clubs
Tell us about the book club those who read oh you guys
It's so much fun last time we had what like five or six people show it
Yeah, yeah, I think so and and some very different takes on the book, which was great
So we had some really good conversation and also talked about like I don't know gardening and pets and other you know
Just human chit-chat stuff. That was really fun
It's nice though to have a conversation and to have someone put in
Information about the book you previously didn't think about which made you think about it in a whole new way
That's the kind of safe space conversations. We're having over there. There's so many cool like hangout things happening on Patreon lately
It's just kind of been naturally expanding. We got the book clubs
I play some magic with some of the some of the patrons over there
We've got the gook hangs. We've got the producers chats. We've got the game times
We're basically just hanging out with our patrons all the time
Oh go ahead Tom I was gonna say is it where Russ and some patrons hang out and listen to Canadian ska reggae band
Magic or do they play magic the gathering only one way to find out? Oh
Only one way to join them and find out. I didn't mean to spoil it
Only one way to find out. It's not it's definitely not both. No, no
Or is it?
So many secrets Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
I've got to go buy that you around now just to make sure it reroutes funny. They don't have anything for dot-clom
Son of a bitch, maybe I'll either I'll be the first to create there we go
We hope we hope to see you over there lots of great things and we've got a goal coming up, too
We're like three people away from our 100 patron goal
Where we're gonna do another live improv night?
And I'm gonna wrangle some guests of NPCs past to come join us
That's fun. This is new information for us, and we love it. We have a little flashback situation. Okay. See you later
episode now
I'm going to
Let's all just do stupid right
What's in your nine?
Just looking at cuz that's what I wasted one level cell. I
Am going to cast psychic scream
Okay, I mean sounds right. I can't hear anything
No
So I need you to make an
intelligence saving throw just the dragon not anybody else
I wouldn't blame you if it was anyone within 5,000 feet actually the dragon and Amy. It's a 21
You're gonna take 7d6
Psychic damage see now this sounds like a ninth level slot. I didn't know what the fuck this was, but it's not and you won't be stunned
You would have been where that would have been great. He would have fallen to the ground
But I still take the damage Kate you that's half damage it was
Roll full just in case you get higher and then divide by two. Where am I? God damn does
Sorry, I have to open. I have to open a different character cuz that one is not really mine
That's why I don't have any dice on it and I don't have enough
Yeah, it's for it's 14d6 now, but if Russ rolled more damage you take hits cuz he rolled 55
She's gonna show shit do you fan?
42 is what I say you take rest is great. I'll take rest mine. I rolled 55. It's a dragon
I would like half of 55. Okay half of 55. So 27. Yep. Love it
And then I'm also going to are we like I don't know that there's any cover we can take but if there is
There's like rock, you know rocky owl coves
The mouth of the fucking cave that we've loved his first jazz album
So
Yeah, there are different alcoves along like the the widening path there there is no like cover
there is the the cavern behind you, but I will say out loud that that's a dead end and
Big enough for the dragon to get into we go to the cavern
Got it
Maybe just not speak for the group
Bar Barnaux
Barnaux, can you you do something? I can't
Can you and
I I do the same like
Punching acting out motion. Don't do it as hard as I did though. I hurt my hand. I was very aggressive
Y'all remind me I'm trying to actually remember I did say Varnaux his name earlier, right?
Good, I actually don't know that you did
I actually don't know that you did either like I think you just said nice to meet you
I don't think you said your name. Oh, maybe
Barnaux is a helper or
Yeah, just making sure you spoke in third person you did weird
You didn't say his name out loud though as you were trying to turn turn all the undead as and get them to run
Yeah, before you're whisked away. Yeah
Ever ever so gracefully. Mm-hmm. I still don't know these people that well
This is Barnaux's internal monologue. Yeah, which I do. There's a dragon there
You like dragons, too. This is kind of their fault. They're the ones who like a cult of dragons
so
I'm gonna use my action and
I'm gonna do this thing
We're gonna just step into the shadows and it's called
One with the shadows when I am in a area of dim light or darkness
I can use my action to become invisible until I move or take an action or reaction
So I'm gonna step into one of those alcoves and do that
Okay, let's say he's a bit was staring at him yelling and was like
Classic bar
Should it alright that that one's on me I should have known that's what I'm gonna do that'll be my action. So
I'm just gonna I'm just gonna live with that decision. Yeah. Oh, he has two fucking actions. Sorry
Sorry, your second action was running away
That's right. I got to keep concentration. Okay, Barnaux is forgoing. I feel like
Well, my action is becoming invisible. Yeah. Yeah, but you're you're disappearing
So there's no real drive in narrative for you to push it to somebody else
So I think the dragon is gonna go make sense sense got
mind
Spikes or whichever one that was by lip-synchy
Psychic screams psychic screams screaming saw Thea accidentally cast this storm
You pressure. Yeah
Hasn't really seen Flint do much of anything. Not a real not a real, you know, Flinton night hunter not real
Problems right now. He's going to try and recharge his breath weapon, which
Maybe tell you if they do or not when our flesh starts melting off. He'll let us
The day giveaway, yep, cuz you'll be dead everybody make a wisdom saving throw. I don't want to
22 for see ya. I hate rolling for two characters right now. Oh zero bonus for night hunter. Hey, okay
Wisdom you say yes, please 18 for
17 she's just here to hit things
She's really good at it. Okay, flint and night hunter who aren't on the dragon's radar are
Both frightened. Ah
So you are frightened for one minute. Oh, this thing is so scary a
Creature can repeat saving throughout the end of its turn ending the effect on itself and a success
So you you basically have to run away?
And it has that night hunter's worst nightmare
I know yeah, no ancient black dragon like Jeepers the two of you is on your turns begin to
It is your I'll say night hunters turn
Affected by this fear. I do not understand this feeling inside of me, but must get away from dragon
Dragon you are so scary. She yells in draconic and runs 40 feet in the opposite direction
And can she now roll to you can roll to save yet. Do it get another 20 believe
Well, that's a 16, so you're still afraid
I'm gonna be afraid forever flint. I'm gonna be a hundred
Billion feet away from you guys by the end of this thing flint almost at the same time you see night hunter beginning
To bolt you also must run away
Perfect sounds like a plan you following a close behind night hunter
Don't make it quite as far because I think you only have 25 feet with your little dwarf
Well, he's a little little itty-bitty dwarf and then you can also make a saving throw
Wisdom perfect
Well, it was a four, so we'll just we won't even bother adding the bonus for that okay night hunter and flint are booking it
Away, dragon answer. What did you say to the dragon?
You're so scary. I know I
Understood that little less scary now
Let's go back to see ya see here's the dragon say I know
and goes
Excuse me. Why are you doing this? Yeah, excuse me. Mr. Dragon. Hi
Thea Amastasia here with the favor and free press
Like soars around and lands on a perch and looks stares down at you. I
Am the guardian of this cavern
You are in my territory
Leave now or perish
Okay, okay
What
You see you like this this welling of
Energy in its chest at the what? Oh, no, she's just deafened. She just can't hear she just can't hear but she's definitely gonna do
Five. Oh fuck with the county. God damn it was guys. Let's wrap. Let's go
Hunters already had that way. Let's we're leaving. Bye. I mean did we run the right way
Is that the way that we were supposed to be going who cares?
We're gonna follow you guys cuz I don't want to we're gonna run our Vorunax will step out and be like, okay
I assume you're like
Semi-close to me and I'm like, oh god. Jesus. No
Let's go
Yeah. Yeah, we I think we run
Mm-hmm. And what a waste of a ninth level spell slot. Thanks, Russ
Run as fast as you can. I'll give you a little bit of a head start
What?
You begin running and your conic I yell rude. Are we doing a chase with the dragon? There's no chickens to throw
What exactly what are we even gonna do? What are we even see james over there? Oh
My god, we killed
We we well unless they go out the way that we came in
And actually they could cuz all the undead followed us so there's hope for james and
Sorry
Flanks, they're very familiar with the Underdark. That's right. They do tours
They're fine back at you know, the office just through the pamphlet stand. Yeah
But there's surprise supplies. They got a home key. Just like here. There's a crossover in the works
I'd listen to that you run off as this dragon is like taunting you from behind
And you make it to this the edge of this forest line that's down a ways down this mountain
flint and night hunter are there first and
Everybody looks behind you expecting to see the dragon
Toying with you it swoops up into the air and careens down near you and then flies back towards the mount
elders blast
I
Can do it
Whoo, okay. Well wasn't that fun wasn't that fun?
Okay, I just want to formally apologize
and
I just mouth story
To lip-synch II because I think
You're deaf and for how long five minutes. Okay. We'll say it's like loose
You know, it's kind of water through a you know through the window
Underwater kind of vibe right now still it's still hard to hear but
Yeah, I'm really sorry about that. I panicked. I actually haven't practiced that spell before it was brand new
it's just it wasn't a good representation of
Anyway, y'all have an act for attracting the attention of dragons. It seems we should have named should have a different name
Yes, that was
Exhilarating to say the least so okay
Are we like in a clearing you made it to a forest like the edge of a forest?
So there is canopy cover around you and you're in like the thick of a forest
We're not in the thick but like on the edge of a forest. I think we have a lot to discuss. Oh, I mean
I'm out if y'all have some things to discuss then by all means I'll stay
No, no, no, um, I think we we specifically need to talk to you
To me
Why would you why would you need time?
No, no that I'm sure you're mistaken. I'm just a local folk hero for a small town. Nothing more. Nothing less
He's so oh
You're really humble
Thank you. I appreciate it. This guy's nice
I've been told I've I'm friendly at that times and you know, so friendly
I mean, I guess if there's something that I could help to do such, you know renowned heroes then
Then may I be at your service? I guess. Oh
Well, I'm that's
that's
awfully massive you I I
Wonder and I kind of start like digging in my bag
Just just looking for something
Night hunter is really confused at this moment because it is her understanding that that
we all know that he is evil and that we're here to convince him to
Join us and he's not gonna want to do that and she's standing there
like this so the social niceties that are going on is very like
Confusing to her and she pipes up and she goes
Listen we need you to to take your big stick and and and to stop being evil and the fight the orcas with us
Why are we saying the things that he is so nice and he he is he helpful. What is
Orcas I'm afraid I don't follow
He has wand of orcas doesn't know orcas. Oh, that's no that's I I mean
I took it from somebody that worshiped orcas
I thought it looked like a frightful presence kind of thing and I figured, you know
I protected my town and I shall claim the wastes of of battle
This was my prize
Assaulting night hunters intelligence. I found it
Vorunax does this
Does this mean anything to you? You see Vorunax like snap and he goes. Where did you get that?
Who gave you that width and he starts rifling through his own bag and you see him pull out the same
carving
well, my
Very good friend and longtime colleague
you
Gave it to me to give to you
To tell you that you should help us
So
Where are you from?
Well, how did you get that you got the future? Yeah, we we got it from you in the future
Preposterous I I know it sounds hard to believe but we were we were very close. We worked together
We were we were very close. We worked together. We kind of took over the whole world together actually
But now we decided we don't want to do that anymore and we're kind of yeah
You guys were kind of a big deal
We we really we had this cool thing where we'd go in the airship and we'd just drop undead down
Anyway, that's that sounds sick
It was we did that
Yeah, i'm i'm making I mean that sounds horrible
What a terrible thing to do to the world making the bad part sound cooler
I guess than I should but what we want to do now is not
Help orcas and the world because if we end the world, that's the end of
us and also
What about that thing about how he?
The the person that that destroyed your town
And orcas just showed you what you wanted to see and said that it was
Uh said that it was the gods who killed your family
um, and
Yes, you don't have to tell me my own history. I know you killed my family
Well, no, but you see we we do have to tell you because because
Future you already knows
Oh, oh
Oh and orcas kills you
Yeah, sorry, I don't know who you think you are but uh that
That is mine and he goes over and he snatches the uh
The the carving away from you. No, you can't you have to believe me. We're very good friends
It snatches it from your hand upsinky and Vorunax. There's like this
For you
There's
Clearly a spell that's activated as soon as you touch it
And the world around you goes dark and you hear the sound of
What you tell me what's what do you hear the sense what's one of uh Vorunax's
earliest memories
That probably would have been stored
By them by the spell that you put on this item
I think one of the first memories, uh
Would have been the memory where this item was made
him, uh sitting with the with the father and son that welcomed him into blackpool and uh malice and acer taught him
You know how to live kind of a simple life and he stores that memory of them carving
This exact sculpture together and then guiding him in that
The scene plays out before you as you are standing in the middle of this building that you're familiar with
Since memory comes back you begin to be able to smell the wood
In the walls and the floor and the hearth burning a stew cooking on the stove
bubbling away and the sound of the the whittling
And the the the wooden carvings falling to the ground
Mm
Peace
I remember peace
Dumbgeons and Dragons season two episode 123
Starring Amy More as thea and knight hunter carla maxedead as lip sinkie tom layered as perseus and flint
With kyle classic as Vorunax and russe More as your dungeon master production and sound design of this episode is by russe More
This episode featured music from epidemic sound and sound effects from epidemic sound boom library and sound ideas
And a huge thank you to our supporting producers gabriel lynch jessica Babyok catwater flame jacob madden christian brown
Devin michaels craig zeiss erin stevens darrell lulahan la branton aLex sarin
perry matey and nathaniel teeter
You can support us and the shows we create directly by visiting Patreon.com
Dumb dragon cast join us today to help us reach 100 patrons and when we do
We'll host another hilarious and amazing exclusive live show for each and every one of our patrons. Thank you for listening
Have a great week. We'll talk again soon
Oh time to crack a cold one, yes
Oh, I forgot I had these pink fuzzy dice
Amazing nice
Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production