previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
time workout i'm so tired do some of that yoga it's weird i usually yeah
really something strange going on with time do you think when we traveled in time we made the
days shorter i don't think we could fuck up celestia like that this creeping blackness
beginning to roll down this crickling creek make sure you get my best side uh oh yeah
maybe maybe your best side is out out of the water though and this eruption of blackness
and you all wake up the next morning and it's a beautiful sunny day
so
welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons i'm your dungeon master rust More he him also with me today
is carla max dead she her playing glim no other information given and tom laird he him
playing moot and Amy More yeah she her and i'm playing sullivan slight and i am going
to say his pronouns are he him because it's not just not the same thing i should have said
the pronouns i just didn't meet i didn't want to make you guys say like the class like i did
last time how is that you're saying like i did we could read our backstories yeah that's right
one of those start again do the backstory oh yeah christopher flamons is here too
hello she her playing i guess she her so very simple and now we're in it playing games
you know where else it's simple clean cut we give you rewards for your patronage and support
is over on Patreon Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast it sounded like you forgot that we always
do like the patron plug and the dedication and then you had to like circle back to it
is that what happened maybe i did maybe i didn't we were pretty close to launching
pretty close to launching into gameplay but i just i just had to ask because it was yeah carlos
like you were 96 percent of the way there and then all of a sudden i was like and you know
you were at the straightforward you don't you don't know what was going on up here
it could have been all planned to not be planned well that's all naked flamingons up
there it's all naked flamingons up there you know uh don't don't put that fan art on social
media because that gets your account shut down it has happened in the past before so was it the
fuckroom drawing it was the fuckroom drawing got them got them flagged yeah yeah whoops sorry
loved that though that was great yeah not flagged by us no not flagged by us not us gotta
clear it with your other followers i guess but you also get an episode dedicated to you
get your social accounts shut down and an episode dedicated to you we give you freedom
and a dedication like today's patron trevor geist thanks trevor thank you so much trevor
thanks trevor i have a friend trevor that goes by the nickname t-bone i'm curious if this trevor
also goes by the nickname t-bone if not maybe a maybe a suggestion oh yeah you could look into
t-bone now does he like the steaks i'm curious did he get into an awful car accident those are
the two options i never asked him one way or the other but i'm sure it's the first one
okay could be the first one yeah that's let's hope for the first one yeah or just it starts
with it yeah i mean that i mean i mean i'm the most likely yeah i'm c unit and c dog and i
well i do love dogs i don't have that i'm a hole me you're a me
me yeah it's real creative
we all have our strengths yep cool nicknames apparently is not everybody's it's okay but t-bone
it's your day today thanks t-bone and trevor you too hey we don't know if he goes by t-bone
he does now i mean i just assumed dot com yeah i assumed he adopted it Patreon.com slash dumb
dragon cast and now we can play the game fuck it let's play do we remember what happened to us
the night before yeah oh yeah so we wake up it's a beautiful morning i assume and we remember
it all yeah but it's beautiful all of you are back round your backs are crickling the creek
is crackling everything's just hip-hopping the zydeco is booming sorry did you want to
some listeners into it i thought that's what you were doing no because you told me i had a full
thought so i felt like i had to jump on it but i don't think that you like that's how you
wanted the episode fuck it let's play do we remember what's happening because while that is
absolutely what my brain does every time i don't know if that's the way you want to start the
adventure all of you sit up in your bed rolls
moot's got a big time sleep apia problem he didn't he didn't come to any realization it's
just the the sleep apia yeah hey you okay there bud you forgot your cpap machine
that's what they call you moot's cpap yep that's that's what they call me we're
workshopping it you all do remember the events that happened the day before the day of that
the the previous morning that you awoke but now appear all fine am i clothed
yeah is flammacons clothed yeah more important yes good question not all the time but right now
perhaps i have my nightie on nightie is it like a baby doll nightie i'm imagining oh see i was
fishing an old lady when it's sewing yeah yeah it's a little bit of all of those it's
a got some of your mesh around the nips just the nips you gotta let those breathe
carla can't
flannel grannies but yeah but the straddle gets too much and sometimes you gotta let
let the saucers go so we're gonna talk about the the goo that um like am i dead right now
because i kind of feel like i may should have had have been can nobody go in the creek i will
not no we can't go in the creek well because that black goo monster attacked us so right
yeah the black goo muzzet yeah but it's not there yet i thought maybe we could get some
of the cinnamon bun smell off that's getting pretty strong i mean you can i i'd rather you
didn't okay no worries you're in charge you're the one communing with their god looks dead into
a god's eyes it's just a staring contest now we really do need to stream when kristin's eyes
her faces are so good they're so good just silent silent staring her down did something
happen between you two's or no apparently not of course not no why would this is how regular
people act to each other nobody said we're regular we're like the odd couple
are you guys a thing well she's like walter mathow i'm jack lemon i'm pretty sure that's
that's that's that relationship maybe the other way around which one was the straight and narrow
one jack lemon i think jack lemon okay then that then then agatha's jack lemon i'm the walter math
out these are some really hot topical references we're making was burgess meredith also in that
movie for a show that happened like god like when my mother was a child and i would also
like to point out just in case you don't know this listeners russ is the youngest one
here yes i don't know how old kristin is kristin could be the youngest i guess maybe but of the
four of us russ is the youngest yes kristin either loves that comment or hates that comment
which one that you could be the youngest you made this face like careful
oh fair it's a good mystery yeah we'll never know just like what we're in right now
happening right now because like okay i don't want to go in the river anymore
yeah no the river is no good yeah but i don't want to walk like all day yeah to get no closer
yeah to just start over again and i don't want to have to go through another squirrel
funeral i mean we we said some lovely words they didn't allow a goth there and actually
that was just me i was just there i held the service things were said and pieces were had
so what are our other options wait pieces were had we could climb a tree
why would we climb a tree because we went in the water it just seems like you're rubbing it into
the squirrels well we went in the water and we kind of we walked along the path i saw someone
in the trees last time excuse me what what like it was yeah as as everything was getting
a little bit crazy in the in the crickling creek right i saw something someone i think in the trees
what the fuck why did you say something you're just saying this now we've been awake for what
seems like look it's new well it's you know there was a lot going on and then we woke up
and then it just took me a minute to get my bearings hold on i'm gonna climb a tree
and i put a dagger between my and my teeth and uh you know rambo style yeah yeah of course um
and i want to try to climb this tree i don't how did how did silly lose his eye again
climbing a tree it wasn't playing with noise it wasn't it's actually it's a bit sensitive
and i well yeah we don't like to talk about it it was fair enough sort of okay climb a tree
athletics please oh i'm plus five i would hope so you're wrong i need to oh wait
athletics is a strength check never mind i oh oh uh 22
sorry i don't make that noise often because i never
ever with muscles glistening in this this high noon sun sully scales the tree quickly
you're up in the canopy now i look around you see i can show leaves and branches
no people in the mountain no no i don't see the mountain uh well you're up in like the
canopy trees like you're not no i want to try to get my head above i want to go high
there's a there's a as a bird flies overhead oh there's birds up here okay that's good
don't shoot the squirrels yeah goth put the put the bow away
she slides it back already have yeah so which direction did the person up in the trees go
well they kind of yeah like a north northeast north northeast you see anything you
gravel oh is it how nimble are you up there i'm so fucking nimble what do you want to do
i want to look north northeast i suppose orient yourself with this imaginary landscape
that i'm building as we're as we're saying obviously the mounts are the north so i'm gonna
you see the edge of the forest you see the rolling hills you see the there's a river that rushes
through there's would you say a river runs through it a river runs through it yeah so
we're looking for red hit when are we not he's hanging out with walter matthew and bill
mary but you don't see people or any humanoid guys i don't see anything going on up here
it's just like some birds and i see the mountain which looks just as far away as it always does
i don't have like a looky-loo i want to like look close at the mountain
no sorry i probably got one yeah you're a fucking pirate there you go huffs it up the
tree it falls back down you want to try again that was that was a little sad
it gets part way up and falls back down okay once more you can do it oh i think it broke
oh never mind god damn it why don't you come back down then you can climb back up can i
catch it with my mage hand before it breaks sure go for it okay i will cast my crab claw
isn't it always cast now because it is an extension of your no hand oh yes but i believe
if i want to like detach it and send it i would probably have to cast it fair enough
right cool um you're gonna roll me a wild magic surge oh of course oh i haven't done that in a
long time uh it's a 17 uh yeah you're fine boo boring lame okay well you mean you could
have just said you could have done that and sent it up there without me huffing it well i just
sometimes again just i'm feeling a little slow today involve yourself in the story here moot
feeling a little slow today i woke up on the wrong side of the crickling creek oh the wrong
side moot moot you genius maybe we gotta get on the other side of the crickling creek maybe
on this side it's the mirror world and everything doesn't work the same way as the
other side and so maybe we have to go to the other side uh to uh have uh and our and with
the world and have it back yeah yeah what sully said did you make that out i mean they're
pretty high up but i do i do want to use the looky-loo quickly to see like is there
movement on the mountain is there like you know like a you know like at the top of mount
olympus you know i'm curious as wearing like i'm sure was previously described when we first
landed in celestia's the the mountain uh extends up above the clouds so now it is like it is like
mount olympus yeah very olympic that is topical the olympics just happened and i live close to
the olympic mountain range they're gonna send a take down notice for this episode
now that you just said the word olympics
can i do like like looking for tracks or i don't know somewhere around where moot is saying
you saw some stuff like yeah absolutely looking for weird things or broken tree branches or
survival survival or nature i'm gonna do survival um because i'm good at it uh
23 nice uh you see uh often to the side like uh a tiny like body drag marks like god really
small like body like almost like there's two two portions of a carcass slowly dragged off in a
way uh you see um footsteps down near the creek like a heavy movement down near the creek which
you can equate to yourselves being down there you see a few um branches that look like they
were uh perhaps snapped off of a tree near the the creek um and when you look up it like
there's there's broken um broken branches and twigs and stuff that has fallen and it seems to be
askew so with the footsteps down by the creek that are us are those ours from yesterday
it's like the footprints are persistent they appear to be so okay and so then presumably
the tracks of the person that moot saw would maybe also be persistent is that sort of where
the broken branches are based on moot's description yeah you could presume that
whatever he saw might have made those okay interesting interesting moot you said you
saw someone over here yeah they may have left a trail you see these branches oh yeah well yeah
they were in they were in the trees so yeah there must be more of those broken branches
can i look around is there a trail we could like try and track this person towards yeah yeah
you can absolutely just try and track them your survival rule holds okay um you make your way
sully are you still up in the trees yeah sully comes down he doesn't know what you guys
are doing so he comes down he's like all right there's two things that we can do we
can go across the river and go to what could possibly be the mirror side of things or we
can do what a god said before and it's like maybe this is like the fe realm and we got to
walk away from that mountain and to get to the mountain so i think those are only two options
that are viable at this moment i came up with that myself at the top of the tree there has
been like a one new development it's been a thing what what thing well a god maybe found
some tracks or like oh well maybe a trail i think in a plan and you guys are down here
just doing a collaborating well it's hard to collaborate when i'm all the way up there
trying to you know see stuff well you were you were very impressive climbing that climbing
that tree so quickly and the amount of yelling you did it was very prevalent i did a lot
of yelling you did yeah okay well tracks that's frankly it's that's a lot more
solid than what my stuff was you follow a goth and catch up with her as she is probably
uh on her own accord um and a goth you're following these and you're you're kind of
keeping an eye up and down trying to see where these tracks lead and they go up and over this
this rocky hill that is off into the north northeast i believe was the directions that
moot gave you um and they lead up and over um the the crickling creek which continues back up
and into this so we are going into the mirror realm you come up to it let's say you cross
over okay okay it all seems very scary it doesn't seem scary it seems like a crickling creek
except that there was black goop in it yesterday is the only reason so i just
yeah giving you the option so it comes up to this to the creek which is cutting through
and it looks like these tracks or the branches and movement looks like it crosses over to the
other side i'll i'll brave the mirror realm uh you cross over does everybody else follow
yeah okay everybody all all in line follows over this uh everybody's stepping through and
splashing over this little creek and walking into the other side which is very very similar
um just an aesthetic because you're just walking across a tiny creek it's not not not wild um
and glim as you step in you hear from often to the right as far as where your directions
are um you hear like this this like slurp sound oh no guys i think it's i hear something
it's happening again how how how wide how wide is this uh crickling creek it's not wide it's
can't be that wide it's a creek yeah it's a creek it's not a crickling river you guys
yeah no it's it's very it like sully was having to use a lot of river rocks in this creek
to be able to cover himself the way he was covering himself artistically yeah so i'm just
gonna go like double quick time like say like a zydeco kind of time just real quick quick
you run across and you're following these um you're following these tracks and you hear like this
crunching noise no longer a crickling noise a crunching noise in behind you like trees are
falling in on themselves until you make it into this clearing as this last loud happens
oh shit oh my god you look back and as you like feel like this this this blast of wind
you look back and it appears like the forest is is pristine behind you
in the middle of this clearing is a is a hole that appears to have been dug or burrowed
and goes down into the earth how big what is the circumference of this hole
at the widest is probably about eight to ten feet and it looks like it narrows down to about
uh three and a half to four feet does it look like it comes to an end at like solid ground or
is it like tunnel it looks like it's tunneled into the ground and do the tracks look like
they are going into and descending into yeah yeah there's there's movement from from several
directions implying perhaps that there is more than one creature all appear to have a similar
shaped footstep though paw or like kind of a um more of a hoof
hoof slash claw hoof with claws hoof with claws in comparison to rex's hooves
smaller bigger same size smaller smaller okay yeah about probably a little less than half the size
okay can i just do like a nature check to see if that
if i'm aware of a hoof with claws this sort of track yeah please
oh i guys i don't don't worry about it that's a five this doesn't look like it in fact it
like it looks like if you weren't actively tracking something or just weren't really paying
attention you would think that there were two separate footprints from two separate animals
like on top of each other but that that doesn't make sense because why um i mean one was
obviously carrying the other but um you know oh they were like daddy daughter dancing with like
it's got its feet on top of their feet and just the claws were hanging thanks for that
amy i does this hole in the you said it was it was narrowest by how much you said it was
eight to ten feet in the biggest part yeah like three and a half to four feet so it's a fairly
sizable hole uh can i be so super sneaky and like stealth my way down there and peek in
you most certainly can roll for that and i will because you guys i'm stealthy as
fuck okay well i rolled a seven but i've got a plus 18 so 25 okay plus 18
i said i'm stealthy as fuck i wasn't kidding level 20 with uh with no multi-class baby
it's like agatha's like so i think they went into the and where's yeah sully's gone
sully's disappeared hey where did sully go uh sully you make your way down silent as nobody even saw
me do it nothing they're all looking into the hole they didn't even see you they were looking
away like a goth turned to look back and then everybody was focused on a goth and turn back
you were gone um you make your way down into the hole and like you hear like the rumbling
of earth um not in an ominous way just that's the sound and the kind of the atmosphere
you hear you go down and this levels off and extends down quite a long ways
and gets darker and darker the way you go it doesn't appear to be lit by anything
natural you carry down i would say 40 to 50 feet before it gets too dark for you to see
anything from the light coming back and there are a couple splinters off and there are footsteps
that are going several different directions and you hear scuffling up and about about in the
dark okay well i run back because i said i peeked into the hole but now somehow i'm
50 feet into the hole so it escalated you didn't even see yourself go i had no idea
was gonna do that um so i run back up and i go okay you guys uh so about like 50 feet or so
down there it's real dark uh and there's a few different tunnels but there's for sure footsteps
going along the way but it got kind of creeped out because like there was no light down there
and stuff so and it's pretty small can i use my divine sense which will tell me if there
is a celestial fiend or undead yes you can great is there a celestial fiend or undead
or any creature affected by the hallow spell answer damn it celestial fiend we want answers
and we want them now russ immediately no not not in the direction that you're going you do
get an odd not for anything in particular you get an odd sense coming from back towards the
crickling creek but not in the direction of the whole and forward for you great well glim
only moves forward so that's why forwards not backwards upwards not downwards and twirling
always always twirling as you're trying to get this sense and maybe you articulate it maybe
you don't uh there's movement from inside the tunnel and you hear footsteps coming close and
then as you're as you're um standing around and perhaps talking amongst yourselves quietly
you hear the footsteps stop and then you hear them start to slowly go back in so like we
could go in there and stuff or we can probably wait quiet out here and like like ambush
but i do think we just heard footsteps so maybe they know we're here true but
what if we pretend we leave home like make a big deal out about it like oh well we
later here we go guess there's nothing here what a big dumb hole there we go
i don't know if it worked how long do we have to wait here
i don't know like well you're the professional you were the drawest right
uh-huh a monsteteer you said that was a drawest that's what you draw stuff yeah we have to wait
and quiet for the animals to come so you can draw them like obviously that's part of it right
no i i drew naked people oh naturalist
get your own schtick
ah rude you got scooped this guy
so this might seem crazy but maybe whatever's in there could help us
oh for sure oh yeah no i mean they don't seem to be attacking us i mean unless it is the
thing that made the black goop happen but it kind of just like came up to the entrance and
then like yeah and i really should i really should have said to agoth for you specifically
that this was like an ambush of like aha you are what is down there could you help us please
not like uh like shoot them immediately as they come out oh that is a very good clarification
that's on me so but now it's on you it's an important clarification yes i did say it now um
well sure uh it's a little crampy down there but i think if everybody were to
scrunch i don't know whose voice that was maybe we could just like give a like go a hello
oh yeah sure or sneak in i think you should do it you have the nicest voice
i mean that's it's just strong from all the practice from the the diaphragm breathing you
know you know exactly um okay well maybe you guys stay here in the trees in case like
50 scary things come out and attack oh fair enough okay okay okay uh so i'm gonna go up
to the hole everybody else is back in the trees as far as i understand it i would like
to be like on top of the hole like from the opposite end of the entrance to the hole just
with my staff okay i wouldn't want to be so far away just ready yeah just like to whack a mole
if something come if more than one thing comes out and it looks menacing glim facing hole
everybody else from approximately a little bit above the hole yeah yeah okay yeah downwind
got it downwind uh are you in that group are you are you are you watching from the trees
uh i oh i guess we should have a little okay i'll watch from the trees okay
kalim you approach everybody surrounds hello hi we're just here we really we just need a little
bit of help if you wouldn't mind we're very nice uh moot you see before uh agoth and sully do
um a figure pop up immediately behind them
and sit and then like leans over their shoulders what are we doing we're waiting for
something to come out of the hole oh okay excuse you did you sneeze what am i looking at
um you see before you kind of a very satyr-esque um but not not in the traditional sense like
there's a uh they're they're furry from like head to tail more bear-like on top uh with
like this more more teddy bear kind of features rather than like a grizzly or anything like
lost boy yeah and then kind of the pan yeah and then kind of like the goat legs uh you know
horse legs and then like these these long bear claws that extend over the hooves and he's got
a like just this little like satyr in a bear suit like yeah a little like uh tattered cloth
vest and loin cloth and he's just okay so this sounds like this is gonna be a lot of
fun let's see who comes out did he come out of a another hole is there where did he come out of
he saunter up behind he just turned up behind behind
we're so good at this so glim can see him too yeah well i figured you were kind of poking
your head in so you pull back when you hear the voice and yes you see them now
oh oh oh no oh my gosh hello hi hi who are you who are you uh it's a very good question
and i asked it first well it's sort of a long story but the short version is
we have a destiny to save the world and like there's time it's a whole thing
ah yeah sounds we're just trying to get to the mail how would you feel about being like a cool
guide like like a welcome wagon kind of celestia uh-huh i mean you seem very
like the guy who knows it all are you that guy well i'm i'm one of one of one of the folks
who knows it all but what's in it for me well i mean i think i said we're on destiny to save
the world everybody everybody who comes here saving the world really wow well how many people
well i mean there's there's you folks yeah yeah and everybody who has come here so far has said
oh so that's like we're like 100 100 100 wow batting 100 it's actually bad
you want to bat a thousand oh that guy right there um he will draw you you will forever be
immortalized in oh that sounds scary i don't know if i want to be immortalized that sounds
like oh hey hey i have some snacks sounds like you're playing with dark magic no it's
just a straw with a pencil which way did you come you just strawed did i i like i
strawed for what with my feet is that what you could you repeat the question
we don't know with the same uh intonations please
a stride a stride a stride can you use it in a sentence yeah
yeah
yeah we're not bad people oh no this guy sounds like a dick yeah very yeah no we're
we're super like trying to save the world good people and then you're saying hello into a hole
well friendly like but the mountains that way yeah we've tried that way it does not work
yeah mountain kind of yeah yeah these have been kind of a little bit on the fritz here lately
did you try turning it off and on again what year is it
well i mean time what's time well it's yeah that's what it is i hear you brother
right um but yeah no there's the crickling crickling creek which we love so much it's
kind of turned a little bit a little bit sour got kind of got kind of creepy and slimy and grabby
yeah i mean i saw you there getting trapped in it but i knew you'd be fine so i just kind
of left you there because i didn't want to get trapped in it because i got trapped into
once and then you just kind of avoid it yeah yeah so does your day reset every day
well doesn't every day reset every day well not like i should have died in a gloop yesterday
but i just woke up in my bed yeah like how did how did he get out of the gloop
uh well like there's this this there's this there's this magic that's kind of creeping
in it's like it's dark and it gets kind of scary sometimes and then sometimes the ground
cracks open it gets a little like i don't want to deal with that right now and then
we go and we hide in our beds and then we come back out and it's all okay again
yeah so this is something happening to you not i i don't think these guys are in charge
what oh so i said that is a whisper rust sully's version of i need an adult we're here to
um like stop the world yeah yeah but like specifically stop a bad person from taking
over sounds like maybe they're sneaking in yeah maybe it's already happening yeah maybe it's
already happening so we'd like to like you want to stop that we would like to stop
yeah okay i came in with a level of mistrust that i was uncertain of and maybe maybe
maybe you're okay i'm just gonna pop my head down in the hole and just make sure everybody
down there is okay and then maybe i'll come back up and then lead you off into
somewhere i mean we where we end up we really have to get to the mountain
oh yeah the mountain yeah i can take you to the mountain
okay okay i mean i've been there in a while but maybe why it's in the same place yeah
yeah we could walk to the mountain supposedly what was your name well i mean i don't think
anybody gave me i am a god oh that is very true this is okay yeah rax yeah okay yeah rax nice to
meet you very very clean steed glim mood sully flamey can stop touching him yeah sorry
sometime please don't touch me yeah well it's okay um just you're the same kind of size and
i ate some mushrooms back there and i'm really tripping balls uh nobody saw me do it but i was
like i'm hungry because i didn't want to end up like moot all hangry and stuff like uh like
everybody do but now his friend drowned in a river will now be forgotten you have to do
stuff for your i will bring it up every once in a while finish that drawing
he had a sense it was gonna be a groundhog day obviously he was fully on board with it
okay well i'm just gonna pop down the hole you just just wait here okay
did you give us your name it just yeah for politeness yeah of course sorry madam are madam
are no not madam are
it sure sounded like you said madam are madam are madam are madam i but madam it has sort of like
a zydeco sound to it which i kind of makes sense yeah the trees make that noise
did you eat the mushrooms too no i just sometimes i just you know whatever
so that guy's weird yeah who's this
so we just wait here he said maybe he'll come back i mean i feel like there's a really good
chance that they're just gone um but what were we gonna do i mean restrain him it didn't seem
right no usually a good way to foster positive relationships with a potential guy he could take
us anywhere it's almost nighttime normal night time or weird celestial night time
that's only comes two hours later uh well it appears to be dusk and the sun is lowering
okay okay so we just make in camp here then are we do you think we're gonna wake up here we
gonna have to find our way back here this is uh how do we know i mean we cross the creek maybe
that oh that might have changed things did something i don't know he said that they
just go back to bed which i assume is in that hole there um and then the earth fixes itself
which is just you know talk about behind your head in the same i have a wild idea
oh okay oh i would love to hear it what if we went into the hole i feel like that's kind of
going into somebody's house we can i agree but i think we should do it i think we should at
least ask if they just go back to their beds that's what he said right so maybe below
the dirt doesn't reset what there's only one way to find out i don't want to go first
i'll go is it too tight for a gas to get through how big is it how tall did we say a gath was oh i
don't know somewhere in the six foot range i would imagine but maybe more you you could shimmy
down there racks definitely isn't going down there yeah yeah no the horse cannot he's not
yeah i mean we got we got racks across a bridge we're not getting racks into a
tunnel not in the tunnel glim is also about six and a half feet tall so yeah i would like to be
at the back because i don't want to be trapped in a tunnel if like these tall people somehow
get themselves wedged in there like you were somehow in between the both of them like no
thank you yeah i i would like to be last like flamingons and i will bring up the rear yeah
we'll keep things safe back here you all shimmy in and you're you're just looking to to
make camp under not looking for anything in particular people make camp in the quotations
uh yeah you go down murder everyone in their sleep
uh yeah you shimmy down and you it's very silent down there you
silly you don't hear the same as you kind of pause and listen you don't hear the same
scuffling going about you figure perhaps everybody's gone to sleep
and as you're crawling you feel like this this tiredness just wash over you
and you're trying to to fight it off and you you feel your head hit the dirt below you all
of you at slightly different times and then you wake up back in the clearing
it's the middle baby here we go here we go it's the middle baby and we start with a book club
did you pick a date yet oh jesus okay wow it got really aggressive okay so carla hasn't read
the book yet i haven't read the book yet it was my book choice um so that should definitely happen
before we have the book club but it will be in april what we're gonna do is we're gonna
give people the chance to vote on the date so that we can make sure that the most people
can come to it join us on Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and when you're in our discord
you can vote on the date for the book club that's the one and it's so great we've had
one so far and it was awesome such good conversation about the book about like life and
the world and existential thoughts and also the book one thing leads to another essentially is
what we're saying the book this month is cleared wit and the city of the dead by
sarah graham thank you teamwork makes a dream work so if that sounds like a mystery you're
interested in come join us over on Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast hop on our discord and
join our book club book clubs happen once a quarter join us today now i'll get you back to the episode
you yawn and stretch awake and the crickling creek is off in the distance
the birds are chirping and from the center of your camp you hear a voice and says well you
guys left well what did nighttime came and then we were here just brought us back here
oh this is a spot well it's a good thing i came back here yeah i just had to i just had to ask
everybody and sometimes like there's a committee that gets involved when there's big things
happening and so you have to ask and then they have to run it by somebody else up the chain
and then they have to just pass it around and get approvals on it and then they come
back with revisions upon which we have to do and so did you guys not fall asleep oh no
we fell asleep uh and then and then we picked up with a conversation in the morning and then
i was like ah it's about the time when they'd probably be moving down to the creek and splash
around in their nethers and uh now we're here so you want to go to the mountain
yes yeah okay off this way and he zips and moves towards the mountain
yeah i was gonna say is he pointing towards the mountain or he was yeah okay all right then
let's go uh you all pack up your things quickly and follow behind matamar and uh he takes you
along the path that you took uh who knows how many days ago um leads you out of the forest
and down through the foothills and you make it to uh uh make it to the river and you cross
the river there's no need for a bridge uh this everybody can make it across it's not super deep
and it's okay um and he where you're following the path he diverges from the path
um and the the one side that you had followed previously wraps up and into another forest and
he turns back after not saying anything for quite a while and he says if you if you go
that way it just kind of just kind of loops and then brings you back sometimes you can get
this way and is it's a little it's a little scary but i mean you all seem big and you
get those sharp sharp objects and you can probably uh we can get through it we
sorry we got to stab someone well and maybe i didn't i don't know it's kind of like the
it's kind of like the gloop in the creek uh and then sometimes other things reach out
um we came down here a little bit uh at first and uh and sometimes some some of our some of
those people didn't didn't wake up the next morning in the same in the same spot so they
went somewhere huh why did they just like disappeared yeah i mean they got they got
pulled in and we're like oh it's the gloop it's like this creek we'll see you tomorrow
oh my god and you left them well your friend left you
oh yeah and we will discuss that later however i mean you can't just assume that the put like
it is going to make you sound much worse mood because now these people automatically knew that
they would be like regenerating but i don't think you can live your life just not saving
your friends just in case the one time that they don't come back yeah well that's something
we learned and then we just didn't come back here anymore okay so and this is also just
like this is a new thing like the river gloop or the creek like the yeah yeah i mean the
scary badness here where people disappear this is new yeah it wasn't wasn't always this way
what used to be here uh what well just just rolling rolling hills and just nice
beauty nice and and and right less squirrel funerals i mean there's been a few of
those i don't know why there's been so many recently um that needs neither here nor there
um so i we go down into this this little this little break in the rocks here and then we can
pass through and that's your way out okay but just like there might be something bad in there
well i mean we're pretty okay with dealing oh yeah guys i mean we we've been around bad
way more than good yeah for like a decade so yeah tell me about it oh honey you have no idea i
don't even want to tell you about it because it's so terrible oh yeah you should just really
just hold close the ones you love and maybe try and save them if they like seem to be
getting attacked even if you think it's going to be fine enjoy the sun because yeah yeah and
the plants and the fresh air oh yeah right and that smell that's here yeah fresh water
no not that smell like the like the fresh grass right right okay okay okay are you gonna are
you gonna come with us yeah sure yeah yeah yeah that was part of the plan as i would
lead you down and we'd get through the through the crack in the ground and then lead you to
the mountain and then get great i mean we're ready so okay great and bahamut's gonna be so
excited to see you i'm gonna be so excited oh yeah bahamut well i mean i know him in my heart
and i know him in the future but not it's a bit confusing but let's the short answer is yes
do you know bahamut yeah well i mean he flies around she hasn't come down a lot recently
oh we've been trapped in this day for quite a while so maybe that has something to do with it
has anyone been keeping track of how many dates you've been trapped in this day like
every time you wake up you like you know make a tally we did that for a while and then we got
bored bored at the data yeah hmm so it's a pretty big number yeah so it's been going on a while
it's higher than six but lower than four thousand nine hundred seventy two okay okay uh let's go
okay you all begin to walk down into this crevasse uh that breaks open and um there's
as you get down into it like there's this immediate sense of like dread that washes over you
oh guys feeling yeah yeah i mean for here it's really bad for here it's like a nine out of
ten but for future time i feel like this is like it's like a low three i agree yeah i mean
right i mean it's bad i don't like it but it's like this would have been a great day
three weeks ago yeah that is true i want to make sure that i just have my um
yeah weapons drawn my rapier of life stealing is in my hand oh fun everybody has their their
weapon of choice drawn then you're proceeding down in the sound of your footsteps is echoing
off and down and you hear down at the end of whatever this cavern is and wherever this
cavern terminates like this sound of like this almost like the bubbling of lava
sound um which as as each like burble occurs like there's this tiny
like high pitched whine that comes after it there's like these crackling noises that
are moving along the stones and matamar is getting increasingly nervous the further you're
walking in um the uh so we're getting towards the end there and it's where it's where the
loop stopped for some people so we just go in there i guess wow all right oh okay
i mean is there going to be like a monster in here or something you're acting
yeah you're real sketchy like are you sacrificing us too then just hoping that
with enough sacrifice that it's gonna make the day you know continue no i mean they did
talk about sacrifices part of the committee but reginald vetoed that uh pretty quick seemed
like you guys were pretty pretty cool with what with you know the cool drawings and and the and
the green one was like uh at the holding the funeral service for that one squirrel's family
uh it seemed like you really just got it um so if you can stop it maybe
maybe be good can i roll like an insight check on this report of the committee's decision
please do yeah i don't see this in the minutes from the meeting at all yeah this
original sounds pretty cool but i don't know about the rest oh dang that's a 19 on the dice
um plus nine yeah the darkest timeline does wonders so he does seem like openly nervous
and and agitated but appears to what you can discern to be telling the truth as he understands
it it is an understandable nervousness about this horrible cavern and not a nervousness of
like ah dang they're gonna figure it out any second yes all right don't worry we won't
well you don't you don't have to come in with us if you're like you look very scared
do you do you have a weapon or my razor sharp wit oh dear do you have family back home do you got
yeah yeah i mean you have those you have claws oh yeah i mean yeah yeah i could i could
i mean and the wit yeah okay yeah um well let's okay let's go i did okay well it's your choice
you don't have to feel like there's like one two three four there's five no i was with the weapon
because i met you i was voted the one to have to lead you and then i'm gonna lead you it's part
of my job would you like to lead from behind me oh that's an option oh definitely okay and on
your review we'll put that that you were just doing just a spanking good job spanking good
job all right love it okay no literal spanking please no i look at flamingands hey look we we
know our lot we know our boundaries okay it's fine all right lead the way agoth agoth leads the
way racks following everybody else kind of narrowing into this this this crevice and you get to
what appears to be like a a wall in front of you and like there's this same black
ichor that you saw on the creek burbling up and out and it extends up um
what do you do you proceed through do you what do you what do you want to do
um glim can you sense anything off this goo yeah i'm gonna use my divine sense again
you get the same kind of vague feeling coming from all around you that you sensed back when
you were trying to sense it at the hole it was often to the distance more towards the creek
that same just eerie feeling but you don't sense a specific celestial undead
uh being uh it's almost even like like there's this this like bubble around you that you can't
sense beyond and it feels like it's it stops at whatever this this material is well i mean
it's definitely something bad but i don't get like specific undead kind of vibes or but i
don't know things feel weird like we're in kind of a bubble or something so we already know it's
bad it's bad i'm i'm gonna take uh one of my less cool weapons just just a plain old mace
i guess i'm gonna poke it when all else fails poke it with a stick yeah sacrificial weapon
just in case you press the mace into up to and into this material and you feel like this this
suction begin to pull it trying to pull it from your hand i'll hold on to it for a bit like just
see like how powerful does the suction get i'm also like yeah i guess i could use a spear to
really see like how far this goop goes but make a strength check all righty uh it's only a
14 uh it's it's pulled and you're trying to hold on to it and it pulls your hand in
and you're now feeling that same suction onto your hand glim you notice a goth begin to get
pulled into this this this material i will let go of the mace at that point i don't care
about the mace that much it can have the mace okay well i mean this it's like this only one
way to know for sure and uh sully runs and jumps into the black goo i thought it was gonna push me
only one i totally thought sully was gonna push like our poor little satyr friend and i was
like damn oh no no okay sully you run at the wall and everybody sees sully run and you like
i do a run and jump because i know it's going to be sticky i've been in this stuff before
you know like the milk for the walls and you're in like the breakfast club pose at the end
i am walking around the field yeah yeah yeah uh sully does that and gets slowly absorbed into
this material he died as he lived so he's gone from sight recklessly as the burbling
continues you see sully disappear into this acre
i'm not telling you anything yet i made my choice you did
i guess it's just gonna shake her head sort of briefly think we maybe should have had a
conversation about are we gonna try and damage this thing first or just go with it and just
walk into it some more bug it yeah i think glim's same like i mean not the choice i would
have made but can't just let my bud be in there so here i go around so i didn't like
i'll like link arms with uh flamacans and we'll skip into the all right yeah the goop yeah
okay here we go we're off to see what's behind this stupid ugly ichor as you all
make your way through and in you get the same thing you hit like you don't hit the wall but
you press yourself up against the wall and you slowly like morph through it until you each
individually find yourselves in a dark space you all hear yourselves kind of coughing and
spitting up whatever this is as it's tried to work its way into your ears and mouth
and it's dripping off of you now and it's a hot humid room when you hear the same bubbling like
more um like quicker coming from the center of the room as you all pile around each other
and try and stand up and wipe off what it what's all on you you see this giant
giant vat in the middle of this room and inside the vat is this pulsating
brain i was gonna say it's lord voltmore
he's trying to get his body back this massive brain that begins uh emanating this like
purple black light and these tentacles begin to lift up and out of this goo
and from high up you feel the presence of different creatures or figures looming over top of you
you
Dumbgeons and Dragons season two episode 118 starring Amy More as sullivan sleight
carla max dead is glim tom layered as moot christin Flemmons as a goth and russe More
is your dungeon master editing production and sound design by russe More this episode featured
music from epidemic sound and sound effects from epidemic sound boom library and sound
ideas a huge thank you to our supporting producers gabriel lynch jessica Babyok cat
water flame jacob madden christian brown devan michaels craig zeiss erin stevens derelith lulahan
charlie warley and la branton to support Dumbgeons and Dragons and our many other
productions and get access to an exclusive podcast called the adventures of bonus
episodes and much more please join our Patreon at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast you
can also follow us at facebook.com slash dumb dragon podcast and on instagram and twitter
at dumb dragon cast thank you for listening have a great week we'll talk again soon
i like she's like we've got more information i don't know what to do with it i'm really hung
up on the ground all day but the whole world not resetting thing is really kind of breaking
my brain a little bit sure love it yeah but that's russ's specialty it is you are a full
cast man you've experienced it all finally you'll get your advil in the moon
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production