previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Maybe I'll leave the latter out, and I'll swing it on over to, uh, to Mannix. See if they can climb on up.
Fia, underneath, as you kind of come back to your, your own form, you see this creature clearly.
Oh, fuck no. Get out of the water. Get out of the water!
Uh, I'm gonna cast Blight.
Blight connects with its flesh, and you see it, like, recede and turn black.
Mannix is, like, propelled with it and towards you, Yenbul, and you two begin to scramble up.
And as you reach the top of this ladder where Flint is standing, you see behind him one of these globes moving towards him.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. We're at D&D 5th Edition Actual Play Podcast, and I'm your dungeon master, Ross Moore, and with me today is Karla Maxted.
Yes, I am here, and I play Yenbul Nury, Kalishtar Cleric.
And Amy More.
Oh, hey, yes, I'm here. I play Thea Amastasia, a high elf druid.
And Tom Laird.
Okay, yes, I'm here, and I play Flint Firebeard, a dwarf champion fighter.
Okay, all right.
Yeah, here we are. We're all here.
Yeah, got a real relaxed attitude going on.
Just getting into it. Actions happening. We're just limbered up, ready to go.
Like, uh...
You know where we're always limbered up and ready to go?
Is that not where you're going?
Yeah, we're always limbered up.
I was trying not to go there, but thank you.
Oh, well.
Yeah, thank you for going there.
This is Dumbgeons and Dragons. We go there.
We go there.
Where we're all limbered up is over on Patreon.
Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragoncast.
We got all the good moves, all the good action, all the good one shots, all the good hangouts, all the good over there.
The goods are over there.
We want you to go check it out, because when you're a patron, you also get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron...
Stan Sitzman!
Hey!
Speaking of good, thanks, Stan.
Thank you, Stan.
And now...
Fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
Alright, we're back in the action.
Thea had just blighted this unknown creature down beneath the murky waves of this pool in this cavern.
Mannix and Yenbul climbing up a ladder.
Behind Flint, they see one of these spherical water orbs moving towards him.
Flint, make a dexterity saving throw at disadvantage, please.
I would love to do that for you, Russ.
A 17 and a 16, so I guess it's 16.
And then also, now that you've made a 16, make a strength saving throw, please.
Much better at strength.
You're so strong.
Yeah.
That's a 23.
You feel like this water kind of splash up against your arm and you feel it kind of suck your arm back and into it.
You manage to pull it back down, but you sense that if you stand in this location for much longer, that it's going to pull you in.
It is now your turn.
Yenbul and Mannix have reached the top of the ladder and they're just climbing back up onto the edge.
Okay. Are they still on the ladder?
I'm going to say Mannix is probably still on the ladder.
Without assistance, they would still be there.
All right, I will, I guess, kind of let the ladder fall.
Like, will it? Is it flat where I am?
Would the ladder start, like, sliding away?
Can I take it with me as I go?
You could take it with you.
What would you want to, like, picture them kind of climbing up and in?
So if you dropped it, like, the surface is still slick, so they could pull it back under if you were to drop it.
You could probably infer that if you were to let it go, that they may lose traction and just slide back in.
Yeah, I guess I'll kind of drag it a few feet away from this weird orb thing that's coming after me.
Okay. And maybe I'll use a follow-up action to throw my dwarven thrower at it.
At the water?
At the water, yeah.
Okay. Okay. Let me see if that does what the...
It's going to be like a slap the water until you become strong enough to eventually bust yourself out of your own grave.
Kind of thing.
The old punch from inches away?
Yep.
All right. That is a 24 to hit.
Okay. And then it hits it. It goes through the water.
Do I need to roll any damage?
Is there a cool splash or anything?
What kind of sound effect are you going to put in here, Russ?
So it hits it and goes...
And then you see it go through and then you see it kind of trail through the water and then emerge from the other side and splashes out.
You don't need to roll damage, though, because I obliterated it.
Because it's a sphere of water.
Fair enough, though.
Thea's inside really sad. She understands right now she's missing Flint doing something dumb.
There's a tingle inside her and she's like, oh, he's fighting water.
I can't believe I'm missing him.
It's good. You know what? Because it's going to come back to you, right?
Like it would follow the same trajectory. Roll me just a straight D20 for the hammer.
15.
On its way back, it slows and is suspended in the middle of this globe now.
It stole your hammer.
I felt like a 15 was a good roll.
It points at you and laughs.
It was a good roll.
But the water sphere was better.
The water sphere strength was better, apparently.
Anything else you would like to do?
Water is really strong.
I think about a meniscus.
Like high surface tension.
Would have lost some momentum coming through one way, coming back the other.
I don't know. Magic, man.
Science, people.
I'm following the DC that's on the page.
Alright, yeah.
I don't think I could really do too much else if I'm still holding onto a fucking ladder.
You'll get it back.
How far do you think you moved?
I don't know, like 10 feet tops?
Like it's got to be difficult terrain if I'm hauling a ladder with me.
Yeah, absolutely.
Well, and it's slick, so it's definitely difficult terrain.
Okay, so yeah, you've moved 10 feet.
Yenbul, it's your turn.
You've made it back up onto the slick edge.
Mannix has been pulled another 10 feet on.
So they're still on the ladder.
But it is your turn.
Flint has just thrown his hammer into a water globe.
Okay, I didn't realize how many spells I had were all fire based.
Until we were fighting spheres of water.
Fighting water?
Yeah.
It could be really good.
Evaporation.
Steam.
True.
Okay, yeah.
Okay, that's true.
No, you're right.
I was thinking water puts out fire, but you're right.
Heat also dissipates water.
So maybe...
I was looking for ice in mine.
I know, that's what I just was too.
Can I turn something into ice and it's like I can make ice and then it's like I think that'll just make it bigger.
That's not helping me.
Now it's going to be like a bludgeoning item.
Exactly.
What have I done?
Oh my goodness.
Okay, then I am going to...
I am going to cast Sacred Flame.
Okay.
And it's not actually flame, it's radiant.
So that might work.
The target has to succeed on a dex saving throw.
For the globe?
What's that?
Yeah, the globe of water has to do a dex save.
It's the one thing that's threatening them.
What else are they going to fight?
Okay.
Yeah, no, that's fine.
I'm just...
I got to figure out how that is going to work.
Okay.
Cool.
It doesn't make it.
You started this water fight, Russ.
Yeah.
That's cool.
It does not save.
Okay.
Then it's going to take 3d8 radiant damage, which is 10 radiant damage.
Did you misplay this globe?
No, I'm playing it perfectly.
I'm just trying to figure out how this is going to affect...
Okay, so light emanates out and towards this globe and hits it and it...
It gets shiny.
The light disperses through it and it heats it up.
It heats it up.
It begins to bubble and steam off the top.
Does it get a little bit smaller?
I mean, a little bit.
Okay.
Yeah, a little bit.
And for my movement, I'm going to go and help Mannix off that ladder.
Okay.
Let's get him on ground again.
Sure.
Yeah.
Yeah, you get Mannix stood up, water steamy is happening.
After your turn...
Yeah, you see, Thea, beneath you see this monster begin to kind of just swim the perimeter of this pool.
Swimming around me?
Yeah.
Oh.
And you feel kind of like this vortex begin to form in the center.
And it is back to your turn, Thea.
Oh, well, I want to swim closer to the edge.
So you want to swim into the path of the monster?
Because it's swimming the perimeter.
Well, you know what?
Maybe I'm just going to...
How big's the perimeter and how fast is your swimming movement?
Let's do some fun math, guys.
My swimming movement is only my walking distance, which is 30 feet.
Depends how big the pool is, right?
So the pool is...
These are 10 foot squares.
10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, 70, 50.
We'll say it's like you could 50 or 60 feet from where you have been knocked into the center of this pool.
To get to the closest edge.
I will dash to get to the edge.
Okay.
What do I have to do to time it so that I don't hit it?
Make a dexterity...
Probably an acrobatics check.
20.
Okay.
I'm going to say that you begin swimming against the force of this vortex that is forming.
Above, you see it kind of like begin to suck down and into the pool.
And then you see Thea...
You see her figure come close to the surface and then much like...
Flipper?
Flipper.
Good.
Like begin to fly out and onto arms back.
No!
Arms back onto her belly and slide across the ground.
I make Thea look like an idiot.
It's majestic and graceful, Thea.
Is it?
You made the noise.
Okay.
Fine.
That's true.
Okay.
I get up.
That's one action to dash out.
So you still have an action.
I still have an action.
You're actually pretty close to where they were.
You're more...
So you're able to see now where the opening where you were headed, you're able to see
down.
It's a long hallway.
You can see some stairs down at the end of it.
Flint, Yen Bull and Mannix are more towards this alcove, more towards your right.
Okay.
There's this giant water steaming bubbling water ball with a hammer in the middle of
it beside Flint.
Have I gotten out and onto the ledge?
Yeah, you're up.
I'm up now.
You're up.
Oh, I've really Flipper dived myself out of the water.
Yeah, you Flipper dived.
I gave you Flipper dived.
Oh, thanks.
Okay.
Well, I'll take this slightly stupid look at that.
I stand up and like quickly squeeze the water out of my hair and then I look at what's
happening and I see the hammer in the middle of the water and I see, I don't know,
Flint putting away his ladder and I just, I kind of...
Is this, is this ball of water bugging you guys?
I mean, yeah.
Yeah?
Ken, okay, there's like a fucking scary squid thing down there with like a big mouth,
lots of teeth.
Don't fall back into the water.
Okay, that's just...
Don't.
We weren't going to, but we definitely won't.
Do you want to help with this?
It stole Flint's hammer.
I see that.
Flint, what?
I walk toward the water sphere and how big around is it?
15 radius of 15.
So it's like really big.
It's really big.
15 feet?
15 foot diameter.
So yeah, 15 feet around.
Okay.
I want to like just gently touch it with my finger before I do anything.
Make an intelligence check.
Check or saving throw?
Check.
Okay.
I'm going to, I'm going to do another lucky thing because I only rolled a four and I
don't want it to kill me.
So I'm going to spend another one of my lucky points and I'm going to try again.
15.
You touch it and like a wave kind of ripples out from where you touch it and
then goes still.
And you feel connected to it.
No, like it's my own little brain parasite.
Like do I not want them to hurt it anymore?
No.
Like how connected am I to this thing?
You feel like you can control it.
Oh, I feel like I can control it.
Oh, that's very different.
That is very different.
Connected.
I'm like, okay, now this is a part of me.
I thought it was your best friend.
I thought it was a lump again.
I thought we have.
Yeah, exactly.
Is it just a lump?
Oh no.
I, I, I cautiously reach or though I guess if I know it inside, I confidently and I
kind of make a show of it like to flint.
I'm like, do you want your hammer back?
Let me just, and I put my hand in and I grabbed the hammer and I pull it out
and I was like, what was your problem?
And then I want to move it out of the way and into the middle of the like, like
out of the way of the path.
Okay.
So like more toward the water, I guess.
However, I could get it out of the way up.
I don't know.
Yeah, absolutely.
So you move it.
I'm showboating entirely right now.
You really are.
I mean, as you should.
While all this showboating is going on, everybody else you see behind Thea, the
other three orbs now have come over the top of this pool and are collecting in the
center.
Let's go.
You don't see it.
Everybody else sees it.
And I just wave the hammer.
You want it?
Got a little welcoming party coming your way.
I look back and I'm like, let's go.
Let's go.
I don't want to touch them all.
I don't want.
Let's go.
Can we hustle ourselves through the passage that now we have a clear walkway for?
If everybody's running out, everybody make a dexterity check.
Oh, I somehow kept all my Dysote except a D20.
So I'm not sure what game I thought I was playing.
Perfect.
Roll.
Wait, I can do it on here.
17 for me, Russ.
Oh my God, a 10.
Okay.
I'm weighed down because of the hammer.
You're dragging the hammer.
My strength isn't great.
Yeah, Flint, you could call it back at that point.
I want her to suffer with it a little bit now.
Aren't you just glad to have it back?
I mean, not with how it was delivered back to me.
It's tainted now?
Oh, please.
If you had the option of making a show of it, you totally would have.
You know what, Thea, you keep it.
It's yours now.
Fine.
It was Dex, right?
Like when Captain America got to pick up the hammer in the last movie.
I knew it.
Oh, fuck it.
Yeah.
14 was mine.
I guess spoiler alert for Endgame.
Yeah.
Oh, well, that was a while ago.
I think we're safe there.
Everyone's been locked in their house for like four months.
If you haven't seen it yet, you're not going to.
Then you didn't want to.
Come listen to our downtime where we give movie suggestions as well.
Yeah.
That'll be one of them that we have coming up here if you haven't seen it already.
OK.
Everybody begins to run out.
Mannix and Thea, Thea weighed down by the hammer.
You begin to slip and you fall.
Not again?
You don't.
You begin to slide.
But as you fall and everybody else runs, you hear a splash from the pool.
And everybody sees this giant, as Thea described it, a squid.
But it is it is it is more than that.
It is.
Everybody make a nature check.
Nature check.
22.
18.
Nine.
Flint, you don't know what it is.
You see it the same as everybody else sees.
But everybody else recognizes this as an aboleth.
It's creepy.
A giant circular spherical body with a giant circular maw and four long tentacles that come out.
And it rides up and into this sphere and is now suspended in this giant sphere and begins moving towards you.
I can't control that big sphere.
Can I battle it with the sphere I can control?
I mean, as we have kind of sideways determined, the sphere is controlled water.
So no, you can try.
It might just absorb into the other one.
No, you can do whatever you want.
Now I feel like it's a good sphere.
I don't want to put it in that position.
It's your friend now.
Thea's turn.
Manix, who also slipped.
Manix is going to try and get up and they are able to and then run 15 feet towards everybody else, which is actually seven and a half feet because difficult terrain.
And then it's Flint's turn.
Was Thea able to get up or was she still sliding?
You know what?
It's not Thea's turn yet, so she's still she's still prone.
OK.
Just lay in there.
Slip and slide in my way.
I yell at her to hold on and I recall the hammer.
Just to help her up.
I yell.
Yeah, sure.
Yeah, I like that.
Well, Thea's a waif anyway.
I assume it could pull her 80 pounds.
Sure. Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, you see Thea zip across like skid across because it's like a slick surface.
Like you're skipping a stone.
Splashes up as she goes until it reaches Flint.
You let go just as it's about to.
He catches it and you kind of slide by and through and in through the next door.
Commence a bow.
Thea, as you enter the next room, you are immediately attacked.
It's just a pit of spikes.
It's actually not a room.
It's actually just a floor covered with glass.
Weirdly enough.
So you you you leave you go through like the caveway entrance exit to this room and bump down some stairs and roll into this cavern, which is rough and has uneven floor with open holes in it.
In the east on a spar of rock is like this big stone that jumps out.
And that's what you see as you enter.
I wait for my friends.
Big bad evil things.
Yeah.
This turn.
And it's going to move the sphere as fast as it can, which is only.
You see like swimming inside.
Yeah, he's swimming forward.
So it moves 40 feet.
It's hard to.
It moves 40 feet towards Mannix and gets within close enough range to swing a tail out at him for 21.
That's just going to hit.
And that's going to be 15 bludgeoning damage to Mannix.
It is Yen Bull's turn.
So Mannix is kind of knocked forward a little bit.
And we're still like.
Thea flew on ahead, I guess.
And the rest of us are still still just there.
Stuck with my mess.
OK, that's fair.
OK, well, I am going to.
Mannix is prone.
No, Mannix is Mannix is standing.
He was just kind of knocked forward from the tail attack.
How far is he from me?
Say 15 feet because you would have.
Well, you would have dashed.
So probably more.
Yeah.
Can I get back to him so that he is not in front of me anymore?
Yes.
Great.
Then I am going to get I'm going to go back because I want to cast Thunderwave and I don't want to Thunderwave my friend Mannix into the sphere creature water ball.
Sounds good.
Seems mean.
Yeah, that's fair.
So I am going to.
Yeah, I'm going to cast Thunderwave.
So you need the water sphere.
Abalith guy needs to make a Constitution saving throw.
OK, that's going to be a 14.
OK, so it fails.
So it's going to take 3D8 Thunder damage and be pushed 10 feet away from us.
So unfortunately, that's only 10 damage.
Not good rolls, you guys.
Not good rolls.
But he's going to be pushed 10 feet away from us.
Also, there's a very loud sound like thunder.
Echoes throughout the chamber and it hits and ripples through the force ripples through the sphere that is housing the Abalith.
And you see it connect and bruise the flesh of this creature and it lets out a cry.
And like you see it cave in in the places where it hits.
It doesn't it doesn't look good.
Is there anything else to do on your turn?
No, I don't think so, because I think that was probably already my movement.
OK, then it is your turn.
I am just taking your new surrounding.
Yeah, pretty much.
Yeah, I don't think I want to go back there.
They should be running toward me.
Hopefully I yell back like my guys.
What do I see?
I see to my east a jutted out part of the rock cavernous wall.
Yeah.
Is there anything on it?
No, you don't see anything on it as you kind of pick yourself up and dust yourself off.
You hear like soft scuffing footsteps coming from off into your left and low groans.
And as you wait just a moment, you see one and then two and then more zombies coming from around this corner.
How far into this room am I like?
Am I able to go back and see my buddies?
Yeah, I would say you would have thrown like 10 or 15 feet into the room.
So you're just seeing it's a it's a pretty wide room, like 60 or 70 feet for you.
Right.
And then even wider.
But I'm just like 15 feet, like a little hallway to get into there.
OK, I walk back.
I like run back and I'm just like, hey, guys, cavern full of zombies.
For one, I can tell.
How are we feeling about this apple with guy?
Like you think that we could maybe like continue on to a different entrance or you guys want to like just like with some zombies?
I could go either way, but there was no different entrance that you saw.
Oh, this is it.
Yeah. Oh, shit.
You guys, this is if this is the only one.
I mean, OK, it's just heads up filled with zombies.
So I go back in.
I'm like, I'm going to start hacking, I guess.
I go back in.
How many zombies can I count?
I have dark vision.
So if it's dark in there, it shouldn't matter to me.
Yeah, no, you can definitely see from what you can see.
There are eight zombies that you can see and you hear a heavier footstep coming from further around the corner.
You can't see what made it.
Cool, cool, cool, cool, cool.
All right.
Well, do I see any exits from this room from that location as far as you can get in?
Yes.
Often to your right, you see the cavern kind of bends up and around and looks like there could be an entrance over there.
You can't quite see as far behind the zombies if there's anything back there.
OK.
How far away from me?
Sorry.
Lots of technical questions for you right now.
How far away from me is would you say the jutted out up part?
It's on the opposite side of the room.
So, I mean, straight across.
You're looking at 60 or 70 feet, I think I said.
And then up.
OK, cool.
Neat.
I grab from my bag the Tome of Thunderstep.
OK.
And I'm going to open it and I'm going to say funda funda malu amat makhuro.
And it is going to thunder each creature within a 10 feet within a 10 feet within 10 feet of me makes a conversation.
Sorry.
OK.
Hold on.
You see the zombies.
They're not 10 feet away from you.
Oh, OK.
They're just back in, which was 15 feet and then back.
So you are you are just where you could see them coming around a corner to you.
So they're probably still 40 or 50 feet away from you.
That was my bad.
OK.
Sorry.
I misunderstood.
But good news.
They're 40 or 50 feet away.
Not 10.
Yeah.
Fair enough.
So I guess what I'm going to do is I'm going to Eldridge blast some of these bitches.
That is a 16 plus seven 24.
I get three beams.
I'm not that 17th level yet.
I was in that one.
That one goes nowhere.
And that one is a 17.
So two beams and one D10 force damage.
That's a six.
And that's a one.
So I'm just aiming it at two different.
Sure.
Zombies.
This energy randomly cracks into two of these zombies, which some of the flesh falls from them.
And they kind of take a step back, but then fall in with the horde that's with them.
I will just grab my oath bow and I would say swift death to those who have wronged me.
And I will pinpoint one that is wearing some sort of garb that I can like pick it out of the crowd.
One's got like a unicorn rainbow shirt on.
Nice.
I thought maybe like some crushed velvet or something would have been nice.
That too.
Yeah.
Unicorn rainbow.
That's the one.
Crushed velvet.
So that's a nat 20 plus seven 27.
You really don't like that outfit.
Wow.
It's so tacky.
And also I want it for myself.
Fair.
So?
We need some serious detergent to get the smell out though.
Do we have a laundry soap sponsor that maybe Thea could do a read for?
Hey guys, you want a laundry soap?
We got it.
I'm in trouble getting the smell of dead zombie out of their new shirt.
17 piercing damage for unicorn buddy.
Okay.
It lights it up.
It was an incendiary.
But now it is.
Describe to me how you kill unicorn rainbow zombie.
Oh, I aim right for the unicorn's horn.
It's right in the middle of its like the back of its chest.
I assume this is kind of like maybe maybe a jean jacket that's been bedazzled.
I like that.
I love it.
Yeah.
This backstory for this zombie is going to be real good.
I'm very excited for it.
And I aim for the tip of the horn.
I mean.
It goes straight through the chest.
What an opportunity for fan art.
Right.
Are you writing it down?
Jean jacket.
Bedazzled.
Yes.
Unicorn.
I'm into it.
Oh yeah.
Hey everybody.
We're here in the middle.
It's where we're at.
It's the middle.
Well, we're not at the start.
We're not at the end.
So.
Middle.
We've nailed it.
We can tell where we are in an episode.
Perfect.
We're I mean normally we're a little funny jokey like you know just keeping it through
the whole episode.
But there are some things going on within the D&D community and within Wizards of
the Coast and Dumbgeons and Dragons that we feel like we need to address and talk
about in that the Wizards of the Coast has been prevalent on social media and in
various news sites and reports from people working within the company that they have
not been representing persons of color well within their company or within the game.
It's not a secret.
It's something that has been going on for a long time.
And because right now that is very prevalent.
That is true for the game that we are playing.
So we want to talk about that right now in that we don't want to stop playing this
game.
There have been different things said on Twitter and in Reddit like why don't Dungeons
and Dragons shows stop playing Dumbgeons and Dragons.
There's probably only one show in the world that can make that change.
We all know which show that is.
Not even the McElroy Brothers could leave Dumbgeons and Dragons and not lose listeners.
And we love you listeners.
But the bigger point I'm trying to make here I think is that because the game and the
company making the game are having problems trying to rectify a lot of decisions that
have been made to this point and made normal within their company.
We want to be the better way to play the game.
So instead of abandoning the game and the structure altogether we would prefer to do
our best to be mindful about who we're playing with.
Are we representing people of all different backgrounds and cultures?
Are we being sensitive to the different topics that do come up in D&D?
And how we navigate those is going to help us hopefully be a part of the positive
change we should be seeing in the D&D community as well as coming from the
Wizards of the Coast.
Because I mean there's going to be a change.
Things won't go on the way it is.
I think we'd like to be a part of that and hopefully show how it can be played and
how inclusive that you could make this game.
Yeah, I think since we started we always that's always been important to us as
people.
So we've always approached it that way without maybe addressing any of the
negative history.
So we just want to say like we know we get it.
We don't want to stop playing the game.
We love the game, but hopefully by being more inclusive and if you have
suggestions about how we can do that or concerns about how we're not doing that,
please reach out to us.
That would be amazing.
But that's our intention going forward.
We want to keep playing the game because we love it.
But we want to try to set a good example about how it can be more inclusive.
Yeah, I know we normally just come off as a bunch of dinguses who, you know,
laugh and play this game together.
But yeah, it is something that we have thought about and we always want to do
better.
So yeah, if there's even if you have suggestions of people that could maybe
come on as guest stars that we're unaware of.
Well, let us know because we're always open to suggestions and anything like
that that improves representation is always a good thing.
And that's what we want to try and do.
We want to try and do guests that come on.
We want to look at, you know, who we're bringing on and representation within
our story, making sure that we ourselves are not painting any persons,
groups, cultures, any of that in a poor light.
So you can, if you have any comments for us, you can find us on Twitter
at DumbDragonCast, on Facebook, facebook.com slash DumbDragonPodcast,
or you can send us an email directly.
DumbDragonPodcast at gmail.com.
We are open and willing to talk and make sure that we are doing the best
that we can for everyone.
So thank you for listening to us.
And we hope that we continue to make a wonderful show that everyone can
enjoy and have fun with and feel welcome and comfortable playing.
But now we'll get you back to the episode.
We hope you have a wonderful week.
Reach out to us if you have any questions, comments or concerns,
and we'll talk to you very soon.
Love you, bye.
Bye.
Crushes in this zombie's chest and splatters out at the others behind it
and it falls deceased.
Um, OK, everybody else, whose turn is it?
Where are we?
Motherfucker.
I'm so distracted by the gene genetics.
I'm so sorry.
That's OK.
It's good.
It's a lot of flavor.
I liked it.
Manix is standing.
They are running, dashing as fast as they can,
and they make it to the entrance.
Abelith is still in tow there.
Yenbul, you're in between them now.
Flint, you are up.
All right.
Let's mosey on over the way that Manix went.
Just mosey on.
OK.
Well, I'll dash, but.
Yeah.
Sounds good.
We'll say you can dash.
So you are, if you dash, you can make it to the door
and then into at least where Thea is.
Perfect.
Let's do that.
OK.
So you're in Thea.
Where Thea is, you now see this chamber.
Higher up alcove where across the way,
you see at least eight zombies,
the sound of crushing footsteps behind,
leading you to believe that there's something bigger.
And off to the right, there is what looks like a recess
or some sort of exit.
Perhaps you could infer.
Howdy, friend.
Any other actions you would like to take?
No.
I killed one already.
He's wearing a baller jacket.
It is the Abelith's turn,
and they are going to move swiftly towards Yenbul.
They can definitely make it to you.
So make a strength saving throw as this orb comes close to you.
Oh, I'm very weak.
But that's an 18 because I rolled good.
Thank God.
I'm very weak.
You feel this water like crash into you
and try and suck you in,
but you're able to pull yourself out and away when it takes.
Actually, it's probably going to do something different
because it can see lots of people now,
which make a wisdom saving throw.
You're probably going to make it
unless you absolutely biff it.
Well, don't set it up like that.
18.
Yes, you succeed.
So it has moved.
It's right in front of you now.
It is your turn.
Yeah, I guess it is on me now,
so I can't run away.
It'll get an opportunity attack.
Unless you disengage, but that would take an action.
Okay, well, great, great.
Glad all my new friends just ran into the next room
and left me here with this thing by myself.
I really appreciate it.
For the worse.
Puzzle it out there, Yenbul.
Okay, that's okay.
I will cast Sacred Flame,
so it needs to make a dex save.
A dex save.
No pluses, no whammies.
That's a nat 20.
Damn.
Okay, I guess I do nothing.
I do nothing.
Okay.
Yeah, okay.
Cool.
Can she back up?
No, it's an opportunity attack.
If I move away,
it just gets to attack me easier, right?
Yeah.
I figured that was like turning your back to it.
Like, just like,
slink away.
Sluck backwards.
Slowly.
Okay, then if that is all, then Thea,
you look around.
Flint is there.
Mannix is through the door,
kind of brushing themselves off
and looking behind them at this point
where you look through
and you see Yenbul face-to-face with this Aboleth.
Damn, girl.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna,
I will take my oath bow again
and I will say swift death
to those who have wronged me
and this thing has wronged me.
And I will hit it.
You're going for the Aboleths, right?
Yep.
Yeah, that one will not hit it.
That was only 11.
No, goes wide.
That one was a 15.
Are you rolling with your advantage again?
No, I have not been rolling with advantage.
When you name someone your sworn enemy.
Roll with,
try again, roll with advantage.
I just rolled twice.
So first,
it goes in through the water
and glances off the hide.
For a 15?
For a 15.
Dang.
Okay, I'm gonna try again.
Okay, what about a 22?
22 will hit.
Okay, neat.
But I'm gonna try rolling again
because it's advantage.
Maybe I'll get a 20.
Get that credit.
It wasn't.
It wasn't bad.
It just wasn't.
Okay.
13 piercing damage.
Tell me how you kill it.
Ooh, I don't know.
Maybe the arrow shoots in
and it gets stuck in the back of its throat
and it can't,
and it,
and then it dies.
And no one's there to pat it on the back.
And no one is there to give it the heimlich
or pull it out or anything.
And it's just like floating limp
in this semi-sentient.
No, that's not what happens.
To make a dexterity saving throw yimble.
Okay.
You told me.
Tell me how you kill it.
But the after effect is not how that happens.
Okay, 22.
Okay, as all of this choking
and no heimlich happens,
he's looking for a chair to try and like
throw itself down on,
it dies
and you see the life leave
its body as it goes limp.
And then the wave of water begins to crash down on you
and you turn and you run
and you ride this wave down to the end of this hallway
that bursts into the next room
where you see zombies
traveling towards you.
Is that just yimble in my back there just like wet?
She like silver surfers her way in.
Yeah, that's right.
Do I just kind of like walk in after?
I assumed you just kind of stood
where you were and shot through.
Oh yes, I did.
I guess I didn't have to come and stand right beside her
and be like, let me put myself in mortal danger.
That's not the kind of friend I am.
Yeah, that's fair.
So yimble, you now see the scene
with the one deceased zombie, more zombies.
And actually coming around the corner now
you see what is making that larger sound
are two ogre zombies
in behind Manix's turn.
And they are going to try and turn undead.
So we'll say Manix rushes forward towards them
and half of them are blasted back.
He throws his mace down into the ground
and this radiant light goes out
and blasts three of these zombies backwards
and they explode in a mist
against the wall behind you.
And that brings us to Flint.
How close are all these zombies to us?
They've had a round to move
so they're like 10 to 15 feet.
And Manix has just moved kind of
in the midst of the first wave.
Alright, I will stroll forward to the nearest one
and I will attack it with my battle axe.
Alright, make a bunch of attacks.
If I must.
Yeah, I must.
Alright, here we go.
First one is a 19.
Second one is a 17.
And third one is a 31.
Oh, no, you've gone too far.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So give me damages each separately
and then you can determine if they keep going
if one of them dies.
Alright, I will do that.
Okay.
One.
What?
He's got like a plus 11.
Plus 13 with the battle axe.
Plus 13, that's what it is.
Who gave you that?
I mean, that's like my...
That's my AC basically.
Alright, first one is 14.
Second one is 11.
So you kill one with that total.
Okay, and third one is 13 damage.
And deeply, so you take two swipes
into the first one that you come up to
and then you drop it
and then this big slash into the second one
and an arm falls off of it.
Perfect.
It is Yenbul, your turn.
So I commune with Ithgara, my spirit guide,
and say a prayer, censuring the undead.
And each undead that can see or hear me
has to make a wisdom saving throw.
It's going to be all of them.
So we killed one, two, three, four, five.
So we got three normal ones and two ogre zombies.
So wisdom saving throw, what are they going to beat?
16.
16, ugh, their wisdom is not great
because they are zombies.
Got a real Flint type bonus here.
Okay, so the ogre zombies,
that's going to be a seven and an 18.
The other ones, that's a one and a two and a one.
And a one, two, three, four.
So all except one of the ogre zombies failed.
Okay, so they are now frightened.
They have to try to move as far away from me as they can.
They can't willingly move within 30 feet of me
and they can't take any reactions.
For its action, it can only dash
or try to escape an effect that prevents it from moving.
If there's nowhere to move, the creature can dodge.
They're all trying to run away now.
Okay, all of them except that one ogre zombie
carrying a large morning star are running away from you.
And it's all of their turn.
So those zombies that have to are dashing away
as fast as zombies can dash.
What do you guys want to do?
How do you want to end the scene?
You've just blasted all of them back.
So you have room to move if you want to try and escape.
Do you want to fight this one ogre zombie
or do you want to run to the next room?
I mean, I feel like we should
because I don't know why we're acting like creatures
can't just follow us
because there's no reason for us to think that, is there?
Well, can they get out of the room?
Like, are the openings big enough for an ogre zombie to get out?
You haven't actually...
The water one, I just kind of assumed that with the water.
We'd go around a corner and then we'd be good.
Yeah.
Hey, I killed it.
It's true.
Solve that problem.
Yeah, I mean, you haven't actually seen...
Like, it could fit through the door,
the entryway you just came through.
But what about the one to the right that we may escape through?
You can't actually see it.
Like I said, you can infer that there's something over there,
but you haven't actually seen that egress.
I mean, my vote is we try and kill it
because I don't want compounding baddies chasing us
through the pyramid.
And there's only one left now, like we have a full minute
where they're frightened of...
Everybody roll me...
I'm going to say that it's going to come forward
and get into the mix of all of you.
It's going to try and swing out at...
It would get to Mannix first,
so it's going to try and swing at Mannix,
which it does not do very well.
So it swings clumsily down with this giant morning star
and is basically surrounded by all of you.
So all of you pick one thing that you're going to do
and just roll to attack it.
I mean, yeah, I'm going to go for the arm
that's wielding the giant morning star.
Okay, roll me your three or 18 attacks,
however you want to do it.
Three comma 18.
All right, first one's a 24.
Second one's a 27.
And another 31.
So last time you did like 40 damage just about,
so we'll just kind of...
Unless you want to roll.
You roll it.
Full damage on that one.
16 and then another 15 is 31.
And nine is 40.
Weird how that one's out.
You really showed me, Ross.
You really called that one.
I really did it.
Okay, what are you doing?
I'm going to step forward
so that I'm slightly in front of Flint
because I don't want him to take any damage from this.
But I grab my Tome of Thunderstep.
I'm actually going to do it this time.
And I yell,
Funda, funda, malu, amat, mak, kuro.
And each creature within 10 feet of the space...
Oh, no, shit.
No, never mind.
That's everybody.
Yeah, that's everybody.
I was hoping it would be 10 feet forward.
I put my book away.
Those cute ones are hard.
Yeah.
Like when it goes in all directions.
I hate how it goes behind me.
Yeah.
So I guess instead of that,
I'm going to cast Toll the Dead.
So I point at the ogre
and the sound of a Dolorous bell.
Dolorous.
I've never once said that word in my entire life.
Except for D&D.
And I say it wrong every time.
Fills the air around it.
And the target must succeed on a wisdom saving throw.
Or...
Or take...
3...
Roll damage.
12.
Yeah.
That's 20 necrotic damage.
What does Yen Bull do?
I'm going to cast Sacred Flame.
So he needs to make a deck save.
Or take 19 radiant damage.
The scene we fade out on is this ogre clumsily swings down at Mannix
who ducks out of the way into Flint, Thea, and Yen Bull.
Flint unloads three huge axe hits
into dropping the arm off of this giant ogre
and tacking into its side.
The sound of this bell rings
and reverberates through when flesh begins to fall off of the zombie.
And Yen Bull lets forth a Sacred Flame
that just begins to peel the skin off of this ogre's face and side.
And it lets out a bellowing roar as it falls to the ground
in a heaping ash and smoke and gore.
And the four of you stand around it
as the other zombies move back and around the corner away from Yen Bull.
And you make your way to the next room.
The intro song, Nowhere Land, is by Kavin MacLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
All other music and sound effects can be found at epidemicsound.com or boomlibrary.com.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers, Christian Brown, Devin Michaels,
Gabriel Lynch, Jacob Madden, Joshua Dixon, Kat Waterflame, and Stevie.
To find out more how you can support Dums and the Dragons,
visit Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
Thank you for listening. Have a great week. We'll talk soon.
Manix's turn, and they are going to do...
Something.
Turn...
Twitter.
Twitter. They're going to tweet about it.
Seems like a poor choice given the situation.
...are destroyed.
Three of them, like...
What's a good description for this?
Because I think that they legit, like, explode.
So he goes and he, like, throws his weapon.
What does he carry now?
Shit. Don't change, don't ever change character sheets for a character, everybody.
It's not worth it.
I'm just going to say, you did this to yourself.
I know. Dums and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.