Yes, hello there.
Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin.
Just one moment.
There is the sound of screaming echoing through the docks as we see Bonwyn and Kavlarananan, Alydin
and Bizard among the mob of the citizens of Vintersmouth surrounded by these three creatures
that are encrouching on their space, moving along the rooftops towards the docks where
everybody is being surrounded and almost herded to.
The city guard and the military are trying to usher people onto boats and get as many
of them out into the water as they possibly can.
Everybody who can is over by the bridge now being moved over to the noble side of Vintersmouth.
Those people are being cut off by one of these monsters.
The three of them turn and focus on the heart of this group and let out this echoing
howl that echoes through the air down on top of this main mass of people.
We see people covering their ears, shrieking in pain and dropping to their knees as two
of them leap down to the street.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Russ
Moore, he him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she her.
What?
I can help.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she her.
This cost so many gold.
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave, he him.
Like steel drums?
Is it like an island rhythm?
And Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, he him.
I'm dancing more than I'm attacking.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast and you can join us today at Patreon.com
slash tumdragoncast.
There's a seven-day free trial and a whole bunch of episodes for you to listen
to.
We hope to see you over there.
And now fuck it, let's play!
The four of you and Dace are right at the intersection of the dock and the bridge and
the roads that intersect and the crunching noise of one of these creatures lands down
some 25 feet from you.
What do you do?
Can I throw that thing that I said I had?
My crazy like super ninja star like just as a reaction.
Because it's in my hand, I've been carrying it.
It took me three years to make.
Exactly.
This cost so many gold.
How I envision it as you like retract it, like if it connects, it like sticks in
with one and I feel like collapses on top of it with like some of the other ones
like almost rolling into whatever you're attacking.
Oh yeah, tearing into.
It's like a bear trap you can throw at people.
Kind of.
Yeah, I love it.
Let's make it cool because you're doing something custom, you're making something really good.
Only the finest materials here.
This is a dope weapon, Bonwyn's ability to use this dope weapon in question.
That's true.
But let's find out.
Maybe it's not quite bAlydinced yet, you know, maybe you haven't finished it yet.
I built it for an elf and I'm a dwarf, like everything's thrown off.
Everything's all out.
He handed over to Kavlaranan.
Let's just make it five daggers, 5d4 plus five.
But I have to, but I have to hit it first.
Gotta make an attack coral first, yeah.
So we're rolling you guys.
Hell yeah.
So that's a 25 to hit.
Fuck yeah.
Amazing.
She's well past beta testing, y'all.
Yeah, right?
Yeah, but this thing's gonna take like a legendary action.
Yeah, 100% for nothing.
God, what a dick move to put a legendary creature against some level ones, right?
Three of them.
14 damage.
Plus five?
Plus five.
Then 19 damage.
So 19 damage.
So this one lands down on the ground and Bon, when you throw this, what do we want
to call this?
We throw this dagger star towards the creature and it impales in its side.
Shitty.
Should be the star.
Bizarre, as you see this dagger fly, you notice that along the side, along the
flank of it, there's this blackening of its skin, which leads you to believe that
this is the one you hit with your earlier.
I'm gonna say, good, you hit the damaged one already.
Perfect.
That was my plan.
Can I make that my sneak attack?
It would be sneaky.
They weren't expecting a star shitty.
Just let me hit an extra d6 on this guy.
Come on.
Give me a d6.
Just give me three more damage, come on.
It's all I got.
I don't know how to play a rogue yet, guys, because I haven't been doing any rogue-y
things.
Yup.
I played a rogue for like three years.
Never did a sneak attack.
Never did a sneak attack, not once.
Monster lands down, dagger flies out, does a substantial amount of damage.
It lets out a growl and turns its attention to you and your group.
You hear from the far side of the docks a scream of pain as you see one of these
monsters is like in the mix of the people over there now.
A couple guards are on it from your point of view, but they are being handily taken
care of at this moment.
One other thing you do hear from the other side of the city, it's a ways away, but
you begin to hear the sound of drums echoing through the city.
Like steel drums?
Is it like an island rhythm?
Steel drums.
The seaweed is always greener.
Kiss the girl.
I can't resist.
Coming like from the far side of the artisan district.
From the noble city.
Oh, from the noble side.
No, from the noble side, more the military barracks.
I did think it was going to be Stomp coming for an impromptu show or something.
That's right.
Implying that more military are on their way.
You don't know how long it's going to take them to get there though.
Through this, Alydin has crouched down and out of her bucket has pulled a small
torch and the thing that she has to light it with.
Like a flint?
Flint?
Flint, yep.
Lights, lights the torch on fire and like is holding it out bravely.
Like it just in front, just in front of her, just trying to be like,
Back beast.
Yes, that's right.
I think with that, Dase is going to step in front of you between you and the monster.
His sword's long since been drawn.
Alydin, you need to, you need to take that and get back.
Find safety.
Well, I, I can help.
Okay, but maybe not in the mouth of this creature that's right in front of us as
it takes a jump towards you and stops like a foot away from him and is going to try to bite him.
Oh yes.
Alydin is staggering back.
So yeah, like takes a leap.
I said he was about 25 feet, takes a huge leap and like the ground crunches underneath
this creature's feet and is going to try to bite him.
It gets two bite attacks.
The first one is going to hit.
Dase isn't level one.
No, I assume Dase is more of like a level seven.
A huge chunk comes out of Dase and he lets out a scream and drives his sword
into the creature with advantage because he's close but not grappled and is going to hit.
And that same one is going to take nine slashing damage.
With that one moving forward, would two of them be within like 40 feet of each other?
You've got one that came down from the bridge side of the docks.
The one in the middle is still up on top of a building and the other one is on the far side of the docks.
Oh, within a group of people, right?
Right.
So no, they have not yet come close to each other.
Well, if none are within 40 feet of each other, then what I'm going to do is go
and take the torch of one of the frightened guards and I'm going to set the barricade
ablaze and I will use my action to cast control flame to assist that.
Hoping that knowing what I know as far as seeing these things in darkness,
they're attacking at night.
Hopefully a lot of light will deter them in some way, shape or form.
So I'll do that and with my bonus action,
I'll bust out my scimitar and start doing a blade dance to help my AC and movement.
Should I light something on fire too?
Do it.
Yeah, fire.
Fire is a great idea.
Everybody.
She sees a hay pile and just starts like literally lighting everything that is wooden.
Don't need to tell her twice.
Or looks dry.
Yeah, and there's debris, right?
I mean, you're at the docks.
There's debris.
There's crates.
So like, grabbing debris.
I'm lighting shit on fire.
Like lighting it, like kind of making impromptu torches,
giving those to other people, like kill the beast.
Flames begin to rise along the barricade as people are rushing to the other side.
The creature that is closest to you, that attacked Dace,
would be closest to that first fire that you lit.
It doesn't leave melee with Dace,
but its attention is quickly drawn to the fire
and away from the immediate danger that it otherwise feels that it's in.
Well, I think if it was noticeable that the flame, like, it didn't like it,
then yeah, like light it up.
Because we're at the river, which is like a natural barrier, right?
So if we light things along that and get everybody on the other side,
I mean, there's one of them over there, isn't there?
But two on the one side, one on the other.
I mean, it seems like the best idea.
Yeah, I think it's a great option.
There's no good.
There's no, yeah, there's no like strong option here.
Plus we know that the soldiers, like we've heard the drumming,
so we know they're coming on the other side.
So in theory, maybe they can help with that one that's on the other side.
We're just trying to make them not kill anybody in the meantime.
Exactly, until reinforcements come.
Heavily trained and armed reinforcements, which is what we need right now.
Did I mention I have 10 HP?
Yeah, don't get bit.
It's not on us.
So flames begin to light all along the dock side
and you see them just running down all of these different hay bales
and barriers that are naturally set up down at the dock.
People are rushing on and now pulling, whatever,
anchors or ropes off of the boats.
We haven't heard from Cav in a little bit.
What's Cav doing?
Cav is attempting to get as much like flammable material
as he can and like spread it around so more fires can be set.
Not the boats.
Not those.
So all along this side of the dock,
flame is making its way down into the dock
and building somewhat of a barrier between the one up on the roof
and the docks itself.
And anybody paying attention to that one,
you see it starts to pace as that fire is being lit.
The one that is fighting Dace is going to,
at this moment, try to back up a little bit
which will provoke an opportunity attack from Dace.
He is going to hit it as it is.
He's trying to just reposition itself.
He's going to take another 11 slashing damage
and moves out of reach of Dace there
and is prowling along, keeping an eye on you and your group
as you are passing these torches down to other people
and getting these flames lit.
I think Alydin is doing something reckless
like a 14-year-old would
and is finding chunks of like wood
that is on fire
and she is quickly scooping it into her slingshot
and is shooting them.
She's burning her hands bad.
It's not a good choice,
but 14-year-olds don't make good decisions.
So you're shooting them at the monster?
Yeah.
Okay, you want to make an attack roll?
And it's a monster that's on Dace
because he's like my guard dad.
Got it.
Guard dad.
He's like my guard dad.
Does Dace live in the divorced dad's apartment building?
Oh, my God.
We don't know yet.
I hope not.
A 15?
Will not hit.
It will glance off of the creature.
It doesn't look like it makes enough impact
to do anything.
Maybe it starts some other fires
closer to it though or something.
Maybe it does.
It ricochets.
Yeah.
Skids into...
Fall short and like some grass on fire or something.
Sure.
Yeah.
Skids into some crates on top of some grass.
The one that was on Dace
is now prowling along the perimeter.
It looks like it's moving in the direction
of the other one that is down in the ground.
If there seems to be fire going
and people seem to be getting the idea
of having torches or something flaming,
then I'm going to move more onto the dock
to make sure people are getting on the boats
untied, pushed off, right?
Like to try and get them moving.
There is a monster in the lake,
but I mean this is a more clear and present danger.
Yeah, absolutely.
I mean you don't know that there's a monster.
That's true.
Like that was seen behind the camera.
You don't know that's there.
I do know there's pirates in the lake.
Yeah.
But still.
Long rumored pirates.
Okay, make an athletics check to see...
Nad 20.
Ding.
Oh my god.
Bonwyn is like leaping over top of any
of these burning crates.
Like a very action moment,
like moving down and helping untie these ropes
and getting these ships out there.
An Olympic hurdler.
You're able to get one out and move on
to the second one before anything else happens there.
And I'm assuming some of these
are hopefully bigger boats,
like shipping kind of boats,
so there actually is like a good amount
of people on them.
Everything in here with the exclusion
of a couple smaller vessels
are all shipping vessels.
Seeing those two reconnect,
getting closer together,
I think that would cue me in
to do the thing I've been wanting to do,
and that is to cast slow.
And as long as they're within 40 feet of each other
because I can do like a 40 foot cube,
I need them both to give me
a wisdom saving throw.
Oh, I hope they're dumb as shit.
They might be.
I hope so too.
We shall see.
14.
Okay, so you are timing this
as they are getting within that range.
So as this second one is moving towards,
the other one is taking people out.
It is dealing with everybody around it.
That's an 11 on the die,
but it has a plus five wisdom.
Plus five wisdom.
Six turns out not dumb as shit.
Deep lore down underground.
Hey, damn.
Damn, damn.
But that's only one, right?
There's two in that cube.
That's one.
That's an eight.
Plus five is a 13.
Well, fantastic.
That one is slowed.
It will take a negative two to its AC
and dexterity saving throws.
It can't use reactions.
On its turn, it can either take an action
or a bonus action, not both.
And regardless of the ability of the creature
or magic items,
it can only make one melee or ranged attack
during its turn.
Sick.
What a fucking awesome spell.
That's pretty good.
Pretty good.
Not too shabby.
That's 40 feet of movement to approach the one
that was moving towards the other one
that left Dace.
Okay.
You would be able to make it up to that creature
if you wanted to
or any distance that you need to be.
Closing that distance.
The sound of the drumming is getting closer
and you see torchlight now emanating
through the main square on the noble side,
which is approaching the bridge.
You not only hear the sound of drums,
you hear the sound of a steady military cadence
of a large squadron of people
coming around this corner.
You see the first few of them,
they're not going to be able to make it this turn,
likely next turn or perhaps even one after that.
Cav, you had been helping set fires.
As you are doing that,
you look up and you see the glowing eyes
of the one on the rooftop.
What maybe was distracted before,
but now you have a better view
with the light all around you,
is you see that this one is,
its neck is beginning to glow
just like a soft red
and it looks like it's taking in a huge breath.
It's doing a mating dance.
Absolutely it is.
It's the male of the species.
Turns around.
It's coming onto,
it's coming onto Cav.
I'm not surprised.
He's very fetching in his sleep outfit.
That's right.
His sleep outfit.
I'm going to call pajamas from now on.
My sleep tuxedo.
We'll be right back.
It's the middle.
Hey friends, welcome to the middle.
It's good to see you here.
It's not just me from the first one
and then me and Amy from the second one.
It's all of us.
We're all here.
Everybody.
The gang's back together again.
Yeah, we are.
That's right.
So talk to Amy about it in the last episode,
but how's everybody feeling about season four?
We're all very excited on this end of the call.
Oh, I love it.
It's so fun.
There's so much action.
It's exhausting, honestly.
Spook, it's scary.
Was a comment in the Discord,
I think from Arachan,
that the stakes feel real.
Oh, yeah.
Not just like we're floating through the world.
Happy and go.
I'm as happy and go and carefree.
Yeah.
But also it is fun to light things on fire.
Yep.
Yeah.
And it's true.
I like how at the beginning of this,
we were like, listen,
we're gonna like lower stakes,
slowly start to build.
Everything's on fucking fire.
Well, we did lower stakes for a program.
You can't have no stakes.
We did like a whole season until heist.
Well, there was pirates in there
that were trying to eat us.
Well, that's true.
That's true.
But anyway.
Allegedly cannibalistic pirates.
Love season four slash season three,
chapter two or whatever we're calling it.
Yeah.
I like it.
Yeah, it's going good so far.
I'm having a lot of fun with it.
We were gonna talk about the fact
that you could get merch on Patreon,
but this feels a lot better.
So if you want to sign up on Patreon
to support us as we're creating this wonderful
high stakes season,
you can do so
at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
You get a seven day free trial
when you sign up
and when you stick around
for three consecutive months
or not three consecutive months,
but three months
because you can dip out
and come back should you need to.
You get some merch.
There's a sticker at the $5 tier,
a mug at the supporting producers tier
and the game time,
which has been pretty much
on lockdown for a little while now.
You get a hoodie.
Yeah, you do.
Oh yeah.
But those ones don't open up very often.
So we appreciate you for thinking about it
and hope to see you over there.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
We'll see you over there.
Okay, let's get back to the episode now.
Bye.
What kind of like debris is around Cav
that hasn't been set on fire?
Yeah.
Well, I mean,
if Alydin has anything to say
about a lot of things
that have been set on fire,
but there certainly would be like planks of wood.
There would be
Oh, you know what?
Let's have it be set on fire
because like that's just going to add to the festivities.
It's better.
I'm going to grab something
that looks like would be okay to throw
whether it's just like a hunk of wood
or whatever it is.
True.
And I'm going to cast the light spell on it.
Okay.
Sick.
I touch it and it sheds a bright light
in a 20 foot radius
for an hour
and then also a dim light
for an additional toy.
And you're hucking it
at the one on the roof?
Absolutely throwing it
at the one with the red neck
that's like inhaling.
Yeah.
Make an attack roll.
We'll see how well you do here.
If you do very poorly,
like you're not going to get it up there,
but if you hit it, great.
If you get it in the vicinity,
like it'll at least be up on the roof.
Yeah.
It'll maybe spook it a little
if I don't hit it.
Calf played high school football.
He's got a perfect spiral on it.
He did.
It's been a few years.
Muscle memory kicked in though.
Right.
Absolutely.
It's 13 on the die,
so that's a 14.
So it doesn't hit to do any real damage,
but you do make it up on the roof,
which distracts this creature for a moment.
It clangs down.
You see the fire begin to swell
around the edge of the building.
Oops.
But like whatever's going on
with that neck can't happen.
So like.
Yeah.
It backs up several steps.
So you lose direct line of sight of it.
You can kind of see the top of its head.
It starts inhaling smoke
and becomes weak from that.
You hear wheezing
and then the sound of a giant inhaler.
The one on the far side of the dock
that was surrounded by guards.
You see all of the guards
that were in vicinity
have now been knocked down to the ground.
They do look deceased from where you are
and it begins running towards
one of the far ships
on the far side of the dock.
So opposite side from where you are.
Perfect.
I light one of my short bow arrows
on fire and shoot it at it.
Yes, of course.
Cool.
That's a 25 day hit.
Damn dude.
And that is nine damage.
Plus like if you wanted to give me
any kind of like special fire damage
or something I'm ready.
Give me a D6 of fire damage.
Three.
Hoping to also distract it away
from chasing the people on the boat too.
So it's like beginning to like
leaps and bounds towards this ship
and as it is getting ready to jump
this arrow strikes into it
and lets out a growl
as it skids to a stop
and like rolls to its side
and is standing up
like pushing itself off of the people
that it has just crushed underneath its weight
and turns and has now
got its eyes locked on you, Bonwyn.
Great.
Loves to be the center of attention like that.
Alydin slingshotted.
Slingshot.
That's it.
Alydin slingshot.
Slingshot.
As much as she could
with her hands
and it was just getting,
it was getting ouchy
and she turns and sees
Bonwyn fire off an arrow
at the one creature
and from inside her bucket
she pulls out her boomerang
and hooks it at,
I'm just Dennis the Menace.
Hell yeah, dude.
I forgot about this.
I forgot you had a boomerang.
I was so delighted.
Yeah, a boomerang.
So I'm going to,
I'm going to throw my boomerang at it
because she's using what she's got.
Absolutely.
Throwing the boomerang
at that Bonwyn just shot.
Yes.
Okay.
Yeah.
Well, that's a nat one.
But it says if I miss
it comes back to me.
But have I hit some innocent bystander
with my boomerang?
Scared citizen number two.
Because it was one
and I know there's punishment
that comes along with that.
You know what?
So it goes out
and clearly misses.
It comes back, but falls short.
And as you look at it
and begin to move towards it
to go pick it up
because you've got a bit of a clear site
debris that's spread across
that's been spread across
in all the chaos
begins to light between you
and the boomerang.
So you are now being
more or less encircled in flame.
Just me?
Well, you and like a couple
like other people trying to run away.
Like, but you are cut off
from that section of the dock right now.
Am I cut off from my group?
So Bizard
is up on the walkway
moving towards the one
that is trying to get over
to the one that Bonwyn shot.
Cav probably be closest to you.
Bonwyn is down
trying to push boats off
or at least in that direction.
So Cav is closest to you right now.
Dace would be not too far
but the flames are growing around you.
Oh, I want to run back to Cav or Dace.
Whoever's
Amy, I'm going to need you to come up
with a move
that you can call the OK Boomer
for your boomerangs.
Once you imbue it with magic.
There we go.
Right?
Then it becomes the OK Boomer.
What's Dace doing?
He done anything lately for me?
I mean, he did get
I think he hasn't done it.
He did get chomped.
He sees Bizard
like rush up to this one
that he was fighting.
Turns and sees Alydin
like being more surrounded by flame.
And I think he's going to evaluate those two
and try and go help Alydin
in this moment.
He doesn't have a monster directly on him.
He turns and sees
that the military forces
which there are a large number of them
now on the other side of the bridge itself.
So they are getting there
and he's going to rush down
and try and scoop up Alydin.
Do you allow him to do so?
Yeah.
OK.
It's a scary situation.
He's going to pick you up.
That's going to be
we'll say half of his movement
because you were running back towards him
and he's going to try and move you
back towards the bridge
where the forces are coming.
So he can make it basically
from his position
to pick up Alydin and back again.
At that
you hear the twang of arrows loosing
from the other side of the bridge
and they're flying over
and towards the monsters.
You see a couple of them stick into
like right in front of you
Bizard a couple of the arrows
stick down into the flesh
of the one in front of you.
Bonwyn you see the one
that's now kind of prowling
towards you
get one stuck in its side
doesn't seem to lose its pace
on this one
and then some others
just scatter to the ground
so there are loose arrows
and I yell
next time light them on fire
just offering helpful tips.
Yeah.
Okay.
That one in front of me
I'd give it an attack or two.
Is this the one
that I happened to slow
or is that the one
that Bonwyn's working with?
The one that Bonwyn is working with
has been slowed.
Perfect.
The one that you are hitting
has taken the most damage
and the one that you hit
with the cold much earlier.
Hell yeah.
Well let's keep that going.
We're going to do
two Scimitar attacks.
Two attacks?
You are a high level.
That is going to be
a miss on the first one
and a miss on the second one.
Shit.
I'm dancing more than I'm attacking.
You're confusing it.
You got so lost in the movement.
Alright.
Remember your steps.
Left, right, one, two, three.
I'm going to stay right up in its face
and that'll be that.
It's going to turn
and try and attack you.
Okay.
A turn.
I mean you're right up on its face
so it's going to
first of all does it recharge?
It does not.
Okay.
First one to hit you.
This one has both of its multi attacks.
It's going to be a 12.
Nope.
Excellent.
And the second one
is going to be an 11.
So also not going to do it.
He's mesmerized by your steps.
So maybe it is working.
Mesmerized.
Yeah.
The two of you are in this dance of attacking
but not hitting each other in this moment.
Bonwyn.
The one on the other side of the docks
is now like pushing its way through people
that are trying to flee out of the way towards you.
Leaps up into the air towards you.
How far is it?
It's pretty close.
Well if it's leaping up into the air
it's going to be within striking distance.
If you don't do something to interrupt it
it's going to land on you.
Well I'm going to do something to interrupt it
or I'm certainly going to try.
I am going to try to hit it
with my short sword
but it has another enemy close to it
so I can still sneak attack it.
And it's a nat 20 again.
Oh my god.
And that doubles the sneak attack.
Dice two.
Hell yeah.
Yeah it does.
Does it?
Yeah.
Okay.
Oh boy.
Oh wow.
So many dice to roll.
I might not die you guys.
I might not die.
It is going to jump off my butt.
Oh my god.
Okay.
12 plus four is 16
and then my sneak attacks
were very bad.
Three more damage.
So it leaps up towards you
and this is the one that is also slowed
so your attack is on point
and it's a little bit thrown off
by the spell that's been cast on it
and you land a gnarly hit
with your short sword into its side
and as it's flying through the air
you're tearing along its side
which blood begins to pour out
as it lands down on the ground
right where you were standing.
Oh cool.
So it's like prone now
so can I like back up
without provoking an opportunity attack?
Yes.
Amazing.
I'm going to go ahead and do that.
That was a real close call.
It was.
It was quite close.
You rolled like a fucking champ.
Yep.
Dice is carrying Alydin.
He's going to finish running
to the other side of the street.
He's going to put you down
and like grab you by the shoulders
and say where are the other kids?
They're in the magic shop.
Okay you need to go
and be with them
and keep them safe.
I point back the way we came
amidst the fire
and the monsters.
He's going to yell go
and then he's going to turn
and move back towards where Bizard is
with that monster.
So you don't have to go
but that's what he's telling you to do.
I think that like...
I want her there
she's part of the team
but oh boy.
She's going to run.
Our dad told her to run.
So and she is...
And you know all the sneaky ways
to get everywhere anyway so like...
So as you turn
and you begin to run that way
like out of the corner of your eye
you see that the military forces
are now on the other side of the bridge.
Since they came into view
like they've picked up their pace
swords drawn are now rushing down
into the mix.
So there's a lot of bodies going on
there's a lot of things going on
and as you round the corner
you're dashing I assume
because you're not really
doing anything else.
So you've got double movement.
You can see the magic closet
down at the end.
Make a perception roll.
Oh I did that 20.
I'm going to roll with my left hand.
There we go.
We've cracked the code.
You make your way
part way down the street
and you're getting there
you're not going to be able
to make it this turn obviously.
But you hear the sound of movement
up on the rooftop
and you turn and you look
like you can see the glow
through the breaks in the buildings
of the fire that's lit
down at the docks.
But you see a sizable red glow
up on top of the building
immediately to your right.
You can't see a body
or a creature
or anything like that.
You just see this glow
and as you hear it
that glow disappears
towards where the action is.
As soon as I hear and see
I come to a dead stop
and I back myself into the shadows
if there's a garbage can
or crates of something.
I don't know.
I hide myself until
I feel like the danger has passed
and then I continue to book it
to the magic closet.
Kavlarananan, I think you're
one of the final ones
in this round
that hasn't done anything
in this immediate scene.
I haven't done fucking anything.
The look of shock
on everyone's face right now.
I'm trying to hit leave session
but it's grayed out.
I don't know what's going on.
It will not let me get out.
I have to put up with Amy's abuse.
So you had previously
huffed this flaming piece of wood
up on top to deter that one
from presumably letting out
another howl.
It's still visible
and it's stepping back towards
and it seems like it's surveying the scene.
If you want to get a sense of
maybe what it's thinking, doing,
you could roll an insight.
I'll take a chance on trying to
understand what it's up to.
11 plus 4, 15.
For the brief moment
that you're able to watch it,
it disappears and then comes back
and it looks like it's going to
recharge this howl again
but then sees that
the military forces are coming in
and it lets out not the same kind of howl
but lets out more of an upset shriek.
A call that looks like
out of the corner of your eye
perks the ears of the other two creatures
and then as you're watching this,
you see a figure come into view
very shadowy but like this
emanating aura around it
come up behind this creature.
Looks humanoid in nature.
I mean I don't love any sort of
like emanating aura
but I also don't know that it's a bad thing.
I'll try and find some cover
and just kind of see what's going on
with this aura that's showing up.
I'll try and find something that isn't burning
and kind of like crouch behind it
and just take a little look
at what's going on with this sitch.
Sure, so we'll say you're moving
more towards the bridge side of the dock
where all the soldiers are coming in.
Less towards the big scary monsters.
It's usually how I like to do it.
So the forces are rushing in.
Bonwyn, the one that you had attacked
they're now surrounding it, drawing in.
It's backing up towards you.
It's retreating from that position.
So I should stab it in the butt?
Would give you...
It's about this time in every season
that we need to stab something in the butt.
Absolutely.
Why have I said that exact phrase?
As every character I've ever played.
But are you just backing up towards me?
It's like getting...
I need to, right?
Yeah, go for it.
Great, sneak attack also.
I fucking love sneak attack, guys.
With my sword again, that's a 19 to hit.
That'll hit.
Eight points of damage.
Not great.
You stab into it.
It lets out a shriek
into you and try and knock you to the side.
Well, I can try.
I am short and stout.
I got a low center of gravity.
That's going to be a 23.
Jesus.
Well, that will do it.
It's not hitting you with its claws or its bite.
It's just hitting you with its back end there.
It is going to give you some damage
from falling to the ground.
This is where I die.
It's not a direct attack.
It's very small.
It's just going to be too bludgeoning damage.
Just 20% of your total life force.
That's practically dead.
If you make a strength saving throw,
you can see if you are knocked prone or not.
Well, that's only a seven.
So I think I am, unfortunately.
Yes.
So you are knocked to the ground.
You take this damage.
You're dazed as the forces are pushing it back.
It turns.
I'm going to try and save again.
That's another 13.
So it's going to retreat
in a manner that is
half of its speed,
which is going to give it 20 feet.
So it's not going to go as far as it would like,
but it would make it to
the edge of the dock
and is leaping over some of the flame.
Still very much within reach
for a lot of other people.
The one that you are on, Bizard,
there are military forces
flooding in behind you as well.
It sees those.
It's going to try and attack you.
It's coming in for a bite.
I'll give you first response to it.
We are going to just attack again.
That would be a 19 to hit
on the first attack.
19 is going to hit it this time.
And then a 15 on the second.
15 will not.
Well, we'll take the one.
That's better than what we got last time.
So we're making improvements slowly but surely.
It's going to be a good three
non-magical slashing damage.
So we're really making a difference in this world.
You're doing it.
Three damage it didn't have before.
That's right. Better steps.
Which is enough to stop its immediate attack.
And now that the forces
kind of have run in behind you,
it's going to try and scale the wall
successfully.
Very successfully.
So it takes a hit. I'll give you an opportunity attack
as it's turning and running.
23.
And that'll be six slashing damage.
Non-magical.
As it turns and leaps onto this wall,
you get one final swipe.
And with a couple of huge pulls up the wall,
it's now on the top.
Vlarin,
you are at a position where you're
watching the one
that maintained its position up on the roof
and you see this other one jump up.
And that figure comes up behind it.
As it gets closer,
like there's this
red flame
about it. That aura becomes more
clear as a flame. And
it brings down two
huge fists down on
top of the back of this creature.
And the creature
itself
disappears from view underneath
the weight of whatever this
thing is that
you're seeing.
Even amid all the chaos,
you hear this huge sickening
thud. And as you see this other one
pull up and see, like it
quickly jumps to the
other building and
is running along rooftops trying to
flee from its current position.
Okay, so something
both hurt and spooked it very badly.
Yeah. Is there anything you
want to do from your position?
No, I just want to take like a mental picture
of what I've seen so I can describe it
to everyone later. So the military forces
have now overwhelmed this position.
The ships have all been either let free
or have like the ropes have burned.
Some of the ships have some
flame attached to them and they're being
trying to be put out by some of the people on the
ships. But they're now
backing out into the river and down
into the lake. Any of
them that can. I'm going
to stand up. You stand up.
There's still one of these creatures
that is down in the mix
so to speak. And
it is now being attacked
by the military forces. Like they have it
completely surrounded. Of course I would roll a nat
one for the first one.
Did they light anything on fire as I helpfully
shouted to them?
My grapes at each other by accident.
Arrows have been
flaming. That's great.
They had initially come in with blankets to try
and put out the fire but then wrapped them
around their swords and were like this is probably
what we need to do. It was the
fire brigade that came over.
So they have
this one surrounded and are now
pushing all of their force on top of
this one. And with the number of military
here it goes down
not quickly and not
without a fight. Some soldiers lose
their fight as
well. But it does go
down in the midst of all of this
chaos. Alydin?
Yes? You?
Present!
You hid
amongst some trash cans
and crates and just watching what
you could see and then as you were
certain that the coast was clear you
make your way back to the magic closet
and you unlock it and lock it behind
you and make your way up to
Bizarre's home
in this place.
And you're looking around for everyone.
I don't have a key
to his personal abode.
I don't think. I have a key to the shop
but the apartment
upstairs I feel like
Tali and I definitely have a
knock. And so
I do my knock.
I'm not going to remember that.
I'll pick a different knock.
Tali, it's me. Hey.
Open it. Okay.
Door opens.
Come on in. Come on in.
We're all in here.
And I come in and I quickly shut the door behind
me. I don't bother locking it.
Is everything okay? No.
I look around.
Are any children
sleeping? No. Everybody's
in sheer panic. There's still
a lot of noise and chaos coming
in. Like there's a glow of fire coming
in through the windows.
Okay.
So.
I look at the kids and I'm like
just one. Just one second.
And I bring Tali out into
the hallway. Yeah. Cause
no sense in causing panic.
Okay.
There are three big
monster things. Three?
Yeah. And they seem to be kind
of scared of fire. Okay.
Is that the glow?
Yeah. We started setting
everything on fire. Of course.
That makes most sense.
Sure. My hands. I'm like
my hands? You set your hands on
fire? Well, sort of.
Anyway. Um. One of them
bit Dace. Oh god. Is he okay?
Yeah. No. He's fine.
But he told me to come here and
stay with you guys. How are the
kids? They're terrified. We're all terrified.
But we've been keeping calm and singing
songs and just trying to
trying to just quietly
just keep everyone calm.
What's that? And she looks out the window
and you turn and look out
the window and you see a figure
leaping across the
rooftop. Doesn't look like one of the creatures. You see a
figure leaping across the rooftop
and away from the
action. I don't know what
that is.
You know what though? Dace told us to stay here.
So let's stay
here. Um.
Let's stay here.
We move from
the magic closet over the rooftop
where we see the one
creature that had stayed most of the time
up on the roof is dead on
top of the roof. Down on
the ground the military forces have overrun
the second one down
in the dock itself and we see
the third one fleeing off
into the distance.
The entire dock
is burning or burnt to the ground.
And we see you
all collecting yourselves
as the military
forces who are sure that
this one creature is dead clear away
and are beginning to help those that are injured
and covering up those that have been
killed in this battle.
I'm
going to start organizing like
a bucket brigade or whatever
we can do to now start trying to get
the fires out before
we actually burn our whole town down.
Yeah Bazaar is going to start going around and
just casting controls flame to extinguish
like five foot cubes. Well that's
way cooler than what I'm doing.
But it's like the same idea.
I'm going
one side you're going the other.
There we go. Yeah.
There's nothing left. It's all burnt.
I'm like splashing water from the river
up. Cav is just
sitting holding his books.
Like I don't know what he just saw
but he's kind of
had his mind blown by
the things that happened tonight.
Oh and that's where we leave you.
It's everybody
working to
help anyone injured
get to the ships that have drifted off
into the lake and just
sitting
in the moment that is this attack
on Vintersmouth.
Dumbgeons and Dragons
Season 4 Episode 3
starring Amy More as
Alydin, Carla Maxted as
Bonwyn Everpain, Tom Laird as
Kavlarananan Goldweave, Kyle
Claset as Bazaar the Wizard,
and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue Editing by Carla Maxted
and Sound Design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from
Epidemic Sound and Slipstream
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and
character designs are by Matt Garbutt
and a huge thank you to our supporting
producers.
We hope to see you over there,
Patreon.com slash dumpdragoncast
and maybe we'll see you in the community
we're over on Discord. You have a great
week, we'll talk to you soon.
And then the theme song goes and it's
really fun and everything's happening
in this...
We can't kill anybody with this music.
They just really won't see it coming.
Is that how you say that?
I believe it's encroaching?
I feel like it was a combo word but
it actually worked great in the situation.
So I say language is always evolving.
It's a new portmanteau.
You're good.
That's right.
Well, if it sounds weird
in the edit, just flag it
and I'll bloop it out with farm noises.
I noticed it when you said it and I thought
I'm not sure that's the word.
They're crouching and encroaching.
But maybe they were crouching.
I think you just made up
the perfect word.
I just had a moment where I was like,
have I been saying this word wrong?
Webster's Dictionary Word of the Year 2024.
Encroaching.
Perfect. I've written it down
as a note to come back to you later.
But it felt right. It felt right in the moment.
Mail it to yourself so when it is the word of the year
you can claim ownership.
Make it the title of this episode.
Word of the Year?
Encroaching.
The other side of the bridge and they
were like, obviously.
Get your nose out of the garbage.
That's what Bonwyn yells to the soldiers.
What are they doing? Priorities, you guys.
Get your nose out of the garbage.
Dumbgeons & Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.