The battle continues. Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
Yeah, it's a 16 on my strength check.
You turn around and strike your shield, which lets out this ring through the air, clashing into all these music notes.
There is a memory that's behind you.
What's the memory of, Tom?
The memory is of the first time Kav went to the Brewed Awakening.
You see yourself in this memory and Bench is behind the counter and you're going up and you see the small talk that you're having.
And the sound wave from this, this smash onto the shield, like waivers this memory.
And then you see it fracturing at the edges and falls apart.
You manage to like for a moment as it as it fractures and like falls into the abyss, the memory fades from your mind.
But then like glimpses of it start to come back like you see like fractures of it floating through space.
And that's what you're remembering.
You're not remembering the full thing.
Not like you used to.
Just getting like snippets.
Yeah.
Okay.
Sorry.
The thing you actually wanted to do though, does propel you forward.
How far does it propel you forward?
It propels you forward 15 feet.
So you're you begin to move and like there's memories floating past and you like manage to not hit another one.
But yeah, you move yourself forward 15 feet in the direction that you wanted towards the music box.
Okay.
Anything else you would like to do?
Or communicate?
No, I mean, I think it was a pretty like clear example.
Like, I don't know if I was watching other people take their turns like they'd also be like, how the fuck does this work?
And trying to just gather information, right?
So I don't think I need to like explain it.
Maybe as you look back and see like, you know, confirming that you have moved in space and where you wanted to go.
And like you grab your head and actually as that happens, you're going to take one psychic damage.
Did I grab my head too hard?
Yeah, from losing the memory.
But yes, you grab your head, you smack yourself a little too hard and you're like, God damn it.
Not again.
You're going to take that damage and then you're going to look back and you see the banjo man like his arms pull up from the strings
and another strum of the banjo rings out.
And the seat stays where it is.
But you see him teleport to one of these memories and he's inside Everbane's like moving around and he's like running his hands
as he's like finger tapping the banjo, running his hands along all of the tools and instruments and like chucking them into the forge.
Moving the small hammer to where the big hammer goes.
Big hammer to where the small hammer goes.
I've got all kinds of crazy things in there.
I hope he pokes something and it turns into nine blades and stabs him in the balls.
Oh, Jesus.
Whoa.
And as he's doing that, Bonwyn, you see like this memory is fracturing around the edges and you're I mean, this is this is your place.
It's very firmly cemented in your mind.
But like that starts to waver as you see these fractures like something's happening in this moment.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Russ More, he, him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
Listen, I did all kinds of stuff to that box.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she, her.
I think we should just like relax.
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave, he, him.
I really hope we have like a Lord of the Rings dwarf toss in our future.
And Kyle Claset as Bazaar the Wizard, he, him.
Stop these little gremlins from devouring us.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast and you can join today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
where when you sign up for any of our tiers, you get a seven day free trial which gives you access to bonus episodes,
backstage access and a whole lot more like the great discord community where people are just hanging out all the live long day having the greatest time.
And with that, we hope to see you over there.
But fuck it, let's play.
Brings us back to the top.
I would just like to say it really seems like I could have finished my Twizzler's Pull and Peel in all of that.
Just throwing that out there.
I just want it on the record.
It's your turn now.
So it has no one, Amy.
That doesn't help me now, does it?
You move through the space, banjo man is up in this memory.
All of a sudden these giant razor sharp music notes begin to crash down from somewhere.
You don't see them and then you hear them land in all of these memories and you see fractures like splinter out and pieces of these memories are falling into the abyss.
One lands on the platform that you are on and splits it in two like earthquake.
You are now on two separate planes.
You were close to Bizard.
Yes, still maintaining.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
So Bizard and Alydin are on one side, Cab and Bonwyn are on the other.
So you're now on two separate pieces of this platform that you are on.
Which brings us to Alydin.
Bizard, I know there's a lot going on.
But I think I've heard this song for like a year straight.
What do you mean?
I'm going to go crazy.
We have to stop the box.
OK, do you think since you're familiar, do you think there's something specific we should do?
I don't know.
He said something about not the song, not finishing or needing needing to finish the song or.
I don't know, maybe it's stuck on a loop.
Maybe it's broken and you have to fix it.
You like to tinker with shit.
Well, yeah, but I mean, like I I did all listen.
I did all kinds of stuff to that box.
OK, yeah, like short of lighting things on fire because I didn't have that.
But if I did, I would have tried to light it on fire, too.
Nothing changed it.
Think about what we had talked about with the coin.
We got you safety.
You were trying to break something.
Maybe you're not meant to break.
Maybe you're meant to fix and create.
I don't know how to do that.
I never knew how to do magic until I tried my first time.
So. Get at it.
OK. Get me there.
OK. Yeah, I'm going to do whatever I need to do to help out and get to the get to the music box.
OK, you're so proud of us right now.
You're doing a great job.
I really hope we have like a Lord of the Rings dwarf toss in our.
That's just what I was a child.
Is he going to throw her in this moment?
Whatever I need to do, Russ.
I said I said I wouldn't try to die.
You miss the void twist.
I come back out fully grown.
I'm going to say you wake up trapped in a in some sort of container and music box.
Is it me? Am I the ballerina?
In the future, you're the archfey that goes back in time.
Oh, God. Stop.
Oh, Carly, you're muted.
Earmuffs. We're not doing time travel.
Yeah, time travel is off the table.
The look on Ross's face is just like, huh, Kyle.
Listen, I know you're new here.
I'm a bad influence and I'm sorry.
We know you're new here, but also the cause of all of these problems.
There is a thread.
No.
All right. Throw me.
No, I'm just kidding.
Just kidding.
You still haven't had your turn, really?
No, I haven't.
But like my turn is me.
Like, I don't know.
Try to think about the things that have happened surrounding any time that I've had a shiny coin.
Make a an investigation or an arcana check.
It will be.
It will be an investigation.
Investigate.
Oh, fuck off.
Ten.
She's back.
I have a plus four.
Okay.
You take what Bizard has said and you are looking around.
You're looking to the music box.
You're looking at these notes and you're trying to trying to make a connection.
And while you don't make.
You don't find the solution.
It becomes clearer that the music notes around you are part of that solution.
You need to find the end to this song.
Your degree in musical theory is finally paying off.
Oh, thank God.
You've listened to this song enough and you hear like a certain.
Like some of the notes hit in different ways and then like something clicks for you.
You have to find how to find a way to resolve the song that you have listened to over and over and over and over.
And it is floating around.
Okay.
Can I touch the music notes?
Do you try to reach out and I try to touch a music note carefully.
I'm not going to be like, you know, one is coming within range that you could grab it.
Make a dexterity check.
How about a 40?
You reach out and you grab this note and you feel like an energy coursing through your arm and up into your shoulder and across your body.
And it's like ringing inside your body.
You don't know if it's the right note, but you can grab them.
Bazaar, you in particular see like Bonwyn, you're a little focused on the memory of him smashing your shit.
Rage.
But yeah, Bazaar, you particularly see that she has like these are animate objects that you can manipulate and grab.
Is it a specific note or is it like we got a quarter note here, half note?
Is it on a staff?
They do have whole notes, half notes, quarter notes, all mixed in there.
But then there are also colors associated more with like the actual note notation.
So they're not on a staff.
But yeah, yeah.
So correlation of pitch to color.
If it's it's not my turn, is it?
It's not your turn.
I'm just giving you.
Okay.
Yeah, because you're the only one actually seeing this right now.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, for sure.
Yeah, I just got to start picking notes out of the air.
Like, does this one feel right?
I'm collecting colors.
I love it.
Wait, if I let it go, does it float away?
Yes.
Fuck, I try to put them in my bucket.
Okay, you begin shoving notes in your bucket.
Never know when you're going to need them.
Bonwyn, it is your turn.
Carry a tune with a bucket.
I have been reading my character sheet and in my inventory I have a bell.
So I am going to start playing the bell to the tune of the music and be like,
hey, Kav, what do you think?
Like, like if we were going to finish this, like we need to like do,
how's this sound?
We should start a band.
Like, you know, like because it just keeps, it's never, it's not stopping.
You know, I love it.
He needs it to stop.
And then remember with like the kids on the stage and then they wanted to end and then.
Yeah, like it was like missing that one thing.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So what can I roll?
Music theory.
Carla, not a musician.
Maybe Bonwyn is.
Maybe Bonwyn comes up with a good solution.
Intelligence or performance would be a roll.
It did sound like that.
100%.
It sounded like the right stuff.
Yeah, yeah.
The notes are ringing out and like, like Alydin scream and Cav's shield hit,
like they begin reverberating through the space and like are bouncing into these musical
notes and some of them are shot off towards the memory where you still see the
banjo man playing around in your space and he gets to like a wall as some of
these music notes are like falling into them and the fractures are getting deeper
within this memory and he's reaching up to like family portraits and he's holding
them up and like the strings are just like tugging and pulling at his face.
I feel like I can't get distracted by that because yes, like that one memory
would be like one moment of my memory of that place.
That's not my entire memory of my whole life there or that would be crazy.
That would be crazy.
Is it that crazy?
It might be, but that would be crazy because that's like the 50 years of my life in
that one thing when the other one like when Cavs was going to Brewed Awakening
for the first time.
Which is really when his life began.
It's when your life, you're right.
You're right.
So anyway, I'm playing my bell.
Love it.
Just like seeing what happens.
Yeah, like all of these notes begin moving and like you...
How far away are Alydin and like have we pushed away from them or are they still
pretty close to us?
Like yeah, you're still fairly close.
Like you could probably jump it if you wanted to.
Oh, I just want to talk to them.
You can absolutely talk to them.
I feel like it's really small.
Alydin is like shoving notes into her bucket at this point.
Okay, so we just let's...
Yes.
I'm sorry.
Is this like a futile frustrating situation?
Like I'm trying to like...
You feel like you're doing something, right?
Yeah.
Well, I mean...
So we can talk.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Guys, we got to finish the song.
Like, like how do we make it stop?
Grab some notes.
Like, you know, at the end of a play and then everyone comes and
bows and it's done.
Oh, should we just clap?
We need to do that but for the song.
Alydin starts clapping and then...
Okay, I'm going to clap too.
I love it.
Immediately the note starts flying out of her bucket and she stops
and she starts grabbing them again.
Okay, so but now at least I see that you're grabbing notes.
So I love that.
Like now because I wasn't watching that before, right?
Yes.
So playing my bell.
I'm trying to grab notes.
I'm like, can I tell what the...
Hmm.
No, that doesn't really make sense.
Bell kind of only plays one note.
Just trying to think if I could like correspond it to a
color is like hitting a certain thing so I can like...
Make an investigation or an arcana check for that one.
You know, what can I...
What conclusions can I draw?
15.
Investigation.
Yeah, you you begin trying to reach and grab some of them
like you you miss they like fly by you but you grab one
and like there's similar to what I described of Alydin
like there's this resonance that begins to move through
your body and you you feel you get a very strong sense
that grabbing the right notes is what you need to do
and you feel like the one that you have just reached up
and and taken hold of is one that you should probably keep.
Okay.
This is one of them.
This one feels like right in my heart.
Begins to emanate this light from it in your hand.
Dope.
This is...
I start like...
I start grabbing them out of my bucket and holding it
and waiting and seeing if a light
shines and if it doesn't I chuck it.
Yeah.
And I totally know a hundred percent and like I'll put my
bell in my pocket.
Like this is what I'm doing now.
Like this seems like we're doing something.
You made one glow.
Hey, did you forget there are horrors in this place?
I don't care about the horrors.
If you just pretend they don't exist, then they don't.
Yeah.
So these horned whalers they come out.
Let's see.
I prefer Bob Marley and the whalers.
If I have my choice.
Does she have her choice?
No.
Surprise.
Of course you do.
So Bob Marley comes out of the corner.
Right?
And that's the end.
That's it.
He finishes the song.
No cry.
It's beautiful.
Three little birds.
We're good.
Love it.
So floating brass instruments with twisted skeletal
faces.
That's way less nice.
Yeah.
Come out of the darkness.
Sure.
The minute we start to figure out the shit of other music
notes, all of a sudden the horrors show up.
One is going to be coming towards you, Bonwyn, and
one is going to be going towards you, Alydin.
So Bonwyn, that's an 18.
Means we're on the right track.
Yeah, that'll hit.
As it lets out this scream from the skeletal face
and Alydin, that is a 14.
Yeah, that'll hit me.
Okay.
I'm getting hurt for the first time, you guys.
I love that it's a brass instrument.
So I assume it's like...
It has been that it goes...
Yeah.
Fucking thing.
It's comedy in it.
It's like now's not the time.
Bonwyn, you're going to take two psychic damage.
Alydin, you are going to take also two psychic damage.
Jesus.
That's a lot when you only have 18.
And they are like surround like they're more of these.
You see them coming out of the darkness.
They're surrounding you, which will take us to Bazaar'd.
Cool.
Seeing the reactions of people grabbing notes and everything.
I want to take a moment to a quick scan of the memories
in the area.
See if I can find one of Calder's that maybe has
some sheet music on it.
Let's see if any of them happen to have any sheet music
in them.
It's like this just seems like...
I don't know.
Can we go back to that memory of him noodling in the cafe?
Right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Some of him with his banjo when he was still Calder.
Yeah.
He might have come down on a napkin maybe.
Maybe.
Make an investigation.
Yeah, an investigation rule.
Okay.
That's a 21.
Sweet.
Somebody's good at rolling dice and being smart.
It is like 30 feet from the platform that you are on,
but you see very similar space to the memory that kind of
brought you here.
You see Calder before he's the banjo man like table
with papers spread out on them and he's frantically
writing.
You can only assume that he's writing music, but that's
what you see.
But actually we've judged him too harshly.
It's his dissertation.
He's working.
I was going to go the opposite direction.
I thought it was going to be like Dear Diary.
Bethany ignored me again today.
Sold my soul to a devil today.
He's just drawing mammaries.
He's doing that S.
Oh no, we've got to use mammaries as a memory.
Like pun in a thing somewhere.
Someone write that down.
Where's Jess?
If only we recorded these for posterity.
Yeah, so it's too bad.
It's gone forever.
Seeing that I'm going to use my action to cast mage
hand 30 feet away from me and then use my mage hand
to bring that memory to me.
Love it.
Very cool.
Okay, not the box though.
We don't know if that box is more than 15 pounds.
It seems like we found something.
Yeah, I don't know how much that box weighs.
And you just said you tried to destroy it.
Like you just told him like I tried to destroy it.
He told me to fix it.
Yeah, then these notes showed up and you started
grabbing those and that seems pretty good too.
Yeah.
So, okay.
Yeah, your mage hand is magic though.
Roll.
Oh, hell yeah.
Maybe the squirrel will come back.
Buster.
Roll me an attack first just to see.
What kind of attack?
Like a melee attack.
So like an unarmed strike.
That's going to be a 13.
So your mage hand much to your surprise actually appears
and you're able to make it go and you begin pulling
this memory back.
It makes it halfway like half the distance to you
and these horrors are like grabbing onto it.
Like they're holding onto the edges which are splintering
and they're like trying to it seems like they're
trying to devour it.
Not cool.
I'm going to let my friends know me like I think
perhaps the answer to the notes we need may be in this
memory.
Stop these little gremlins from devouring this.
Do what you can.
Welcome to the middle everybody.
Thanks for listening.
Thanks for being here.
Thanks for having a great time with us.
Hello.
Hi, how you doing?
Assuming you're having a great time.
I only assume that they're having a great time.
That's what we hope.
We don't sound like we're having a great time.
We are also having a great time.
Are you having a great time?
Me?
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Great.
Well, like I mean like throughout the frustration and
sometimes in the game it's hard and bad things are
happening.
More so than generally having a great time.
Indeed.
You know where else you can have a great time?
Nailed it.
Got it.
Over on Patreon.
Is that what you were going to say?
She did it.
Thanks to Jess for reminding us that we aren't in
fact having a great time.
We are in the fight for our lives.
That's fine.
Yeah, you know.
It's fine.
I mean.
The adrenaline rush is great.
Player knowledge, character knowledge, player Amy's
having a blast.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Character maybe not so much.
If we die, that sucks.
But hey, it's exciting to get to play new characters.
Exactly.
Would Russ kill a kid?
Well, I'm sure I've done it before.
Well, you say Alydin, you said Alydin's not a kid.
Oh, it's true.
She said she's not a kid.
Yeah, exactly.
So, you know, like.
Yeah, that's different.
Yeah, that's fair.
That is different.
I'll steal children.
I won't.
I won't kill.
Actually, he has a code.
Yeah, that's right.
I've got a line.
Gonna do a time jump down.
He's like, you're 23 now.
Look out.
Yeah, murdered.
God damn it.
But you're correct.
You can join us over on Patreon.
Right, Carla?
Patreon.com slash DumbDragonCast.
All kinds of fun stuff going on over there.
Let me tell you about one thing.
That's all we need.
Like a hundred episodes.
That was a terrible hyperbole.
That was the worst hyperbole I've ever done in my life.
Yeah, that was actually one third of the number of episodes that
we actually have over there.
A billion extra episodes of a whole other show that Tom runs
and it's very fun and unhinged.
And are there cooking competitions?
Yes.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Yes.
Are there weddings?
Is there an intern memorial wall?
Yes.
And yes.
So you can listen to those.
What else we got going on guys?
If you're a supporting producer level, you can watch us
record episodes.
Yeah.
You can be with us right now.
This is amazing.
But I'll take an episode dedicated to you.
That's another thing that happens.
Yes, you do.
Like today's patron.
Nine elk.
Thanks, nine elk.
That's so much better than eight elk.
Wouldn't you guys agree?
I was going to say that, Carla.
Yeah.
I think so.
Wait, how is nine spelled?
The number or N-E-I-N?
The number nine L-K.
Just making sure.
It was going to be like no elk.
It could be nine L-K.
Well, like no elk, right?
Nine elk.
There's a Christmas song in there, I think.
No elk, no elk.
Yeah.
It's a story about...
It's like the most fucking Canadian version of a...
You just come up here.
Come on up.
You belong up here.
Come on.
It'll happen.
But yes, join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast like nine elk as well.
And when you do join you get a seven day free trial.
So that's going on all the time.
Come check it out.
It's going to be a great time.
And now we'll get you back to the episode where we're not having a great time.
Except we are.
We are, but we're not.
Just keep that in mind.
Yeah.
Yes.
We have a great time when we're not having a great time.
Exactly.
80% of the time, all the time.
All the time.
You got it.
Yes.
All right.
Love you, bye.
Cav is going to fish another war hammer out of his pack, but it's like a mini throwing war hammer that's identical to his bigger war hammer.
Got a two pack.
It's his mini war hammer.
Yeah.
Look, I had the two payments of $29.99.
I had to send away.
It was a whole thing.
And yeah, he's going to take his little throwing hammer and throw it at one of the monsters that are trying to like devour this memory.
Okay.
Love it.
Give me a ranged attack.
14.
Okay.
So yeah, that flies through the air and crashes into one of these.
Give me some damage.
All right.
I'm just going to use my daggers throwing stats because they don't give novelty identical war hammer.
It's like an available stats.
That's messed up.
Yeah.
How dare they?
Oh, it's a max damage.
So five all said and done.
Okay.
So yeah, one of these horrors that's like devouring this memory gets struck in the face and lets out this hideous scream and disperses into the darkness and your hammer keeps going.
Luckily, it's still under warranty.
So it's totally fine.
Yeah, that's not for yet.
Like when you get untethered to your spacecraft and then you're just floating in the darkness.
Let's not bring up existential horrors Amy.
You know better than this Amy.
Which if you're in orbit, you're basically just constantly falling.
So, you know, yeah, cool.
I learned something weird about tides later.
Remember, remind me to tell you.
I don't know if anybody, I don't know if Carla's face wants that.
I'm going to make her learn anyway.
I can't be the only one with this knowledge.
Okay, that's fair.
And can I guess do my like movement again to get me closer to the box?
Sure.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Do you want another strength roll on that?
Yes, please.
Yep.
Oh, solid nine.
Yeah, you do the same hit.
You're moving towards the box.
It's not as strong as the first one was but it is in the right direction.
So you continue your move forward.
Look, throwing that tiny hammer really took it out of me guys.
Yeah, absolutely.
It's the banjo man's turn and from your memory of Everbane's up there,
Bonwyn, you begin to hear him singing in this like hideous raspy voice.
This lullaby and it's not the same thing.
He's been singing and everybody starts to hear it as it echoes out
and the music notes that you're trying to grab at now are beginning to disperse
more and are harder to grab.
Everybody in the space.
That's everybody.
Make a wisdom saving throw, please.
At least Kat's got some wisdom.
Ten.
Fourteen.
Nine.
Fifteen.
Alydin and Bonwyn, you suddenly feel a wash of comfort and calm.
Am I being charmed?
Yes.
Oh, then I get advantage.
Why?
Because I have advantage against being charmed and it also says magic can't put me to sleep.
But it did.
You've only since gained that.
It's a 15 now.
Okay, so Bonwyn, you?
I just didn't know what was happening.
I didn't know if I was supposed to roll with advantage yet or not.
Yeah, fair.
Hey, I'm starting now.
I kind of like it here.
Now.
I'm like getting calm.
Yeah.
Chilling out.
Let me just quickly try to find something.
Worse things than losing all your memories.
So you, yeah, you feel like you are in a safe place.
You, for mechanical purposes, you are under the effect of a calm emotion spell for one minute.
So do you have immunity to charmed or frightened in any way?
Okay, great.
Love it.
Yeah, so you're just chill.
You're calm.
You no longer feel a need to grab at the notes.
Make a...
Do you drop the one you have?
I don't think so.
You're going to keep the one you have, but...
Roll for the amount of fucks you have.
But your desire to continue to grab more until you save from this,
which you can do so at the end of your next turn, or if you take damage,
you are just floating in the space.
Okay, just chill.
Maybe Bob Marley and the Whalers did show up for Bonwyn.
Just chilling.
As that washes over you, what do you do or say to Cav,
who is like actively trying to like propel himself in this direction?
So there's a lot of racket happening behind you.
Right.
You know, man, I think maybe we just need to like chill out a little bit.
I think that might help.
You know?
I don't know if that's really like the time for that.
No, I think we should just like...
relax.
So Cav, you get the sense that something's fucking.
Sure.
Okay, cool.
Another like crushing note echoes through the place,
which causes these music notes to like bounce down and off of every memory
that's floating through the space, which causes six of them.
Like you see like a memory of specifically the Brewed Awakening
shatter and fall to the ground.
You see, you see Gorsh's butt tight behind, smash and disappear.
Now we're just going to have to describe it to you,
and it's not going to be the same.
We'll be around the campfire.
Tell me again.
Tell me again about sweet, sweet Gorsh.
Six of these memories, each one.
I'm sorry.
I took one from you, Tom.
No, that's all right.
Tom, you get to take one from Bonwyn.
Does that make you feel better, Tom?
It doesn't.
No, I'm going to take like a bad memory that you're going to get rid of.
So you went to forge a blade and it ended up breaking on you.
It was very expensive.
So embarrassing.
Okay, Carla, you get to take one from Kyle.
Well, the very first day of dance class, he tripped and everyone laughed.
Now he doesn't even remember that anymore.
He's better off.
Better off.
That one's not, you're not going to wake up and think about that in the middle of the night.
Thank God.
Kyle, you get to take one from Amy.
Ooh.
Careful.
I'm only 14.
There are only so many memories in here.
She's in her formative years.
There's quite a few bad ones.
Well, yeah, there are quite a few locked in a tunnel memories as well.
Yeah, right.
They're all very formative though, you know.
Very formative.
True.
I'm going to do a John Coffey and take the memory of her pain that just happened to her
away.
Yeah, that's real nice.
We turned that on you Russ.
We made it nice.
Yeah, way to go.
Try to turn us against each other.
You solved my puzzle.
You're back home.
Everything's fine.
It was all a dream.
We did it.
Guys, we did it.
It's all through the power of niceness.
Alydin, it's your turn.
Friendship is magic.
Well, Alydin is going to follow directions.
She was told to keep the little gremlin things from eating that memory.
So she's going to pull out from her bucket her.
Oh my God.
Slingshot.
Anti gremlin spray.
Yes.
Slingshot.
And she is going to try to hit the thingies out with just grabbing spare music notes
and just fucking slinging them because I don't know.
There's probably a few rocks in the bottom.
You're shooting them with music notes.
Saving those rocks for something.
You don't need to know it.
So you're stopping trying to find the correct music notes and you are shooting music
notes at the monsters.
That's what we're said to do.
Just so I understand.
Well, when I grab one if it doesn't light up, I'm like fuck you and I and I'm
going to use it and I'm going to sling it at the memory devouring gremlins.
As you grab one, a roll.
I believe that's how Bernie Toppin writes all those great Elton John songs too.
As you grab one, roll investigation or arcana.
Okay, I snag one.
It's pink.
Pony Club?
Don't get rid of that one.
I love that one.
Not great.
How about an 11?
Seems fine.
Give me a ranged attack.
Oh fuck off.
Five.
There it is.
I sling it backwards.
I hit myself.
I'm embarrassed.
I wish someone takes that memory from me.
All memories are concrete now.
Nobody's taking any more memories.
Now I have to live with this one forever.
Yeah, so you grab one.
It does not glow the same way that you saw Bonwyn's glow and you shoot it off and it
goes far off into the distance.
It doesn't even come close.
I look a bit bizarre, just kind of like oops.
Bonwyn, your turn.
You're chill.
Oh right, what can I do?
I'm just chill.
You can make a wisdom saving throw.
Oh, nat 20.
Yes, finally.
Oh my god.
As you're like, Cav, we just need to chill.
His look like, don't worry.
Yeah, you're singing and the look he's giving you is like, what the fuck?
But then that like triggers something.
You snap to and you're seated on the ground, crisscross applesauce.
And now you're back in it.
But okay, end of your turn.
I don't know what I was saying.
Don't chill.
Oh, I wasn't going to chill.
Okay, okay, good.
Don't chill.
Okay, the horrors on the memory you're trying to pull closer to you are the horrors on
the end, on the memory that's trying that you're trying to get.
The horrors on the mammary, got it.
The horrors on the mammary.
Yes, continue following.
They continue to try to fracture and destroy this memory some more and you see it like
splintering down further into like the center of this memory.
It is not, has not shattered yet though.
Bizarre, it's your turn.
Dumb, I have nothing to stop these things.
But I am going to like keep pulling it close with my mage hand observing it.
And I'm just going to blindly grab it and note nearby that it's a good one.
Okay, so you continue to pull closer to you.
The memory or the music note that you're trying to grab at, roll investigation or arcana.
We are going arcana.
That's a 12.
It's not a right one.
But you managed to pull this within 10 feet of you.
So it's like within 10 feet of the platform that you are on.
So there is a gap still and the horrors are trying to like continue to devour this
memory.
It's totally dwarf throwing distance though.
So is checking one of the music notes considered an action?
No, we'll give it to you.
Everybody's been kind of checking a note.
Okay.
I just wanted to double check.
Yeah.
Would you consider these little things creatures?
Yes.
Awesome.
Well, then yeah, I'm going to do frostbite on one of them.
Constitution saving throw DC 14.
It's a seven.
That's magic too.
That's magic.
Yeah.
Sorry roll.
Question anymore.
Give me a ranged attack first.
Okay.
Wait.
I'm just trying to determine a six.
I said 19 if it's not proficient.
Okay.
Cool.
Love it.
Okay.
So you can do the thing.
But something else is also going to happen.
Oh, yeah, I love that.
Roll a d100, please.
Sick.
92.
I have a good feeling about it.
Yeah, this weird slow chuckle that Russ is doing is very calming.
I'm uncomfortable.
Buster's coming back.
For the next five minutes, you can only speak in rhyming couplets.
I think this applies to Kyle.
That is fucked and I feel like I'm out of luck.
Perfect.
But yes, it does work.
So did you give me damage on that?
No, you have to give me a damage roll so I can tell you the damage.
I did not succeed.
I think I got a seven.
This is fun.
The damage is 12.
Get back on the shelf.
So the horror that is you see this spectral hand grasp onto it and like freeze it showing its form really for the first time and it ices over and shatters and the piece that it's trying to like devour itself to like you see the ice form around the edge and begins to crack it as well.
So a little collateral damage there.
It didn't fuse it together with its ice.
God, not a benevolent DM.
No, no, I'm the worst.
That's not exactly what I wanted it to do.
I guess the rest will be up to my crew.
Amazing.
Okay, calf your turn.
Okay.
How close am I to the box at this point with a good hit you think you could you could make it there this turn or at least within reasonable jumping distance.
Okay, let's let's try to do that.
Another strength check.
Yes, please.
13 you strike your shield as Bonwyn is coming to which propels your platform.
The two of you platform towards the music box and as you're moving past this memory Bonwyn the banjo man's like watching you do this and he he throws shade shade.
You see his smile like be quickly like with these strings be pulled down into a frown and he begins like hurling all of these family portraits into the fire into the forge and the memory itself is cracking and his his body is expelled from it.
So is now floating up in the space as this memory explodes and begins to fall down into the have your motion gets you within five feet like you don't crash into it.
But you are within reasonable distance.
I mean that seems like a decent jumping distance.
Yeah, you're a tall guy.
Yeah, I want to grab whatever the nearest note is to me and see if it if it reacts favorably.
Investigation Arcana please or Arcana.
What's an 18 on the die?
Let's go.
Oh, they're okay 16.
I did so good.
If you picked one, which one would you pick?
I mean, what notes do I have choices?
Sorry between investigation or Arcana.
I was so glad you answered that way because my brain went what does it matter?
And I was like, no way.
No one else had to pick like what fucking note they were grabbing.
But all right, Russ.
I mean, I said pink.
A minor.
I guess I'll do investigation.
Okay, great.
Yeah, you grab one and similar to what you saw with the one that Bonwyn has it begins
to glow and emanate out.
So you now have two notes that are giving off the same energy.
Okay, I'm gonna I'm gonna make my like jump to the box and I'm just gonna try
to like slam the notes into the box.
Like I'm Michael fucking Jordan don't get so you grab sorry you grab Bonwyn's
yours and are just gonna go for it.
I've only got a hammer.
I'm just okay.
So as Cav as you run and you grab these and you're slamming them down like the
two notes are ringing out saying Kong Kong Kong Kong.
There's no musicality to it.
There's nothing that's really happening.
Everybody else even Alydin and Bazaar who are now, you know, a distance
from you.
The two of you look over and you see Cav trying to match them into I mean really it
was only like the one dunking motion.
But yeah, no, I like this better.
They're in the computer.
Yeah, you do it once whatever.
All right.
Yeah, I'm clearly it doesn't work.
So I look up and I kind of give like the I don't know what the fuck to
do with these hand symbol.
So but you are now on their platform with the music box.
You've got two of the notes you as far as you are concerned in hand which
will bring us to the banjo man as you look how they always get a turn.
And our turns are so long that I forget about it and then it comes around.
And I'm like he had previously smashed this memory of Bonwyn that Bonwyn had
and is like floating through the space Cav.
You're assume Bonwyn.
You're also looking back at him, but anybody who can see him sees he
teleports like right behind Cav and emits off the banjo this jarring
note Cav make a con save, please.
We hate a jarring note.
You don't know that is an 18 18.
Okay, so you feel it resonate and go to cover your ears.
You save against whatever effect this is has but then he's going to take
his banjo and try to hit you with it.
Okay, which is a 21 to hit.
I mean, yeah, like a desperate move.
It does guys.
We've got him on the ropes.
It does it does 21 definitely hit.
Okay, that's going to be seven slashing damage and one psychic damage.
Cav you okay, bud?
That was 80% of my current hit points.
So the banjo man in this form is like he takes this huge hit in Cav like
you're you're you're bad off, but he's still standing behind you
like like deep breath like hatred in his eyes ready to wind up
for another one, but that will bring us back to Alydin failed miserably
with trying to slingshot realizing that's probably not the best use
of my time.
I go back to grabbing notes.
Okay, so I want to grab a note and see if that's a good one.
Maybe I'll roll more than a five who knows anything's possible.
Who knows you guys?
Nope fucking rolled a one plus four.
So it's a five.
Look at me manifesting poorly.
Get new dice that won't suffice.
Thank you.
You you go my birthday is coming up.
You go to you go to reach for one and like as your hand gets close.
It begins to glow but you knock it out of range and it begins to float
and it goes into the memory that bizarre is trying to grab as the
fractures are getting deeper on this memory and you see it floating
there above the table where Calder is like writing and tossing
papers and like continuing to scrawl on these pages.
So would you say like as it got close and floated over it was almost
like pulled toward the memory like my I think I said you knocked
it there but like you but like it stopped there and it's just
kind of hanging out.
Yeah, like they're yeah, it's it's you feel like make an
insight roll.
I'm not going to roll the same dice.
No, don't do that.
I'm going to roll a different.
Insight is a 17, 17, a one and a seven.
You have a feeling that this is like that was the note
and it is now inside this fracturing memory.
Do we know what color it is because there are different
colors?
Yellow because it's glowing because it's glow is that okay?
I want to yell to Cav to throw the notes.
He's trying to dunk into the box to this memory.
Cav, Cav look and I point over.
Cav, Cav who's near on the ground near death.
I'm a kid.
I only notice 10% of what's going on.
There's a lot going on.
Do I pick up on what Alydin is trying to like tell me I
I'm going to tell you exactly throw your notes over there.
Okay, can you do it or do we have to wait for his turn?
So you want him to throw your notes over there.
I want him to throw his notes over.
Well Bonwyn's over there and it's Bonwyn's turn.
Okay.
Yeah, you also hear this obviously if Cav can hear it.
You can hear it.
Okay banjo man behind Cav Alydin telling Cav to throw
the two notes toward that memory toward a fracturing
memory.
Yep.
I don't like how you said a fracturing memory.
I did say it many times and you did roll a nat one
for that thing to get there.
So yeah, but then I thought it was maybe a happy accident.
That's how now one's working this game.
I thought maybe you were being nice.
Fuck I fell into a trap.
I think like banjo man being there feels like a more
existential threat at the moment as I watch my friend
Cav like bleed out.
So also in my inventory, I have oil.
I only care about fire guys.
I'm a fire person now.
So I'm going to throw oil on him and then like flick
my tinder at him to try and light him on fire.
Hell yes.
Because fuck that guy.
So it's making me really mad.
Like you're like flick my tinder.
I just imagine a cigarette.
Yeah did I mention Bonwyn's been smoking this whole
time.
She smokes like two packs a day.
Shit.
I never just lighting them off each other.
It's wild.
Okay, so you're throwing what is that?
What is what vessel is the oil in?
Let's see what it says easily breakable glass jar.
Now, where's your second line of your rhyming?
It doesn't in a flat so that you can throw it near
or far.
There you go.
It's in a flask.
I guess I was more thinking.
Oh, no, a flask is probably glass, right?
Yeah.
Your flask you would do.
So you're going to do that and you're going to approach
the banjo man to like flint.
I think so because I also need to be there because
Cav is down on the ground.
So I'm also like going.
Okay.
So ranged attack to see if the oil hits if the
oil hits the flint will ignite.
Okay.
Well, I rolled an 18 and then what do I have?
Decks.
Oh, so that's a 24.
Hell yeah, that will definitely hit.
So yeah, this glass bottle of oil shatters over
the banjo man and you leap over to this this other
platform and ignite it and flames go up.
He lets out this hideous scream and like notes begin
to like trickle out of the of the banjo and he
his wings propel him up and off and away from
your position and as he does that more of these
these shard notes begin to fall down all around
and on top of you make a dexterity saving throw
with disadvantage.
If you're also going to try to save Cav.
Oh, because I like throw myself on him.
Yeah.
Yeah, I probably do.
Well, I rolled a nat 20 but obviously not going
to get to use.
Back to back 20.
No, then I rolled a nat one.
That's not great.
Not great.
Okay, don't that's it.
That was the opposite of what I would have taken
a 10 and a 10 over a 20 and a one.
Yeah, honestly.
Okay.
So you jump over I leap on top of Cav and you
are going to take as these these notes crash
down on all.
Any of them light up when they're killing me to
give my friends a clue.
No, these are different notes.
And one of them lands directly on top of you
as you land on Cav and you are going to take
10 force damage.
That's so many.
That's a lot of force damage as like this
echoing laugh rings out throughout this space.
We see this memory with this this note inside
of it splintering as more of these horrors
are coming out of the woodwork.
proverbially.
Sorry, what?
Whatever it is.
That made my life.
Thank you.
Dumbgeons and Dragons season 4 episode 24 starring
Amy More as Alydin, Carla Max dead as Bonwyn
Everbane, Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave,
Kyle Claset is Bazaar the Wizard and Russ
Moore as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design of today's
episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound and sound effects
are from Epidemic Sound and Boom Library.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt and
we'd like to say a huge thank you to our
supporting producers including Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babyok, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Angaron Kiersen, Perry Matey, Old School Gamer D,
Craig Zeiss and L.A.
Branton.
Have you been enjoying your time with
Dumbgeons and Dragons?
Well, thank you so much for being here.
If you're looking for more of what you
love, come over to Patreon.com slash dumb
dragon cast where you're going to get a
seven-day free trial.
And when you're a patron for at least
three months, we're going to send you
some merch based on the tier you're at.
Come on over.
We hope to see you over there.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Have a great week.
We'll talk to you soon.
What's happening?
I don't know.
Wait, this is your job right now.
I know.
Tell everybody what's happening.
I didn't think you'd survive this long.
Finally.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb
dragons production.