Oh, hey, friends, we're back.
Dumbgeons and Dragons will start in just a moment.
Alydin, Bonwyn and Dace are running through the streets of
Intersmith and quickly following a fast disappearing trail of
leaves that's leading to the Verboten Forest, making good
time. The leaves are scattering, though, and as you
get to the edge of the forest, all of you stop and
have this sense of unease.
Alydin, you begin to hear music playing from deep within the
forest.
Make a wisdom saving throw, please.
I'm rolling dice.
Roll it.
Bonwyn, you don't hear it at this point.
I hope there's just like a haunted piano somewhere.
Just a nice old crone out there humming to herself and
we're all freaking out.
Oh, well, a four.
Oh, shit.
I ain't wise.
I'm a child.
It's my excuse.
And not precocious enough to be wise.
Not precocious enough.
I'm working on it.
Alydin, you hear this music.
You're feeling compelled to move.
You try to fight it off a little bit, but you hear what
you what you think you hear is calls of Tally screaming for
help in the forest.
Do you guys hear that?
No, it's Tally.
It's Tally.
This way.
Take off.
I'm running full tilt.
I mean, I'm going to follow her.
I don't hear it, but I'm also going to follow her because
I'm not losing another kid.
Tally!
Alydin bolts off into the trees.
Bonwyn and Dace roll an athletics check to see if you
can keep up with Alydin as she begins like ducking under
branches and skipping over logs.
Like an adult could totally outrun a child, but the
speed in which a child begins running is unreal.
Pfft.
14.
Alydin takes off into the woods and like disappears from
sight before you even realize what's happening.
You hear their footsteps and you follow quickly behind.
You trip and Dace kind of catches you as you're going
and helps you to your feet and you make your way onto
this path and you see Alydin up a hedge about 25 feet in
front of you.
Alydin, you turn to see if they're following you and you
see them behind you.
And up ahead, you see a clearing come into view.
Moonlight is beaming down into this space and you
hear Alydin, you hear the music getting louder.
The closer you get, you hear calls from Tally echoing
through the trees, drawing you into this space.
Bonwyn and Dace, you continue to run.
Alydin kind of stopped there for a moment and you
make it up to her.
Do you hear that?
It's Tally.
I don't hear anything.
No, which way?
Point toward the clearing.
Over there, but I can hear the music too.
Like the song, the music or banjo music or what
kind of music do you hear?
Banjo music, like the one the guy was singing.
Well, we have to, we have to go to her.
We do have to go to her.
I agree.
But I...
Alydin, you begin to walk forward and Dace reaches
out a hand to try to stop you.
And you...
What do you do?
I think I'm going to try and grab her hand,
like to actually hold her hand.
Okay.
Because we're in the woods.
I don't hear anything and I don't want to lose her.
Yeah.
So I'm going to grab her hand if she will let me.
You have, well, you're feeling compelled to continue forward.
So you tell me if you, if you let her.
Oh, um, I, I think I, I, I'm a bit nervous.
Can you, let's hold hands.
I'm nervous in here.
Okay, come this way.
I don't stop walking, but, and I'm kind of like yanking on your arm.
Like, come on, she needs us.
Come on.
The three of you make your way to the edge of this clearing
and you step out into it.
At this point, Bonwyn and Dace begin hearing faint echoing music as well.
You don't yet hear the calls from Tali that Alydin is describing.
And as you step out further into this clearing, Bonwyn, you step on something
and the grass is tall.
You step on something and kind of like your ankle rolls a little bit, not, not
enough to like seriously injure you or anything, but you roll an ankle and
you look down and the ground is littered with wooden toys.
Oh, come on.
Dace, Alydin, this is the creepiest thing I've ever seen.
This is-
Sorry, now that we're in there, am I compelled to go anywhere else or am
I where I was drawn to and now?
You, Alydin, look to the far side of this clearing and like your dream, you
see this large tree come into view and it's almost like the trees around the
edge are moving to make way for this tree that now comes into view and you
are, like your body's moving towards this, like you're pulling on, on
Bonwyn.
Bonwyn, whether you choose to try and stop her or not, she's moving towards
the other side of this clearing where the same imagery isn't, isn't happening
for you, but you do see this, this large oak tree with this bored out
hole in the side of the trunk.
Bonwyn, do you see that?
Do you see that?
I think she's in, come on.
I think she's in there.
Okay, but we have to like, let's maybe be sneaky because it's right.
Sneaky.
You're so good at that.
Let's try and not just run into the scary hole in the scary tree in the
scary woods.
I think she pretends to tip toe, but it's like, when you're being
compelled to a big tree with a hole in it, I can't talk sense into her.
I know that, but I still have to try.
You all step into the clearing and you're making your way across.
And the, the moonlight is, is coming down on top of you.
Um, Dace and Bonwyn making a wisdom saving throw at this point.
16.
You all continue forward and you're stepping between these toys that are
littered all over the clearing.
And as you get about halfway, the world around you begins to shudder and each
of you find yourselves in a space, in a room, a child's room.
And the more you kind of take in the, the, the feeling of this space,
it is your room from when you were a child.
Am I just like back in a shack or?
You're actually just back in the hole you were hiding in for several
months.
Stop trying to get her stuck back in the hole.
I don't want to be underground.
I don't want to be in a cage.
The kid hole.
The kid hole, of course.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D and D actual play podcast, and I'm your
dungeon master, Russ More, he, him also with me today is Amy More
as Alydin, she, her, my boss is mad.
Carla maxed out as Bonwyn, Everbane, she, her number one daughter and
live, laugh, love Tom Laird as Kavlaran gold weave, he, him.
There's no time.
We've got to go.
And Kyle Claset is bizarre.
The wizard, he, him, it's up.
Yeah.
Kat, Hey, what's up?
We're so excited to be back.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast and you can join
us today for a seven day free trial at patreon.com slash dumb dragon
cast, where we have an entire other podcast for you and an amazing
community that you can be a part of.
Like the second you join, we want you to come check it out.
Just give it a little taste.
patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
We'll see you over there.
And now fuck it.
Let's play.
It will cut down to the Doc's Inventors myth.
There's a, a large passenger ship that's pulled into port and we
see bizarre and Kavlaran, and Clara following behind and Clara's waving
to the, to the crew saying it was lovely.
Thank you so much for teaching us all these games.
Did, can you believe how many games they actually knew?
More than I ever could have imagined.
Tic tac toe gin rummy.
Oh my goodness.
I haven't played so many things since I was just a child.
I feel like you're like some sort of card shark or something like that.
Like you came away with like quite, quite a bit of gold.
Like you kind of cleaned out.
Seven pocket watches.
People are mad.
She stuffs, she stuffs some gold pieces into her purse.
And you see the, we flashed to the crew who are like, who are waving, but also
they have this defeated look on their face.
Like she just hosed them for everything they were worth.
Oh, Clara.
Oh, that was just the most exciting, a couple of days on, on, on the, on the
river there, wasn't it?
And this is Vintersmouth.
I haven't been out this far.
Where are we going first, Bizarre?
Uh, well, um, first I'd probably go back to my shop and home.
So, uh, not a lot of space, but we'll make it work.
I, you know, I've got a nice bed you can sleep in and I, I have a cot
that I can put down in the storage area.
So I, yeah, I don't, I'm not here to put you out, you know, we'll,
we'll, we'll make it work.
And I can help out around the store as much as you need.
Um, uh, just to kind of, you know, get, get my feet back under me here
and figure out what's what in Vintersmouth.
This is a lovely town.
Little, little torn apart in this area.
Oh yeah.
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
We had a problem with some monsters.
Some monsters.
Yeah, don't mean you didn't mention that on the boat.
It must've been too busy with the game.
Well, I was just awestruck.
How did you learn to play cards like that?
Don't tell those, uh, those ship boys, but, uh, I've played a few games in my time.
They didn't know what hit them.
Don't feel like I've seen this side of you, mom, but I'm very, very excited
to see you open up a little bit.
Gav, do you need to get anywhere?
Or, uh, I was going to head back to the shop, check on Alydin
cause I left Alydin in charge.
Uh, so yeah.
I mean that's, unless you're headed back to, uh, to Bench's place.
Uh, yeah, I guess I should swing by my room and just make sure
everything's good there.
And yeah, then probably go see Bench.
Maybe talk to Oak tomorrow.
Probably not today.
Maybe a tomorrow thing.
Fair enough.
Well, um, then yeah, we'll, we'll head on back to the shop.
You're of course more than welcome to join us, but I'm just going
to get my mom settled in and yeah, make sure everything is, uh, on
the up and up with Alydin.
Excellent.
Start walking towards the shop and say, Gav, I'll see you.
Yeah, we'll, uh, we'll catch you later.
Clara's got like a new lease on life.
She's like, springing her step.
Stella got her groove back.
Ritted the dead beat, right?
She just lost like 180 pounds.
She's slubbing it.
Bizarre, you and Clara, you make your way through the streets.
And so tell me all the sites here.
Uh, you know, how far to, to the store?
Where should I stop?
What should I see?
Who, who's good?
Who do I stay away from?
Well, I mean, everybody is fairly kind here in the town.
I mean, it's once you get into the richer side of the town, which
you'll, you'll obviously notice the difference between the two.
But, um, my shop is right between a fantastic clothier and a nice
barber, uh, so we can get you set up with any clothes that you need.
Get your hair done.
Um, you know, we have a couple of shops around, uh, there's
a place called the hot block where my friend Bonwyn has their shop Everbanes.
Uh, great place if you need any kind of utensils, metalwork or
anything crafted for you, really.
Um, oh, that sounds lovely.
And, uh, I can't wait to meet all your friends.
Yeah, absolutely.
We're not going to meet a guy named, if you meet a guy named
Ignatius, just, just say I'm good.
Okay.
Just say I'm good.
Shady, shady character.
I mean, just a weird dude.
Like what are we?
He's very upfront about his business.
Uh, he runs an establishment called the quivering Hills and it's more of a house
of what people would consider ill repute.
So, well, all right, just so you know, if you go, it's your call.
You live your life mom, but you know, Ignatius got us in some trouble
and it kind of fell on us.
So I don't necessarily like the guy, but fair, fair.
Okay.
Well, we'll stay away from Ignatius now.
Yeah.
So fast forward to romance between Ignatius.
Oh, you son of a beach.
Well, you just want your mom to stay away from him.
It's a rebound, you know, like let her have a little wild fun.
Yeah.
Anybody knows how to show a woman a good time.
It's probably Ignatius.
Oh, God damn it.
You can call me daddy.
It's fine.
Disgusting.
I love it.
I can't wait for this.
I was that polymorph spell.
But, you know, for the time being, before we get back,
we can get some food at those buns dough, which talk of the town.
Got to get got to get you from there.
So good. Let's go.
You make your way to those buns dough and grab some delicious
pastries and coffees for for the next little bit.
And you make your way to the shop and it.
I mean, it's the late morning, but the closed sign is up.
The shutters are drawn.
The store, which by all intents and purposes should be open, is not.
And you unlock it and go inside and things are things are dark.
There are I mean, differences in the place is there are several hand
drawn signs of people who are not allowed to shop behind
behind the register.
Like, I mean, how many are there?
Well, like like like five, six that you can see.
OK, yeah.
The other one, she's still working on perfecting the sketch.
The other wall was just go up to him.
I look at some of the names.
I'm like, I get it.
That makes sense. That one's a shit.
Jackson with an X.
Oh, I say, well, it's odd that Hallidon wouldn't be here.
So I wonder.
Well, I want to get you settled.
Just go ahead and mom, take your things upstairs.
I need to.
I need to I have no idea where alladin would be at this point
if they're not here, so I'm going to cast the sending spell.
Reach out to Alladin and
I'm going to send a 25 word message or less saying,
hey, just got back.
The shop's not open.
Where are you? WTF.
Yeah. No, my boss is mad.
And in case you need to know, Russ, for any reason,
if the target is on if the target is on a different plane than me,
there's a five percent chance that the message doesn't arrive.
If you need that information.
I do need that in five percent.
That's pretty good.
Odd still. Yeah, it's a pretty powerful.
That's five percent chance.
All right.
You wouldn't change your cell phone provider over five percent drop it now.
It's close.
But you wait a good
a good long moment longer than you think you need to.
And no message comes back.
Oh, shit.
I'm going to tell my mom, Mom, just settle in.
Chill. I'm going to.
OK. Lock the door.
I have to go check on something.
I think someone's in trouble.
Oh, oh, OK.
Well, if you need anything, you come get me.
OK, I'm happy to help, but I'll just tidy up around here
until I hear from you, OK?
Much appreciated.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
I'm so sorry.
I'm good to rearrange the shelves. Yes. No.
OK, I'll just take my stuff upstairs.
OK, I tell you what, here here is a key.
If you want to go walk around the city, just,
you know, just maybe stay around the hot block and,
you know, check out some of the stores around town.
People are very nice, but I'm so bad timing.
I hate to do this.
Oh, no, no, I love you.
And I'll be back. Of course.
It's OK. Handle myself.
You take off and door locked behind you.
Where are you headed?
First thing first inclination would be to head to Everbane's
and check if Bonwyn knows where
Alydin is.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
We're back, baby.
We're back. We missed you.
So much. It's been a long time.
You know, when you when you go away for a long time
and then you actually start to hear from people
that you've never heard of being like, hey, is this show still on?
What is going on?
Thank you for reaching out and connecting with us.
The show is still on, clearly.
You're listening to this episode.
Just a bunch of these dum-dums got sick.
Yeah, yeah.
And then Amy followed up with also getting sick.
Yeah, but I don't know what you're talking about, because she's pushing through.
Whereas we were like, yeah, we couldn't.
None of us know. I absolutely could not.
I was too sick.
We were all. I just love you more than they love you guys.
So I just made that.
Oh, wow.
Wow. Sick Amy fucking comes for the headshot.
No kidding.
Oh, we love you. We missed you.
And we're back. Yes.
Yay.
Excited to be back.
We got together in January, where we all got each other
sick from the intense makeout sessions that we all had, obviously.
That's right.
And planned a whole lot of things that we then now shifted down
one month in terms of scheduling.
Yes. But we got new stories that we want to do, new games,
new new bit of new structure coming to some Patreon
places, tiers.
That's what those are called. Or plates, whatever plates.
Yeah. Yeah.
It's like we're setting a plate for you at the Patreon table.
You can come join us for the buffet at Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast, where there's a smorgasbord
of new bonus content for you each and every month.
Yes. You nailed that, Russ. Well done.
Yeah, that was really good. You really rolled into that.
Felt really natural.
I don't know if I said the website, though.
So Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
One of the things part of the smorgasbord, is it the jello
with the skin on top?
Probably not, because that's good slash gross.
Is it the shrimp? It might be.
It could be. Is that you get an episode dedicated to you.
Yes, you do. Like today's patron, Paul Litch.
I know. It's scary.
It's Paul. Thank you so much.
Litch with a T.
So maybe he's not an actual litch, but just like,
that's his secret to tell.
You're not. Yeah, no.
Well, I think maybe he's going to spill the tea.
Ancestrally was a litch, but it got changed
like when they came through spooky Ellis Island.
Yeah, exactly.
You got to cover things up if you're going to be
if you're going to be going that route.
Exactly. No. Yeah.
We appreciate you, Paul, and you can be like Paul
and join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
for the all you can eat smorgasbord that we've got over there.
We're delicious. So delicious.
Right. And now we'll get you back to the episode.
Thank you for being here.
Thank you for being patient as we all got healthy
and are now putting all of the good, good funnies
back out for you. That's right.
Next next episode, two episodes.
We actually recorded around the table.
We did. So much fun.
We got to like look each other in the eye
as we made bad decisions, as we made bad decisions.
And it was so weird because Amy and I make a lot of eye contact
virtually. Somehow we somehow know we make eye contact,
but we are sitting right beside each other in real life
and we couldn't. It was a real change. Yeah. Yeah.
We had to turn and face each other, which was weird.
It was such a delight.
They're making us talk.
And I feel like the delightfulness of it,
fingers crossed, translates to the episodes.
I believe we'll talk about more how
we'll talk more about how awesome it was next week.
So now get you back to this episode.
Thanks for being here, everybody.
We'll talk to you soon. Love you. Bye.
Love you. Bye. Bye.
Bon, when you find yourself in your childhood bedroom,
what does the space look like around you?
So this would be upstairs at Everbane's,
like where the living quarters are, because of course,
it was the family shop before it was my shop.
I have now converted that into like a workout space.
But what was once my childhood bedroom?
And it's honestly, it's wonderful.
Like, it's so nice.
Maybe too much.
Too many handmade metal signs from dad
that say like number one daughter and live, laugh, love.
But it's nice. It's cozy.
There's there.
She has a little desk with her books from school,
a nice bed with a handmade quilt that her grandma made.
Window looks out over over the hot block.
And it's lovely.
Bonwyn's parents are great.
She had a lovely childhood.
And it's it's nice.
It's you know, she's got everything she needs in there,
including some secret hiding spaces,
because a girl's got to have those, too, right?
Absolutely.
You are instantly transported here into this.
And there's the warmth of the sun coming through.
And it feels feels safe and comfortable.
You go and you run your hand along the quilt
that your grandmother made you.
And like the stitching is exactly as you remember it.
And the smell in the room just overwhelms your senses.
And you sit on the edge of the bed and you're instantly
transported to this space.
And you sit up on the bed and you like
you for this moment feel like you are child Bonwyn again.
Your feet dangle at the same.
I mean, you're in, you know, say, dangle at the same distance
over the edge of the bed and you throw yourself back on your bed
and pull the pull the blanket around you and and sit back up.
And then on the other side of the room, you see your
favorite toy in a chair on the other side of the room.
What does that look like?
I think it is probably
an old kind of like slidey rocking chair
that my mom would have used when like when I was a baby to help rock me.
But it ended up in my room and it's got a bunch of cushions on it.
And also my favorite soft toy,
because there wasn't a lot of soft toys in Bonwyn's life.
A lot of a lot of metals.
And, you know, she loves those, obviously made her life with them.
But she has one soft stuffed pig that is just
destroyed, basically like it's squished, it's flat, it's a non color.
But it was, you know, it's the one she's had since she was a tiny, tiny baby.
It's her it's her favorite one.
You see this toy and like it, it's drawing you to it.
You get up off the bed and you run across and you you grab the toy
and hug it tight and lean into this chair that begins rocking back and forth.
And as it begins rocking back and forth,
you begin to hear this music kind of permeate the space, quiet at first.
Then after a moment, it starts to pick up and you begin to hear
like the sound of banjos echoing through.
And the music isn't isn't scary.
You're like, you know, you contextually, you adult Bonwyn
know that everything is scary and terrifying.
But suddenly everything is safe.
And the door starts to creak open.
And that's where we'll cut to Alydin.
Alydin, very similarly, you find yourself.
And now Alydin didn't have the same kind of upbringing,
but you find yourself in a safe space.
Somewhere, you know, it might not even been that long ago,
but you find yourself in a place where you feel comfortable.
Where do you find yourself?
I find myself in.
The little back room of the magic shop.
Oh, God, take you to the magic shop.
I have something in my eye.
Yeah, she finds herself in the back there and
is surrounded by the dusty jars
and scraps of paper that she's been keeping
and kind of practicing,
making her printing nice and neat so that she can redo
any, like, labels or price tags for him.
And yeah, she's just.
Just in the back room.
You are writing down price tags and and and
playing, not playing, but using things that may be
bizarre, probably didn't want you to necessarily
touch and play with, but you're you're not doing anything.
I'm so careful.
Yeah, no, you're you're being careful and you're
picking these things up and examining them and spinning them in your hands.
And as you place one of them down,
you place it on top of a box that looks familiar.
This box is and I say it looks familiar.
It it has a it has a a feeling to it that as you place this
this beaker down on top of it, you quickly move it off,
knowing that this box is very important,
not just to you, but perhaps to Bazaar as well.
Like the box itself is is red and it has yellow and
it has yellow kind of edging to it.
It has a lock on it.
You kind of patch your pockets and look around on the table
and you can't find a key for it.
I want to look in my bucket.
You put a key in my bucket.
You look down into your bucket and shimmering
in the bucket in this iridescent rainbow to it.
Is this skeleton key?
Oh, yeah. Oh, I pick it up like so careful, so slow.
Like I like there's something in this box.
I have to know.
I think. I think he would want me to know.
I think Bazaar would want me to know.
You grab the key and there's a warmth that runs through your arm.
And you reach out and put the key into the lock.
And you hear it, hear it latch and click.
You turn it, you unlock the box.
And like there's this
small plume of what looks like dust
that kind of comes up from the edge as the lock.
The latch clears and the box kind of tips open.
A light begins to emanate from the seal in the top of the box.
Oh, Alydin is excited.
She runs her hands along the edges of the box and like.
It's the same warmth that's coming from this light slowly,
like just like ever so slowly.
You know, when you feel like you're the main character in a movie,
she's having her moment, her main character moment.
She's like, this is like the most important thing ever.
She opens the box.
You lift the lid on the box and light begins to pour out towards you
and it dims and clears.
And sitting in the middle of this box is a small wooden toy.
What does the toy look like?
I'm going to give you Amy's answer first.
It is a small hamburger, a Royale with cheese, if you will.
Thank you so much. Oh, my God, thank you so much.
And it's stamped with B-A-M-F.
OK, but that's not what it really is, because it'd be crazy.
What is sitting there is one of those puzzle boxes,
one of the and not not like Rubik's Cube, but like.
I don't know how I'm trying to describe it.
We're like Hellraiser.
The Lammershants configuration.
Maybe I like Amy's face right now.
Is it like like one of those ones where it doesn't look like it has anything,
but there's like a sliding panel and then you push a button
to be able to undo a magnet and a ball rolls
shit like that.
Yeah, something like that.
There's like there's intricate carvings of
runes or letters that
Alydin can't make out.
And there are symbols and it feels somehow hollow
but heavy at the same time, like there's
like there's something in it.
And she shakes it and she hears nothing.
But there's a way to open the box, but there is no visible
hinges or any sort of seams
that Alydin can find.
You take this puzzle box and you go sit in one of the chairs
and chair squeaks beneath you.
And you're running it over in your hands and trying to decipher the runes.
And there's this wisp of light
that you don't really pay much attention to.
You're so enthralled with this this toy.
It begins to encircle your head.
And then goes out the back door.
And that's when you lift your head
and you turn and you look towards the back door,
which is open and it's not usually open.
Not leaving the box, she is.
Just like obsessed with this box.
She walks over to the door and kind of peeks
out because she could have sworn that it was closed and
Bazaar always keeps it locked.
You poke your head out the door and it's it's dark.
It's pitch black, dark of night, and it feels
it feels off like there feels like something's not quite right.
But from somewhere in that darkness,
you hear the faint call of Tali.
Tali.
Alydin, where are you?
She puts the puzzle box in her bucket
and slowly steps out into the dark.
Tali.
Here, the creak of the door slowly closed behind her.
Here, the creak of the door slowly closed behind you as
the safety of the magic closet
leaves as the door latches.
You enter this dark space.
I'm in the dark again.
Do I feel like I'm outside or am I in one of those moments where
the door shuts and it's just black?
We'll come back to you.
You just sit with that for a bit.
Yeah, just wait there in the dark.
You're used to it.
You've left your mind still.
Kav, you were going to go see Bench or you were going to go back to your place?
You're going to go have a drink, like.
I was going to go see Bench, but I get waylaid by the handsome
first officer from the ship.
Oh, OK.
We we cut back down to the docks.
And Kav, you are chatting with the first officer whose name
I wish I pulled up all the fucking names because Jess gave me shit for giving
someone an unnamed NPC.
Well, yeah, but we also explain that we don't want to just use their good
names on potential throwaway characters.
Look, Tom's making a pass at the first officer from the ship here.
So I feel like he will be a throwaway character, but that's fine.
You don't know that. What if you really feel a connection?
You know, this is how Kav does it.
Yeah, Kav keeps it easy breezy.
Love them and leave them.
Set them free if they come back, yadda yadda.
File a restraining order.
Oh, season three responses.
If it took me any longer than that, I would have just come up
with a name it at the exact threshold of time that Russell's willing to put
into it before just saying like Garnie Gorsh Gorsh.
Never mind. I don't talk to this person at all.
His name is Clark. He's so hot, but I can't.
I mean, I just can't with the name Gorsh.
He's all. Can you imagine moaning that?
No, no.
It's a gnome named Gurgungl.
Yeah, that's a Gorsh, am I right?
You're talking to Gorsh.
No. I'm happy to talk to Gorsh.
Gorsh. Gorsh is, well, I mean.
Yeah, let's go with Gorsh.
Love it. Sorry.
People who've given us names and we've found ourselves here.
The first mate of the of the captain of the captain,
first mate of the ship that you just arrived on.
Nice to see you back here.
Is this where you're stopping or are you getting back on?
Well, no, I'm you know, I'm here for the for the time being.
Do you want to go grab a drink or something?
I'd love to. Yeah, we don't leave for, you know, here for the day at the least.
Is there a good spot around here?
There is a great spot.
It's called the Brewed Awakening.
My buddy Benj runs it.
All right. Fantastic. Can't wait.
I can't wait. Just give me a moment.
I'll let them know I'm heading out and I'll be right down.
Perfect. Hops up onto the ship there.
I'm sorry. This is an iconic, just like memorable
Dungeons moment.
I don't think Tom's ever had a character that had any romantic interest.
I don't think so either.
I like that it's been so easy, too.
Till now, we just pointed it out.
Now we're going to make it off.
Yep. Yeah. Well, you know,
like Russ named the love interest Gorsh.
That's true.
Which we haven't found out yet.
Oh, that's true.
So they haven't interacted on this voyage.
They've just been like eyeballing each other.
Just like some knowing glances.
Yeah, polite small talk, probably.
But that's about it.
Yeah, that doesn't sound like being on a ship.
Yeah, it sounds like some.
Well, I'm trying.
Clara was running. That's true.
There was some intense gambling going on.
Yeah, right. That's right.
You wait a moment and you see this gentleman coming back down
and he calls to a couple of people, says, yeah, I'll be back soon.
Don't worry. I'll bring you back some food as well.
And he comes down and Kav, make a perception check.
Perception check.
Do you see his nameplans?
Is he wearing a uniform? Tell me more about it.
I want to know, like, I mean, I would have to assume
he had some very tight fitting pants.
And that's what drew Kav's interest.
This is what I'm wondering what Kav saw in him, that he was like, OK.
You can tell what kind of underwears he gets from chest of drawers.
You know what I'm saying? Absolutely.
If any. None.
None. You said perception?
Yes, please. All right.
So that is a 16 after bonus. OK, 16.
So, yeah, you see the first mate coming down
and, you know, describe the first mate for us.
What did draw Kav into this gentleman?
Well, he's got like a very nice, crisp uniform on.
It's very white with some like navy blue accents.
And yeah, just like a real nice, like sculpted butt in those pants.
Kav has no idea what his face looks like.
Oh, no. Yeah, no.
Well, that's how we miss the name tag.
Yeah, you see that sculpted
button, those nice navy blue pants coming back down the gangplank.
And out of the corner of your eye, you see
Bazaar tear around a corner like full sprint
heading towards the hot block.
And there is an intersection that kind of passes by.
You see him like bolting.
Bazaar. Sorry, sorry, one sec. Sorry.
What's up? Yeah, Kav.
Hey, what's up?
You're in a hurry. What's what's shaking?
Oh, yeah, I I don't I don't know.
Alydin's not at the shop and a spell that I use to talk to people
didn't get answered.
And that means maybe they're not on this plane of existence anymore.
Oh, I don't know what that means for a child, but it's not right.
OK. Oh, I'm I'm I turn over to the first mate.
I'm I'm so sorry, but a friend of ours is missing
and I'm going to have to reschedule that drink.
That's that's OK. Is there anything we can do to help?
I guess if you see a young girl with a bucket,
you let me know. All right.
OK, no other distinguishing characteristics.
Just a young girl with a red hair.
Well, I mean, red hair about yay high, you know, got it.
OK, poor looking.
Yeah, we'll keep an eye out.
Like I said, we're we're here all day.
If you need any help, like we got a full crew, we can we can do
we can do something. Perfect.
OK, thanks. Yeah, I'll let you know.
Sorry, I didn't catch your name.
We didn't have a chance at Gorsh.
Gorsh. OK, yeah. Yeah.
Is that a family name?
Yeah, it was my my grandmother's name.
There's no time. We've got to go.
Because I say, man, like I'm going to Bonwyn's
going to Everbane's right now.
Check with Bonwyn, see if Bonwyn knows where she is.
I just the lack of response.
Yeah, that's crazy.
Yeah, OK. All right, let's go.
Two of you book it down to the hot block and
you make it to Everbane's and the door is ajar.
And there's there's commotion inside.
And as you as you enter, you see Thane
and all of the children
that you've known to exist in and around Alydin.
And there's June on the other side of the room
helping kind of wrangle and feed some some of the kids.
And Thane sees you enter and he calls you over.
He says, Bazaar, you're back.
Kav, good to see you.
So he he just he's something's wrong.
Something is not is not right. OK.
Bonwyn and Alydin and Dase have
so kids have been going missing.
Oh, Cedric was first.
We brought all the kids here.
Tally went missing while we while we were here.
And then the three of them
followed this path like there's a banjo man.
And there's there's there's music.
And like I don't
I can't explain it, but they followed these leaves.
They just said there was leaves and they had to follow them.
But they've been gone for two days.
Yeah, that's way too long to be gone.
Where are these leaves? Where do we go?
They went down to the there was a path to the forest.
June, June, are you are you OK?
I can take them as far as as far as I remember seeing.
Oh, yeah, I got these little ones.
Don't you worry, you guys, come around, come around.
I'm going to tell you a story.
Oh, is it a scary one again?
No, of course not. You're living the scary story.
OK, good. Once upon a time, there was a vampire.
A vampire? Oh, wow.
That's not as scary as this.
Thane takes you out.
Did you guys just get back?
Yeah. Yeah, just got back.
Went to my shop.
Alydin's not there.
Yeah, we've had we've had every every day since been gone.
Like the the guard has been out looking like they
and nobody's been able to find them.
They've been into the forest like they can't.
Anyway, they're OK.
Banjo Man
Bard came down was singing a song.
Kids picked up the song, started singing the song.
The song was creepy.
Like the song was like really like, why do kids sing this song?
You know, talking about like a banjo man is going to come
get you in your sleep kind of vibe.
That's terrifying. Not cool.
And then what did they say?
And then there was Cedric went missing.
There were there were leaves.
They were in a bag because Bonwyn put him in a bag.
And then she said something about a shimmering musical note,
something like that.
And you guys are walking towards the forest.
The shimmering note where it was etched
is etched into the into the floor, etched into the floor at the school.
OK.
Um, let's go see if we can find this trail.
And then if we don't find anything there, that's our second stop.
Yeah, of course, of course.
And he takes the lead and down the street
towards the Verboten Forest and
a large wind picks up at that point
and leaves from the entire Verboten Forest
begin to move off of the trees and swirl around you.
Bizarre, do you you sense
a similar feeling, not the same,
but a similar feeling to when you were down in the mine
and you saw that portal in front of you, like there was a
a disturbance, something that in you,
in the essence of your very being sensed
was different about the space that you were in, a difference about the world.
Was there a disturbance in the force?
No, I didn't say that. I didn't say that.
Come at me, Lucas.
No, it's Josney.
They're going to get Josney now.
Yeah. Oh, boy.
You get this feeling and it's like the wind passes by
and it comes on as this chill as you continue forward.
You're unsettled.
You know that something has shifted in the direction that you are going.
Um, Cav, do you have all of your equipment with you?
Are you? I have a feeling this is giving me the same vibes
as what happened down in the mines.
Oh, shit. No. Oh, yeah.
No, I have everything.
Like, I didn't even get a chance to go home.
So. OK. OK. Just just double checking.
Um, like at least Bonwyn's with her.
We've got to go in there.
We'll get him back. It's going to be totally cool.
We got this.
Yeah, we do. Let's get after it.
Welcome home, am I fucking right?
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 4 Episode 14, starring Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue, editing and sound design of today's episode is by Russ More.
Music is from Epidemic Sound and sound effects are from Epidemic Sound
and Boom Library.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
And we'd like to say a huge thank you to our supporting producers,
including Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babiak, Kat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Angaron Kiersen, Perry Matey, Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss
and L.A. Branton.
We'd love if you joined us today
at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast for the amazing community.
All the bonus content and so much more.
Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast.
We'll see you over there.
But until then, have a great week and we'll talk to you soon.
It's a grumbly dog. Apologies.
No, these are just noises from inside the woods.
They're just forest.
Yeah, street noise. We're running down the streets.
We can hear people snoring through their open windows.
That's right.
Should I roll my speed?
Tally takes off and you. Nope.
What? I'm Alydin, Alydin, take, sorry, Alydin,
going to go save some kids and go fuck a sailor.
Hell, yeah.
I mean, I would have preferred the order had been the other way, but whatever.
He said he'd wait for me. It's fine.
Did he yell it like, oh, wait for you
till the end of the day.
And then you do have to.
And then we've got to get out of here.
Seems like you had a dodged a bullet. Kind of needy.
He's named after his grandmother.
That's where we'll wrap the episode.
There's no time.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.