Do you remember what you hit play on? It's Dumbgeons and Dragons, and we'll begin in a moment.
The group of you make your way back to City Hall and Kav splits off and goes back to at least pretend that he's doing the job that he was tasked to do.
While Bonwyn and Bizard head off into City Hall, you've left Alistair back at Dembunsdo, still asleep at the table.
Yes, we don't need to bring him with us everywhere. He really slows down and escape with the sleeping.
I'll be safe there.
Kav, you walk up to the rubble, which is basically what it is. And the stone arch that was there collapsed in words. There's just this jagged cavity. Since you've been gone, they've replaced
You can breathe for the first time.
Yep.
I heard it as I said it.
Amy's not here. I had to. She would have sang it like a beautiful princess.
You feel this weight lifted off of you really more than anything.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast, and I'm your dungeon master Russ More, he-him. Also with me today is Karla Maxtad is Bonwyn Everbane, she-her.
I feel like this is above Kav's pay grade, oh boy.
Tom Laird is Kavlarananan Goldweave, he-him.
Wait, what does that mean?
And Kyle Claset is Bizard the Wizard, he-him.
Nerd.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast, and we'd love for you to join us today at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast. You'll get a seven day free trial to check things out. And now let's get right to it. Fuck it, let's play.
The small wooden barricades that were put up, somebody's replaced them with this temporary iron barrier. It's too thin really to stop anyone who's determined, but just sturdy enough to discourage anybody who's curious. There's a sign that hangs so you've missed some things. Slightly crooked that says structural instability do not approach.
Around the area, you notice that there are a few people who, I mean, you've spent some time in Vinter Smith, so you don't necessarily know everybody, but there's some people that are milling a boat, and they look like perhaps they're from out of town.
There looks to be, you would classify him as a mason. He's got a work belt with like a hammer and trowel. He's inspecting the damage, but never really touches his tools. There's a man seated on just like a stoop, not too far away. And it looks like he's writing down something, looking up at the wreckage and then continually just jots back down in his book. He's keeping notes.
None of them seem to be interfering with anything. They don't seem to be asking questions. They're just watching. There's a couple people also who you've noticed now that you've returned that have done a couple laps.
As one of them passes, and they're just barely out of earshot, you hear one of them say to someone who they're passing in the other, in the opposite direction, barely whispered, we only intervene if it changes classification and then keep walking.
I feel like this is above Cav's pay grade, oh boy.
I'm gonna go over to the guy with the notepad.
And I'm gonna say, hi, did you happen to see who put up the sign and the barricades?
Oh, yes. Some folks from City Hall, a couple guards and some other more clerical workers came down and helped set everything up. And he goes back to his book. It looks like he's writing on a report. You've seen many of them filled out, half of them poorly.
But it looks like a very official like City report. And he flips the page and there's the same report and he begins filling it out. What started, what you caught, very similarly to the first report that you saw on the other page.
You filling out some reports?
Oh, yes. He kind of is a little guarded with it. We're just making sure no one assigns it meaning it no longer has.
Wait, what does that mean?
Well, it's better to leave it visible. As we can see, rumors die faster that way. You'd understand, right?
Uh, sure. Yeah, I think so.
Okay, good. He goes back to writing in the report.
Are there any other people walking by, like making their circuits again?
You kind of start walking back and you hear another voice from one of these people who have stopped and are observing casually. And you hear, no, we're not sealing it yet.
Okay, so I've heard classification and sealing it. I head back to the guy with the notebook. Hi, sorry. Sorry to bother you.
Oh, no, of course.
So what will happen to this? Like, you want to leave it visible so people don't think anything is askew or whatever. No rumors.
Yes.
But like, you guys fill it in, seal it off, dig it out. What happens?
We don't do anything to it. He looks at you like dead in the eyes.
So you don't you don't do anything?
We don't do anything to it.
Oh, okay. Who's we?
He looks at you confused. We're gonna cut into City Hall.
Why did they leave me alone?
I know I need to be doing something, but I am a himbo and this is beyond me.
Who's we?
Do we work together?
Oh my god. Do you also work at City Hall? I wasn't there much.
You two are looking for Oak, correct?
Correct.
Okay, you head in. Bonwyn, you know, whereabouts his office is. You've been here. Bizarre, you work here. You know exactly where his office is.
The two of you stroll past the front desk and they look up at you.
Are we? Isn't there like 10,000 stairs?
Okay, you don't stroll past.
I mean, we're all a bit fitter now than we were a few months ago with all the adventuring, but still.
Oh, maybe they'll put in some kind of moving sidewalks.
It's like they don't want people coming to complain.
Exactly.
You stroll past the front desk and there's a new receptionist there this morning and she looks up at you and says, yeah, do you have an appointment?
Oh, we're just going to see Oak. Don't worry about it, hon.
Your name?
Just keep going.
Layla.
And sorry. Well, Oak actually has a pretty heavy schedule today.
He's such a hard worker, isn't he?
Yes, yes, yes, yes. I can call ahead. Just make sure that there's nobody in his office if you'd prefer.
I mean, sure. We're used to just dropping in on him, but that's okay.
Yeah, give him a call. Spawn win, Bizard.
Pro persuasion.
Come on, Layla.
Got me on my knees here.
That was only a 13. Bizard, do better.
I was brushing her off.
So you were engaging with her as I was like, I'm an asshole.
Don't worry about it.
I'm actually also going to my office, so I'll swing by.
Of course, I know the etiquette.
If there's not somebody there, then we'll talk to him.
But of course, if he has a meeting, then we won't bother him.
So persuasion is going to be a 14.
Well, that was better.
She looks concerned.
But then down to the books, he actually does have a clearing in his schedule.
I'm sure if you're as friendly as you say you are, it should be fine.
Okay. As you were, as you were.
Great to meet you, Layla.
Are you new to town?
I don't know you.
Yeah, well, they they've been bringing in some new people to work at City Hall.
Great. That's good.
So I'm that's really good.
Brought in from from Kingstown, among with some others in the office.
You might see some new faces if you haven't been in in a while.
Well, if you need any weapons, come see me at Everbane's over on the hot block.
I'd love to see you or, you know, we'll probably see a Brewed Awakening one night.
Have you been there yet for Wing Night?
I haven't made it to Wing Night, but oh, you have to go.
You have to go. It is a must.
It's really something.
Well, I hope I hope to see you there.
You know, you know where it is.
Great. OK.
You two make it back and we cut and there's a and you knock it to his door
and you hear from inside. Yes, come in.
Open the door for Bonwyn.
Oh, Bonwyn, bizarre.
Hi Oak. Lovely to see you.
Excuse me. I was just moisturizing my feet.
I'm glad you're doing self care as well.
You can't just give and give.
You need to take care of yourself.
This is the time when I just have my tea,
moisturize my feet, read a little book before I get back into the meetings.
How are things going?
You have a lot of new responsibilities.
A lot of new responsibilities.
Yes, they've really started to recognize the type of work
that I was doing as well as other people's work.
Where's Cav? Yeah, no one.
Oh, he's Nina gave him a little assignment to watch the rubble.
He watching stones. Yeah, he's watching stones.
Exactly. But he said designated there if he was back from leave.
Oh, that does make sense.
We were wondering.
It seems sort of not in his department, but that makes sense.
You know him better than anyone.
You are best friends.
I mean, when you're on leave, you don't really have a department.
So I'm glad he I'm glad he showed back up to work today, though,
because otherwise I probably would have had to go do that job.
I don't want to do that.
You can't do everything.
Oh, you know, you don't come to talk about feet and rocks.
What are you here for?
Russ, real quick,
I want to roll insight to see if he's basically alluding to Cav
getting canned if he doesn't do his job.
That's what it sounded like.
I mean, that is the way it came across.
That's definitely the way it came across.
Which like from Oak.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
It's very it's very forward for Oak.
So that's a 12.
Yeah, yeah.
No, that's definitely the implication that you're gathering from him.
Well, I mean, he hasn't showed up for work for a long time.
So it makes sense.
You know, your dad's fifth wedding doesn't really cut it at that point.
Especially last minute.
You didn't you just like no call, right?
Like you didn't.
Yeah, no, we we totally get it, of course.
Oak, we're here for two things.
OK, the second one is super fun.
So we're going to save that till after.
But maybe like bizarre, do you want to tell him?
We were wondering if you could put that big brain of yours
to help us with something. Oh, yeah.
So there is this old abandoned town
outside of Lingersville, you know, the ghost town.
Yeah. Yeah. What is it called? Lingersville.
Lingersville. That's Lingersville.
I know. I know. I couldn't remember.
It was just standing around in the back of my mind, just waiting there.
And I couldn't yeah, I couldn't quite remember.
Yeah, it was the original settlement before before Vintersmouth.
And, you know, Vintersmouth came in and then it all dried up.
And well, now it's now it's a ghost town.
Kids just go out there looking for ghosts, I guess.
I don't know what's out there. I don't make it out.
You know, probably just make it out.
That's that's what people do.
We're wondering, OK,
if you could use your research excellence to find
like a deeper history.
I kind of just know I'd already forgotten, to be honest.
But what you just said, like, I remember that Lingersville and,
you know, the river dried up.
But maybe in the old library, there's like something like an older book,
because that was so long ago, right?
It was actually a more contemporaneous source.
Right. As to perhaps more more information on the exact like
what was the town like?
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah. And you said it was it was abandoned after Vintersmouth.
Yeah. Vintersmouth was just a little
just the speck on the map when when the
when the when the river dried up and, you know, everybody had to
you had to vacate. A lot of people, I understand, went back
and went to Kingstown and then several others.
Some came here. Just came here.
You know, it was the closest, closest place.
River drying up is kind of wild, though, like it's because the river
is so wide here and it's just not that much further away that just.
Yeah, I know it just kind of forks off.
But I haven't. Yeah.
And you go by. The town got forked.
It's like it's like a buildup of like rubble, right?
Like you go by it when you're on the on the boat to Kingstown.
But yeah, yeah, it's a little grown over.
So if you didn't know that it was out there,
you probably wouldn't have realized that it forked.
Exactly. Yeah.
I bet kids these days, they don't even know about it.
They're probably not making out there.
They're probably making out somewhere else.
I mean, they're probably making out somewhere else.
Likely you guys think about kids making out a lot.
Yeah, I you know, we were kids once, too.
And yeah, I guess I was just reminiscing about, like, you know,
when we were in school together and that was where, you know, that's
ghost towns, abandoned towers.
That's what I was. Yeah.
Oh, you get it.
I'm sorry if that made you uncomfortable.
I was curious. I said it's fine.
Yeah. No, thank you for questioning it.
That's the right thing to do.
To the to the point of why we're here, Oak,
we certainly don't want to take up your time.
You're very busy.
Do you happen to have a clerk that you could send
to fetch these records for?
Well, Cav's back, right?
Well, Cav's on assignment at the rubble.
Oh, right. Cav's on the assignment at the rubble.
Already assigned. We can't send Cav down there.
No, that would be ridiculous. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, we've got.
Wouldn't really play to his strengths, though, would it?
No. Yeah.
Really be. Let's. Good call.
Hey, you, how you doing?
It's me. Just just just me today.
Hanging out in the middle, having a great time.
I hope you're having a great time, too.
This has been just a wonderful little episode that we're doing.
And we get to we get to keep we get to keep doing it.
Hey, and we keep doing it because of people like you.
That's right. You know, it also helps podcasts
is when you spread the good word of the podcast,
share it with your friends, your family,
we haven't done a call out like this in a while,
where we get you to go over to your grandparents house
and go onto their phone that they they may or may not use so much,
depending on where they exist in the grandparent spectrum and subscribe us.
They'll get notifications, they'll get a little pop up.
Maybe it'll be a little surprise for them.
They'll click it and they'll hit play.
They'll be wonderfully drawn in to the world of Dumbgeons and Dragons.
And depending on which episode it is, it may be wholesome
and fun like that, or it may be a little bit
outside of the wholesome nature, but still fun.
Both instances will be fun.
One just might be a little less wholesome.
So, yeah, what I did tell you is to go subscribe
all of your parents and grandparents and friends and family and siblings
so that they get notifications and maybe it'll just appear
and it'll be like that YouTube album that just showed up on people's phones
that everybody got really upset about.
But they won't be upset about it because it's Dumbgeons and Dragons.
So I don't know where I'm really going with this.
They the the gist of what I was trying to say was,
if you could share us with your with anybody
that would help us reach more people.
We're trying to find new creative ways.
We haven't done a giveaway in a while.
So more details to come on that.
I'm talking with the team tonight as we record
about what we can give away and how we can give it away.
But don't let that hold you back.
We won't be doing any specific.
How many people in your family did you spoof and add the show to?
So more details to come on that.
Hey, another thing that we do is we dedicate an episode to a patron.
So we will do that right now.
Today's episode dedication goes to Pinji.
That's with a P. Hey, Pinji.
I actually don't know if there's a Binge on here,
so that might have been a clarification that I didn't need to make.
But you never know, right?
Thank you so much for being here, Pinji.
We really appreciate you.
You too.
If you're on Patreon or if you haven't signed up
to be a patron, you can do so right now
and get a seven day free trial.
And if you are signed up, well, recommend somebody.
Does somebody have a birthday or a big event coming up?
I think Easter's the next big one.
Not generally a big gift one, but maybe that's where you spin it.
Is every Easter you gift somebody
patronship over on Dumbgeons and Dragons Patreon feed?
Yeah, Patreon.com slash dump dragon cast.
Thanks again for being here, Pinji.
And we'll get you back to the episode
and hope that you have a wonderful week.
OK, love you. Bye.
Look, I'll get a couple.
I'll get a couple of people on it, see what they can find.
If they can't find it, well, I might go.
I might I might know where in the where in the archives
down in the basement they are.
Do you think?
I mean, it's just first thing in the morning right now.
We could get that info by like tonight.
And if so, the second fun thing I mentioned
is that Cav said he really wanted us to all go out for dinner together.
Our treat.
He said specifically, oh, I miss Oak.
I haven't seen him.
We should all go out for dinner at that at that cool restaurant, Cave.
You can get a reservation at Cave.
I haven't been able to get in at all.
And I'm like next to the head honcho here at City Hall.
Exactly. Exactly.
Well, the owner of Cave is in the Business Owners Association.
So bizarre. And I made a couple of calls and yeah.
What do you think? Does that does that work?
Can you send some of your minions to get some info and then meet us?
And, you know, reunited with your best friend.
Yeah, I can send them.
I can send them right away, get them on it.
And if they're too slow, like they take longer than 20 minutes,
I'll just head down there myself. Amazing.
So like seven, seven at Cave.
And you know, Cave, Stonebreaker.
Gosh, you guys know everybody, don't you?
Of that business association, we all know each other.
It's not that big of a town.
OK, so information on Lingersville.
Seven o'clock tonight, Cav will be there.
Should I bring should I bring?
Is it like a black tie affair?
I've never been in.
I don't think black tie.
I'd say, um, business casual.
OK, smart casual. Yeah, OK.
I've got not a polo.
I know you love a polo,
something a bit more elevated.
Yeah, I would go with dark tones.
I hear that there's like a nice blue lighting.
So, OK, because it is in a cave, of course.
OK, that sounds great.
I have just a few minutes to my next meeting
and I have to finish my exfoliation around.
I appreciate you coming in.
I will get all the information I can hear,
get those clerks on it right away, me on it following
when they don't find the right information.
And then I'll meet you at seven at K.
I believe they will find the right information,
but all of that sounds fantastic.
I hope so, too.
Thank you so much for your time.
We know you're so busy.
Good to see you both.
Good to see you, too.
We cut back outside to Cav.
And this purse, this person who you've
who's writing the reports is looking up at you, says, yes,
we don't do anything to it.
And he's looking at you like you should know
what he's talking about.
OK, but then like, who will?
He looks and like you kind of look where he's looking
and he's making eyes to the other people
around this location.
And he goes back to writing in his book
and you hear like soft footsteps behind you,
someone you just assume that there's someone
who's been walking around the perimeter.
And this person just whispers behind you and they say,
Lord Harrison prefers this approach.
And then they continue to walk.
Who put the what now?
There's a this person continues to walk
and the person writing the report,
he looks back down, flips the page
and continues to fill out a new version
of the same report.
You
perhaps standing in slight confusion
are tapped on the shoulder
and there's a clearing of a throat.
Excuse me, Mr. Kavlarananne Goldweave.
I have a report for you to fill out.
It's the end of your shift.
OK, sounds great.
Tom's face right now is so cute
because he totally is calf and is like, what now?
What?
I have to what now?
Oh, sweet, sweet summer child.
It's wonderful.
Tom, I'm going to send you a report.
OK.
I'm getting homework, Tom.
That's right.
Anybody can look at it.
I'm not looking at paperwork, not my job.
Oh yeah, that's right.
F that.
I saw two people pop up
I'm not even in this scene.
From one person back out.
You are handed this report and this clerk
just nods at you and hands it to you
and walks off and before they walk off,
they say just file it with Leila before you head out
and someone else will come to take your position.
Wait, who's Leila?
The receptionist.
Oh, OK.
She must have got a new receptionist.
A couple of weeks ago.
I mean, you've been on leave.
So yes, you look at the report
and it's the Department of Infrastructure
and Public Assurance Interim Status
Confirmation Structural Irregularity Report.
You look this over and give me a...
I'm a snoopy bitch.
I looked at it too.
I couldn't resist.
You read through it.
There are a number of things that appear very
just stock and standard for looking after an event
or a location like this.
Area secured against casual access.
No active structural movement observed.
Pretty standard things.
One piece does draw your attention
based on like the conversations you've been having
and it's under operational determination.
The final checkbox there says
site retains no functional significance.
Something about that, you're not exactly sure,
but something about that isn't...
You've seen these reports.
Perhaps you've filled one out
without paying attention to it,
but that feels different somehow,
particularly with the events that have happened recently.
I also thought the event did not materially manifest
was an interesting checkbox.
Oh yes, yes, that one as well.
So I'll just fill this out
and take it back to City Hall.
City Hall, that's, we're all good then?
Yeah, you got it.
Oh, there's the next watch coming down as well.
Okay, yeah, I'll just...
Should I fill it out here or do it as I walk back?
What's your preference?
Wherever you like, it's paperwork.
If you need to just observe any additional remarks
you would like to state about your time here,
you can fill them out.
Sometimes that's better on site.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, no, I like that, I like that.
I'll just, I'll move off to the side
and get out of your guys' way,
but I'll fill this out here.
Of course, of course.
And Ross, I'm gonna try as hard as I can
to eavesdrop and not be obvious about it.
Okay, eavesdrop with the people taking over for you?
Yeah, yeah, for sure.
There are two guards that come down
and they position themselves closer to the rubble
and it's not long after
that you've been reprieved of your duty
that Bonwyn and Bizard, you hear them conversing
coming down the steps from City Hall as well.
As they're approaching, you hear one other piece
that jumps out, a couple other pieces.
One of the guards says to the other,
well, amid some other conversations,
people relax when they can see the problem.
It's fine, everybody, look,
they're not even paying attention anymore.
And the other, it's stable enough,
it's not going anywhere,
so we might as well just keep watching it, I guess.
Eventually, people will move on
and we can just brush everything away.
Bonwyn and Bizard, you make your way back to Cav,
who's seated, filling out paperwork.
Oh, I thought you were on site today,
you weren't gonna have to do any paperwork.
Ew. There's always paperwork.
Oh, yeah.
Bureaucracy, right?
Speaking of the king of bureaucracy.
Guess who's so excited to have dinner with you tonight?
Yes.
Well, with us, it's the four of us, right?
With us, yeah, yeah, yeah.
All of us, sounds like, I mean,
Bizard, correct me if I'm wrong,
he said he would send a clerk,
but I think he's doing himself.
He wants to impress you, because he loves you.
So he's gonna find out.
He just remembered off the top of his head
some information I'd already forgotten, Lingersville.
Oh, right, Lingersville, yeah.
Yeah, as soon as I heard it, I was like,
oh yeah, of course, but...
So, yeah, was it super boring here?
What'd you do, just stand here?
It was pretty boring, and then I whisper it,
but legit, they are just gonna leave this here
and hope people don't notice it.
Yeah, that sounds like the plan.
How are people not gonna notice
a giant pile of rubble in the middle of...
Oh, no, it's what's under the rubble.
Oh, I see.
Yeah.
So wait, they still assume that
there's an entryway underneath the rubble?
I mean, it sure seems that way.
Yeah, just to fill out this paperwork.
Would that make sense considering
how Alydin got out,
or was Alydin just caught under the rubble?
Typically, I don't feel like a portal would stay open
without its structural support.
At least based off of what I've learned.
Can I look at that form?
Let me, I pull out of my book,
Portals, Portals, Portals,
and I start referencing with the book
that I have that's all about portals.
Thank God for Kyle and his memory.
Sorry, what is it you're looking for?
Oh, I'm looking to see the effects
of the collapse on portal containers
is what I would, is how Kyle would say it.
Make an investigation roll just to see
how quickly you might be able to find this
as you're just kind of sitting around here.
That's an 11.
Yeah, you scan through, you find a couple entries,
but more or less what you found is
any portal, be it a runic portal
or some sort of other dimensional rift or planar event.
If those, if those features
that went into creating it are destroyed,
this book leads you to believe
that the portal itself should also be destroyed.
Okay.
So, yeah, based on chapter 13, section four here,
it says that if the structure,
if the housing of the portal collapses,
then the portal should collapse too.
So there's really, really, but then again,
this is, I guess, the archive or a false,
and the fee, we have the fee and we have the fee.
Is that too confusing?
I'm starting to realize it
now that I'm saying it out loud.
Oh, I think if it sounds like they make sense,
they go together.
Like two sides of.
Oh, okay.
Yeah, right?
Kav, what do you think this means?
Maybe considered inert for municipal purposes.
Not sure. There is some weird,
is this normal for like city property damage?
Look, there's a lot of interesting.
The event did not materially manifest.
Yeah, but that one really stood out.
Public narrative remains consistent?
Yeah, and what does corrective action mean?
Well, and the do not copy to public record.
I thought we were getting away from that
under the new regime.
I don't know.
Look, it's my first day back.
Maybe we can ask Oak about this tonight too.
Oh, good call.
Because he probably,
God, he probably designed this paperwork.
We know Oak.
Nerd.
No, I respect it.
So who gave you this to do?
What, did like a supervisor come down or something?
Yeah, like that guy over there with the clipboard.
Oh, it's always the guy with the clipboard.
Always.
Russ, is the Mason still there?
No.
No, he's not.
Fine, I won't go talk to my fellow trades person.
Bro out with them, find out what's up.
Talking stones?
Yeah, exactly.
Are you like stone, bro?
Did you see that I'm a dwarf?
So we should, we have a lot in common.
No, a lot of the people that,
Cav was like, they're around.
They've seemed to have filtered away.
Okay.
Well, this is all weird.
Which maybe just is normal.
So do we change?
Do we just say, well, this is normal now
when things are weird?
Well, that's true.
A lot of weird things have been happening lately.
Yeah.
I'm getting a bit too existential.
Yeah, I don't know.
Let's live our life like normal,
which is very weird at this point.
Yes.
So their normal doesn't have an impact on us.
Let's just do whatever we need to do
and we know it's in service of the town.
Yeah, yeah, great.
You're right, you're right.
Yeah.
So are you gonna fill that out and take it back
or there's so many stairs.
Do you remember how many stairs there are?
I haven't been to city hall in a while.
Here, I'll fill it out for you.
I just take it and I mark it haphazardly.
Then I hand it to Clippy McClippersen.
Love it.
Kyle, I will, you don't have to do it right now,
but I will get you to actually fill it out.
Nope.
You've said you would, Tom Smith.
No, no, I'm saying,
you said I don't have to do it right now.
I'm saying, nope, I am doing it right now.
It was way funnier when you were just being a jerk.
No, no.
I'm glad it was funnier.
Cathar's a new receptionist.
Her name's Layla.
She seems very sweet.
I've heard about Layla.
Okay, yeah, I think she's down from Kingstown.
There's a lot of new faces.
A lot of new faces down there, as one would imagine.
I mean, yeah, it's been a hot minute.
Yeah, yeah, a lot of changes
with the shuffling out of Mernops, so.
Bizard, do you finish filling out the form
and you perhaps give it to Cav to take to the clerk
or you take it yourself, regardless of how that happens?
You're walking back to the group
and you feel a pull in your jacket pocket.
Oh shit.
Same pull that you felt earlier
and you reach your hand in
and you pull out the spool of thread.
It's reacting.
It's not violent or dramatic in any way,
but it feels like it's moving intentionally
and the thread begins to unspool on its own,
only about a foot or two.
It pulls out into the air and then stops.
It's not pulling towards the false entrance.
It's pulling north of the city.
From the map that we looked at,
which there was a line going north,
which one was that headed to?
That was the one that intersected with Lingersville.
Well, son of a dick.
All right.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season four, episode 53.
Starring Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane,
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard,
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design
of today's episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyuk.
Music is from Epidemic Sound
and sound effects are from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library, and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyuk,
Angaron Kierzen, Perry Matey,
Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss,
L.A. Branton, Chibs1012, and Kudzu828.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast,
and all of our amazing community
help make sure that we have adventures
for you every single week.
Come join us today, Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
We hope to see you over there,
and you have yourself, right now, a great week.
Yes, and we'll talk to you very, very soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.
Dumbgeons and Dragons.