Hey, friend. So glad to have you. Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in just a moment.
Bizard, you are running your hand along the stage and you feel an inscription of sorts.
You direct your attention away from the children and down to this and you see
symbols similar to the ones that you saw along the path. But even more so,
like there is a hint of recognition that comes to you from your schooling.
You run your hand along this one and then you notice that there are several more along the
stage. If you can roll arcana or history. I believe it will be arcana.
Oh, that's a natural one. I'm really fucking up in the magic area today.
Everyone's very confused.
These are really difficult to read. I'm having a hard time. So I'm going to take a bottle of
ink and I'm going to pour it in to fill in the worn out sigils and runes so that they're
clearer and easier to read.
I like that. I like that. Yeah. Do that. And Bonwyn and Cav, you
see Bizard do this, like pouring ink onto the stage and like pulling out a scrap of
parchment. So that brings your attention over there as well. And you see that he's pouring
it into these symbols along the stage. Allow you to now that everybody's kind of crowded
around looking, allow you to roll again with this new version of the same symbol.
Thank you, Ross. And what are we rolling?
Arcana or history.
Yeah. Could I also roll? Like I would have done, you know, like research into
even not understanding it, but just for like artistic flourishes on things, you know?
Sure. 13.
13.
I got a 25 this time.
Oh, that's so much better. Thank God for Bizard.
The ink has brought it all together. So you do that and you're flipping this over
and the two of you, Bonwyn and Cav, are looking at them like,
yeah, we know what this is. You don't know what this is.
The first one, you pick up the symbol and on the paper, it immediately comes to you.
The symbol represents a movement. Maybe it's a class that, you know, you said the dance
wasn't a particularly strong one, but maybe it's one you kind of like nodded off through
and didn't quite pay attention. But this movement is says or is interpreted as
step forward. With that context, you look at the next few. The next one says spin.
The next one says bow. The fourth one says clap.
However, one section as you're looking between these, one section of the dance
floor is slightly cracked and you go over and make an investigation roll at that.
Twelve.
You pick away at this crack in there and it reveals another inscription hidden beneath
and the inscription says only the banjo man may end the song.
So are these kids doing this step forward, spin, bow, clap move?
They are doing step forward, spin, bow, clap and then they are stumbling over the final step.
Gotcha.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master,
Russ More, he, him. Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
I grab it and I pull him over me and I flip him over.
Carla Maxstead as Bonwyn Everbane, she, her.
We're very weak. We don't know anything.
Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave, he, him.
Which unfortunately is actually radiant damage, but that's all right.
And Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, he, him.
Sorry, I've never fucked up this bad at dancing, y'all.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast and it wouldn't be around if it
wasn't for fine patrons just like you. Well, you can sign up today at patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast, get a seven-day free trial and access to a whole bunch
of additional adventures that are ready and waiting for you.
And now, fuck it, let's play.
While you think on that, we're going to cut back to your room, Alydin.
You're staring at yourself in the mirror with this music box that you've released,
released the mechanism on.
The mechanism, when you turned it backwards,
it distorted into an eerie whisper that repeated the phrase,
not real, not real, not real, not real.
You've released it and the song continues forward again.
Well, I'm done with this.
So, Alydin is going to strip the bed,
tie the sheets into knots, carefully open the window
and throw out the music box.
Fuck that thing.
Fucking things going first and throw out the makeshift rope.
Tied it to like the bed frame or something like that.
But I don't go down it.
Um, you said that there was a closet.
I said there was a dresser.
A dresser.
I go under the bed.
Okay.
Um, and then I get out from under the bed
and realize I have to make a big noise.
Or you'll just be waiting by yourself in a dark space.
And now I'm just under the bed and it's cold because I've opened the window.
Um, I'm gonna, I need it to be, I need it,
I need to make them think that I really went out there.
Alydin throws her bucket out the window
and make sure that it hits the roof.
Like it doesn't clear it.
It's in the middle of the field.
Uncle Rico's that bucket over those mountains.
And then I quickly hide under the bed.
You throw the bucket and it goes over the edge of the roof
and you hear it hit, um, like a, a porch post or a banister
or something down below.
Like you hear it strike wood, um, and clatter the contents of,
inside the bucket rattle together.
You hear like the sheet pulling against the window frame.
The conversation you hear silenced downstairs, like it stops.
And then you hear some slow footsteps
move towards where the sound came to the front door.
You hear as the door opens and a few steps out onto the porch.
I, I, I'm, I'm waiting because I only heard one set of footsteps.
There are two creepy not parents in this house
and I'm hoping they both go look for me.
You hear this, this, this storm door close at the front
and a few steps, uh, muffled steps out on the front porch.
Um, and then you hear the heels again.
Of your mother and they're coming up the stairs.
They come up the stairs and round the, the mid landing
and come up again and you hear slow footsteps
and a, and a soft voice that calls out.
I do not respond.
I'm holding my breath.
I'm out that window.
Roll stealth.
How about a 19?
Yeah, you did.
You hear the, the handle on the door turn
and then light creek of the hinges and a few steps come in.
The woman pauses in the room and she calls out again.
Alydin, are you playing hide and seek?
She slowly walks over to the window.
She pokes her head out the window.
Sorry, a lot of visual comedy going on right now.
Kyle's just miming what I'm thinking and just like,
I just push her out the window, but I don't think,
like they haven't actually done anything to hurt me.
It's just weird and so I don't think I'm ready to murder a person.
Strong urge for defenestration.
Roll for self-control.
No, I just, I stay hidden.
Woman's still looking out the window.
You can't see her.
You can see her feet.
You're tucked as far to the wall as you can.
She's standing by the window and she's there for what is a good long moment.
And then from outside, you hear this low warping note
that feels like it's being carried on the wind.
Then the woman pulls her head back inside and pulls the sheet back up.
You hear your bucket kind of clanging as it's being dragged up and over.
And then she pulls it back in and then closes the window.
Says, Alydin, when you're done playing your game, come down for dinner, okay?
And she walks back out your room, back downstairs,
and you hear the door open downstairs.
The man come back in.
Damn it.
Ugh.
As you hear the door latch shut and the footsteps begin to move back downstairs,
you hear the clattering of plates being set around a table.
Again?
Again, the low conversation starts back up.
You can't make it out.
Okay, that didn't work.
Um, Alydin is gonna play along.
She goes into her dresser.
She finds clothes.
She changes into whatever pretty dress is in there.
Very out of character.
And she opens her door and skips downstairs.
What's for dinner?
Back up a little bit.
You open your door with your dress on,
and you immediately hear the conversation downstairs stop.
You walk downstairs and enter into the dining room area
where there's another meal set.
You don't know how long, like this is going back to like your hands, right?
Like you don't know how long you've been here.
Is this meal the same meal that was here when you got to this place?
Or have you been here for a long time?
You don't know.
Do I feel hungry?
I'm an orphan.
I'm always hungry.
You're an orphan.
You're always hungry.
On the table, there is a roast in the center.
There's some potatoes.
And at each of the place settings, there is a bowl of soup.
You sit down at the table and you see all of this wonderful meal.
And your mother reaches over and says,
I'm sorry we didn't find you in your game and hands you this basket of rolls.
Oh, that's okay.
I was just fooling around.
You know, I'm such a good hider.
Oh, of course.
You play those games so, so well.
And she passes the roll down to your father.
And you look down into the soup.
I guess first, do you go to eat anything?
Play our knowledge because Amy isn't tired.
It's so tough.
I ate the first time, didn't I?
I believe so.
I think you did.
I think you ate at least something.
It was a meal.
You've been gone for who knows how long.
I'm a starving orphan.
I ate.
Yeah, I remember you ate quite well.
If they were going to poison me, they probably would have already poisoned me.
But I'm going to kind of like pick at my roll and drop the pieces of bread into the soup.
Because I like a mushy because I'm a fucking animal.
Sure.
Yeah, you tear apart the roll and you drop it in.
I mean, you're just used to like day olds that you get your hands on.
So it needs it.
You drop the pieces into the soup and like there's pleasant
nothing conversation happening between your parents.
Um, you drop the pieces into the soup and that bowl of soup
begins reflecting a distorted version of your face.
The surface as the soup begins to settle at the bottom begins to clear.
And it begins showing a memory that is like rushes back to you.
It shows you at the orphanage where you had grown up for the majority of your child life.
And then as this memory comes flooding back to you, the image in the soup is gone.
You're broken from that moment as the father figure who you pictured right beside you
is now standing, like standing over you and he's put a hand on your shoulder.
He says, is everything all right, Alydin?
Yeah, dad, every everything's fine.
And as he puts his hand on your shoulder and you look up at him,
I grab it and I pull him over me and I flip him over.
No, I'm just kidding.
Sorry, go on.
As he put his face in the soup and drowns in the soup.
I just hold it in there.
I'm gonna waterboard my mom with the soup.
I'm gonna get all kinds of weird, I'm on cold meds.
Things are getting weird.
As he puts his hand on your shoulder and asks you that question, you turn and look up at him.
You begin to feel a weakening in your body, strength leaving your body.
And he looks down at you and says, okay, that's okay.
You just eat up, eat up, okay?
And he goes back and sits down at the table and he himself begins
slurping on the soup and eating the roll.
You feel lightheaded and woozy.
I don't fucking touch the soup, but I eat the, I eat the roll.
What's left of the roll in my hand.
You begin to put the roll in your mouth and you're looking between
the parents.
They're looking at you and smiling.
And we'll cut back to the stage.
So much more than what we got done.
Welcome to The Middle, everybody.
The Middle.
Hey there, so glad to be here.
We just got out of our recording of The Adventures Of,
which you can now join us and watch from the backstage over on Patreon.
And while you're talking about all the great experience that everybody's having with that,
I'm going to go and do the thing that I should have done a while ago.
Oh yeah, we know what you're talking about.
You know what though?
This was kind of like our trial time of doing this live record with our backstage.
We got two backstage beauties.
And maybe they can let us know how it went.
I can't put a heart.
Less than three.
Wow, that's harsh.
Oh no, the alligator ate the three.
That's all I'm going to think about now every time I see that, Kyle.
But if you want to hang out and do the backstage thing while we play live,
you can go to patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Anyone on the supporting producers tier and up is welcome to join us.
Kat says much fun.
Very wow.
Very well.
That's a ringing endorsement.
Yeah, get that gook hang too.
But also if you join us on Patreon, you get an episode dedicated to you.
Yeah, you sure do.
Like today's patron.
Who is the amazing, wonderful, fantastic, stupendous, intelligent.
I got to keep track of this better.
Jason Quinn.
Thank you so much.
And I mean all those things that I said.
All those things are true.
Also, I think you look great in jeans.
They really work for you.
Way to go, Jason.
Thanks for being here.
Way to do it.
Thanks, Jason.
And thanks everybody for joining us tonight in The Adventures Of,
which you can go listen to over on Patreon too.
You don't just have to join us for the record,
but there's six seasons of amazing, super fun stuff
where we're now realizing that we do secretly love us.
That's what we're realizing.
It's been my long con to make us the ultimate big bad in the end.
Oh god.
Nah, we're fine.
Yeah, you guys are all right.
That's right.
Thank you all for being here.
We'll get you back to the episode.
We love you so much.
K, love you.
Bye.
Love you.
I'm going to turn to Bono and Cavan and be like,
okay, so he obviously didn't teach these kids the final move.
And these kids don't understand, they learned the steps,
but they don't understand why they're doing the steps.
And, you know, music and dance correlated with each other rhythmically.
And in the song that brought all these kids here,
says with music suite, your steps he'll guide.
So hopefully following the rhythmic pulse of the music
and filling in the steps, that's literally all I've got.
Okay.
Okay, let's do it.
So I'm going to hop on stage and I'm going to try to create my own move
that fills in with the rhythm where these kids keep messing up.
Okay.
You get up on stage and you step into formation with these children.
Mm-hmm.
Are all three of you doing it or are you just letting Bazaar handle this?
I feel like I'm going to see what he's doing.
Yeah, I want to see the move and then I'll.
See what the vibe is.
Are we all going to like freestyle our own move?
Are we all going to try?
Right?
Okay, get up and you get into position.
You begin the steps that you've watched them.
There's four steps.
You've picked those up.
And then roll me either a performance or dexterity.
Oh, performance, definitely.
Okay, guys, go fuck yourself.
That's a nine.
Was uneven.
I mean, you trip.
I don't know.
Yeah.
So slippery from all that ink.
Damn it.
You get up on stage and you do the four moves and then you attempt a fifth move.
You whatever you do causes you to stumble along with the children.
And then Bonwyn and Cav, you hear this now, too.
Bonwyn, you hear the creaking coming from the surrounding forest again.
Bazaar as you're trying to find a new step.
You keep attempting this and the correlation clicks
for the two of you off the stage as you're watching him.
The more bizarre tries and fails, the louder this sound gets.
And as you look back to him and Cav, you're looking over at Bonwyn.
You see like a parting, a bending of the trees as this
nightmarish creature resembling a twisted marionette of roots and broken instruments,
its limbs held aloft by invisible strings, and it begins moving out of the forest.
And all three of you look over now as its joints creak like old wood
and its hollow chest cavity thrums with the haunting echoes
of the banjo music that you've been hearing.
As horror steps into the clearing and is making its way over to the stage.
I'm gonna get you to roll for initiative.
Sorry, I've never fucked up this bad at dancing, y'all.
Even on his worst day.
And these dice can go away for tonight.
Yeah, my dice are sucking.
14.
Four.
Oh, jeez, guys.
Wow.
Why don't these guys do puzzles?
I don't know.
I'm switching from green to orange.
Bonwyn, you're going to be up first.
So the two, Bonwyn and Cavalarin, you are off the stage.
Bizarre, you are still on the stage.
You can see all three of you have seen this creature making its way towards you.
It's not moving quickly, but it is moving directly towards you.
And like the roots and its limbs seem like they can extend
and like the vines from trees are wrapping around itself.
Like this entire thing, like its face looks like a, well, I mean,
kind of like an ant from Lord of the Rings, but much more marionette.
Like there's a movement to the jaw that's happening.
Great.
I am going to like pull up my flint and steel and light an arrow on fire
and try and shoot it, because wood.
Burn it up.
All right.
Also, I have no weapon.
Bonwyn, no fight.
Bonwyn, no do anything good.
Level two.
Okay, but let's see.
Oh, 19.
Nice.
19 will hit.
Yes, yes, it will.
Excellent.
So that's five damage.
I don't know if you want to like gimme a little something because of the fire.
You want to roll a d6 worth of fire damage.
Okay, that's a three for fire damage.
And then because I hit, I can sneak attack it, I think.
Yep.
So that's an extra five damage.
There are some real dry roots right in like the lung area.
Yeah.
Yes.
I don't want to think of it as an end because I love the ends.
Yeah, no, this is.
But as some other creepy treat.
Yeah.
Call it a waltzing horror if you want to.
It's not an end.
Oh, cool.
Yeah, your arrow looses and sticks into the chest of this and you hear like this
discordant like string snapping as it strikes in and lets out this low droning note that
echoes out over all of you.
You see where the arrow hits, like the flame is still a light.
It doesn't appear that it's completely caught on all of the tree yet,
but it is still a light and stuck into them.
Do the children, like I'm going to look behind me, like are they, what are they doing?
They continue the dance.
Oh, OK.
It is this creature's turn and he lets out this low note and then begin and then continues
to move towards you.
He's going to, you know, you who's just tried to hit him Bonwyn or just hit him Bonwyn,
you, he's going to reach out with his hand and coming out of his hand are not only vines,
but these very thin strings of an instrument.
He's going to try to ensnare you with this so you can make a strength saving throw
to try to avoid this.
Oh, 19.
19, all right.
I am a hearty dwarf.
It reaches out for you and you feel these things trying to wrap themselves around your
hands and your feet.
You manage to pull yourself free and it releases itself and it takes another few
steps towards you and Cav.
Bizarre, you're still up on the stage.
The children continue to dance.
This creature has come out of the forest and is now attacking Bonwyn down off the stage.
There's an arrow that's a light in its main body as well.
You said that plank that says the banjo man can only end the song is broken already.
Yes, I did, banjo man.
The floor was slightly cracked and you pulled away at it which revealed a hidden
inscription beneath.
I'm going to try to break the whole idea of like what I know to be incantations or spells
and I'm going to try to rip the entire board out just to remove that part.
Of the equation.
Make a strength check.
That's a 14.
You break away from the group of children as they stumble on that last step and run over
to the board itself and you're pulling at it and the nails are prying themselves free
and as you're doing that, the creature before you, you've gotten quite close to it now.
The creature turns and acknowledges you as you do manage to pull this board up and out.
It splinters and breaks but yeah, you've pulled the majority of it away.
There are a few little pieces closer to the nails.
I'm going to take the inscribed part that I ripped off and just throw it off
away from the stage.
I assume that'll be my action.
I'm going to go ahead and pull out my scimitar and start up a blade song.
Just the humming of my scimitar as it spins,
creating its own little music to counter the music going on.
Amazing.
Okay.
And I'll move up to Bonwyn and Cav and be in the thick of it with them.
Got it.
That brings us to Cav.
All right.
Cav is going to have his war hammer drawn and rush forward and take a swing at this
horrible tree banjo monster.
Okay.
Unless it's a terrible idea but we're doing it anyway.
Got to do it.
We got to do something, right?
Yep.
All right.
That is a 19 to hit.
Oh yeah.
19 is going to hit.
Switching to the orange dice is paying off, Joe.
Drop that bitch down.
Excellent.
And that is seven points of crushing damage, bludgeoning damage.
I'm over here so jealous.
I'm fighting some sort of stupid mind problem and you guys get to punch and hit stuff.
Absolutely.
You crack into like the leg of this creature and you hear.
Similarly, you hear like as if you took your hammer to like the back of a guitar.
Like that's the sound that comes out of it and then the splintering wood
follows quickly after that.
It lets out this thunderous scream for lack of a better term as you do that.
Okay.
Anything else you can or would like to do?
I could probably do more but I'm going to leave it there.
Okay.
Look, after you've torn up the board, the children continue to stumble on that last step
but now that you've removed that board from the stage, you turn and you look
and the children continue to stumble for a few more paces but then they start to correct
themselves as the music continues.
However, instead of stumbling, they hit that beat in the music and they freeze
and then they continue on with the dance.
So the pattern has changed but there's still a beat in the music that's missing.
Bonwyn.
Drop that beat.
I guess.
Well, it's all up on me now.
Yes, yeah.
The three of you are basically right up on it.
Yeah.
Okay, then I'm going to switch to my short sword better.
Oh my god.
And close range and that is a now one.
That's gross.
Going out the way.
No, I'm just kidding.
But it's going away.
There's a way in the bucket.
That's right.
You try and swing out with your short sword and it ends up getting wrapped up in the vines
and branches of one of its arms and because it's a now one, you feel the same pressure
around your wrists that you felt when it first tried to attack you but this time it latches
on.
So along one of your wrists and one of your legs, you feel these strings now attached to
you.
So you are grappled for all intents and purposes but you still have, is Bonwyn left
or right handed?
Oh, I don't know.
I guess right.
I had not said.
So your right hand and right leg are both bound.
You still have your left.
Anything else you would like to do?
I don't think there is anything else I can do.
You are grappled and you begin to feel an urge to move like this.
You now feel the strings pulling up on that side of your body and it's going to try and
grab the other side.
You can make a strength saving throw to save yourself from this.
17.
So it tries to latch onto the other side.
Your right side, however, starts to dance uncontrollably, which is throwing you off
bAlydince.
So it's puppet mastering you.
It's trying to puppet master you.
Now that it's up close to everybody, it's going to swing down at you, Bazaard,
and try and strike you.
That's going to be a 15 to hit.
No, sir.
Okay.
It swings down and it hits the ground beside you and you hear this thunderous echo
throughout this space.
Ground is turned up underneath you.
Like you could tell, if this thing had hit you, it would have knocked the wind
out of you pretty hard.
Which after that happens, his arm is crushed into the ground and you see
Bonwyn trying to fight off half of what's happening.
It's your turn now.
This is very dangerous and we need to move quickly.
So I'm going to use my action to cast haste on myself, giving myself a
secondary action, which I'm going to use that to attack the vines that
are holding Bonwyn.
So I'm going to make attack against each vine, if that's possible, or
against the creature, however it works out.
Yeah, I think based on proximity, you could slice down through both of
them.
As long as you hit, you should be good.
That's a 17 on the first attack and a 16 on the second.
Both of those will hit.
All right.
1d6 plus 2.
That is 8 damage on the first attack and 6 damage on the second.
Good hit.
Same echoing string breaks happen in Bonwyn.
You quickly find yourself released and free from the need to move as the
way you were, but because your bAlydince was thrown off, you're now prone
at the foot of this monster.
Makes sense.
Kavlaran.
There's a lot going on.
There's a lot of things happening.
Yeah, a lot going on.
All right.
And if I remember correctly, Russ, our characters don't really know
shit yet.
Yeah.
We're very weak.
We don't know anything.
It's an accurate description of our characters.
Yeah.
Fair.
We don't know shit.
Yeah.
Is there shit in particular that you were hoping to know?
No, just knowing, just reminding myself that he doesn't really know
the things that he could do with his class if given the training.
Yeah, I mean, you've been in battle already, so you did pull some of your
abilities out.
Like, I think you used, what did you use?
Did you use a spectral weapon or do you have a spectral weapon?
I don't have a spectral weapon.
You did something because you saw Christina's character.
Maybe like a sacred flame?
Yeah, maybe a sacred flame.
Yeah.
Flame would be great in this situation.
Yeah, but you did pull some pAlydin or, yeah, some cleric type feature out
that we didn't really get into.
But yeah, it was after she had done hers and then you did yours.
Yeah, I'm going to, I'm assuming it would have been like spectral flame.
Yeah.
That makes sense to me.
Now that you say that, I think that's what it was.
Yeah.
And seeing the fucking kind of shit that's going on with this weird tree thing,
Kav tries to call down that spectral flame.
Okay.
Describe to me what that looks like.
Kav kind of raises his war hammer a little bit and like then like points it at the
tree banjo man monster.
Yep.
And like a crack of like really bright, not quite lightning, but like flame, it's
got a whole lot going on, kind of like comes down from the sky on top of this guy.
Okay.
Does, which unfortunately is actually radiant damage, but that's all right.
That's fine.
Yeah.
And yeah, you need to do a dex save.
Oh, that's a nat one.
Any big pluses?
Four.
So that's a max five.
Okay.
Well, that is going to hit you.
How can you have a plus four to dex?
It's a giant tree monster that seems unfit.
It's a giant instrument tree monster.
Right, right, right.
You're right.
All right, all right.
So yes, you'll take five points of radiant damage from the sky.
And that's amazing.
That comes down and like, although it's not flame, it does sear into this creature.
And one thing we missed on your turn, Bonwyn, was additional fire damage because it is now
a light from that position.
So if you want to roll me a d6 on that as well.
Six.
Oh, shit.
Okay, cool beans.
The flames are building and like smoke is billowing through and like out of this
creature's mouth now.
And we go back to the children and like you see you've been,
all of you have been kind of clocking them out of the corner.
You guys seeing if anything changes and you see that same pattern.
Like they have now, they are no longer stumbling.
They are still continuing to dance.
But there is that pause in the dance that they are not resolving still.
Have they become any more corporeal or they're still just okay?
Yeah, still everything is still the same for all intents and purposes.
And we will go to Bonwyn.
Oh, that's me.
That's you.
Okay.
Well, I mean, really all I can do is just try again with that short sword.
That is 25 to hit.
Yes, it will.
So that is a seven piercing damage and then I'll do the fire damage for this turn.
And that's a six again.
Oh, and because I hit sneak attack.
Yeah.
Which is an extra two.
That's okay.
Limbs and strings and vines are beginning to fall off of this creature.
Like it's falling to its knees.
The flames are engulfing it now.
Roll me another fire extra d6 of fire damage.
Five.
The flames now moving across its body and up over its head.
Like this discordant tune and melody begins like fracturing itself out of this creature
as it falls to its knees and splinters.
You hear crackles and pops of the wood as it falls to the ground at your feet.
There's this echoing musicality that happens.
And as the banjo music that's coming from the chest of this creature begins to fade,
you look back at the children who are slowing their dance.
But then there's a surge of music that happens and it begins to play faster.
And the children begin to dance faster, still missing that beat.
But it continues to pick up pace.
The monster appears to be defeated.
But whatever is controlling these children is not resolved.
Well, with my super speediness, I was going to go over and use four attacks to attack
the other four planks that dictate their movement.
Just go ahead and take those out.
Quickly you hop up onto the stage and you don't need to roll damage.
We can just say you go up and you hit the planks.
You destroy the symbols as they exist there.
And you see their movements as they are moving faster.
They begin to miss the steps that you are destroying.
And they begin to, rather than stop on the steps,
they begin to walk in the circle that they are creating this dance for.
As the dance stops, they begin to move around you and they all turn and look at you,
their hollow eyes staring down at you.
And in one voice they all say,
He waits for you at the hollow.
The mist that engulfs this space begins to part.
And it reveals on the far side of this clearing that you catch your eye.
A forest path that leads out of this clearing.
As this mist dissipates and the children before you become part of the mist.
Follow out into the forest.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 4 Episode 17 Starring Amy More as Alydin
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard And Russ More as your Dungeon Master
Dialogue editing and sound design of today's episode is by Russ More
Our community manager is Jessica Babyuk Music is from Epidemic Sound
And sound effects are from Epidemic Sound and Boom Library
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt
And we'd like to say a huge thank you to our supporting producers
Including Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyuk, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Angaron Kierzen, Perry Matey, Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss, and L.A. Branton
We'd love for you to join us over on Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast
Where there's so many amazing bonus episodes
And now we're opening up the backstage of our actual records
Join us today! Hey, you have a great week, we'll talk to you soon
Hope to see you over there!
What's for dinner?
And she's going through puberty, obviously
Do you want to give me another what's for dinner?
What's for dinner?
That's okay, that's okay, you try
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production