Dumbgeons and Dragons begins in a moment.
It's a beautiful day in Vintersmouth and we hear the sound of children running
through the playground outside of the school, which has been well repaired and
classes have actually started this past week.
We see Tally and Alydin walking through the playground, eyeing up a flagpole in
the middle of the school grounds.
So, Alydin, you've been like, we've been like trying to, trying to practice, but
it seems to only be able to get to do it like every, every once in a while.
Do you want to like try it right now?
Where you, where you, where you, where you like point and then you just go?
What?
Oh, come on.
It's like, we do this like every other day at least where, where you
visualize yourself some, some distance over there, and then you make yourself
go and then there's like some water and some swirling things and then
bam, you're over there.
Is this a dream you had?
No.
Quentin, do you remember seeing Alydin do that the other day?
Right?
Yeah.
We all saw that.
And then you were there and then you were over there.
And you're a little bit wet.
Yeah.
You were a little, and you like, and shook your hair out like a dog.
Remember?
I'm feeling gaslit and I really wild.
I'm just gasanding.
I haven't been here in 10 months.
I have no idea what's going on.
Did Alydin learn a new spell?
Tally, you're crazy.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Tally walks over to Quentin and say, give me, can I have your ball for a second?
Okay.
Yeah, of course.
Okay, thanks.
And she turns towards the school and hucks it on top of the building.
Rude.
Thank you.
Been working.
I mean, Alydin, you're going to get it back, right?
Yeah.
Now just do what you've been doing.
Just go up there and get it back for me.
Can you try?
Alydin walks up to the, to the edge of the school and just jumps.
Terrible vertical.
I'll let it swerve.
Reaches up and see, I don't know if I can do it on command, but she's going to try to mage hand that business to get the ball.
Okay.
Make, you have mage hand.
And it's a cantrip.
Okay, cool.
Yeah, but I haven't really used it in public.
So I'm like, really it.
Okay.
A little self-conscious about my mage hand.
Yeah.
As you focus, roll arcana.
Just, we'll just use that as a base for.
I'm going to borrow your dice.
Yeah, for sure.
We'll just use that as a base for how confident you are in making this happen.
Amy is not very confident.
I can't.
Welcome back, everybody.
It's a one.
Make sure Russ keeps using those dice and he's rolling damage on us.
He's going to roll 20s.
Yeah.
I'm going to roll ones.
Shut up.
I mean, it's, it's still.
Whatever.
So we're just proving that the dice works.
I walk up to the school and I'm like, okay.
And I reach my hand out and like squint and I screw my face up.
And I peek out from one eye.
You're straining and everybody's kind of crowded around watching you.
And you feel like the mage hand flicker.
You've done it before.
You know what it's supposed to do and look like, and you feel it like
flicker and then you hear like a little gasp and you close your eyes.
One more time and you feel like you are being swept away in a river.
Water is rushing around you.
You feel like fabrics being pulled all around your body.
And then suddenly you feel between your hands.
You're grasping onto the flag pole.
The top of it.
Correct.
Everybody turns and looks and tally screams up.
I knew you could do it again.
Told you.
Get my ball.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your
dungeon master Russ More, he, him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
We'd be sweating now.
Carla Maxted is Bonwyn Everbane, she, her.
And his new dad.
And Tom Laird is Kavlaranan Goldweave, he, him.
I mean, I don't know if I would call what I did work, but.
Yeah, I was there.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast and you can join
today or better yet, put it on your Christmas wishlist because your
friends and family can gift you a one to 12 month membership to
come join the community.
Find out more details at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast slash
gift for all the greatest gift ideas this holiday season.
And now fuck it.
Let's play.
Bonwyn, it's been a while since we've seen you, since the trial has
ended, you've been, even during the trial, you've been spending time
catching up on the work that you couldn't do while the Forge was out.
Yeah, long list of custom jobs, including the job for Follon
Varam and his team of adventurers who, you know, are due in town
today and you're just putting the finishing touches on those things.
You see Thane cleaning up their workstation and they come over and
they say, so I don't, I don't know exactly like how we could have
done this sooner, but Nina taking office even as acting mayor has
been really great.
Yeah, I kind of hate to admit it, but I mean, she knows how to
get things done in a way that, you know, the last mayor certainly
did not.
I mean, I still wouldn't trust her with anything, but
I heard she was like an undercover, like a plant from Kingstown.
Huh?
Like sent long time ago to kind of get in there.
I feel like they really allowed her to do some crimes as part of
her undercover work, but I guess you'd have to.
I don't know what a political undercover nature is, but yeah,
she's been doing, like there's, they're planning an election, but
like if she's running, I might just vote for her.
Have you seen they're tearing up the gold on the, on the
rich side of town and like reinvesting it everywhere?
Yeah, it's, it's kind of amazing actually.
Business association meetings are going to be, I think a lot
more chill or they're just going to have to invent things
to complain about.
Yeah, I think I don't, I don't foresee a change in the tenor of
attitudes at the business association meetings, but I don't know, generally
it's just like kind of, kind of good from what I've seen.
I mean, I feel like I've barely left the forge, but.
No, you've been locked up here.
You're doing some great stuff and it's kind of walks over to one of
the tables where you have like stacks and stacks of all of the
wrapped boxes that you package all of your items in.
It's like, I haven't seen you pump out this much, this much stuff
in a, in a long time.
Like, is it, is it the eyes?
Like, is that helping?
Oh, um.
Sorry, I know.
No, I mean, that's, you, you have eyes.
You can see my eyes, you know.
Um, that they're on fire.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
It's, uh, maybe it is.
I don't know.
Also, it just felt really good to be kind of back to normal, just
like tongs and hammer and using my brain and designing and rather than
all of the, uh, terrible, weird, spooky stuff that's been happening.
Yeah.
You know?
I mean, it's still been weird.
Uh, like, yeah.
I mean, can I point at my.
Yeah, no, I mean, the eyes, rainbows coming out of, uh, puddles
in the middle of the street and thinking you see something in
the reflection of a mirror.
It's not really there.
Like a forest or something.
There's things happening.
Yeah.
I don't know about that last one.
What do you mean?
Oh, well, uh, I was walking by mirrors, mirrors, mirrors.
And, uh, of course.
And you got to check your look as you go by.
You can't not look in a mirror when you walk past it.
You got it.
Exactly.
And it is by the way.
You look great.
Thank you.
I was, uh, I wasn't fishing for compliments.
There was more just saying how this morning I walked by mirrors,
mirrors, mirrors, caught me, caught a second me, caught a third, not me,
somebody else walking through a forested space, then a me and then
backtrack there's a me again.
Uh, so.
So not, was it you in a forested space?
No, not me, somebody else.
Uh, just, no, I'd never seen the before in my life.
They were, they had a very, like, I don't know how to describe it.
Like a floral attitude.
Like they were like, there were like vine, they were dressing
themselves in like vines and roughage.
I, that's the only way I could like lettuce leaves.
I'm sure it wasn't lettuce leaves.
It was out of my peripheral, but I mean, it would take your brain
a minute to just like catch up with what you even saw.
Did the forest look familiar?
Like it, was it like verboten?
Was it something local?
I mean, it looked like a forest, but it definitely didn't
look like any like regular paths that we walked through verboten.
Hmm.
Well, I think that might be a you thing thing, or at least I have
not seen any images for us, but I mean.
Yeah.
So I should probably, I should probably talk to somebody about that then.
Um, okay.
Yeah.
Great.
I mean, when Bazaar's back, he would be good.
You know what?
I just default to asking him about anything that's weird.
And that's probably not fair.
But he knows the most about weird stuff.
He does seem, he does seem to have a lot.
And if not, he's got a lot of books that seem to have even more weird stuff in them.
So that's super helpful.
Yeah.
But maybe later we should, let's do a walk by mirrors, mirrors,
mirrors, and see, see what we can see.
Maybe they're playing tricks.
Maybe it's more of this weird stuff.
Maybe there's one magic mirror and it's just that.
Yeah.
It could be that it could also be why we've been seeing like
animal shaped smoke coming out of Jimny's.
Those things could be related.
But around here lately, who knows?
Hear a knock at the door and it slowly opens.
And Follan Varam followed by five other people come in behind him.
He says, sorry to bug you, Bonwyn.
No bother at all.
I've been waiting.
I have this stack.
It is, I maybe shouldn't have wrapped so much.
I normally do for every custom job.
I do the wrap, but yes, no, it's good for you.
Good to reveal absolutely all along the way.
Now, this is wonderful.
Thank you.
Russ, there's another knock on the door and Cav opens the door
and it's like, oh, it's always a lineup here.
Cav, Cav, you can come in, too.
You can come in, too.
OK, I'll just I'll hang over here till they're all done, I guess.
Well, we're doing like a big reveal thing.
It might be a while.
Oh, OK.
I'll see all the see all the things.
I do. I mean, you're welcome to stay.
I think there is that's OK with you.
Of course. This is my Cav.
You guys met, right?
Yeah, I think so.
I'm not great with names, though.
Sorry. Oh, that's OK.
Follan Varam, nice to meet you.
Cav, Cav Lauren for if you want to extend.
You're the one that the trial.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That was me.
Our own little celebrity, Cav Lauren.
Really put a spin on the whole town here.
I mean, when I came, you were complaining, not complaining.
You were stating.
I mean, I was probably complaining that there was just a lack of funding,
at least on this side of the town, and that seems to be turned right around.
Yeah, it's true.
It's pretty great.
It is. School's open again.
Oh, amazing. Amazing.
Yeah. You worked at City Hall, didn't you?
I mean, I don't know if I would call what I did work, but yeah, I was there.
So did they like because of the trial thing, did you like lose your position
or like are you still working there?
Like, look, I'm not entirely sure.
No one has like come to get me and I haven't been by to like
see if I still work there.
Are you still getting paid?
I can say as long as the checks clear.
They keep like slipping,
slipping some money under my door every couple of weeks.
So they're paying you under your door.
Yeah, isn't that how everyone does it?
I got to talk to Oak.
You're just finding random money in your pockets.
Oak is sneaking in and slipping.
Oh, this is my bonus.
We cut back to the school
and several people have come to help you back down,
Alydin, because whatever you've done to get up here,
you weren't able to replicate it to get back down.
That's embarrassing.
Surely you just slid down and went, whee.
Yeah, right. I'm a kid.
You're in a flake wall.
Anyways, there's a couple of people who have caught you at the bottom.
And are you doing OK?
Oh, yeah. Mm hmm.
OK. Yeah, no.
Tally rushes over.
See, you can.
It's like you're you're swept up in something and then you can move.
You've been doing I don't know why you can't remember.
Maybe you lose your memory.
Do you remember doing it right now?
Yes. OK.
How long have I been doing this for?
Can you get my ball from the roof?
I'll work on it.
You can like, I can't just move.
Well, we saw it.
You ended up on the flagpole.
I ended up on the flagpole.
That's true. She's got to work.
She's got to work on it.
She's got to practice next time.
Next time you get up on the roof.
Can you just get my ball back for me, though?
Yeah, for sure.
OK, thanks, Alydin.
Well, you've been doing it since you got back from that place
that you talked about and then you had those dreams
that you were talking about with the person
who said like some I can't remember exactly what they said,
but it sounded very scary in the dream.
And then you started doing that.
You like jumped down the street, you said.
And then you've been practicing.
Listen, Tali, come here.
OK, come here. I'm here.
You have to shh.
Why?
About because I don't know what's going on.
And obviously, I'm not very good at it yet.
OK, yeah, well, practice makes better.
Well, yeah, you don't necessarily need perfection.
You told me that.
You don't need to be throwing kids balls up on the roof
and then telling me to go get it.
There was a crowd of kids.
They were excited.
No, you looked great.
You were up on the flagpole.
The wind was blowing.
The nice mist coming off of you
looked really elegant.
I'm just saying you looked like a hero.
I didn't get the ball.
Quentin doesn't care about that ball.
You look over.
Quentin's just sitting sadly on the street.
Bouncing an invisible ball.
I throw balls up on the top of the roof every other day.
It's fine.
We'll get it back down.
I know we will.
I'm just saying he can go up there and get it right now.
He's just lazy.
Put me on stage.
I won't put you on the stage anymore.
I was just trying a pressure tactic.
Well, I didn't like it and it wasn't appreciated.
I'm sorry.
Now I feel silly.
So you want to go to the Dembuns though?
I mean, yeah.
Maybe go check on Bonwyn.
We haven't seen Bonwyn in a while.
She's been very busy.
She has been very busy.
Yeah, we could go to the Dembuns though and get some stuff
and then go see Bonwyn.
Let's bring traits.
OK, let's go.
Back at the Forge, Follan and all of his crew
have tested everything out, have brought everything out.
Everybody is very thrilled with all of the work
you've done.
Follan comes over, I know we've got to settle up,
but this is amazing work.
The bAlydince in these, we cut ourselves three times,
no fault of your own.
No, I mean, they're so sharp you don't even notice at first.
Just slices.
I mean, that one guy, I'm not sure why.
You know, you don't run your hand up the blade.
What was he thinking?
Well, look, my group is new.
My group is new.
New adventurers, I understand.
And we're trying something new.
He was an accountant.
And now we're going to go see if we can't track down
treasure and monsters and whatever else is happening.
That's amazing.
Right?
Russ, are they all a similar age to him?
Is this a bucket list situation?
Yeah, yeah, I think so.
Oh, I love that.
I love it.
Yeah, it's good.
So yeah, looking like they're in their 50s, probably.
Have lived a good life, have done a lot of things.
This guy's clearly got money,
and he's bringing his friends along for an adventure.
It's what we could all hope for, right?
Sounds great.
Which one of us is going to get money?
That person can bring the rest of us along.
Yeah, whichever one of us gets money.
Kyle's not here, so let's say Kyle.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kyle is hard.
He's got the business plan.
He knows what's happening.
Where are you going on your first adventure?
Do you guys know yet?
Well, yeah, we're going up into the Mi Mountains first,
and then we're heading over, and there's
a little township over on the other side there
that we've heard some pretty good things about.
And there might be a lead on some buried treasure
off further into the marshland beyond there.
OK, cool.
I'm sure I told you this before,
but I couldn't live with myself if I didn't reiterate
it.
If you find what appears to be an old mine shaft,
an old factory shaft in the Mi Mountains,
you do not want to go down there.
There is not treasure.
There is only terror.
Oh.
Not the fun adventure kind, the like you might die kind.
So just give that a pass.
Maybe go practice first before even thinking
about any of that.
Yeah, hey.
Practice would be really good.
He looks to you and Kav as well,
and he says, you two look like you
didn't usually sound like you may
have adventured a little bit.
I've done a little dabbling.
A little.
A little, yeah.
Yeah, we have.
Yeah.
So like what would it cost to bring the two of you along?
Oh.
Huh.
At that moment, I kick open the door.
Treats.
And Tally and I are like, we have snacks.
Hey.
Hey, hey, hey.
Thank you.
Come on in.
We just did the big reveal.
You know all that stuff I was making?
There's a lot of food.
A lot of gesture to all of the people,
all decked out in their new armor and weapons
and all their cool new stuff.
How many people are we talking about, Russ,
when we say like, it's full of people?
So what did I say?
There were five others with Folland.
So six unknowns to you, and then
Baldwin, Kav, and Thane, and then you and Tally.
OK, it's crowded in here.
There's like 10 people shoved into the forge here.
Yeah.
All right.
You thought it was hot before there was 10 people in here?
We'd be sweating now.
Yeah.
Are you guys having, I didn't, we didn't bring enough.
Oh, no, no, no, that's OK.
We're on our way out here.
I was just settling up with your friend here.
And yeah, think on it.
We're going to be in town for another couple days,
just making sure we've got everything we need.
Leaving pretty soon then, hey?
Yeah, well, we've been, like I've
been in town for a while.
They just got in last week.
We had intended to go earlier.
Have you done any training?
Like, I know that June was doing like a side hustle thing,
where she was kind of doing some basic combat training
and survival skills and things like that.
You know, now that-
Might want to check it out.
She is a well-rounded individual.
She's had a lot of different experiences,
not the least of which was teaching school, which
gives you a lot of skills for facing wild animals out
there.
Oh, you mean her June Doe classes?
June Doe classes.
That's what she calls it.
Yes.
Cav, thank you.
Thank you, yeah.
You should check it out.
I will check it out.
I think I've seen some flyers up around town.
So yeah, absolutely, we'll check that out.
See if she's got one before we want to head out.
And if it's close, we'll just make sure we catch one.
If they're as good as you say they are.
He turns and looks, and somebody else
has like dropped one of them through the top of their shoe.
Just barely missed their foot.
Like pulled it out and like, we got a little practice to do.
Yeah, there's scabbards for all those.
You're fine.
Maybe just put them away for now.
Yeah, I'll put them back.
OK.
Be careful with them.
Think on it.
We will.
I'll check back in before we go.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
Great to have you here.
So happy you're here.
It's a beautiful, sunshiny day somewhere,
and we're hope you're enjoying it.
Hopefully where you are, unless you prefer the rain,
then I hope it's raining.
I hope it's your best favorite weather.
Yes.
But we're not here to talk about the weather.
Oh, no.
We're here to talk about Tom's favorite thing.
Oh, boy.
Pray tell.
Which is?
Oh, it's a question for me.
I thought you were going to tell me.
I'm not going to tee up your favorite.
I'm not going to take that thunder.
Who am I, Justin?
I'm not going to take that thunder from you.
I mean, maybe.
I don't know.
OK, favorite thing?
Well, I'm kind of like thinking about homemade pasta,
because I did homemade pasta on the weekend.
You did homemade pasta on the weekend?
And it was so good, guys.
We're talking like a linguine, like a spaghetti.
We did a ravioli that was stuffed with pumpkin
and ricotta.
Yes, it was.
And then it was cooked in a brown butter
sage and walnut sauce.
Shit.
Is that recipe going to go up on our Discord?
I mean, it could.
I think it should.
And if you join our Discord, which is entirely free
to get all of Tom's pictures of food,
he posts some recipes, but mostly just pictures.
You have to reverse engineer them
to be able to remake them.
Taste with your eyes.
I see we need the clues now.
Make the meal.
That's right.
You see all of the layers.
Now put it together.
But yeah, join us in our Discord.
There's a link down in the description.
Pretty sure it's there.
So you can find it.
Because if it wasn't there, you wouldn't be able to.
But it is there.
I'm pretty sure it's there.
Russ is like 80% sure it's there.
It's hidden somewhere.
I've hyperlinked one period somewhere.
And now it's a scavenger hunt.
Now you're on a quest.
If you can't find it, ask somebody in the Discord.
They'll help you out.
That's true.
We have really lovely people in the Discord.
A lot of our patrons are in the Discord.
They are in the Discord.
And when you're a patron.
They don't put up with any of this bullshit.
They do not.
But they do get an episode dedicated to them.
Yeah, they do.
Today's patron, Faust the Heavenly Demonic Monster.
Oh, wow.
Sounds like a deal.
I knew we had some powerful listeners.
But I maybe underestimated how powerful.
I want to follow this person immediately.
Not on socials, but to the depths of hell.
To the edge of the world.
On a quest.
I mean, what are we fighting?
To the grocery store.
Whatever.
I mean, to infinity and beyond.
Oh, no.
Litigious.
Yeah.
Throw in the bed and the bath, too, while we're at it.
Let's fucking go.
You know it.
All right.
Well, thank you, Faust.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you.
And all the honorifics that follow it.
The Heavenly Demonic Monster.
That's the one.
You nailed it.
Not just any normal Faust.
That specific one.
So you, too, could be like Faust.
You could be a Faust of your own sort
at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Where you get one week free.
When you sign up, it's pretty fun.
You can test it out.
See what you like.
And then hopefully you enjoy all of this.
All of this.
But slightly different.
Just how could you not?
How could you not?
You made it this far.
What are we, like, 800 episodes in?
You're still listening?
Like, obviously.
Come on now.
What is this middle?
10 minutes now?
You're still listening?
Come on.
We're obviously best friends.
If this is your first time, though,
give it some time, please, because you're super cool
and we just want you to just give us a chance.
But the rest of you, you get it.
Yeah.
Thanks for being here.
Time to get back to the episode now.
Love you, bye.
Kav, did you hear that?
He wants to hire us to go with them.
What?
Go with them where?
Where are you going?
Like on an adventure.
Adventuring.
You guys are leaving on an adventure?
Well, no, no.
We haven't even talked about it.
He just offered.
Yeah.
So something to think about, something
to discuss amongst ourselves.
And I mean, we can just leave.
We need to talk to Bazaar.
I need to talk to Thane.
We need to talk to you.
Like, there's a lot.
Oh, she beams.
What?
There's a lot of things to consider.
Yeah, like who would stay back and babysit me?
Do you feel like you need a babysitter?
I feel like you've really been taking care
of a lot of things yourself.
Yeah, you're right.
I could probably stay back.
No, I think.
I don't think that's what anyone meant.
No, no.
Yeah, no, you would come with us.
Because the school's open now, and the kids are all OK.
And like, I don't know, I kind of feel like.
You don't need to babysit anymore.
Yeah, I feel like we're like a team, kind of.
I do feel like we're a team.
I mean, whenever there's nobody else
other than you two and Bazaar,
I'd want to go into a weird other plane
with terrifying creatures with.
Tally hands you a coffee and a muffin.
And you've got Tally to make sure the younger kids are OK.
And that's a really important job,
because you were doing that for so long.
I do rely on her a lot.
But now you can really trust Tally
to make sure everyone's OK.
I will put them through the same rigorous training
that I put you through today, Alydin.
You're going to yell at them until they transport
themselves on top of a flagpole?
The teachers can do that.
You are there now, I think, Tally,
more for emotional support, for people as a confidant.
OK.
Solving problems on the playground.
Just sort of a respected authority figure
among the children.
Someone to look up to.
But don't get power creates.
OK, OK, OK, I'm on board with this.
Yeah, so you guys brought treats.
What kind of treats did you get?
Oh, you know, they had some fresh doughnuts.
Oh, love it.
The filled muffins.
They're here, too.
I think they're the pumpkin muffins with the spiced
cream cheese inside.
Oh, all right.
Thank you.
That's so nice of you two to bring treats.
You guys have been so busy lately.
And Bazaar has been, like, really busy
and doing super important stuff.
And so, you know.
Yeah, I mean, the life of a small business owner,
when you have a few weeks where you disappear,
and then you're, well, first, you're fighting monsters.
The town half burns down.
Then you disappear.
Then there's a court.
Like, I mean, that's a lot to catch up on.
Thank God for Thayn.
Thayn, seriously, you are a saint.
You're amazing.
Say no more.
And he kind of puts his keys in his pocket.
I was just heading out.
Are you heading down to Bench's tonight, Brood Awakening?
Yeah.
Hey, swing past Mirror, Mirror, Mirror.
We're going to as well when we leave.
And just take a look.
I'll let you know if I see anything.
OK.
Well, good to see everybody.
I'll hopefully see you at the Brood Awakening.
I appreciate you.
What's he looking for at Mirror, Mirror, Mirror?
Well, his beautiful face.
I was going to say, Little Vane.
But also, we saw something weird.
What?
What weird?
Weird, like, so he's walking past the mirrors,
saw himself.
And then in one of the mirrors, he saw a figure in a forest,
not someone he recognized, kind of dressed
in flowers or something.
That sounds nice.
And then when he went back, like, did a woo,
they were, it was just a mirror again.
So something to keep an eye on.
You guys seen anything like that before?
Well, things have been kind of weird since we got back.
Uh, Tom and Amy, roll a D100.
Oh, oh.
Are we playing Cthulhu?
I'm worried.
Right?
34.
Nope, that's a 7.
37.
62.
Amy, that's what you've seen.
And 62.
OK, I dropped into the studio chat.
Amy, you can read yours there.
Yeah, no, I don't.
You know how when you're going walking down by the river?
Right, of course.
And it's, like, dusk, and it's so peaceful.
Golden hour, lovely.
And I just kind of like to sit and, you know, think.
And you know how sometimes the river just sings?
Like through the majesty of, like, gurgles and burbles,
like of a river sort of sound?
Yeah, I love that.
It's really soothing.
More like a beautiful, like, ah, like, I don't know.
I can't sing.
But like a voice, they're not saying words.
And like, it's a river.
Huh.
I have not experienced that.
It sounds actually kind of gorgeous.
I mean, it wasn't the worst thing.
Is it nice?
It seems maybe unsettling, but kind of lovely.
Only at the golden hour, or?
Yeah, what's the hair on the back of your neck
like when you hear this?
Oh, great question.
Great question.
Well, it stands up a little bit,
and I get the goosebumps.
And sometimes you get that just from hearing beautiful singing,
so.
Yeah.
And I don't, like, I've been doing this thing
where I'm in one place, and then I'm in another place,
and I'm all wet.
And so I don't know, I kind of, like, maybe the river
is apologizing to me.
Oh, through song.
Yeah.
I'm damp most of the day.
I mean, I feel like literally anything
is possible in this town now, so.
That's true, yeah.
I've had, like, a little back of the neck thing lately, too.
You know, it hasn't been, like, very, like, moon forward
lately.
It's been kind of cloudy.
Well, I've been seeing that, like, the lanterns are glowing,
but there's no oil in them.
Maybe, is there a candle?
No, no, no candle either.
Good question, though.
Firefly in there, something?
Oh, the glowy things that Bazaar can do, the glowy magic.
Oh, maybe that's it, yeah.
The glowy magic.
When he does that, like, the hair on my neck
doesn't stand up.
Well, and he's, like, usually there.
There to, like, make it happen.
This is just like, you see a lantern,
and you're like, oh, that's weird.
I thought it was empty of oil, but still glowing.
100%.
Convenient.
Sure, yeah.
But also weird.
Also a little weird.
Are weird things happening again already?
Did we bring weird things back with us?
Oh, Alydin, an insightful question.
Is it our fault?
Is that what you're saying?
Well.
I mean, it might be.
It might be our fault.
They sound like nice things so far,
but I don't trust weird things,
whether they're nice or not.
I wish Bazaar was here.
Oh, me too.
Where is our weird stuff expert when we need him?
I could go get some books, but he really
asked that I give him and his mom some time to.
And his new dad.
Don't say that in front of him.
No, he would be so mad.
It's not funny to him, and I understand why it's not.
There's a lot of raw emotion there,
but it's nice to see her so happy, isn't it?
She sings.
Not like the river, but dusting around the store.
So we can't ask him.
Tali, any ideas?
This muffin is very good.
Good.
Solid, solid, solid input.
Astute.
I don't know.
Maybe go to the.
Maybe you could just go just call it for the day
and go to the Brewed Awakening with your friends.
I don't know.
I mean, there's nothing wrong happening, like bad.
There's nothing wrong happening.
Nobody's hurt.
We could gather some intel from other people.
I mean, it doesn't sound like it's just happening to us
who were in the weird place.
Thane's also seeing weird things.
And now we all know, and we're now
actively thinking about it.
So we could start noticing more.
Yes, gathering the clues.
This might be, Tali, a great time to,
let's do a little test.
If Alydin were to leave town and you were like the official
oldest kid, let's see how things would go.
Let's do a little test.
Why don't you head back to the school
and then let us know in the morning that things went OK.
Oh, yeah, sure.
I could do that.
Easy, peasy.
Yeah, lemon squeezy.
Hey, we totally trust you.
You're going to do a great job.
You can do this, Tali.
I trust that you trust me.
Are you guys going to eat all the rest of those muffins?
No, you go ahead.
You should take them.
Well, I want, and I take one and I put it in my bucket.
She picks them all up and she starts heading up.
Now that you're in charge, those
are also for the kids, right?
Oh, yeah, of course.
You just don't want them to leave them overnight
as she's heading out.
Because, you know, food left overnight that's out
just grows those tiny mushrooms.
She heads out into the street.
Wait, what?
OK, I think I think that's maybe
another one of those things.
Maybe, or she's confused and she's
talking it when it gets all moldy.
Like mold?
Does she think mold is tiny mushrooms?
I mean, maybe, but also, I don't leave a lot of food around.
You know what, it could be me neither.
Yeah, let's go to Brewed Awakening.
Let's see what everyone else has seen.
Yeah.
You all make your way down towards the Brewed Awakening.
It's a, what time?
I didn't say it was a beautiful day.
I didn't necessarily place a specific time.
No, we sent her back to the school.
We sent her back to the school.
Thayne finished off for the day.
So it's the end of the day.
Like 2 PM.
Yeah, love it.
You're all heading down to the Brewed Awakening.
And there's a few people heading there.
It's a busy night.
And as you're all walking up,
you see a youngish man in perhaps two big robes.
He's carrying a satchel that's bulging
with papers and journals and loose scrolls that
are tied haphazardly together.
His glasses, you notice as he's kind of looking down
and trying to filter through this bag,
keeps sliding down his nose, and he
keeps bumping them back up.
And he's crossing the square towards the Brewed Awakening
as well.
And something catches his attention.
And he trips on a cobblestone.
All of the papers, all of the parchment,
scraps everywhere.
And he starts scrambling around.
A couple people are stepping over him.
One kind of passes.
I mean, I'm going to try and go help.
And nobody can stop to help at all.
You guys rush over.
I expect more of the people of Vintersmouth,
but I'm going to help him.
Oh, sweetheart, you got to watch where you're walking here.
It's busy.
It's everyone's heading to the pub.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Thank you, thank you.
This one was in a puddle.
It's wet.
He's scrambling.
He puts it.
He kind of just brushes it off and slips it in his bag.
Obviously, I try and read these as I'm like,
I can't even help it.
I just know how to read.
And when I see words, I know what they mean.
What do I see?
You see?
Anything cool?
Is it just pictures of naked girls?
It's pictures of exclusively naked women.
And like being in Vegas.
And he's just got flyers he's handing out.
No, it's not.
They look academic.
They look like there's perhaps
on some similar things that you've seen with Bazaar,
different magical scrolls.
You see different historical events that
have happened through time.
And as you're handing them back and he's collecting them,
he quickly stops and looks down to the ground,
very distracted.
And all you can see is a bit of glass.
And he goes down and picks it up and holds it up
to the light that's still left in the sky.
And he says, oh, fascinating refractive qualities
of this.
Isn't that just glass?
It's just glass, isn't it?
What was I doing?
All your papers.
All your worldly possessions have spilled all over.
I don't think you're from here.
New to Vintrosmith?
Yes, yes, yes.
And I'm Alistar.
And then his eyes get very heavy.
And he looks like he paints.
Alistar.
And falls to the ground.
Can I try and catch him?
You can.
What do I do, athletics?
Roll athletics, yeah.
Oh, great.
Or dexterity.
Calls on you, crushes you.
Or acrobatics, crushes you.
Oh, acrobatics is better.
Oh, my dex is pretty good.
Still only a 13, not a great roll.
You see, and with just barely enough time,
catch him as his head lolls back.
And he begins snoring in your arms.
Oh, my goodness.
Is this one of the weird things we should
have been keeping an eye out for?
Are people going to just start falling asleep?
I hope not.
I barely caught this guy.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season 4, episode 40,
starring Amy More as Alydin.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane.
Tom Laird as Kavlaranan Goldweave.
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard.
And Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design of today's episode
is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound.
And sound effects are by R.E.A.
And we're going to be talking about
Music is from Epidemic Sound.
And sound effects are from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library,
and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Angaron Kierzen,
Perry Matey, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss, L.A. Branton,
Chibs1012, and Kudzu828.
We'd love if you joined us today
at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
for the amazing community.
All the bonus content and so much more.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
We'll see you over there.
But until then, have a great week
and we'll talk to you soon.
Is this Alydin or Amy amnesia?
Amy's pulling the, I am not yes.
Anding anything.
I'm having trouble today.
I've had the worst couple of weeks.
My brain can't.
It's hard to remember if things you can't remember
because of game amnesia
or because Alydin doesn't remember.
That's true.
I mean, I don't remember any of this.
Me neither.
Okay, I just wanted to make sure.
I'm like, I either am just gonna guess and this or.
Jess fully remembers all of it.
Shut up, Jess.
No, you don't.
Usually how it works.
God.
I just need to know I'm not being gaslit
and made to look stupid.
You're not being gaslit.
There's too much in my brain.
It happened once in the actual game
and then we went into trial mode
where everything got sidelined.
I do not remember this.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.