Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
I'm pretty sure I had an idea or part of a plan. Like,
Well, I think the plan was like the putting the thing in the thing though, right?
Well, it didn't not work. You did the thing. There's no confirmation because there are still two things that aren't there.
So we need to get all the notes to the music box.
I'm not gonna say all of it out loud.
And we need to finish the song.
We'll require another yeeting.
Yeah, we'll need to get another note from the sky first.
Yeah, and throw it into the memory of him like writing at the piano, right?
Because I pulled that close.
Yes, you did.
And that's what I got thrown into.
Yes, but Russ made a face when we did throw a note in there.
I make faces for everything.
You know what? I think the throwing it into the memory is more beautiful.
So we should just go with that plan and see what happens.
Can we interact with the memory guy?
Plus, it's also Russ's time bullshit, so we probably love it because we're like affected because we're affecting the past.
We're like, it's a memory of when he was writing the song and if you give him the song, the completion of the song.
Well, I don't think it's a time fuckery thing more than it is like a revealing of, you know, unblocking a memory.
Oh, okay.
Well, great.
We're opening pathways.
We're connecting neurons.
That's right.
We're brain surgeons right now.
We're basically brain surgeons.
We're basically brain surgeons right now.
Just get a thing and yeet it.
We're basically brain surgeons.
Just fucking.
I mean, that's how they do it.
Throw that shit in the brain and let's go.
Okay, that's our cold open.
Alright, throw that shit in the brain and let's go.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master, Russ More, he, him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
Wait, wait, wait, never mind, as you were.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she, her.
Are they as big as this beer?
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave, he, him.
Cav was like mini football champion growing up, so it's got a pretty tight spiral.
And Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, he, him.
I'm not really sure, but there's always a chance we could give it a go and join in his dance.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast and we'd love for you to join us over at Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast.
Right now, when you sign up, you'll get a seven day free trial and instant access to so many
amazing bonus episodes, more of what you love.
Come find it today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And now fuck it.
Let's play.
Okay, now we get into the actual episode.
Perfect.
Love it.
I was trying to come up with something narrative and good, but no, that's
that was that was much better.
Just nonsense.
Let's stick with what we do best.
Okay, to reset the scene, you are all in a floating face space.
You are standing on various platforms.
Cav and Bonwyn, you've just been hit by these falling musical notes that have come down
and hit you pretty hard.
But you have the music box and two golden notes that you've plucked from the air.
Bizard and Alydin, you are on a piece of the original platform that you were on when
you came into this space and you just pulled over one of Calder's memories, one where
it appears that he's he's he's creating he's writing music in that it's a it's like
a stark like stone tavern that he's writing at a table kind of all by himself.
And you've thrown one of these musical notes in there.
The shadowy horrors, horrors coming out of everywhere, like they're climbing up onto
the various different memories that you see of Everbane's in the stables and of
I've forgotten every location that it has those shadowy horrors have already
gotten there.
Exactly.
They've taken those memories from you, too.
I did play it yourself.
Got got climbing up on them.
And like attacking them, you see fracturing happening on all of these different
spaces.
And Banjo Man is over nearest to Bonwyn and Cav.
He is this grotesque figure, long arms strumming his banjo.
He's got big wings and was also lit on fire.
You threw some ink or oil rather on him and sparked him.
So he's a blaze or whatever clothing is left on him is a blaze and letting out a
hideous shriek.
And Bizard, you have to speak in rhyming couplets for at least another couple
I believe.
So, Alydin, you begin the round.
OK, feel free to converse with Bizard or yell across the football field.
OK, well, I have a question for the DM.
So, DM, what do I see happen when the who threw the note?
I think Bizard mage handed it over.
And then who held the note?
I think I think Bizard, you had the note.
Well, it's not super important, but do I notice anything happen to the
memory when the note enters it?
Yeah, like is the memory played on a loop and now there's like an extra beat to it
at the end of the set.
You throw that note, which I mean, all the notes that are floating by are
various different colors.
But when you when you've seen and found these other ones, they turn turn to
like a golden, a glowing golden hue aura about them.
So when you throw it in, yes, you see it like passes a barrier, something
that you've seen the banjo man go into some of these things, but you haven't
quite seen this same effect like passes a barrier like and it almost
glows like it's passing through something in order to get into this space.
There is a noticeable like waver as it enters this memory.
And then is it just like on the floor in that memory?
It's like floating in the space.
Yeah, does memory Calder notice that?
I don't know if you would have noticed him.
He's on fire.
No, no memory Calder.
Oh, memory color.
No, I would call them the banjo man.
If we're talking about that, a blazed dude.
No memory.
You don't memory Calder like is is within this memory like it doesn't
look like he is affected by anything that's happening anywhere.
Bizarre. You know, when he went in and started smashing all Bonwyn's
stuff inside of Everbane's, do you think that we can go inside of that
one and talk to him?
I'm not really sure, but there's always a chance we could give it a go.
And join in his dance.
Okay, she's like, this is going to get old real fast.
Wow.
This is going to stay for a while.
Is this a forever thing?
I really don't know, and I certainly don't hope so.
Okey doke.
All right.
How many things can your hand lift?
Your fake hand.
Your ghost hand, your fake ghost hand pause for rhyming couplet.
Fuck shit.
Fuck shit under five pounds.
I don't know stuff under five pounds.
Why do you keep making me make sounds?
Okay.
Well, I'm just going to try.
And she's going to be a stupid kid, and she's going to do a run and into Calder's
because it's been pulled over, right?
So not just.
Well, I don't think we said it was like bumped up.
I think we said like 25 feet.
Okay, then hold on.
Oh, jeez.
Yeah.
Alydin thinks very highly of herself and her athletic abilities, however.
There was previously talk of like throwing a dwarf.
Yeah, there was a dwarf.
That was before Cav went over to another location.
And pretty much is dead almost.
Yeah, Cav can't throw me now.
Well, there was talk about throwing you too.
But yeah, we could throw you, not the literal dwarf.
Yeah, yeah.
Just something like that.
There are things like this is in constant motion, right?
Everything's just kind of floating around.
Do I see anything that I could jump on and kind of like make my way there?
I don't know why it made that noise over, you know, it does like stepping stone.
Sure.
So a lot of these memories are like moving through space.
So as you look to Calder's memory and then are trying to figure out how you
could get over there, you see another memory coming from the left passing
towards you a closer distance that you feel like you could make.
What is the memory that you see?
It is one of Cav's memories.
And it is very like this memory is blurred and very difficult to
actually see.
Oh, I hope it's Boy's Night.
It is. It's the tattoo.
It's it's you and Oak and oh, my God, headache.
Bizarre.
Nope. He wasn't at Boy's Night.
Oh, Bench was. Yeah, sorry.
Bench. I forgot.
I was like, rude dude is what I was going to say.
We did the fishing summer one where there was another Boy's Night, OK?
OK, but I'm talking crazy Boy's Night.
OG Boy's Night.
So Cav, Oak and Bench are getting their tattoos done in this one.
And Cav is actually doing fine.
Oak is weeping openly.
OK, so, yeah, this memory is coming from the passing between you and Calder's
memory. You could attempt a jump between.
Yeah, I want to hitch a ride.
OK, make an athletics check.
Athletics or acrobatics?
Or athletic or athletic.
I have a negative one in athletics, but a plus one in acrobatics.
His athletics, I think, is strength based.
And then, oh, baby, 20, dirty 20.
OK, oh, I mean, watch me jump.
You chose acrobatics.
Yeah, so it looks good.
OK, I probably have to like hurtle over something or like vault.
Yeah, you like basically it's a decathlon and you're killing it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So you have enough movement to be able to make it to Calder's memory.
So as you leap to this to this Boy's Night memory, you step into it.
And now you find yourself in the tattoo parlor like it's like you go
and it's like you space.
Time.
The final frontier.
I'm imagining them like shop windows.
Yeah, so you like go and you're going to land on it.
But it's like you pass through this bubble and like music's playing
and you smell incense burning and you hear Oak crying.
Bench is like trying to console him.
And Cav is getting his done.
And are you going to obviously continue forward?
Yeah, if my if my dice roll got me good enough to just continue
running through and to jump onto Calder's, I will.
Yeah.
So you land in, you hear all of this as a quick sensory overload
and you jump through like a window of this place
and launch yourself towards Calder's memory.
Make a dexterity saving throw, please.
Eleven and I smacked my mic.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Never mind, as you were.
As you leap out of this memory and towards Calder's,
like a cloud of these notes start like as you leap out,
like start slamming into you, which throws you off
and you begin floating through space
and like grab the edge of Calder's memory,
which you feel like begin to splinter beneath your hands.
It's like, it's hard.
Like you're grabbing onto hard glass.
Ow.
I think what it would just be,
ah, ah, ah, oh no, no, bizarre, bizarre, bizarre.
Okay, so you're holding onto this, like just by the edge,
you're out floating in space,
which brings us to Bonwyn.
You've just been struck hard
by one of these falling music notes.
You hear behind you the screams of the banjo man,
the echoes of the song that he continues to play.
You hear his wings flapping,
trying to beat out this fire.
What do you do?
Hmm.
And we're far away though, right?
Like you said, we're like a football field away now from.
Yes.
Alydin and Bazaar.
Maybe not quite a football field,
but like a fair distance.
You'd have to really book it to get there.
I can't physically grab her,
which is literally all I can do.
Okay.
I think for movement, I know that
when Cav tried to put the music in the music box,
was he like.
It's a polite way of putting it.
Was he like, just shove it,
he didn't like open it and try and put it in?
He like just was like hitting the top?
It was open, wasn't it?
It was open.
Yeah.
And you tried.
So I like, I tried to just like dunk it in
and like didn't go.
Nothing happened.
Real Shaq move going there.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Can I try and do that more delicately?
Where I like open it, put it inside and close it?
Or it's like huge. Sure.
How big are the notes?
Maybe it's like an intention thing.
In my mind though.
The notes are like, you're grabbing them.
I don't have a close approximation.
Are they as big as this beer?
Larger than that.
Are they as big as this mug that Amy made?
They're like this.
Okay.
So like half a torso.
Half a torso.
Or a torso.
A standard unit measurement.
A Carla torso or an Amy torso?
Exactly.
The Carla torso's much longer than mine.
All right.
It's true.
It's an Amy torso then.
Anyway.
Okay.
So it wouldn't fit in the box.
No.
So this doesn't make sense.
Okay.
I mean, not to your non-magical brain, obviously.
I guess what I'm going to do is try to,
is just keep grabbing notes,
trying to find more golden notes.
Cause I know we had three and now we only have two.
So I'd like to get back to at least three.
Three seemed like at least a base number.
Okay.
So can I try and grab at notes to like get a golden one?
Yes.
So it was investigation or arcana
to be able to find notes in the space.
Okay.
Well, that's an eight.
So I guess I just gently pat Cav's head.
They're there.
Shh.
Just brushing the hair from his face.
Yeah.
100% health.
Great.
So I guess that's nothing.
I've done nothing.
Tried to do some movement there, I guess,
or was that, I guess that was my action.
I rolled on it.
So that's what I do.
Wait, is he still cut?
Like, is he covered?
He got, he got smashed by...
Well, I did.
I like threw myself on top of him.
She took the majority of it.
So maybe I help him up.
Can I help him up?
Yep.
So we're both standing
cause we were probably both prone.
You were, yeah, you were both, yeah.
Knocked, knocked down pretty hard.
Okay.
As your turn ends,
you see the hands of some of these shadowy figures
coming up over the edge.
And like one of them comes up and over the edge quickly
and like opens its mouth and has these sharp jagged teeth
and lets out this, this resonant tune
that shakes you to your core.
Make, do I need you to make something?
Does the tune act as any sort of like indicator
for the music notes nearby as to which ones might react?
Great question.
And are they able to notice that
and be scared at the same time?
Also, please remember that in the house,
I had advantage on a sound-related thing
because I'm used to extremely loud sounds.
Yes, you do.
From all of my smithing.
All of the hammering.
Exactly.
Is the, is the mouth kind of like
the really creepy guy?
I'm picturing Venom, so I don't know what that sounds like.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Like, yeah, like shark teeth kind of vibe, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'd say that.
Okay.
Make a dexterity, not a dexterity,
a wisdom saving throw with advantage
because you got your ears plugged.
Oh, wisdom.
I am not a smart woman.
Uh, so that is unfortunately a 14 minus two
on wisdom saving throw.
It shakes you to your core,
but you manage to-
I do pee a little bit, probably.
You do, yes, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Definitely-
Good thing I'm not laying on calf anymore.
We both got up, so I'm glad I said that.
Yeah, you do pee a little, but you do save.
You do manage to shake off whatever effect
this being is trying to bestow upon you.
And as we kind of move back to Bazaar,
we catch Everbane's,
which is still floating through space there,
and you see it out of the corner of your eye,
and these fractures have gone deeper into the memory.
It's like a pane of glass
that is about ready to shatter.
Bazaar, it's your turn.
Alydin, hold on and be strong.
If we can get in the memory, we can help with the song
and make my way to Alydin while looking for notes.
Kind of saying to myself,
I'm gonna search and find the right pitch
then throw it in that memory to help this dumb bitch.
I'm assuming that Calder's the dumb bitch.
Yes, I would assume that.
Not sweet, Alydin.
No.
Yeah.
Dumb bitch.
Okay, so you're looking for more notes.
And making my way over to...
Okay, so you are also launching yourself
between memories?
Yeah.
Cool.
That's what all the cool kids do.
Absolutely.
Seems like it.
Alydin's a cool kid, I know.
Alydin had kind of passed through, has moved on.
A new memory is coming in from up above.
You see it coming downwards
towards you.
What is that a memory of?
I honestly couldn't paint.
I honestly can't tell you.
It's a really fancy looking party
and there's some really odd things going on
with a giraffe.
I don't know.
Okay.
Love that.
That was precious.
We can't lose that one.
Yeah, that must be protected above all else.
Athletics or acrobatics as you jump into this memory.
All right, we'll definitely do acrobatics.
That's at least better than 14.
14, all right.
So you time it so that you leap through it.
There's laughter, there's these two giraffes
which have mounted each other.
And as you're running through,
you see an opening in the back of this memory.
There's another doorway which passes through
into the memory that you're trying to get to.
As you kind of look to your side,
you see these giraffes
and you see the face of Bonwyn and her friend
all dressed up in this attire.
And as you pass several doorways,
you see that you are in fact in the quivering hills.
Oh, shit.
You carry on through and launch yourself
towards Calder's memory.
You want to try and find another note.
So roll investigation or arcana as you leap out.
Let's do the arcana and get a 27.
Oh, wow.
Sorry, that's so wrong.
That's so wrong.
It's not that much wrong, but it's a 23.
I apologize.
Okay, well, both are amazing.
27, you find 18 of them.
I don't know how that happened.
Amazing.
23, you definitely, as you leap through
into another cloud of musical notes,
your hand is almost guided towards one
and you grab it as you continue to fly through
which you crash into this memory.
It, you have a,
make a dex check.
Okay.
Dex check would be a 19.
So you have just like a split second
before you find yourself completely in this memory
that you are launching yourself towards to grab Alydin.
You manage to like reach out and grab her arm
as you are sucked into this memory.
Like you feel a pull into it
and you grab hold of Alydin
and she follows in behind you
and both of you fall and tumble to the ground.
You look to your left and you see Calder
just madly writing and crumpling up the paper
and madly writing.
He doesn't seem to acknowledge you.
Welcome to the middle, friends, family, loved ones.
It's great to have you here.
Hopefully you're enjoying the episode
and having a great day.
Yeah, I agree with that sentiment.
We don't really have a lot to tell you.
I don't want to sell you anything today.
I just want to make sure that you're, you know,
you're enjoying yourself.
You're out there giving it your all, 110%,
sports in as hard as you can.
Unless you're tired and you can't,
you can't give like 60, that's okay too.
110% of what you have to give.
Exactly.
That's the important caveat there.
Give yourself 110% grace.
Yes, that's quite beautiful, Kyle.
Wow, that was lovely.
He'll get you through.
That's where that music degree comes in.
That's right.
It's the philosophical poetry unit that they do.
Right, yeah, okay, sure.
Yes, all the prose and-
The sidewalk ends here, that's the sharp edge.
Kyle Silverstein into this.
Yeah.
Good times.
I only mention Patreon,
which you can join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
but we only mention it because you get an episode
dedicated to you when you join us over there.
Like today's patron, Jonathan Wen.
Jonathan. Thanks, Jonathan.
Thank you.
Jonathan is a classic patron.
Jonathan's been with us for a very long time.
It's so nice.
Since January, no, yeah, January 8th, 2018.
Do you know what episode released in January of 2018?
Oh, I would love to know.
I had like a whole different life.
Okay, here's the part where you gotta give me
a second to go find it.
Okay.
Well, I hadn't even met my husband then yet.
Yeah, I hadn't met mine.
Like this was a whole lifetime ago.
It's amazing you're still here.
I hadn't met any of y'all.
Oh, and we hadn't met Kyle.
Didn't meet Kyle for years until after that.
Is that right?
When did we meet Kyle?
Yeah, Kyle was in LA.
2019, D&D Live.
Right.
Okay, so wow, we've known Kyle a long time.
Good while.
That's pretty nice.
I love that.
Not as long as we've known Jonathan,
but still a really long time.
Oh, yeah, yeah, for sure.
So Jonathan, you got one up on me.
Good job.
What, yeah, what was coming out January 2018?
We won't remember, but just tell us anyway.
Why won't it let me search?
I'm gonna see if I can find it.
I won't be able to.
Russ is way better at this stuff than me, but.
Everybody's doing it.
Oh, if I expand the view so that I can see
a hundred pieces rather than just 10.
Oh, that'll be helpful.
That's a good way to start.
It goes much faster.
Hey, there's actual episodes, not just planned ones.
Uh, 2022, 2021, we're getting there.
Okay.
2020, but then the episode.
January of 2018, that was.
Thank you, Kyle.
Yeah, that was like episode 29, 30, 31,
like things go sideways,
a council meeting in Waterdeep,
a Grant's Solstice vacation.
I just had a little panic
because I accidentally filtered the time window
and I got to the end and it was like,
there's only 40, where's, where's the first 40?
Well, it sounds like there was a council meeting
in Waterdeep and there was one of those
that went really badly from like a gameplay
kind of standpoint.
And then the next one was better.
Yeah.
So probably it was the one that was better.
There was one where Tom, Amy and I 100%
did not know how to talk to humans.
No.
Like in game, we couldn't do it.
Yeah.
Yeah, we could not do it.
And now we don't know how to roll dice.
We only know how to talk to humans.
Yeah, it says here,
surrounded by a cult and unknown ally, Diem Dock.
Yeah.
That's the one.
Wow.
That was the one.
I'm gonna go back and listen to this episode.
Isn't that the bad one?
No, that wasn't the bad one.
Okay.
That was where,
oh, I feel like we can't talk too much about it
because if they've only listened to these episodes.
Exactly.
Yeah, exactly.
This was the one where we actually got information.
Is it where the thing happened to Flint?
No, no, it wasn't that one.
It was where the thing first happened to Grant Sis.
That thing.
Just ask Jonathan.
They remember.
Jonathan knows.
Jonathan.
Again, thank you, Jonathan.
We appreciate it.
Yeah, thanks, Jonathan.
Good trip down memory lane.
Oh, it was fun.
Solstice Vacation, this isn't spoilers,
but this is where we tried to set Flint up.
Oh, yeah.
But then Grant Sis and everybody got shrunk down
and taken prisoner by grunts.
Oh, wow, grunks.
Gosh, that was so long ago.
Yeah.
Love me a grung.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wow.
It's good times.
That's fun.
Okay, well this one.
They remember that stuff.
Hey, you know what?
Thanks, Jonathan.
Thanks for being here.
Since the grung era.
That's what we'll refer to it as.
Yeah.
It's good times.
A little trip down memory lane.
That's all.
Yeah, that was fun.
That's what tonight's been.
Love it.
Hanging out at the Goo Kang.
Trip down there.
Exactly.
All right, well we hope to see you over
on Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast like Jonathan's.
Ah, sorry, I sold you again.
But also we hope you're having a wonderful time
and you're doing your best at what you can do today.
And we love you and we hope you have a wonderful.
Bye, Patreon.
What?
We'll talk to you very soon.
Patreon, Patreon, Patreon, Patreon.
Okay, love you, bye.
Bye.
Love you, bye.
Okay.
Still have the note in my hand
and there's the note that was thrown in before.
So we got two of them?
Yes.
Okay, I'm gonna grab one of the notes
and I'm gonna go up
and I'm gonna say, enough with the rage.
Put these two notes right on your page.
Help.
No, I grabbed you, didn't I?
Did you grab me?
Yes.
Okay, sorry, I heard grabbing of the notes
and I was like, am I still ready?
No, yeah, he grabbed your arm.
Okay, and the notes.
So both of you.
Hang in there, kid.
I'll be back.
Both of you are in this memory now.
Roll insight or intelligence.
That's an eight.
You go over to him, you're holding the notes,
you're looking down at the page
and you're trying to figure it out.
You just can't quite piece it together.
Either he hasn't got to the point in the song
where the notes you're holding are gonna make sense.
Something is not quite connected there yet
and he has not responded to you
or even acknowledged that you are present
in this space right now.
Rude.
What a dick.
I think that's probably the end of your turn.
Yeah, sure, that's my turn.
Cav.
I'm still quite a distance from the memory of note
that we're all kind of fixated on.
It's definitely shifted in space
so maybe come a little closer to you
but you'd have to do either jump,
as you've seen your friends do,
jump between memories or propel this platform
that you're on closer to to be able to get there.
Is there the ability to throw?
Like how far, is it close enough
that I could throw something at it?
Yeah, how good's your strength?
My strength is okay.
It's not amazing but it's okay.
I guess it's ranged, it would be a ranged attack too
so it could be Dex or whichever you'd prefer.
That's okay, they're both okay.
Both okay?
Both all right.
Cav is just a middle of the road kind of guy.
Just really you.
Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
Just a little everything.
Okay, yeah, you could absolutely try,
and one of or any, you could try any of those things.
Okay.
Once you throw it, you're kinda committed but you know.
Yeah.
How heavy is the music box?
It's like relatively small, right?
Yeah, no, I mean it is the size of a music box.
It doesn't feel like it's super heavy.
Yeah, we'll say like mini football size.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, lucky for you, Cav was like mini football champion
back growing up so it's got a pretty tight spiral.
Love it.
I'm gonna try to throw the music box at the memory.
Okay.
That Alydin and Bizard are in.
Okay, whichever, yeah,
just tell me which one you're rolling there.
Let's do Dex for the hell of it.
Okay.
All right, adding my plus one, that's a 14.
So you throw this and like the memory that they're in
is spinning through space, so you throw it
and it gets a decent spiral.
Like it's not heyday, yeah.
Real Uncle Rico situation.
That's right.
It starts to waver a little bit
but maybe that's helping you.
So it flies through the air,
passes through another cloud of notes
which do not affect it and it hits in
and from your view it like hits with enough force
that you think it should just like fly through this
like an open window.
Or see like there's a resistance to it
and like almost like in like Looney Tunes
when something's trying to go through some fabric
like there's a bend, yeah.
You see it do that until finally it snaps
but when it snaps through
you see more of these fractures around this memory
start to develop around the edges
and you see off and behind more of these horrors
jumping between memories
trying to get closer to this memory.
Okay, well I mean I don't know
if the extra cracks are both good or bad
and also my pals are in there
so there's a lot going on.
All right, I guess in the meantime
I'll use my movement to try to like get closer.
Do you want to physically move through the space
or do you wanna try the shield move that you had done?
I'll try the shield move to kind of create that motor
I guess we'll call it.
You're almost dead, you don't wanna hurl yourself
through like infinite space. Shockingly I don't.
And I think we did a strength check
to determine power and precision.
That's a 19 on the die so it should be a dirty 20.
You throw it, you see this happen,
you quickly rush to the back
to try and propel yourself closer to this memory.
You strike the shield which as you turn around
you look up and you see the banjo man
like staring down at you.
Waves coming off of his banjo
and these flames covering him
and you hit it and it propels you forward
and away from the banjo man
even like kind of knocks him back.
Doesn't seem to damage him
but just knocks him back in a way a little bit.
Bonwyn make a dexterity saving throw please.
12.
Because you're paying attention
to like the monsters climbing up on
you feel the ground move beneath you
which causes you to stumble back a little bit.
You're still standing almost like catches you
before you fall off and puts you back
as you find yourself now within 20 feet of this memory.
Really putting all of our eggs
in this memory basket aren't we?
That's right.
Well I mean that's the one all the whores are going to so.
Not even the quivering hills.
Okay it's the banjo man's turn.
So he's going to beat his wings together
in an attempt to put out the flames
which Carla if you wanna roll a d6 for fire damage.
Mm-hmm.
Five.
A million.
Thank you.
A million yes obviously.
But also you don't fan fire to put it out so.
Faze weird.
Ah fuck you.
So he beats his wings
and from as you kind of turn around
and look at him as you're floating and drifting away
you see him surveying the scene around
and then he locks eyes with Ever Baines
and he flies as fast as he can straight into it.
This fucking guy.
He flies straight into it
which causes the entire memory
that you see to shatter and go dark.
Alydin it's your turn.
I run over to Calder writing
and I go to poke him.
Your hand almost goes through him
like you're not in this space
or he's not in this space.
One of the two.
One of us isn't here.
Neither of you can interact
seemingly this way with each other.
Okay.
I say hello.
There's no response.
God this guy.
Hey McFly.
Why are you hitting yourself?
Just bully him more.
Bully him more.
Yes.
So we have the music box now.
Oh yeah.
So yes the music box came through
and then looking back out
like you see Bonwyn and Cav
and they are getting closer
but you're also seeing fractures
across like a window pane
where you came in.
Bazaar what happens to us
if that smashes?
I really can't say
but it wouldn't be a good day.
Oh God.
Okay.
Alydin runs to pick up the music box
and can I interact with anything in this space
or is it all just kind of like hands going through it?
We are witnessing the memory.
More like that.
Yeah.
Okay.
And do we have any notes?
There are two notes in the music box in this space.
I take both notes and the music box
and I just kind of bring them over to Calder
and like.
Uh?
Does that, do you want me to roll for uh?
Does the muse move him based on the uh?
The expert presentation.
Your Vanna Whiting does not appear
to make him look at you.
Oh this fucking guy.
Kick up the Sajak protocol instead.
Alydin, he hasn't heard a word we said.
Maybe we need to put the idea straight into his head.
Oh I love this.
I take one of the notes and I like
awkwardly push it into the back of his head.
Okay, cool, cool, cool, cool.
Half hoping it just kind of goes through him
the way that my hand did but.
Absolutely the only thing I, when you said that
I was like, this is the only thing I can think of
at this point.
Oh yeah, it was gonna be like,
can we move over to the side of him?
Get in there, inception.
Right?
You slide the note into the back of his head.
Bizarre, you are watching this.
You see it come out like the other side.
Like it's like glowing and coming through.
You look down at the page that he's writing on.
Make an intelligence or performance check.
Bizarre.
Okey dokey.
Meanwhile, I'm just sliding it through his head
like spaghetti.
There's nothing in there.
Oh, the rolls tonight, that's a nine.
Yeesh.
Can I look at them?
You, yeah, yeah, yeah, I think so.
So you notice that it's not doing anything, right?
You also make, what did I say?
Intelligence or performance check.
I notice him looking down and I'm like,
uh, performance or intelligence?
Yes.
I'll do, oh fuck, five, that's with the bonus.
And rolls are.
I don't know how to read music.
I've never gone to school for actual anything
so I can read just.
For fighting or dance.
Okay.
None of those things.
We're gonna leave you there for a moment.
Bonwyn, it's your turn.
You've just been propelled forward
which you've seen has knocked some of the horrors off.
There's a couple of them still on the platform.
You've seen Everbanks shattered into the ether.
So you're within, what did I say?
20 feet of this memory.
Kind of just want to say like,
we're doing dwarf tossing.
My calf is so weak.
But it's D&D so he's not.
He's actually just as strong as he is
even though he has two hips.
But also shattering memory.
If you jump through, are we all gonna die?
Hmm.
That is just my concern,
being a person inside of this memory.
Get there.
I mean this is a fair concern, absolutely.
Okay then, I'm going to try to just move us closer.
Like let's get like right there, right?
Even if we're not gonna jump in.
Yeah, cause we need to jump out at some point.
We could be the getaway helicopter for them,
absolutely. Get the cars.
Start the car.
Wheel man.
Okay, great.
Let's kill these bitches.
What are you using to maneuver yourself?
Kav was using his shield and hammer.
Yes.
She takes Kav's shield and hammer.
I mean absolutely.
When in need, take whatever you need.
But it's just sound, right?
Like I just need it.
So maybe I'm like that X-Man.
Secretly guys, I've actually studied opera.
You didn't know that.
It hasn't come up.
But as a child, so I just like launch into,
I was gonna say an aria,
but I feel like Bonwyn would actually be like a tenor.
Even if Carla isn't.
She's got those big wide lungs, you know?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
So let's try that.
Let's try that.
Make a performance check.
For fuck's sake.
I can't believe these rolls tonight, you guys.
I haven't rolled higher than like a six all night.
Oh my God.
I've had good rolls so far.
Oh God, did I just curse myself?
Yeah, I just said that.
So that was a three.
Okay.
Oh, just cracks.
It's just nothing.
Something, yeah.
It's frog in your throat.
You've forgotten how to sing.
Oh no.
You have the memory of going through these opera classes
and like doing all of that.
But as you go to belt it out,
like it doesn't come to you.
It doesn't work anymore.
Too bad my one core memory's gone, guys.
I don't remember shit now.
Yeah.
Anything else you would like to try to do?
Bonus action style.
Or I guess action.
That feels like a bonus action to go go.
Where's my guy?
Is he still just floating around on fire?
He's no longer on fire.
He is some distance away
because he like torpedoed himself through your memory.
Right.
What kind of distance away?
50 to 60.
Let's try and light him up again.
Okay.
So I'm going to try and hit him.
I'm going to light an arrow.
Try and shoot him.
Fuck me.
That's an 11.
Yeah.
Wow.
11 does not hit.
All my dice are in jail.
Just going to have to pop over to your house real quick.
Grab another G20.
Sure, sure, sure, sure.
They're all fucking dead to me right now.
So this arrow goes through and just misses him.
And he turns back and you see these strings again
pulling at his smile and his eyes wide.
And I give him a.
I blew a kiss.
There was no sound.
Because Bonwyn's like, fuck this guy.
Absolutely.
He just blew up Everpaints.
And I maybe don't even remember that
because I don't know what has happened
with this memory, but I'm really tired
of his bullshit.
Yeah, no, understandably so.
We have been fighting him for seven years.
Yeah.
Exactly.
The horrors are swarming the memory
that Bizard and Alydin are in.
You see them climbing up and picking away at it
as you're trying to get closer.
Someone fight them.
Bizard, it's your turn.
You hear this pecking and chipping away
coming from outside.
And you would be able to have,
you would have line of sight on Bonwyn and Cav now.
Okay.
And this will be the last turn that you have to speak.
At the end of this turn,
you will be able to not speak
in rhyming couplet anymore.
Awesome.
I'm gonna look at Alydin and say,
I'm at a loss of what to do
and if we don't make it out,
I'm sorry, I failed you.
That's loser talk.
It is.
Kyle respects that.
Strong loser talk.
Yeah, I'm really tempted to,
the only thing I have is like,
well, it's a con save.
So,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna cast Frostbite on one of the,
one of the little minions crawling around.
And since it,
well, it is up to you Russ,
but it causes the frost to form on one creature.
So there's no like piercing the veil that's going on.
Okay, yeah, absolutely.
Yeah.
So that's our con save.
Con save DC 14.
How about a five?
Yeah, that's not gonna do it, so.
These rolls tonight,
that's gonna be three frost damage.
Okay.
You see this creature,
but all of you see this creature begin to freeze
and like stick to the side of this platform
as more start to try and get over it.
And as you do that,
you look and you see that there are still,
Bonwyn and Cav have two more of the music notes.
I'm gonna try to yell out at them,
throw those music notes in here
and maybe we can get them in his ear.
And we like, no one knows why he's doing this.
Totally.
Like a weird time to try out a new bit.
I've heard it cause we've been like,
True.
Yeah, we've been so far away,
we might not even know.
Yeah, no clue in on it.
Such a weird time to start out a new aspect,
but I guess like,
battle brings out different things in people.
You're allowed to reinvent yourself whenever you want,
I guess.
Roll me a D20 before we finish your turn there
for Bizard.
All right.
It's a six.
Okay.
Cool beans. Just a six.
Roll me D100, please.
Ah, shit.
That's okay.
This is necessary.
All right, 67.
Nope, yeah, 67.
Rhyming couplets again?
No, Iambic Pantamani.
No, no, I'm...
My mistress eyes are nothing like the sun.
But I can't remember what I had for breakfast yesterday,
or why I walked into a room.
Roll me a D6, please.
Two.
On an even number,
you gain plus two to your AC for one minute.
Oh, what?
That's so much better than couplets.
That's really dope.
Yeah, so that puts me to 16.
How does that transfer in game?
Does he just feel super confident all of a sudden,
like, I can do anything?
Feels like he could dodge a little more shit.
Just.
Yeah, punch me, punch me.
Is it like one of those things?
That's right.
No, that's how Houdini died.
Yeah, that's right.
Don't do it.
Okay, with that we go to Cav,
who you've just heard the couplets
of Bizard calling for the notes.
Okay, am I close enough to like,
just step in to this memory?
Yeah.
I guess, well, maybe not.
Not quite.
It didn't quite work with the singing there.
Yeah, because Bonwyn wasn't able to propel you forward.
Like, you're all kind of like moving.
These two memory, or the platform that you're on
and the memory are like moving together now.
So you're not quite close enough.
I don't know how far Cav can jump.
How far can he throw?
Or how far can he throw?
I mean, we've established he's okay at throwing.
The throwing's been on point so far.
Now, Javelin?
Not as sure.
Okay, I'll try and hit the shield again
to move us closer.
Okay.
As like my movement portion of things.
Sounds good.
Give me a strength.
That's a 12 plus one, so 13.
Okay, you hit it and you hit it like,
you feel like you hit it harder than you want to
and this platform begins to move quickly
towards the memory.
Can make a dexterity saving throw
to try and stop it from crashing into the memory
or you can let them collide.
I'm gonna, yeah, I'm gonna try to do like a little
like extra tap on the shield to like,
buffer us a little bit.
To like course correct the other way, yeah.
Buy it instead of into it.
Okay.
Great.
Do you see the fear in our eyes
as we see you hurling towards us?
Like, coming in hot.
That's for Dex this time, that was a 15,
so 16 overall.
Okay.
So yeah, you see yourself,
you see you and Bonwyn moving quickly towards it
and you give that little course correct,
which slows you down and like you bump into,
which causes some of these horrors to climb up
on top of the platform you're on now,
but you are right next to it.
So you bump into it.
You hear like a little shatter down towards the bottom
where you hit, but it's still standing.
Okay, do I still have control of the notes as well?
Or had they been kind of just like put to the side
while we were figuring shit out?
One of you has to have them, I think.
So like they're there.
If I have them, I wanna give them to Bonwyn.
Okay.
Because she'll be next up before I get to go again.
So I'll hand them over and say like,
we gotta get those in there.
You hear the banjo man, his song begins to play louder
and like the loop of it is becoming
more and more apparent.
Like he is playing with ferocity.
You hear all of the memories around you splintering.
You see little fractures of them flying off
and he's in the middle of this space.
Like he's in this space.
You see now the strings being strung up
to some high up area.
And he is playing with such ferocity
that things around you are fracturing,
are breaking, are falling apart.
Alydin.
Um.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season four, episode 25.
Starring Amy More as Alydin.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane.
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave.
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard.
And Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design
of today's episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound
and sound effects are from Epidemic Sound
and Boom Library.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
And we'd like to say a huge thank you
to our supporting producers,
including Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok.
Kat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Angaron Kiersen, Perry Matey,
Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss, and L.A. Branton.
Have you been enjoying your time
with Dumbgeons and Dragons?
Well, thank you so much for being here.
If you're looking for more of what you love,
come over to Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
where you're gonna get a seven day free trial.
And when you're a patron for at least three months,
we're gonna send you some merch
based on the tier you're at.
Come on over, we hope to see you over there.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Have a great week, we'll talk to you soon.
Okay, just blew up everbanes, everybody.
Who's?
Wang Chung tonight?
Everybody, Wang Chung tonight.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.