They said you were looking for Dumbgeons and Dragons. Well, you found us. We'll begin in just a moment.
It is the next day and the three of you have gathered at Dem Buns though, hoping to see
Bizard. But instead, as you're having your morning coffee and pastries, Foll and Ferram
comes around the corner and sees you and gives a nice wave and goes in to get himself some
breakfast, leaving you three out front as the morning crowd is just opening up shops.
So he wants us to go work for him, like, like go adventure with them. And he's like,
you know, retiree adventure buddies. Do we what do we think about that?
Well, would he, would he, would he pass?
Yeah, I think like as a job.
Yeah, it sounded like it.
What do you guys think? I mean, I don't hate the idea. I gotta say though,
the Alistair thing with the, with the archive like that.
Kind of seemed important.
Yeah, it definitely has some like gravitas.
Like history important, you know?
Yeah.
Like maybe they'll write our names in a book somewhere if we find it.
Ooh, I hadn't even thought of that.
I've read some of those.
Huh.
How many?
Like at least five.
Alydin pretends to look impressed.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Russ
More, he, him. Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she, her.
You should be looking for ghosts. Nod children, agreed.
And Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave, he, him.
That totally like loosens up that whole area, right?
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast and you can join today or better yet,
put it on your Christmas wish list because your friends and family can gift you a
one to 12 month membership to come join the community.
Find out more details at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast slash gift for all the
greatest gift ideas this holiday season and now, fuck it, let's play.
The door chimes and Folan comes back out.
He doesn't have his crowd that you saw him with the other day there, Bonwyn.
And he comes over to your table, he says, good morning to you.
I don't know, I believe, Kav, we've met Alydin, yes?
Yes.
Alydin, it's a pleasure to meet you all again.
Apologies. I just wanted to know if you thought about my, wasn't really an offer at the point,
more of an ask. If you've had any consideration for it?
We were just kind of chatting about it. And I think no decision has been made yet.
I know you folks want to hit the road pretty soon.
Oh yeah, of course.
Yeah, I guess we just don't know yet. And of course, like, our fourth amigo.
Oh, just probably, you know, just just working.
I mean, Kav's probably free entirely. I don't want to speak for you, Kav.
Thank you. That's very kind of you. But yes, yeah, yeah, available.
Oh, what'd you have in mind?
Me and a couple of the guys, Merrick and Rudyard, are heading out into the woods.
We've heard rumors that there's a, it's going to sound silly, but there's a ghost elk that
roams the forests outside Vintersmouth. We took a little quick course with June yesterday,
so we felt like there was enough that the three of us at least could go out and
do a little initial exploring while, A, you're making your decision, and B,
the other folks are kind of getting the rest of their gear together.
Question about June's class. Was it just like Hunting 101,
or was it like more focused on weapons? Like, what was, what was the vibe of the class?
Oh, well, we did take your recommendation and go straight for the June Doe orientation.
Did she chop someone in the neck and they passed out? Because
she starts her classes like that.
Me.
Oh, wow. Yeah, that's actually, she probably said, but that's a compliment
because she knew that you could take it.
I could, I could definitely feel that. And, you know, I was, I was worried that it would,
that it would hurt. And, you know, there is an initial pain, but afterwards,
like a relaxation that comes from that.
Lutions up that whole area.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
She's pretty incredible. So ghost elk, do you, are you, forgive me, I don't know
a lot about ghost animals. Are you hunting it or you just want to see it? Or you?
Well, I mean, did you get any unfinished business? I don't know.
I don't know about any, anything beyond the fact that there's been rumors around
town that people have been seeing it. So, I mean, I don't, I'm not a big like
hunt for the game of hunting. Like, obviously, if we're going to hunt something,
it's probably not going to be a ghost in order to sustain ourselves, but we have enough in this
town. So I would really more just love to see it. And anything else along the way,
we'll do a little survival, you know, rigging up some traps, that sort of thing.
Of course, taking them down after, because I know, and he looks to Alydin,
I know the children play in, in the streets and the forest.
They, they would see your trap coming a mile away.
Oh, I'm sure, I'm sure. But also like if you caught one of them,
it wouldn't be the end of the world. Oh, my gosh. It'd be so funny, especially,
you know, if it was, if it was tally. Oh, okay. Well, maybe I don't want to be
in charge of catching children. Yeah, no, that's it. That's it.
It's like we're off topic. Yeah, I'm not trying to catch
a rich elderly white man coming to this town who I barely know anybody here.
You should be, you should be looking for ghosts, not children.
And are you going to catch a ghost elk? Well, that's the question. Is it actually a ghost?
Is it just an elk with perhaps some albino qualities? That might be an interesting find.
Yes. And I think you really get a kick out of Merrick and Rudger. They're,
I mean, Rudger, he tells a, tells a tall tale.
Merrick's a bit much, but he foots the bill a lot of the time. So
kind of helps to keep him along. He did get a lot of items from me,
like an excessive amount. I tried to talk him out of it. Like I don't like to
take advantage of people, but he, he wanted like quadruple of everything. So who am I?
You know, and he has, he has like the butler guy that's always with him that
like carries all his stuff. So I guess you'd never have to carry your own stuff.
What? Steuben is his butler. Yes. Yeah.
Do you like a caddy? Yeah, he does carry all of his, all of the,
all of his equipment around in what you could describe as a golf bag.
Yeah. Yeah. So I mean, I don't, if you've got other plans, I don't,
I don't worry about it. But was that, was that sort of an
invite for a little, well, just like into the woods adventure, you know,
get to know part of the crew. I know you're still making your decision on
whether you want to come with us or not. That could help us decide,
could help us decide, see, do kind of a vibe check with the crew, see how we get along.
Also, I just finished a bunch of big orders for you guys.
So I was not going to go to Everbane's today.
Didn't she just, no, it's fine. It's fine.
She can always find work. Yeah, fair.
Yeah. Oh yeah. There's always so much to do.
I mean, Zane's been taking over a lot of anyway, doesn't matter, but I can be free,
I guess is what I'm saying. Great.
And it would be nice to go to the woods for a little low stakes adventure.
Perfect. I would like to see a ghost elk.
That would, yeah. No, me too.
Okay. Well, I'll go grab. I mean, it does sound pretty cool.
I'll go grab the guys. I assume you've got to kind of gather some things,
but we'll maybe meet back here in an hour or so, and then head out.
Yeah. Spending the night, you think one night out there.
I mean, probably have to be out at night to find a ghost.
Again, I don't know a lot about what are the rules with ghosts.
Yeah. Well, we're going to find out, but we don't feed them after midnight
and don't get them wet. We'll bring enough stuff that we
can have. We can camp if we see something along the way and we want to come back.
No worries. Amazing.
Sounds like fun. It does sound like fun.
Let's do it. Yeah. Just like a little,
a little day trip. I love it.
He goes his own way to go find his friends and we,
we cut to an hour or so later and everybody has gathered all their gear
and you're heading off towards the Verboten Forest.
Sir Merrick Longwhisker is being followed by his caddy helper, Stupin.
And Merrick is very bejeweled. All of his armor is encrusted in
rubies and diamonds. He's a heavier set fellow who has a long handlebar mustache,
bit of a goatee, flaming red hair, very pale skin and
Rudyard Brasney, who's been introduced to you, is an even older fellow.
He looks like he's probably in his late 60s, early 70s,
has a few deep scars on his face and a couple tattoos up and down his arm.
And we step into a conversation, mostly driven by Rudyard at this point, as we step in.
Why, during the siege of Redwall Keep, I'll tell you, and he's pointing to Alydin,
I held the line single-handedly. 20 men against me and not a scratch did they leave.
It was quite the time. How did you do that?
Oh, well, I had this trusty sword right here and he just kind of half unsheathed an old
rusty sword. Not anything that Bonwyn has crafted for him. He has another dagger and
another long sword on his belt. So he's just carrying that 20-pound
sword for sentimental purposes. Just to tell this story.
Just to tell this story. He's committed to his bit.
He tells this story five times a day. Of course he does.
I think that's something old men do. Absolutely.
I have to have something on me. I think so.
To tell this story. Well, I had this sword and I was one
of the last ones there. And as he's telling this story,
Steuben, who's kind of walking behind everybody, kind of quickly nudges you,
Alydin, to fall. He's signaling you to fall back a little bit.
How long was that story going to be? Oh, well, just don't you worry, dear.
There will be 20 more similar like it. Important thing to know that Red Wallkeep
was in fact abandoned decades before Rudyard was even born.
Yes. Okay.
Anything he tells you, grain of salt. Grain of salt.
Oh, he's a liar. Yes, yes.
He is grand and verbose in all of his storytelling.
But perhaps has never even seen half of the things he said.
Cool. And he has all those weapons.
He does. Yes. He doesn't often pull them out much more than
look at this one and then puts them back.
Okay. I once stared down a troll
and the beast turned tail and ran.
It knew better than to test my steel.
And he again pats the sword at his side as he treks off, trying to catch up with Folan
and Steuben who pushes in behind you.
And he says he must took a drunken man in a fur coat for a troll once.
Well, I'm how.
Hey, Bonwyn.
Bonwyn. And she runs to catch up with Bonwyn.
Sorry. Sorry. You were calling me.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. I definitely was definitely calling you.
How are things going? Are you hearing some some tales back there?
Oh, yeah. These guys, they are great storytellers.
Yes. Yeah.
About one. I mean, he's been talking by my estimation,
85 percent of the time we've been on the trail.
I think this might be the exact opposite of our other option of going for the academic
archive with the sleeping man library with all the information.
This one is old man fairy tale.
Yeah. But aren't you a little bit interested in him?
And I point at the at the other gentleman, his name, I can't remember, Russ.
I'm so sorry. Marek.
Sir Marek Longwhisker. Marek.
Quiet. Scars. What's his name?
I don't know, but look at all the shiny.
I feel like he's actually lived, you know?
Yeah. Those guys never tell their stories. They're like quiet and mysterious.
Yeah. Makes me want to know even more.
The ones who are always shouting their tales from the rafters.
Hard to believe the words they say.
I could be quiet and mysterious.
Oh, totally.
Marek Longwhisker steps up to you, Cav.
You've been, you know, rather quiet, just kind of hanging back.
And he gives you a nudge and says, so you've adventure much?
Just a little bit a couple of years ago.
And then just like recently have kind of picked it back up.
Mm. And what got you back into it?
Um, well, there was like a bit kidnapped.
There was like, remember when the monsters showed up in town?
That kind of that kind of spurred everything on.
These are the monsters in town here.
Well, a little while back. Yeah.
Oh, wow.
Oh, did you not hear about that?
Oh, well, um.
It was kind of like all the rage.
That one newspaper reporter just kept writing stories about it.
Wow. I don't read much.
Yes. No, I have I have Stuben read for me.
Oh, OK.
I mean, I personally have read at least five books, so.
Well, I asked Stuben to skip over anything too scary.
It keeps me up at night.
Fair.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Fallen here has had this grand idea to come out.
Adventure.
And I thought, well, he's a dear friend of mine.
I could foot the bill along the way and perhaps have some tales of my own
to write about and not keep me up at night.
I mean, I hope that you have all the tales that you could ever ever write about
because that sounds dope as hell.
Oh, well, perhaps we could have a have a have a mutual tale.
One that where we get rich in the end, but don't have to.
But don't have to fight monsters.
Oh, OK.
All right.
Monsters sound a bit much.
What about like a monster singular?
One singular, sensational monster.
OK, one monster, perhaps a smaller monster, though.
Oh, OK.
Like a little appetizer.
Yes.
What do you think?
What what say you about that?
I'd say me, yes.
Real meeting of the minds we got going on here.
Look, it's entirely possible Cav has gotten stupider
since he has not been going to work.
You know, idle.
Like you use it or you lose it.
So that's right.
That's right.
I love it.
Lauren, I feel like we're two sides of the same coin.
I think we're going to get along quite handily
and he gives you another nudge and he's like,
Stupin, I need another roll, please.
It always comes together.
Are you ready?
Welcome to the middle.
Did I take you guys?
Oh, yeah.
I'm trying to tell everybody.
Russ, hold on a minute.
We're in the middle, but first, let me tell you
about this amazing video I saw where a guy makes
an eyeball granny square jacket.
So he makes granny squares and then crochets the eyeballs
and then crochets like upper and lower eyelids
and then puts it together and then made a jacket.
And it was really dope.
But not as dope as this week's patron.
Oh, oh, whoa.
Threw it right to you.
I really, I threw it back to you.
This week's patron is Monona.
Tried to get me, but I had a name.
We gave you so much time.
I think Monona can pull off an eyeball granny square jacket.
Oh, hell yeah.
Absolutely.
Nobody's business that would look dope on them.
Thank you.
Yes.
Thank you for being here.
And thank you for that lovely eyeball story.
Eyeball jacket sweater story.
I'm going to need a picture later.
Yeah, Amy can whip that up for you.
No problem.
I mean, I understood like 25% of what Carla was saying.
So I felt like I was right there.
I imagine it's like the cloak of many eyes,
but made out of granny squares.
Yeah, but like I don't.
Or the robe of many eyes.
I'll try and find something, a picture and post it.
Just imagine if somebody stitched
the cover of a Tool album.
But whimsical.
Because they're dramatic.
Here, I'll tell you what.
Here, I'll make this easy.
Bam.
Hey, speaking of gifts and joining Monona over on Patreon,
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
because we're still in the middle.
We told you about it last week,
but also we'll tell you about it again this week.
Patreon has this great thing where you can ask
your friends and family to gift you subscription to Patreon.
What?
I know.
Tis the holiday season.
Jingle, jangle, jangle, jangle.
Fill your stocking with Dumbgeons and Dragons.
I don't know if there's a physical handout,
but they'll figure it out.
They're crafty people.
I'm sure.
Yeah, they can just make you something.
They'll make you a fake little certificate and give it to you.
A little handmade card.
I do digital gifts.
That would be adorable.
Yes, exactly adorable.
That's what we need.
So Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast slash gift
is the place to go or rather the place to send people
that you love who love you in return
and then you can join the community.
And it's just all love.
All love, baby.
Love.
Not a cult.
It's all love.
Lightly a cult.
Like barely.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just like a, yeah.
Just a mutual respect to the kind of society.
It's great.
That's where we're gonna stop.
It's time to get back to the episode.
We'll talk to you later.
Love you, bye.
Steuben, I need another roll, please.
Like a dinner.
Like he's just.
Okay, all right.
Okay.
I was like, like a cigarette.
Oh, I was like like a D20.
This is very meta.
What are you talking about?
Oh, okay.
He's just feeding him constantly.
Yeah.
Love it.
Follin drops back to you, Bonwyn.
So maybe they weren't the best of the group
to perhaps sway you on,
but it's who wanted to come today.
That's fair.
It's fair.
I mean, a nice person.
Just a just I guess I'm more used to like a loud banging
constantly in my ears
as opposed to like a yap yap yap yap yap in my ears.
Yes, yes.
It's just an adjustment.
My brass knee.
Is that what you're talking about?
Absolutely.
Got it right after taking a spear right through the leg.
Doctors said I'd never walk again, but here I am.
A miracle.
Wow.
Steuben quickly behind you.
He slipped on wet stairs, shattered his knee,
and had it replaced with a custom brace.
Yeah.
It's nice of you to fact check him, Steuben.
I don't like him spreading so many ill truths.
What's your deal, Steuben?
Is this a good job?
He probably pays well.
Very bejeweled seems like a wealthy man.
Yes.
No, it pays magnificently.
I just have to put up with the group.
You know, one on one, they're generally okay.
Once they get together, everybody starts telling stories.
But they're old, right?
So like, do they take a collective nap?
Yes, they do.
Usually about midday, which he checks his pocket watch
and is like, we're coming up on it soon.
And as he says that, everybody make a perception check, please.
Here we go, guys.
A 12, let's see.
Oh, okay.
I rolled a double digit right away.
Like, I'm excited.
Wow.
That is a 10 for Cav.
And a 10 for me as well.
All right.
You're just lulled by the tale of a-
We are.
We're just like-
Crazy old guy.
Trying to let it wash over me.
Following along this path, hearing half truths and stories of old,
and the path crosses over a river and you make your way down.
And out of the-
It's not a true fork in the road.
It looks like there's a-
Is it a fuck in the road?
It's a fuck in the road.
Exactly.
There's a bit of a path that looks like has been somewhat used going off to the left.
And the three of you catch out of the corner of your eye what looks like
a scrap of paper that kind of is rolling down.
Off the small breeze that's cutting through the trees,
rolling down this path towards you.
Boy, I scamper after it.
Paper blowing in the wind.
Child's got to chase it.
Dot two.
Not a child.
Teenager.
You're basically an adult, but still.
Pretty much.
Like 14 is so close to adulthood.
No, it's not.
I want to chase it.
You zip down the path quickly.
You're able to catch it.
You don't need to roll anything.
It kind of gets brushed up into a little shrub off to the side,
and you grab it.
And roll me a d20, please.
There it is.
Five.
She's back, baby!
The double digits did not last long.
That 12 was a little too lofty.
Yeah.
It was getting too comfortable.
That's right, Icarus.
You just were flying towards the sun.
Had to come back down to Earth, I'm sorry.
You pick it up, and this is the phrase that you see on the page.
Is it the phrase that pays?
Just a whole range of emotions on Amy's face.
I can't wait to hear it.
I kind of jog back to the group, and
I'm looking at this paper, and I'm reading it over.
What'd you find?
You know when things happen, and you're like,
oh, like, that's funny.
Like, we were just talking about that.
Oh, I don't like that.
Makes me uncomfortable a little bit when it's like,
This is going to make you uncomfortable.
Okay.
I'm ready.
So I just saw the scrap paper.
Went to get it, obviously, because you never know what it could be.
Like a love letter or something.
It's not a love letter.
It says, the archivist will fall asleep and dream the door open.
See, Mike, a little, like...
That's very specific and relevant to our current situation.
I mean, not our current current situation.
But like our overall current situation.
Our overall situation.
As you say that out loud, everybody collectively stops,
and there's like a whisper on the wind,
and you hear almost like coming in and out of a conversation,
and you hear, hollow hearth, broken teeth, the book, bit back.
In a voice we recognize, or just like a weird, ethereal...
Weird, ethereal...
Okay.
What did you find there?
Did anyone else hear that?
Yeah, I heard that.
The voice on the wind, that?
Yeah.
Did you, Follan, did you hear that?
Yeah, I thought I heard something.
Is everything okay?
I don't know.
I don't feel like...
A danger situation, you know?
Agreed.
I just don't love an unearthly voice.
It doesn't like...
Yeah, I don't really have enough information to base things off yet.
In a weirdly specific note, just randomly in the forest?
In the forest.
Yeah.
Look down the half-trodden path where the page rustled from,
and you think you hear more like rustling of paper somewhere up ahead.
Oh my god.
What...
What's the chance that this belongs to...
What's his name?
Alastair?
And he's like...
Oh, he probably...
Up there sleeping, and this is paper that's blown out of all this stuff.
Or on his way into town.
He came this way.
We should maybe go look, because he had all that...
You know, he was carrying that huge satchel with all those papers.
Maybe it's important.
Maybe he's up there, like you said.
I mean, we should go look, right?
Gentlemen, we're gonna go this way,
because part of adventuring is following a strange clue.
We call them side quests.
Did I ever tell you about the time I parried a lightning bolt?
Tell us all about it.
As we walk this way.
And then I speed walk away.
Steel blade to raw magic, I tell you.
The sparks were something to behold.
So you quickly walk ahead.
Yeah.
You don't have to walk for very long, just a few minutes,
and the paper rustling sound gets louder.
And you cut through this cove of trees,
and you stumble upon what looks like an abandoned camp.
A fire that has long since been put out.
No smoke or anything.
Not hot to the touch.
Looks like a couple turned over bedrolls.
But what really stands out is fluttering up in the trees surrounding this camp
are pages that look like they've been torn from a journal.
Cav, can you reach those?
I can't.
I mean, I can get some of these ones, but.
I want to climb a tree.
All right.
As not child children do.
Yeah.
Roll athletics or acrobatics with advantage because you're a child.
And I'll be trying to gather anything lower down.
Sure.
I'll acrobat this.
That's a 13, and that's an 8.
13!
Your foot slips a little bit at first,
but you are able to climb the trees.
It's not elegant is what you're.
No, it's not.
It's not as quick and nimble as you were kind of making it out to be.
Maybe it's a little mossier than you thought.
It was going to look really cool.
Exactly.
Yeah.
You do have a little slip, but as you're getting up,
you can reach a number of the pages at the very least.
Everybody's kind of collecting them and bringing them back around.
And you look down at the pages and everybody roll a d20 just for the first
thing that you see.
God damn it.
Three.
Six.
Nineteen.
Oh, I thought we were going to have like a three, six, nine,
but then he said teen, and I was blown away.
Did the dice go that high?
I didn't even know that those numbers were on there.
Sorry, I couldn't help it.
Never seen 19 before in my life.
OK.
I've been rolling a d10 this whole time.
I have a question.
Depending on what you roll, the higher up you roll,
is it like the more information that you get from what we're looking at?
Or is it just random?
I have them bucketed into different types of information,
but no one is more important than the other at this point, perceptively.
OK.
What do you guys...
Is the writing all the same for us?
Like, and do we recognize it as...
Alastair's?
Alastair.
I keep wanting to call him the Sandville.
I don't know why.
That was Cthulhu, Carla.
That was Cthulhu.
I know.
From, yeah, from, I mean, he had lots of journals
and was scrawling things down as he was talking to you.
It doesn't look like his writing.
OK.
There are some similarities between some of the pages,
but it doesn't look like it is one person's journal.
OK.
Well, this one, I feel like Kav, you're going to be interested in this.
Listen to this.
Oh, OK.
Kingstown's first scribes chained their souls here,
so Wintersmith might endure.
You know anything about that?
You're from the city.
No.
As you say that, that wind pipes up again.
If you burn the book, it only writes itself again than you.
Did anyone else feel like it kind of cut off halfway through?
Yeah.
Or in you, like in your body.
What did that mean?
Folan's like, yeah, that didn't sound great.
Do they have a fire pit?
I assume they can.
Yeah, yeah, it looks like it's long since been put out,
but it looks like there was a fire pit, whoever used this last.
When I look around there, I want to look to see if they've tried to burn pages.
Pages.
Yeah, there's no danger or anything.
You kind of sift through the soot, and there are bits of paper in there.
Long since blackened, some have kind of blown away.
Nothing really remaining that you could connect to the pages
that you're seeing that you've pulled from the trees.
What does your stake have?
Its shelves were carved from the bones of Oathbreakers.
You are late.
The archive already opened.
Does anyone else get the feeling like we're late?
Well, does that mean like did Alistair find the archive?
Dude was like just asleep.
Like just today?
Yeah.
I saw him on a bench.
Wait, do you think the archive was inside him all along?
Well, I don't, this piece of paper says he will walk these halls again,
though ink has claimed his tongue.
They chained me in the margins.
I can still hear them turning the page.
Someone's stuck in a book.
It sure seems that way.
It does seem that way.
Can you get trapped in a book?
Ethereal voice, are you a good guy or a bad guy?
Legally, you have to tell us.
It's worth a shot.
That's what June says.
No response.
But as you're kind of pausing and looking around,
everybody in the group of gentlemen with you is like stone still,
even though they have weapons piling up all around them.
And as you kind of relax just a moment,
you hear something move in the trees behind you.
You all turn and look,
and you feel like you see an animal disappear off into the forest.
Oh, was that, did you guys see that?
Was that the ghost elk?
I don't know.
I just saw like rustling, like something moved over there, though.
Perhaps we, do we want to take these pages or leave these pages and perhaps?
I'll take them.
I think we should definitely take them.
We can't just leave all this litter in the forest.
No, no, you're supposed to leave no trace.
Leave this space and go see if we can't find that elk.
And Merrick heads off into the woods.
Stupid!
He's nervous.
I get it.
I fold the pages.
I put them in my bucket.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 4 Episode 42
Starring Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane,
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard,
and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue Editing and Sound Design of today's episode is by Russ More.
Our Community Manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound,
and Sound Effects are from Epidemic Sound Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our Amazing Cover Art is by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babyok,
Angaron Kierzen,
Perry Matey,
Cat Waterflame,
Jacob Madden,
Old School Gamer D,
Craig Zeiss,
L.A. Branton,
Chibs1012,
and Kudzu828.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast,
and all of our amazing community help make sure
that we have adventures for you every single week.
Come join us today, Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
We hope to see you over there,
and you have yourself,
right now, a great week.
Yes, and we'll talk to you very, very soon.
It starts like this.
I like big butts, and I cannot lie.
You other brothers can't deny.
The girl walks in, that's why it's taking so long.
It's really long.
Rambling in your face.
You get feelings.
Or sprung, whichever.
Same, same.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.