Welcome back. We missed you.
Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
Bizard.
Uh huh.
It's been a while.
Been a while.
Thank you.
You've been talking to your mom about maybe taking over like the actual
responsibility of the store is where we kind of left you. And if you don't
remember that, maybe I made it up. Maybe I didn't.
Sounds sounds right.
Sounds like something that we came to in one of those last sessions that we
played together. But she's actually because of the conversations that
you've had, the kind of arrangements throughout the story of making, she's
actually wanting you to meet Captain Jacob.
Okay.
So she's invited you out to dinner tonight. And this is in the terms of
like where we are in the episode release timeline. We're backing up a
little bit for our other friends that we will catch up with. But you're
busy getting ready. She's given you the Brewed Awakening is having a
prime rib buffet.
Oh, okay.
Bench.
Very nice.
So you're getting yourself ready to head out, lock up the store at the
end of the day. What's Bizard doing to prepare yourself to head out on
this?
Adventure of your own sort.
I mean, honest like that. This is this is going to be an interview for
Bizard. So he is like dressing like he's going to his like final
seminar at school. He is presenting himself to the highest degree that
he possibly could to use his knowledge and station to dominate this
conversation. That's how he's going into this.
So yeah, you've got cloaks on cloaks. That's right.
Prim and proper. Everything is quaffed. It's got a lovely haircut from
next door. And you're locking up the store. It's evening dusk. A few
people on the street, but really pretty quiet. You're making your
way giving yourself a little pep talk for for how you envision this
to go. And as you kind of round a corner onto Main Street, you
pass by an alley and you hear some commotion down this down the side
street like tweaks your ear. It doesn't it doesn't sound positive.
You hear someone yell out and then there's some there's a bit of a
scuffle that happens.
Yeah. I'll rush down there. I'm a businessman in this town. Got to
represent.
You run down this side street and you can it's pretty shadowy and
dark and you see one person on the ground up ahead of you. And
another taller, much heavier set man just lay a kick into this
person.
Okay.
I'm going to walk forward and I'm going to cast reduce to make
them a size smaller. And I need a constitution save DC 14 from
them.
That is a 13. So that's not gonna make it.
All right. He's reduced by one size and has a negative one D four
to any of his attacks. And I'm just going to walk him say you
seemed like you were such a big man before. What's what seems
to be the kerfuffle here?
As you cast this like he's laying in one more kick and
then you see him shrink down in size and it's like
surprises himself as the kick lands and he's confused and
turns and looks at you. Make a perception roll.
Okay.
Perception that is a five.
You're preoccupied.
Oh, yeah, I'm constant.
Mom's boyfriend.
Yeah, you can say just say new dad.
We'll see. It's an interview.
It's an interview.
He turns and he looks at you. And like his face is is
covered in shadow and he says, Hey, you the magic man.
I don't know. You tell me you're smaller than you were
a moment ago. What do you think?
Before you have time to react, there's a hood pulled over
your head.
And inside the hood, these runes begin to glow.
And you feel it cinch around your neck. And you hear
footsteps coming from behind you.
And someone pushes you to the ground. You hear one of
them speak up and they say you picked the wrong side rope man.
They lay a kick into you.
Shit.
Let's see.
I'm going to try to cast something. Actually, no, I
would observe the runes and see if I can decipher what
they're likely doing. Like Zard's assumption would be
that okay, well, this is going to keep me from using
verbal components of my spells.
Make an arcana roll.
Man, it's really like in those threes tonight. That's a nine.
You're looking at them and like you feel like you can
piece together like just a couple quick runes before
another kick slayed into you're going to take three
bludgeoning damage for based on the two of those. You
can tell because he spoke before the smaller big man
says, stay out of the ink wizard to drown in it.
The ink as these runes kind of flash across your
eyes, like you get a quick sense that whatever these
runes are doing, their goal is to stop you from
casting anything. As the three of them gather around
you, you hear a fourth set kind of get themselves up
off the ground. And that's where we fade out as you
are being laid into dope. The four of them exit out
into the street and one of them as they reach the edge
of the road, you're laying on like coughing up
blood. One of them yells back, Kenny's not the only
one watching you. You hear the footsteps fade. The
fuck do they mean by the ink?
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast
and I'm your dungeon master Russ More, he him. Also
with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she her.
We just got here. Carla Maxstab is Bonwyn Everbane,
she her. I mean, you can't miss a wedding even if
it is the fifth. Tom Laird is Kavlaran Goldweave,
he him. Gorsh, hold the bow. And Kyle Claset
is Bazaar the Wizard, he him. One guy was big
but I made him small and then there was a bag
over my head. Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon
supported podcast and we'd love for you to join us
today at patreon.com slash dumb dragging cast.
You'll get a seven day free trial to check things
out. And now let's get right to it. Fuck it.
Let's play. We're gonna cut ahead. It's been a
couple days catching up to where everybody else
is. Kavlaran, Bonwyn and Alydin, you've just
returned from this, what was supposed to be a
camping excursion going out to find this ghost
elk. You arrive back in town with some of your
findings. I'll leave you to kind of describe
those as we're reunited with some with some
friends in a moment. And there's this this
large gathering in the center of town. There's
this lectern that you've never seen it
before, but there are people like looking into
the book and there's shock and confusion on a lot
of their faces. And one woman who we said her
name was Melody Shore, who is a younger girl in
town, often has worked part time, we said,
with Neven. She yells after reading in the
book. It can't be true. It's not true. I
swear. And she storms off as more people
gather around and there's this growing
cacophony of confusion. And as that happens, a
rather royal looking page comes up to the three
of you and has this this large envelope in
their hands. And they immediately like you see
them, catch them out of the corner of your
eye and they like clock on to Kavlaran. And
they quickly walk up to him, hand him the
letter and say, You've been cordially
invited to your father's fifth wedding.
Kavlaran looks down at it and he shrugs and
says, What can I say? He loves love. And the
page says, What a Tom answer. We must go
now. Quick, post haste. We have to make the
next ship. And Kavlaran looks at you too
and says, Gorsh, hold the boat. And heads
off to the boat with the page. What?
See ya. I mean, you can't miss a wedding, even
if it is the fifth one. Oh, my God. We
really could use his help around here,
though. Across the way, you see a little
bit, well, definitely more shrunken than
usual. You see Bazaard enter from the
other side, surveying the scene, not
really clocking you two yet. Oh, thank
goodness. Oh, thank goodness. Alydin, look,
look, we have. Oh, my God. Oh, thank
God. I mean, we're just, yeah, we're
just going. Well, I'm kind of limping.
I did get, I have not gotten a bandaid
yet. I am very hurting. Why? What
happened to you? Oh, um. Before you
answer, you look at Bazaard, he's got
like a black eye, he's bruised, like
he's like cradling an arm, like he looks
like he, too, has been through some
things. What happened to you? Are you
OK? You look not well. I have so
many things I need to ask you. But
first of all, how are you? Are you
OK? I'm doing good. Who did this? You
know, honestly, I can't say their
name because I didn't get it. What do
they look like? One guy was big, but I
made him small and then there was a bag
over my head. That made me. I think I
couldn't cast spells if I wanted to.
How small? She's thinking maybe she
can take this. Oh, no, it's no,
not at this point. I would have worn
off. But what is going? I'm fine.
Thank you. I appreciate it. I will be
OK. There's other things I want to
talk to you about. Maybe you know,
maybe you don't. But what is
happening here?
Alydin, do you? Well, you go.
I'll add. She kind of like lifts her
bloody hands off of her bloody torso
and is like there was a mean ghost
elk and they stabbed me. Mm hmm.
And. It was made, it was, it was
bleeding ink and there were all these
papers and we met this guy.
This happened first.
We met this guy, Alistair, Alistair
out all the sleep all the time.
Yes, narcolepsy.
Over by the book, as you're
describing this, there's an eruption.
Someone screams, you lie and
cheat. And you look over and you see
another man, Rufus Douglas, who is a
local farmer in Vintersmouth.
He takes a swing at Bench.
Oh, no, come on, hey, what the
hell's in that book?
I want to run up and see the book.
Nosey as fuck.
You all make your way over there.
Bazaar and Bonwyn trying to break
up Bench and this Rufus.
Alydin, you go look at the book
and inside the book, the latest entry,
it looks like it's written in very
nice calligraphy.
It says, Bench waters down the
ale when he thinks no one will
notice.
Is this a burn book?
The phrase before it, what you
can presume was Melody's, she
dreams of another's bed, even as
she vows loyalty.
What?
Scandalous.
I'm going to I'm going to take the
book and I'm going to close it.
As you close it, it begins to write.
Do you wait?
No, I slam it.
I think that Alydin has worked
with enough tricky books with
Bazaar to know that a book can be
dangerous.
The words that you do see before
you slam it are the maker still
dreams and it continues to write.
I'll read that later.
This is just this is going to cause
trouble.
And I thrust it into Bazaar's one
good arm.
The whole town behind you begins
to erupt like, hey, what are you
doing?
You don't even know if any of
this is true.
Oh, you guys are all just
causing a big problem.
Few people like throw punches at
each other like this is very
unusual for for this town.
The friends.
Yeah.
I'm getting caught up in it right
now.
A couple town guards come finally.
There were a few in the mix, but
they seem to have been caught up
in whatever whatever stirring
everybody up.
But a few more come and like
knock them out of it and they
begin dispersing the crowd.
I mean, we'd need to take this
book, right?
Can't just give it to them.
We can't just leave it here for
people to get in fights.
Seems to be a bad book.
A bad book.
Have you all seen this before?
This is no.
We just got here.
Yeah, lots of bad, lots of book
things, though, going on.
Maybe this is why they close
the schools.
I don't know.
Here, books make you gay.
Is this true?
Bizarre.
I read about it somewhere.
That's OK.
I was already gay.
Welcome to the middle,
everybody.
Well, it's the middle.
I didn't even see you.
And it even has I didn't either.
Just yeah, you were busy.
I was a minute and 35 seconds ago,
man. Where you been?
That was that was that other podcast
you were trying to pitch.
Bird talk, bird talk.
And he's not going to budge on that.
Ooh, I get that.
Hey, we're a little cuckoo over here.
OK, did you miss us?
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, yeah, we did.
We're glad to be back in this this year,
which is twenty twenty six,
which somebody just joined
the discord not too long ago
and said they were listening
to an episode in season one,
maybe where we mentioned twenty
twenty six.
And I was recorded in like twenty
twenty twenty seventeen or twenty
eighteen. So like future premonition.
I don't know what the context was,
but we were talking about it.
So I think flying cars
and everyone's living on the moon.
Yeah, well, I nailed it 100 percent.
Yeah, we've done no wrong.
I think that's yeah,
that's the only future premonitions
anybody can ever have is one time
they're going to be right, though.
Yeah, maybe we can be right.
All right. Twenty thirty eight.
If you're listening to this in twenty
thirty eight and there's flying cars,
come into the discord
and tell us that we were right.
We finally did it.
Finally, finally did it.
Twenty thirty eight.
Yeah, which which brings me
to another fun point,
which Google reminded me is this
January, of course, celebrates
the anniversary of this
Dumbgeons and Dragons.
And we're in our
a ninth year.
So then next year is our tenth year.
So we got to plan something big.
Oh, damn.
For our tenth year of the show.
Oh, we got to start thinking about it.
And so do you guys.
I'll work time.
What do we got there?
Yeah, I don't.
I didn't look that far ahead.
I've just thought of the concept
of thinking of an idea, Tom.
So here's what we do.
We get together.
Everyone we've ever played with.
Oh, my God, that's a lot of people.
I know the boy.
And that's all I've got.
OK, Kyle.
And then we do what?
I'm sorry.
Actually, you know, you're good.
We have to write an entire like ten.
No, never mind, Tom, go.
OK, we fly.
Everyone we've ever played with
to five star resort in Hawaii
and we all hang out for a week.
Oh, I love it.
OK, so, yeah, my idea.
Yeah, your idea was work.
I'm always going to choose
vacation over work.
Always. Yeah.
Yeah, that's fair.
But you know what?
Also, I will always choose our listeners
over our non listeners.
Oh, yeah.
For listening to us
because the non listeners will never know.
They'll never know.
How could they know?
They can't know unless you tell them
to come listen and then through inception
or osmosis or some other
persuasion, threats,
any of the above, they'll become listeners
and then they'll know.
OK, what are we talking about here?
Well, I mean, that's the middle.
I think we've talked about it,
but what we haven't done
is dedicate it to one of our patrons.
Let's do it.
So today's episode, which you're
we would love for you to come join us
at Patreon dot com slash dumb dragging cast
where when you are a patron,
you get an episode dedicated to you
like today's patron, Les Wenzel.
Thanks, Les.
Oh, Les, thank you so much.
Amazing. Amazingly awesome.
In that.
Shout out from Loki.
Our dog.
Yeah, let's go.
But you can join us like Les again.
Patreon dot com slash dumb dragging cast.
Help us fund this Hawaii was a Hawaii trip.
Maybe it could not be Hawaii.
Maybe it could be.
Greece.
Oh, sure. All right.
Mecanos. Yes, here we go.
Mm hmm. There we go.
So see myself in Greece.
Help us fund this 10th anniversary,
something that we're going to do.
And you two can get an episode
dedicated to you, as well
as a whole bunch of other bonus content.
But that said, we'll get you back to the episode.
Thank you so much for being here.
Excited to be back for the new year.
Hopefully you are having a wonderful time
and we'll talk to you soon.
Love you. Bye.
We did it. Love you. Bye.
I. Thanks, guys.
Thanks, guys. I'm sorry.
I. Are you OK?
Yeah, I feel like I'm asking people,
are you OK?
Way too much.
Benj, where did this book come from?
I don't know.
I was I was working and
I mean, to be fair, it's he's not wrong.
It's not wrong.
I do and I'm sorry.
But like, I don't know.
I think it's just a crowd started started gathering.
And then I came out and then this this
stand was here with a book on top and.
Uh, I don't know where it came from.
It's been lots of lots of strange people in town.
Like like Alastair.
Yeah, Alastair, there was another guy
who left a book, a different book at the at the bar.
I thought he'd come back for it, but I haven't seen him since.
Do you have it?
Yeah, probably.
It's underneath the counter.
Lost and found.
I'll be right back.
We should look at that.
Yeah, you kind of push through some people.
Someone like takes a one last swing towards Benj
and before they're pulled away by one of the guards.
This is this is bad, guys.
This is it's good insight.
I've taken the book with me.
For sure.
We're in Benj's accent.
Do you get punched?
Did it get punched out of it?
I got punched out of it.
Now he's got a normal voice.
Why? It's only in the bar.
Somebody else punch him in his bench.
Yes. Oh, my God.
No, I've become a custom post.
Yeah, let's go inside.
I've got that book under the desk.
He lets you in and locks it behind you.
And I think we should close early for the night.
And he goes behind and pulls out.
Where did that book go?
Oh, you said it was under the counter.
In lost and found.
Lost and found. Yeah.
That's where it went.
He pulls out this slim leather bound journal.
There's no title on the cover.
He says, I don't know.
They left it a few nights ago.
If you want it, you can have it.
It gives customers the heebie jeebies.
Was it the sleepy guy?
No, no, Alistair, your friend?
Not Alistair? A different guy.
Different guy, yeah.
Okay.
What did he look like?
Yeah, he was kind of tallish.
A little bit taller than Bazaard.
He had a dark cloak, a long nose.
Like I only say that because it was unusually long.
I mean, it was a normal nose,
but it was kind of long.
Big bushy eyebrows.
Olive skin.
He looked like he was, I don't know,
kind of my age, which is like 30-ish.
80, oh, 30.
Yeah, no, 30-ish, maybe 40, maybe closer to 50.
He's an age.
He stopped in, had a couple drinks,
and then just, you know,
he had a couple different things with him,
met with somebody, and then left.
And this one, he left this one here.
I take the book, lay it on the counter, and open it up.
So you open the book, and all the pages,
it kind of flipped past a few,
just to kind of get to a center point,
and everything is blank.
And as you look at it,
words begin to scrawl themselves
in shaky ink handwriting, forming an entry.
That reads,
the maker dreams of chains that bind the waking world.
As you look back, you see that Alydin
has kind of like poked herself up and over,
and her eyes are locked onto the page as well.
The maker.
So there's this thing called the Weeping Archive.
Oh, right.
We haven't had a chance to explain
because of the book and the punching,
and Bench losing his accent.
Devastating.
Alistair told us about the Weeping Archive,
and he's looking for it, and it's like this,
I don't know, all the world's knowledge or something?
Okay, and where did this Alistair person come from,
and how did you end up talking to them?
Oh, great question.
Oh, we saved all of his stuff.
He fell asleep, and then.
He has narcolepsy, so he fell asleep,
his bag, everywhere.
I caught him, so he didn't get a head injury.
We started picking up all of his stuff,
and he is like a scribe, I guess, and.
A scholar of some kind.
He had a bag just chock full of books,
all kinds of books,
and he's looking for the Weeping Archive,
and then we thought, well, I don't know,
maybe that's a fun adventure we could go on,
but first let's go on this fun camping cosplay adventure
with the old guys,
and then the elk thing happened with Alydin.
I should probably get this taken care of.
Yeah, we should head, yeah.
Did I hear something about bleeding ink earlier?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So we were looking for a ghost elk, found it,
when it bled ink,
and also there was random pages all over the forest.
And the wind was saying stuff.
Yeah.
All of this is to say, my god, we missed you.
Oh, wait.
I have so many questions.
The archives.
Are meant to close the gap
that is being made bigger between our world
and the fae world.
Yeah, so it's kind of important maybe
that we go and help with that
because we need to stop all those super weird things
that have been happening.
Yeah.
Okay, Bizarre, you look back at the book
and there's another phrase that has written itself
since you've been talking,
and it says the wizard's spell book
is already on the shelf.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
I don't know if that's referring to me
or another wizard.
So I have a couple of things coming together
and it involves, now that we're here,
it involves the event I had the other night
that caused all these things.
So I don't know why,
but they kicked my ass and said,
stay out of the ink.
Oh.
And I don't know why they would say that,
but they're not,
I was expecting Kenny's people,
but they said Kenny's not the only one watching me.
Real bummer of it all is I did not get
the delicious prime rib from the other night.
Oh, the buffet.
Oh, it was so good.
Ah, that's where you were.
Uh-huh, bleeding.
The whole town was writing about it.
I'm so sorry.
Oh, I'll get it another time,
but did y'all happen to collect any of the ink blood?
Yes, and I hold up my bucket,
which is stuffed full of not only the regular accoutrement
that one holds in a bucket,
but also ripped pages of journals
and two vials of inky blood.
Oh, right, yes, and I do,
I have elk antlers that I'm just kind of dragging around
like a backpack at this point.
They're mine and they glow.
Sick.
Are you making them glow?
No.
Well, good, let's work on you then.
So yeah, if you let me see that ink real quick.
So I'm thinking of a few things,
and I'm pulling out a quill
while I'm prepping this ink
as if to use it for writing.
We've had a couple of very strange events.
The very first one being the monsters coming from the cave.
Perhaps this is part of the gap that's being referenced.
That could be a reference to that.
We have the maker still dreaming,
or the maker dreams of chaos
that binds the waking world.
Who's the last person that we know
tried to bring chaos and binding to the waking world?
Like the banjo man?
Yeah.
Yeah, we also, there was that entrance too,
like through the tree when we went to see the banjo man.
So there's some, there's a few options for.
Well, and Alistair said that it could be starting
to kind of happen anywhere.
Yeah.
And more often,
like people have been seeing some really weird stuff.
Yeah.
Like smoke in the shape of animals,
like teeny mushrooms that are grown on the food,
like lanterns. Candles.
Yeah, burning with no oil.
And, you know, looking in a mirror
and seeing like a forested background.
The river was singing.
Yeah.
So many weird things have been happening.
It's almost hard to keep track of it all, but.
I'm thinking though that nature talks a lot.
The river singing, then the wind whispering.
Bazaar, you would have seen a lot of these.
Bazaar, you would have seen a lot of these,
like town happenings,
like written in the Vintersmouth Gazette.
Okay.
Sorry if this has been answered and I'm forgetting it,
but why did you go kill a ghost elk?
Oh.
So Folin Verham, that nice older man who was my new client
and I was making all that stuff for him,
his other adventuring friends all came,
kind of a group of retirees out for an adventure,
you know, inexperienced, I would say.
And a couple of them and one of their, I don't know,
butlers said, you guys should come.
We're going to find this ghost elk,
you know, go out for a couple of days.
We thought it would be kind of nice, you know,
like kind of a camping trip.
And we were kind of testing them out because they were like,
why don't you come adventuring with us?
Yes, they invited us to go adventuring.
And we're like, well, let's see if we like this.
We didn't like it.
It was for boring reasons and then blood reasons.
Sport.
One of them like moved out of the way
and then I got hit by an elk.
Yeah.
Yeah, so we will not be going adventuring with them.
They're not even taking care of,
are not a child, but still a young person friend, Alydin.
So that's how we ended up out there having an adventure.
But we did not, we were just like,
we didn't go out to like kill anything.
No, no, no, we just wanted to see the ghost elk.
And it looked so cool.
It did look so cool.
But then it looked at us and like, we weren't cool.
And then it's antlers were dripping
like black blood ink stuff.
And then it just lost it.
It lost it.
As they're telling me this,
I dip the quill into the blood ink
and I write into the book, who are you?
As the ink touches the paper,
like you get to the end of the phrase
and the ink behind it begins to smear across the paper.
And then it begins to form entangled glyphs.
There's definite familiarity to a lot
of like the glyphs and runes that you've seen
over these last events that you've been talking about.
In the hood?
In the hood.
In the hood, in the hood?
Yeah.
Yeah, there definitely are some similarities
to the one, there are some similarities
to some of the ones you saw in the hoods,
but definitely more so in the fey.
Like the ones you saw written across the path
and that sort of thing.
It forms into these tangled glyphs.
You don't know what they're saying.
What they're saying.
But there's something trying to communicate back.
Appears that way or may appear that way.
And as it does so,
you pick up a faint smell of burnt parchment.
Can I like see what he's writing?
I'm not hiding it yet, it's open on the counter.
What if you drew a picture?
I spin the book around and hand you the pen.
Art, art with tallies thing.
And I draw very crude sketches
of like a deer's head with antlers
and then a question mark beside it.
And then a happy face with a question mark
or a sad face with a question mark.
Because how do you communicate with someone
who doesn't speak the same language as you?
I mean math, I guess.
But I don't know math.
I didn't have a lot of schooling.
Exactly.
So, hence these pictures.
There were no art classes.
Yeah, so you draw pictures of the deer or the elk,
I assume is what you're reflecting.
Happy, sad and similar,
same thing as with Bazaar.
Like the ink smears itself behind you
as you are writing it.
And instead of what did,
I mean you couldn't read it,
but what did look like it was maybe writing a phrase.
Like it draws this circle
that is made up of tiny runes,
tiny glyphs that go all around this circle.
Then they smear to form this doorway
that opens into blackness.
I have, and I'm searching through my bucket frantically
for a piece of paper and I read,
the archivist will fall asleep and dreams the door open.
At that, you hear a fast knock at the window.
And Bench looks over top of everybody.
He's just been kind of standing there.
He served you drinks and like just kind of standing there
watching everything happen.
But looks over at the window
and he points before anybody turns around.
He says, that's your friend from the other night?
You turn and you look and you see Alistair
and he's like waving.
I'm already running so I can catch him if I need to.
Yeah, before you can even get there,
like his eyes roll back and he falls to the ground.
Oh, speak of the devil.
I really tried.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season four, episode 44,
starring Amy More as Alydin.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane.
Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave.
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design
of today's episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babiak.
Music is from Epidemic Sound
and sound effects are from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babiak,
Ongarong Kierzen, Perry Matey,
Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss,
L.A. Branton, Chibs1012 and Kudzu828.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast
and all of our amazing community help make sure
that we have adventures for you every single week.
Come join us today, patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
We hope to see you over there
and you have yourself right now a great week.
Yes, and we'll talk to you very, very soon.
Do we see him?
Yeah.
Okay, we see him.
He doesn't see us.
Correct, yes.
Sorry, my brain just reversed that.
Nobody sees anybody.
You're all blind.
We all just stand around not looking at each other.
Perfect.
Masturbation does cause blindness.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.