Thanks for your patience, Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
The four of you find yourselves at the bottom of the stairs and behind you extending down
the hallway that seemingly never ended there is a golden window that opens and it glows and you
feel a cool breeze come from it and then on the other side the front door to the house
crashes open and the banjo man staggers in cords fracturing and splintering light coming off of
his banjo and he drops to one knee and you hear this cracking his bone crunching sinew pulling
emanating through the space wings sprout from his back and his legs and arms extend into these
long hideous claws and he looks up at you with these dark sunken black eyes
i can't remember what he said fuck you guys i thought for sure when you said he dropped to
one knee we're gonna say like busted out a crazy guitar solo or a banjo solo i mean he's
proposing oh my god this is so unexpected it was all set up he was gonna propose to that
piano to the piano no oh no oh well he's gonna kill us for sure then definitely in his heart he
is the piano man um he's a fanfic uh side story banjo man and piano banjo man is just Billy Joel
this isn't the narration part it's fine oh oh god i mean in my defense you stopped
to do something else so i felt like i could yeah that's why i can't jump in
he looks up at you and with this raspy voice that it sounds nothing like the person that had
come before you says no the song's not over yet and he strums with his hideously long
fingers and the walls begin to peel and fall to the ground and everything beneath you begins
to shake what do you do Alydin immediately grabs on to bazaar and is like all the all the bravado
all the facade of the like i'm a grown up like like i'm 14 like you guys come on i've been
living by myself taking care of kids for like i don't know how many years because time means
nothing to me because i'm a child all that has been dropped and she is just a scared kid like
the fuck is happening right now yeah bazaar's just like standing there like ready for whatever
the fuck's gonna happen as Alydin's climbing up and just kind of like i don't know what
happens like he's like protector feels emboldened he's ready to go he's spent on
spell slots you get an inspiration point he's got nothing in the tank wait a minute he's
ready remember when we used to do that guys i've got two first level spell slots
everything else was spent oh my god should we just jump in the portal is this gonna be my origin
story is my father figure gonna die don't you die on me i'm not gonna try but i make no promises
don't kill my fake dad i asked what you do
you know what we're not asking him enough questions you guys there
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dnd actual play podcast and i'm your dungeon master russ more he him also
with me today is amy more as Alydin she her because obviously i should be the one to go
first carla Maxted is Bonwyn everbane she her my weapons are ready tom laird is
Kavlaranan gold weave he him and i'm like frantically waving them to come through and
kyle Claset is Bizard the Wizard he him russ with a nip slip dungeon the dragons is a Patreon
supported podcast you can join us today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where
you'll get access to hangouts backstage access recordings a whole lot of extra episodes and
we know you love those so come come give it a try plus when you sign up before the end
of april 2025 you're going to save 25 off your first month or your first year 25 off your first
full year is a pretty great deal if i don't say so myself Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast we
hope to see you over there and now fuck it let's play still just scrolling through as if
there's going to be more on my character sheet like no dog you're level two there's
nothing else on there that's all you got it's real short sheet it's really short sheet as
you're all hesitating like what am i gonna do ready in action with a dagger like come on
yeah like i'll grip my shield i guess yeah my weapons are ready can we see the banjo man yes
yeah sorry yeah he's like him in the front door morphing into this fae creature in front
of the portals behind us right like we're those are the two ends of the hallway the
portal yeah everything else is crumbling and collapsing down how far away from us is he
uh i 20 feet 25 feet tops beautiful i just every time i imagine stairs and an entryway they're
always very close together so like if we're just clumped to the bottom of the stairs like we're
very close well then as Alydin stands like hops on my shoulders i'm gonna just cast bane
i would like to just clarify you like clamored up on top of me like god on my back or something
no i clung to you like oh i don't know that's not the way that bazaar's telling it like a protect
me fake daddy i know that i would just be slowing you down you'd be i'd be dead weight on you
well i want you to actually protect me as as you come to me i fucking cast bane at this so i
need a charisma savings throw dc13 a disadvantage because he's gross now yeah he's disgusting
okay he doesn't have a nice voice anymore he's yucky so that's a 26 sure like enough
even in this form he doesn't lose any of his charisma even with the disadvantage carla called
for what about just the display of pure love that's happening right now what about that
that's nothing what about that all right disadvantage that's uh 92 that's a 92 no that's
a 22 damn i guess all right then hey i appreciate you all trying so what uh what happens oh nothing
because as you passed uh so as what does it look like as you pass as i cast the spell uh three
rays go out uh two of them disperse into nothing one focuses on him and creates a swirling
mass of purple clouds around him in the shape of a skull they just kind of like little
skull pieces floating around them uh you know but they just they dissipate very quickly yeah no he
like swats them away and then digs his long claws into the wooden floor beneath you and it's
like it's pulling the floor that you're standing on closer to him can i shoot a flaming arrow at
that floor oh fire has been my solution and it's been working i love it it's literally all i have
sure i'm not gonna i'm not gonna try and dagger him up in close combat i want to stay further away
so arrow and he's like pulling us closer like like he's turning the floor into kindling so i
feel like yeah sure uh yeah you shoot you light an arrow everything's on fire and falling
apart besides you so you yeah you shoot an arrow um you don't have to roll to hit the floor
you you hit the floor uh what are you hoping happens when you hit that it lights on fire and
slows him down oh yeah okay well you shoot an arrow into the floor and it definitely lights on
fire um and he continues to pull you so now he's pulling us into the fire i just lit
i'm sure you were gonna say and it makes him stronger yeah i mean basically but he's made us
low low low that's correct yeah yeah exactly and as that happens Alydin you're uh you're
you're clung to bizarre but you feel that cool breeze on the back of your neck again
uh i i tug on bizarre cloak i say we should go that way okay if we can back out let's back out
uh i'll start backing up okay disengage uh well yeah you're you're you're like 20 feet away
right so we're not quite engaged yet okay and if we're like walking backwards yeah on this
he did drop to a knee though yeah true yeah i'm happy to back up you're backing up towards the
glowing window behind you and uh you see him stand up now and like he's like getting ready
to launch himself towards you you're within 10 15 feet tops of this window i mean i guess
i'm going through it because i what am i gonna do i know that thing's gonna kill me y'all go out
the window i'm gonna pull out a bag and i'm gonna loose a string on it and when he lunges
at me i'm gonna throw it in his face i'm so excited just you let me know when he lunges
i'm throwing that little baggy i'll tell you what it is uh okay so bizarre's giving you uh the
cover ask to go do the three of you go i'm going going okay so the three of you oh no
okay so she's scared she's not gonna leave the one person who she relies on rude one person
came here to save you plan uh bond went in there cav you turn and you start running for
this window and the closer you get to it the clearer uh the picture beyond looks and it is
of the clearing uh where you first encountered the the pathway through to the fate to where
you are right now um like that is clear to you and then as you're as you get to it you turn
and you look and Bonwyn is still at bizarre and bizarre you see this this the banjo man now he
digs his claws in and like launches himself and these wings extend which cut through the walls
all around him um and he's flying towards you now cool yeah i'm gonna throw that bag
i'm saying magical flying pocket sand and i'm throwing a bag of sand in his face
so you're throwing uh is it it's a literal bag of sand or it's a literal it's a literal bag of sand
okay uh yeah just a small bag of sand typically found in a scholar's pack okay um well uh roll
to hit deck stick but you know well it probably hurts his eyes i would assume yeah
uh all right come on come on uh the arranged attack yeah oh that's going to be an 18 okay non-proficient
i assume so i'm not adding my proficiency proficiency excellent well i don't know how much
you practice the dance kind of move i mean you went to a school of fighting and dance
well if that's the case then let's make it a 22 all right let's make it a 22 all right
let's make it a 22 all right let's make it a 22 let's make it a 22 all right let's make it a
well if that's the case then let's make it a 22 all right um the the pocket sand flies out and
like disperses in the air and gets caught on these waves of wind that you see hit into his
face and give enough that he like has to shake his head um and like veers into the wall
crashing into it wood splintering and shooting out towards you that's when you look down and
see that well Bonwyn and cav are gone but Alydin is stuck beside you was that magic sand
no run like uh and i'm going to just like move my way out like take advantage of it
now that this guy's like veered into the freaking wall uh and be like let's go and
help Alydin out the window yeah you run the two of you run and uh Bonwyn and cav
you're looking back seeing them coming which gives you the the enough to start walking through
or climbing through this window um oh we haven't gone through yet they're like we're actually like
this is all happening in that case i'd like to like field i'd like to hold like my hand up
against the top of it like i'm holding it open and i'm like frantically waving them to
come through okay you don't know if it'll close i think that's a great idea it might slice
me in half i have no idea we're new like we don't know anything about magic
uh i gotta hold the window open bizarre you look back over your shoulder and you see
the banjo man now like climbing across the walls and up on the roof gaining on you as you
and Alydin launch through the window cav your last through you're holding the window open as
you see he's within 10 feet now like he's closing fast um anything you do obviously aside
from jump through the window uh no i'm gonna like jump through the window and like roll
to the side as soon as i get through there because like if he's coming through after me
i don't want to be in the path okay um as you go through you're the last one to go
through everybody tumbles out into this clearing and the window behind you slams shut
yes i knew i was holding it open
and it like sucks into the air and poofs away
and you all are listening for a moment and it's quiet there's a cool breeze and you all stand
up and as you do you look around and it is the clearing where the children first were
thought to have gone missing and then after a quick moment before you have a chance really to
to collect yourself completely the clearing shudders before you the trees begin to wilt
and twist their branches form gnarled hands grasping at the sky
and across the clearing you see the large tree that well um Alydin and Bonwyn you didn't really
get a chance to see this tree but Bizard and cav you ran through it of your own free will
and volition you see this tree and you see the gnarled hands of the banjo man pulling
the banjo man pulling himself through and into the space he's doubled over and clutching his
head and his banjo is slipping from his fingers the world around you tears apart like paper
revealing a void of endless music notes suspended in blackness you hear faint whispers
and sorrowful hums that fill the air as the banjo man lifts his head his grin or anything of
it is gone his face hollow and carved with endless cracks in his eyes those same black
voids filled with flickering burning music notes his voice is no longer mocking no longer
playing a game it's raw broken and deeply terribly human i didn't want this i only
wanted to fix what was lost to play it back note by note until it all made sense again
Alydin the music box that you held in your hand suddenly stops playing for the first
time since you've been in this place
but you and he looks at you you ruined the song you brought back the silence
the moment he says that you're all hit with a wave of a memory but it's not your own
it's a memory of his here comes the narration i hadn't begun already
well wait you've been talking i'm ready you've been muted sorry sorry my nash came through
wrong game kyle yeah i know it's hard to keep most of the world around you flickers
not with light but sound you see a dim tavern a young man alone plucking a banjo with trembling
fingers this is the face of calder bramble no crowd no applause just a desperate song
echoing off empty walls begging to be heard then you feel a presence shadows in this space
stretch a voice unseen whispers let your music never end all i ask is you never stop playing
me there's a long moment and calder hesitates but then nods and suddenly the song changes
notes spill like black water twisting the room and staining the air laughter children's laughter
faint and layered trapped beneath the melody calder's hands move without him
you see him try to stop but he can't his name fades and his body warps flesh into strings
voice into chorus where calder once knelt the banjo man as you have seen him rises
yes if i stop playing he says we all vanish then the vision ends
and the silence that follows feels wrong and cold like something is missing
and as the final notes of the memory reverberate through your minds this crushing
silence falls over the space you see images of the false house the bedroom the picket fence
the comforting illusion it shatters like glass around you breaking away into Glimering shards
that vanish into an endless void the world around you begins to fall apart you stand
now in a fractured dreamscape suspended in nothingness floating islands of memories drift
around you see the stables and everbanes the magic closet each fragment hangs weightless and
disconnected and fading and then you hear a single banjo note cuts through the void
so the banjo man stands at the center of this unraveling reality his form splintering like
an overplayed chord his limbs twitch with unnatural rhythm his smile forced wide by invisible
strings i gave them joy i gave them peace i gave them forever he growls voice hollow
overlapping with laughter and the cries of stolen children but you you wouldn't let it end
let them be forgotten with a screeching strum he pulls twisted echoes from his strings
shadowy figures begin to step into view distorted echoes of toys and instruments
born not of delight but of desperation they crawl fly and skitter across the floating islands
towards you snarling through melodies that pierce your thoughts like daggers beneath it all
a music box rests atop a floating stone dais its lid closed humming faintly you feel it
calling Alydin you look down and the music box in your hand is gone
it pulses in rhythm with the banjo man's playing a counterpoint a way to end the song
but the ground beneath your feet is vanishing every few heartbeats another memory island
trembles and crumbles into the void dragging whatever stands upon it down with you
the final verse has begun everything begins to move and shift in the space around you
what do you do i mean i think we have to smash that box bizarre what do we do should i send a
flaming arrow at it seems seems to be the the right thought uh you know if that music box
played such an element to have disappeared from your grasp Alydin then i'd say let's make that
stop playing i tried to break this thing so many times well we're going to try again we're
going to fail forward and this time we are going to break it welcome to the middle everybody
thanks for being here uh in this epic climactic battle with the banjo man
so much battling so much banjo a lot of battling it's not even this is like
the beginning of what is going to be a triumphant conclusion to this arc that's
maybe maybe tbd tbd yeah it's good times all around though that's what it is all hope
yeah everything is just usually on fire so if it's not on fire it could be that's our new
strategy right yeah yeah it's potential fire waiting to happen you have to ask yourself why
why is it not already on fire Bonwyn's in the scene why is this everything on the dance floor
if it could burn why isn't it yeah everything everything um you know where we have great fire
sales going on oh my god where's that it's Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where you
can till the end of the month still get 25 off your first month or your first year when
you sign up that's still going that's still going that's a great deal april a plus transition
thank you thank you yeah uh yeah till april 30th 2025 in case you're listening to this in the
very far future we'll probably have another sale going on so keep an eye out for them but uh
for now you can go do that and then when you are a patron you get an episode dedicated to
you i had wrote it down but the page is gone like today's patron shay talison
thank you shay we appreciate you that's right jess in the producer booth dancing for shay
absolutely what's going on yeah we never mentioned we dance all the time yeah all for
shay yeah you got it um speaking of the producer booth when you join us uh you can come
hang out with hang out with us in the in the backstage of the episodes yeah that's true all
the shenanigans it's a great time you get to see them before they happen and because the
schedule's set up so that like if you're if you're you know like not currently caught up
you could wait until the next rotation of dumgeon's episodes because by then all of the
episodes that we've just recorded will come out so you'll always be caught up or ahead oh but
never behind and you know what's great about it is technically you get two different versions
of the dungeon's episodes that you listen to because you get just like the experience and
then you get the raw uncut yeah yeah exactly and then you get that produced polished uh
sheen that ross and carla put on it so you know like treat yourself twice that's right
i'll rest now i do nothing but you should still treat yourself carla's done a lot for the last two
seasons uh uh but yeah no we're doing a great we're doing a great time over there that's not
a saying yeah no we're doing a great time over there we have good fun yes yeah join us and
you can too at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and now get back to the episode you crazy
kids yeah get out of here get out of here love you bye
these horrors that have come out of the darkness their hands grasp onto the
the platform that you are on and pull themselves up and let out this scream at you
you that's roll for initiative
also just an fyi if you're ever like doing a project and you hear a disembodied voice offer
you some sort of deal that's too good to be true just turn it down yeah yeah yeah like
what the fuck i feel like we all learned a valuable lesson here today i think so i feel
like this was a him problem that he's making it an us problem
didn't ask for this i didn't ask for this he did he could have said no i got an 11 15
numero tenno
18 hell yeah because obviously i should be the one you have the most experience with
not destroying the music box yes i could show you all the things not all the things that
do not work you tell us all the things not okay so i did this and then i did that smash it
we tell him to hold on we pull out a little like you know chalkboard like okay this
okay and you pulled it apart you did okay um can't throw it at the window smashing it on
the ground did you try that i tried smashing it against a window did you try winding it up so
much that the that it broke the coil yeah and i tried riding it backwards because now you like
to do your thing you know how you can do it like and then unscrew the little pin actually i don't
know if i tried that what if i took the pin there are creepy things around it we just got
to make them eat it shut down it's fucked up kyle i love it yeah i said that just for you
i appreciate it
okay Alydin you are up first before you take your turn though
the banjo man strums a chord and the space around you as as all of these memories are
moving like they're moving through the space and you're moving on them so they um this is
i was like i tried to put together a map but like everything's fucking moving around you so
wasn't gonna happen um the dais itself is on its own like stone pedestal
that is moving through space so well so we're all like on separate asteroids
you're all on separate asteroids that are like moving in three dimensions like
around exactly cool are the four of us on separate are we on one together you are all
on one and the music box is on one it's on one there and then there are like memories there's
places so you see all of these places from Vintersmouth and from the the uh the experience
that you've all just collectively been through together yeah now universal between it is this
black void and as he lets out this strum this black void begins to fill with these um glowing
music notes that as like they bump into things they make a musical note like anybody who has any
musicality to them is able to tell like these are you know c goes over here g and sharp you
know all of that's happening around you so like this dissonant echoing vibration begins to fill
the space and they're like they appear there's a lot of them and then they kind of tone back
and they just begin floating around take that for what it's worth put that in your pipe and
smoke it take this dreamscape that i've made your decision amy you okay so in moving through
this space it's probably going to be very difficult for us to like put a location to
things so is everything a disadvantage everything is moving every everything is awesome when
you're part of a team in order to you have to like call where you want to go
if you're trying to move location or if you're trying to affect the the platform that you are
on in some way um so then there's going to be a role to succeed on getting to a place and
then whatever action you want to do once you get there it will likely take based on your
position now like three move actions to be able to get to the stone die so you'd have to like
get to another location and like propel yourself or cause something to move you forward
just say you want to do something we'll figure it out i want to get to the music
well i'm probably not going to move away from the adults i have i have a 13 ac
d and only five more hit points than that so you're talking riddles
oh i think uh Alydin knows what she's good at and it's talking so uh she's gonna like
i don't know so open up some dialogue here she's never had the opportunity to talk to
anyone except for the non-parent parents who didn't really give her much so she's she's gonna
she's gonna go ahead with her with her background of solving conflict and problems between
uh the children that she was caring for on the streets uh
uh your name is calder right your voice echoes out into the space and like you
you see it materialize before you and it like slams into these music notes with
which push these different platforms further away from you it makes its way towards him
and he turns his head he doesn't doesn't respond except for that that small acknowledgement
my name is Alydin you're colder right you know you don't have to do this you know
he lets out another strum on his banjo and this
this stone chair begins to like come up from underneath him and these strings come down from
this ethereal place above him and attach themselves to his arms and legs and they begin
strumming the song and his smile gets wider and is pulled up by these strings
i don't think you're like this we can help you is this landing at all
anything else you'd like to do uh i saw the notes from my voice push
the other floaty thingies right this is really hard to talk about my child brain is just going
to because we are so we we're on our floating situation yeah um is there anything in the path
between us and the box or is it just like black void except for yeah like occasionally
a memory passes by kind of thing um just my child brain uh also amy's brain i i see well i see that
my voice does something so i i turn around to look like toward the back of like behind us
and i just i let out a yell and i want to see if it propels us forward okay you know maybe
it's like water uh seems reasonable okay yeah see thank you seems reasonable aren't trying to
you're just trying to test the theory that this yeah i'm wondering if i'm trying to direct
yourself somewhere but i'm just trying to see like can i use sound to push us on our platform
uh yeah then you do that and as you're like shaking your head back and forth the platform
beneath you and everybody else feels it like you are you are quickly moved through this space
and you crash into another one of these memories which shatters and falls and disperses into the
black void whoa i'm sorry i'm sorry i'm sorry i'm sorry and i just like kind of like whoop
like like when you break something out of story just kind of wait what the
fuck did i have for breakfast that's the memory
it's been so long uh pop tarts bonway well i think i'm just going to do what i said and
try to light an arrow on fire and shoot it at the music love it let's do it 19 shoots off and uh 19
you you see it like hit right beside the box which causes the whole platform to like shift
backwards and rock in space and the arrow skids and it gets lost into the darkness behind it
we just see it falling yeah falling till it well i mean that's all i got guys i don't know
i don't know what else to do in front of you these horrific creatures pull themselves up
and there's these two marionettes that uh that rush over to oh god are they kids
she shrug yep i mean aren't all yeah i did isn't every marionette someone's child carla
well but earlier they were kids right yeah yeah okay those were mannequins these are marionettes
yeah those were mannequins okay i'm gonna tell myself these aren't yeah so they are hollow
wooden dolls with violin bows for arms and they come swinging and slashing so there's two of
them at this point one's going to come at Bonwyn and one is going to come at bizarre
uh Bonwyn that's going to be a 14 to hit do it bizarre that's going to be a 16 to hit
a 16 will hit okay this dice uh that's going to be four slashing damage okay cool you feel it
cut into your leg as these two things look up at you and just let out this like hideous laugh
and then like into the darkness yeah bizarre your turn cool um
all right then this box needs to get fucked so i'm going to use my fei touched ability
as a varying human to do misty step over to the box uh okay hold on i gotta find my magic
oh shit oh no you said it it's good i didn't say it hey you know what it's worth it's worth
the gamble roll a uh so you're doing misty step which doesn't require a roll right like
no no it you do uh okay so roll a d100 please okay come on unicorn 33 oh my god please not
another unicorn it's a random uh generator right yeah okay great uh so you go to cast misty step
uh do you like take a running jump at it or is it just like no no it's just like a
okay great uh so instead of that um where you were intending to go which was like right
essentially right beside or as close to as you can get um instead of you just just
just apparating and uh reappearing over there uh you see this tiny squirrel like creature that
appears beside the box um it's got these long like super long sharp teeth and these huge ears
with tufts on the end and this massively bushy tail um and it it's tough to see from this
distance exactly but it looks um like it's stuffing um what appears to be pockets full
of acorns and then it looks around at the space and like zips off the edge and falls
into the blackness i thought it might chew up the box i thought maybe we had a good ally
over there yeah okay i don't well Alydin is like this is upsetting this is upsetting
why didn't that work damn it i wouldn't name it in buster
fuck it that's my bonus action so i'll take my action to i'm just gonna cast frost
nope it's not an object so i can't do a con save has to be against a creature so
so can the box do a con save box cannot do a con save no the shadowy creatures moving
through the space could uh banjo man obviously could yeah yeah we'll do it i'll keep banjo man's
actually no like Alydin's trying to do something so i'm gonna stick with the box and i'm gonna
cast i'm gonna cast magic missile on the box
so three 1d4s you said you had nothing left this is the last thing oh shit oh and all
fours hell yeah let's go so that's 15 force damage to the box okay rest looks happy i
don't like that yeah that's magic missiles fly through the air and all of them strike
with precision on top of the box and you hear just this resonant echoing laughter come from
the banjo man and he looks down at you and says you haven't figured it out yet you're going to
fall and perish here and the silence will take control of you and as the dust clears over the
the box it's been knocked off the dais but it's still spinning and you can hear
the sound of the song um Alydin make a um death saving throw
a perception or an insight check you know what i don't want to do either of those Alydin just
starts singing this little light of mine i'm gonna let it shine i'm sorry a perception or
insight oh jesus let's see perception insight what about an inception how about a 19 with plus
zero okay we'll take it amazing roll thank you very much so as this strikes and you hear more
of these music notes like slamming into things and you hear him laugh you um you remember
something it is the music box you remember it from my bedroom your bedroom you know
your bedroom that's what i think of it now is it's my bedroom but something about it
strikes you the banjo man's power he wants this song to continue and you've listened to this
song every moment that you've spent awake asleep it's resonated for you this song doesn't end
but all songs must end unless it's the song that never ends does it just go on and on doesn't
end don't get me started yeah something about the music notes in the space as they
they clink into and the sound of the song playing and echoing throughout this endless void
triggers something that maybe the two are connected
cab it's your turn all right i get out my bluetooth speaker we've got it hooked up to
spot nice um and what do you put on starts playing this little
i get out the lighter um so we're like as you said three turns away from this thing essentially
by whatever means it takes to get us there yeah yeah have we figured out how to like
propel ourselves forward uh Alydin has shown i've crashed like the screen did a thing
has shown sound has moved you through the space okay um has propelled you um like things are
floating in space nobody's tried like leaping or jumping yet so they think that is an unknown
but there is you know Alydins move you into something else but uh did shatter the mammary
memory
i thought it was don't kill my fake daddy but it's going to be don't kill my fake daddy
parentheses nip slip yes if that doesn't draw listeners in i don't know what are we even doing
here
Dumbgeons and Dragons season four episode 23 starring Amy More as Alydin carla max dead as
Bonwyn everbane tom laird as Kavlaran in gold weave kyle Claset as bizarred the wizard
and Russ More as your dungeon master dialogue editing and sound design of today's episode is
by Russ More our community manager is jessica babyuk music is from epidemic sound and sound
effects are from epidemic sound and boom library our amazing cover art is by matt garbutt and
we'd like to say a huge thank you to our supporting producers including gabriel lynch
jessica babyuk cat water flame jacob madden augur on kiersen perry matey old school gamer d
craig zeiss and la branton we'd love for you to join us over on Patreon at Patreon.com
dumb dragon cast and when you sign up by april 30th 2025 you're going to save 25 off your
first month or your first year that's huge bonus episodes hangouts backstage access we've got it
all over there so we hope to see you over there okay you have a great week we'll talk
to you soon Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production