Today's episode will start in just a moment. Go grab a snack. Hurry, hurry.
If something rounds that corner, I'm readying a Frostbite spell.
So you would have like gone, you would have hit. So as as you're being pulled back in,
everybody now hears more movement from within this cavern. All of you see this light extending
up into the roof. And often to the left and right you hear scratching and you hear climbing
and you unless you make another move, it's not long before you see one of these creatures
rush past the cavern. They don't rush down the cavern, but like you see a silhouette of
them against this light run to from right to left. Oh, yeah, we found them. That's
this is them. Yep. And that big light looks like however they're getting in. So I think
that our goal is to close that up. Okay. How do we do that? Yeah, how do we do that? How does
good question? How does one close a rift in time and space? This wasn't covered in any
of the modules. Excellent question. We're going to learn through experience.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast. And I'm your Dungeon Master Russ
Moore, he him also with me today. Tom Laird is Kavlaranan Goldweave, he him. That's right,
a whopping two. Kyle Claset is Bizard the Wizard, he him. Let's go clear our names,
Cav, because we did this with special guests from I Seduce the Dragon, Christina Van Epps
as Penance Olive Tree, she her hazard fee. Absolutely. And Ryan Keeley, she her as
Bond and Cove, he him for wisdom damage. Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast and
you can join us today at Patreon.com slash Tom Dragon cast. There's a seven day free
trial and a whole bunch of episodes for you to listen to. We hope to see you over there.
And now fuck it. Let's play. Another question is, who could have caused that rift to
happen? It's a great question. Great question. Above my pay grade. Did they file a permit with
the city? I would guess not. I don't think we have anything for magical portals, but
we'll see. You really should. I feel like it could destabilize some important infrastructure.
Yeah, that's a good point. You know what, I'll bring that up. I'll bring that up with Oak
as soon as I see him next time. Next town hall meeting, you should really check. Yeah.
Yeah. 100%. As you say that one of them comes around the corner and you see the
Kavlaranan and Bizard, you see the glowing red throat of this creature again, which you know
is not a great thing. You see it come around and these beady red eyes and teeth and this
one doesn't have the same tusks that you saw on the ones previous. And it looks like it's
preparing to let a howl go straight down this corridor at you. As far as what you three,
Bench, Bizard and Kav have known of these creatures. Let's roll for initiative.
Oh, not 20, bitches. Not fucking 20, which means that is a 22.
Nice. Speedy little guy. Young blood.
Okay, so Bondin 22 pennants. 12. Kav. 7. Beautiful. Olds. Fresh. Fresh and naive. Bizard. 16.
Keep up, dance boy. That's right. Got to be quick. Great. Cool. Love it. Bondin,
you get to go first. I am going to go through, go for the throat with my quarter staff.
That's great. Roll to hit. That's a 17 unnatural. Yeah, 17 is going to hit. That's going to be
eight bludgeoning damage. Okay. Now with your monk abilities, are your attacks magical?
They shouldn't be yet. I don't think you get that at level three. No, I was going to,
but I am going to do a bonus action, which is magical. It's not magic because it's your
astral self. You do get, your strikes are not considered magic for the purpose of
overcoming resistance until a higher level. Got it. Okay. For example, I mean, not saying
that there's resistance or anything, but you know. But just like maybe.
Subpoenaed questions are being asked. Okay, so you're going, sorry, you're going in
striking the throat. You do so and like it, it's hitting. With my quarter staff.
With your quarter staff. Yeah, like it's, it's hitting like tough leather.
It is a beefy creature that you're coming up against. And these creatures are large
fiends. As you run up, they tower over. Good thing I got a sweet quarter staff.
And then I would like to use my bonus action. Actually, should I just do an unarmed strike?
So you got a couple of options for your bonus action. So you can summon. I'm thinking of
saving the, yeah. Summon your arm, saving your arms. It lasts for 10 minutes.
Oh, okay. So then I am going to want to sense, but, and then I want to spend a key point
to fuel my arms of the astral self. It's not giving me an option to roll to hit.
It's only giving me an option for damage. Yeah. You will, you, you're summoning them
right now. So you use your action to attack and your bonus action is going to be to summon
the arms. So on your next turn, you'll be able to hit with them. Hell yeah. Yeah.
Then we will go to Bizarre. I am going to draw my sword and begin doing the steps
that I learned through my schooling to begin my blade song. And as my,
that'll be my bonus action. And as my action, I am going to cast, I'm going to
cast magic missile on it, sending out three bolts of force damage. And that will be
for 10 force damage. That's three bolts. Just kind of fire out. It's pretty cool. Perfect.
So those zip over top of everybody. And, uh, Bond and you see these explosions like happen
like right over top of you into this creature, which knocks it back. Um,
and then in your closest, you see that, uh, that glowing throat begin to
blow a little less with these hits. Brings us to penance. Does it still look like it's charging
up to some kind of scream? Like it's, it's still getting ready to howl. It looks like it was
perhaps interrupted at this moment. Okay. Not that it won't try, but it doesn't look like
it's actively able to on its turn. Got it. So then I will hold back on one thing. I'm
going to, um, once again, gripping tight to my holy symbol. I'm going to start to
mutter a prayer in celestial and I'm going to use my Twilight sanctuary.
So, um, channeling divinity, a, a sphere of dim Twilight light emanates from me
to surround an area of a 30 foot radius. Everybody gets seven temporary hit points.
Sick. Oh, hell yeah. And you cannot be charmed or frightened. Sick. That's awesome. Nice.
So long as you are within my sphere, uh, which is of dim light, but that doesn't bother you
right now because you can see through it. So we're all good to go. Um, so that is what I do
for my action. And then as a bonus action, I am going to cast spiritual weapon. Oh, hell
yeah. So I will raise my other hand. I've got one hand gripping my, my holy symbol,
and I raised my other hand and a, uh, it looks like a axe, except for like the,
the face of the axis, like several spikes. It's sort of like, if my holy symbol is like half
of a many pointed star or is a full many points are the axis half of it where it's just like
spikes coming out of a handle. Um, and that will raise up and slam down on top of this
creature. Excellent. Okay. You got, uh, wait, Russ, did you say excellent?
I believe that is correct. Yes. I believe that's what I said. Yes.
Uh, I'm actually, no, no, I, I rolled the natural one on that. So I'm going to use a
lucky, I'm going to burn one of my luck, uh, to not fail that all the stops because it
was a cool move and I don't want to be, I don't want to absolutely beef it. That's a 17 to hit
on the second go. 17. Also I'd be very unimpressed. Yeah. You lose a lot of confidence
from, uh, this acolyte over here. I do that whole cool intro thing. And then something I
just whiffed totally that would suck. Uh, eight damage from my spiritual weapon.
Magic missiles bludgeon in. And then this weapon comes down on top and it is the first
weapon that actually pierces the skin, um, of this creature. So blood begins to pour out around that
hit. What color is it? It is a deep red bordering on black blood. Ooh. Yeah. Okay. Yeah. Right.
Fondant doesn't like this. Fondant, it's really grossed out.
Cav, you're up. Going to, uh, raise, um, his hammer in the air and call down a sacred flame
upon this, uh, this beastie. What does that look like? And what do I got to do? Uh,
you have to make a dexterity saving throw. Perfect. Of an undetermined amount until you
tell me what it is. Then I'll tell you if you pass or fail. Uh, it's like a, it's like a very
bright white light that, uh, that comes down. Awesome. Uh, that's going to be, uh, that's a
nine. Uh, you have failed good, sir. Darn. You get nothing. You, uh, will take two radiant
damage. That's right. A whopping two. Oh snap. I'll take it all. Fondant's very impressed.
Bench's turn and Bench is standing at the back with his, uh, dagger and bread knife in hand and
saying, you just let me know when it's time to throw the picnic basket. Okay. I will, uh, uh,
I'm just going to hold in the fort here. Uh, he, he hesitates for a moment and then he's
like, ah, well, I'm just going to, I'm just going to throw it. And he throws the dagger
and it goes wide and skids into the room. He's like, ah, sorry, guys. Um, uh, big muscles. I don't,
I don't know my strength at the, at this time. I'm going to stop now and, uh, uh, let, uh,
let you all take over. Uh, he just cowishly walks back and is like, I'll just be here. You
let me know when we got to, uh, make a sandwich. Sorry. Fondant back to the top.
Poor Bench. I'd like a ham and cheese. And then I hit him with my quarter staff again,
or at least I attempt to with my throat with, uh, hit him in the throat with my quarter staff.
Ham and cheese coming up. Well, 12 will not, uh, uh, no, no, a 12 isn't going to hit. Um,
so like you're close enough that you're going to hit it, but like the natural armor of it,
like you don't do any damage for that. Okay. And then so my arms of astral self, 17.
17 is going to do it. Yes. Do I get to slap him? Yeah, you do. Oh, I'm so excited. I picked,
I picked this classic character because when Christina was explaining, um, what a monk could
do and what this mechanic was, it, to me, it sounded like just bitch slapping someone
repeatedly. That's basically it. Yeah. Yeah. And I do like, I do love a slap fight because
I'm a little less awesome with, with blowing extra later arms. That is four wisdom damage.
It's bludgeoning. It just uses your wisdom modifier. Okay. Yeah. It's, it's forced
damage. It just uses your wisdom. You challenge it to us to touch the wisdom right out of them,
which could, which, which could baffle it. Okay. We don't know. That's true.
Battle of the wits. Okay. So it takes that damage. It is that monster's turn now,
and it is going to, uh, actually try and back up from your position bond. And, um,
so it will give you an attack of opportunity. If you would like to, can I roll intimidation?
Sure. Absolutely. You can roll intimidation. How is that going to work for you? How is,
I am blonde and fresh and new. Literally on a leash, but like, yeah.
Don't worry little guy. I rolled a four. That's not going to work. That sounds about right.
Yeah. Hell yeah. We'll be right back. It's the middle. Hi everybody. Oh, hey.
Paul, come to the middle. Hey, it's the middle. It's good to have you.
Glad you're here. Thanks for joining us. If this is your first adventure with us,
because you joined us from I Seduce the Dragon to come listen to the great and amazing
Ryan and Christina. Um, that was an exciting day. It just sounded like a creaky door.
October. I do all the sound effects. Yeah. I'll change the credits to be from epidemic sound
to Amy. Amy does all the sound with my mouth. Um, but yes, thank you for being here. And
thank you again to Ryan and Christina for joining us from I Seduce the Dragon. Um,
they're lovely and you should go listen to their show. Um, not just because they're amazing,
but because Amy and Carla are going to be over there and continue to be over there
this coming week. Yeah, that's right. The next, the second part of our two part, a little,
um, horror one shot that we did over there will be released, uh, on the eighth next Wednesday,
but they're doing a fun video pre-watch on the Tuesday, the seventh. Does this sound right?
Monday, the seventh. I'm getting my days wrong. Monday. The pre-watch is on Monday.
The episode comes out on Tuesday. There we go. The numbers were correct. The numbers were
correct. The days were wrong. But if you go to their Patreon, you can sign up for that.
You don't need to be a member of their Patreon, but you can go and watch along.
All the details are there and Amy and I are going to hang. I put it in the calendar,
so it's got to happen. Amy and I are going to go hang out in the, in the chat as well.
Nice. Um, so we hope to see you over there and maybe Kyle and Tom will pop in.
I mean, maybe. Yeah, it is very, it's a, it's a fun,
it's fun. It's fun guys. It's fun. I'm looking forward to relistening because I have
a goldfish's memory and I'm just going to be snickering alongside everyone. Like I wasn't
actually there. It's also that podcast memory too, where like something happens and then it's
immediately deleted from all my memory banks. Absolutely. It's like, I don't need to remember
this. There's a recording of it that I can enjoy. That's gotta be why it is. But you
don't need to commit it to memory because it's rolled, the tapes rolled. That's right.
Yeah. Yeah. It's podcast science is what that is. Well, listen with us,
listen with us. Um, and then once you, once you listen to all of us specifically,
you can come join us on Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast, where you get an episode
dedicated to you, but also you get a whole bunch of extra bonus content. Uh, Tom,
describe to us how the next session of the adventures of might go in your own words.
Okay. Uh, Russ is still possessed working on cure, but also maybe not because they
kind of like it this way. Not working very hard. Yeah. Like at 30% effort. No,
it's fine. You don't know how I got possessed or what I'm possessed with. No, that's true.
Or for how long or why you might like me better possessed than not possessed.
But you can guess. You can get there. There might be some strong signs,
but you also get an episode dedicated to you. Like today's patron, Sarah inskeep.
That's fun. I would like to stay at your in sometime. Yes, indeed.
For a moment, I was like, the fuck are you talking about? I know it took me a second.
Like, okay, Tom, that's kind of a, kind of a weird thing to say.
How do you know she runs an inn? Lorelai Gilmore, what's happening?
I get it. Names. Names. Names. Thank you, Sarah. We're happy to have you here.
Yeah, thanks, Sarah. Thanks, Sarah. Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast. We hope to see you
over there. And then of course, go listen to I seduce the dragon and continue to listen to
this amazing fun time right now. We'll get you back to it. Thanks, everybody.
Have a great week. We'll talk to you soon. Love you. Bye.
So what with yeah, so we'll give you the attack of opportunity. So just,
I assume we're going to just punch it again or your quarter staff just roll
to hit or roll another attack. I am going to use.
You know what? I am going to use an unarmed strike because I know Kung Fu.
And 19. All right. So as it's backing up, you're going to connect with another hit.
Give me some damage. Four. It's not going to let out a towel, but it does let out this
this like guttural bark out into the room. And you see around it in this room. Like
there are four more figures that like scurry away and towards the light.
Do they are they the same type of creature?
They look to be the same type of creature. They look smaller,
but they look to be the same type of creature.
Bondin is convinced he's very intimidating.
I think so. Yeah. That's the only explanation. However, is going to try to
bite you. Now it's going to retreat. It's going to make this bark and then it's going to try to
bite you. It gets two bite attacks. That's the first one's a nine to hit. Second one is a 17 to
hit. So the second one hits. So you are going to take 10 piercing damage.
Ow. But don't forget, Ryan, you also you have your temporary hit points that I don't think you put
into your sheet yet. I did not. So I there's seven, right? So I'm only down three. Yeah.
Cool. And then make a wisdom saving throw. Oh, wait, are you protected from being
frightened from your aura? Yes, I ended on my turn, actually. So the so that he can still be
frightened. But on my turn, I can choose to end that. Oh, so it'd still be active then. Yeah,
it would still be active though. So wisdom threat saving throw or no. So he can get frightened,
but you can stop him from being frightened on my turn. Yeah. On your turn. OK, so yes,
please make them with I have to actively. I have to actively do it. Got it. 18. Not too
shabby. OK, you are not frightened. So that one chomp comes down in front of you and
misses the other connects with your shoulder and like this less huge gash because of the
temporary hip points like torn tears through your shirts and like into your skin. But you are
unphased as much as you can be being chomped by a big monster. But a scratch behind that
monster. You see those four others retreating into the light. You see them like disappear
one after the other as this final one in front of you is standing its ground.
Bizarre, it is your turn. You said the final one standing its ground, so it does not
show to be OK. You could roll insight to see if you can get gauge anything from
what's happening behind it and what you can. Yeah, if you want 15, I really just I know the
other ones are running. That's fine. This one does it seem like it's actually going to at
some point bolt. So that's a 15. Yeah, you definitely get a sense that it's protecting
everything happening behind it. But you can't with a 15 quite tell if it's going to stay
in fight or if on its turn after everything gets through, if it's going to try and run
as well with that. I guess what I'll do is try to make it less threatening by casting
reduce on it. So I need a constitution save DC 14. I have a feeling it's going to have a
good constitution. But science, we're experimenting and learning. This would be so
good if it works, though. That's a that's only a 13. I didn't roll very good. OK,
well, the target size is halved in dimensions. And OK, the reduction decreases size by
one category from medium to small, for example. And the target also has disadvantage on strength
checks and strength saving throws. And the it deals one D for less damage while it is
reduced, shrinks down in front of you bond and is now like what was hulking over top of you is
now horse sized in front of you. Nice move. Yeah. And I sneeze blood. And that's the end
of my turn. Penance, it's you. OK, so how far back is what like the the rift that appears to be?
I'm making an assumption that this is like the gate to the plane these things are coming from
about how far back from us is that you were 50 feet back from Bondan.
You didn't move on your turn last turn. So I'm going to say you're 80 feet from the rift.
OK, I will move closer so that I can get everybody within my 30 foot radius of my
Twilight Sanctuary. And I'll resolve that first, because everybody who ends their turn in there
can get a benefit. So sorry. Yeah, you said you had cast that and I said you were close
enough last time. So you would have been 30 feet. So minus. So you're actually 60
feet from the rift. Yeah, that's perfectly easy. I'm going to give Bondan some more temporary
hit points because he ended his turn in my in my zone. So he gets five and I will leave
bizarre as is because seven is a pretty good number. So you haven't
needed to use them yet. So I'll leave those. I am going to actually.
Can I peek into the cavern at all? Is there like can I see like other
stalactites on the ceiling? Is there anything? My goal is to try and collapse the area around
the rift. You would have to proceed forward to the opening a little bit more because I said
Bondan couldn't see in there until they were 10, 15 feet away. So if you do that,
you'd be able to see up and in. And yes, there there would be
stalactites hanging tight from the ceiling. The ceiling is probably 50 feet high.
It's a rather deep cave or cavern that you're going into.
That's totally fine for me. I'm going to try and orient myself as best I can. And I'm
going to cast guiding bolt, which has a range of 120 so I can totally breach it to try and
collapse the cavern over there in front of the rift. And I can do that at a higher level if I
think that will be more effective. I mean, if you're dealing more damage,
I would say that, yes, I think that would be more effective. So you're trying to
close the rift, which in turn would trap this one final creature on this side. Yes.
Yes. Yeah, we need one to get paid. We need one to get paid. That's what's up.
That's true. So I'm going to do I will do
guiding bolt. That's how she wraps up every single book. And then we got paid.
I'm going to cast guiding bolt at second level to strike those rocks and try and
collapse them down in front of the rift. Okay, no need to roll attack. Just give me
damage on that because we're just hitting a wall or a ceiling. So that'll be 5d6.
So that was 19 total. Tell me what your guiding bolt looks like. So I think this is going to be
successful in this moment. I don't see why it wouldn't be. So your guiding bolt goes. Tell
me what it looks like as this as enough boulder as enough stone and earth is coming down on top
of it. So I sort of rush forward towards the mouth of this cavern. And after taking a quick
glance around, I say another incantation in my my celestial prayer and I shoot forward a hand
sort of like I'm making a throwing motion and a ball of glittering starlight emerges and
streaks upwards towards the top of the cavern and smashes against those rocks.
As it does the stalactites and the rocks begin to crack and and loosen. And then like in a
cascade they release down on top of this cavern and begin building up and you see this creature
look back at it and then turn back and that throat begins to get brighter again. Oh no.
Oh boy. We got incoming. Throat punch it. And then as a bonus action,
I'll hit it with my spiritual weapon. All right. Which is still there.
That will be a oh god where are you spiritual weapon. That'll be an unnatural 20 to hit.
And that does come on. That is 11 damage. As this is glowing like the glowing doesn't stop
when it hits it but another huge strike comes in as this axe comes down on top of it.
Blood begins pouring down the side of it. I mean it's a smaller smaller creature now.
So it appears to do more damage to it and it lets out just like this grunt as this
light continues to glow in its throat. And then we go to calve.
Are there like more rocks above it that I could also knock down?
Directly above the creature itself? Yeah.
Yeah. All right. I really like what what Penance did with that guiding bolt there.
So I'm going to do the same thing but just at a lower level.
Sure. Same, not as advanced.
Yeah. Just give me some damage then on that one.
Absolutely. It's just 46. Hang on one sec.
What? That's what my guiding bolt says.
46. Okay. Thank you. Oh, I see. I remember I've got those things in my ears.
46 would be quite the thing, wouldn't it?
Just a smooth 46. 17 damage for us.
So stones begin to fall. They're cascading down and like huge hits onto the creature.
You want to roll me 2d6 for bludgeoning damage there?
Sure. 8.
So these stones are falling down on top of it and it's trying to sidestep.
You see the throat begin to waver like it's still growing in intensity but it's wavering
now that it's taking these damage, trying to avoid taking as much damage as possible.
Whoa, is it gonna cry? Is it gonna cry? Oh, a little baby will cry.
Bondin's feeling very confident.
This is part of Bondin's intimidation. He just starts schoolyard mocking the-
Now we learn why Bondin is homeschooled.
100% and that's why it's an unnatural form.
Bench is going to give bardic inspiration to Bondin and toss you a sandwich for that.
Hell yeah.
He's a sandwich bard?
Yes!
That's amazing.
He's a sandwich bard.
I mean he is now.
I snatch the sandwich out of the air and eat it with the gusto of a teenage boy.
And then that brings us back to you.
Does this do?
So you get a d6 on an attack roll, a saving throw, or an ability check.
Okay, so there's a little baby now?
It's smaller but yeah it's still the same creature because bizarre cast reduce.
Okay and the other four have all-
Yeah.
Okay and so now all the four have gone into the rift.
I'm gonna just keep on doing what I'm doing because I haven't learned better.
I'm gonna roll a hit with my quarterstaff.
Okay.
And that is an unnatural 24.
Damn.
But it's a nat 20 plus four.
Oh dang!
Oh then yeah roll double on your dice there for damage.
So the first one was nine and the second one was five.
Oh wait no no no no no no no I rolled two dice at the same time.
Sorry I apologize.
D&D Beyond figured it out for me so it was the nine.
Good D&D Beyond.
It was the nine damage?
Disregard the five.
Describe to me what it looks like when you kill this creature, Bondan.
Oh my gosh he's doing it!
Monster hunting!
Oh I- Bondan runs directly at the creature and leaps through the air with its quarterstaff
in hand and smacks the creature so hard in the throat.
Maybe it partially comes off?
I don't know.
And manages to do it with enough slack on his backpack leash to land in the superhero pose.
Staff down.
Knee down.
Fists down.
Bam!
Because he's young and he can hit his knees with it.
He can land his knees on hard stone and still get up and be okay.
God we wish we were like Bondan don't we?
Yeah I can do a flying leap and land on my knee!
That is the true, that is the power fantasy that we're all pursuing in D&D is knees
that don't hurt when you stand up again.
Full mobility.
God yeah.
Amazing okay so yeah you land in the superhero pose and then as you do that the
monster lets out one final shriek up to the ceiling and like releases the howl that it's
been building which reverberates through this cavern and everything begins to fall
and everything begins to shake.
You have one action each to decide what you want to do before I'm going to tell
you you've got to run to get out of here.
Oh snap.
This monster is too big to carry.
The departments had come off when I hit it really hard in the throat with the neck.
How off is this dude's head?
You snapped its neck but it's a pretty like meaty creature like I don't think you took
its head clean off unfortunately.
I'm going to run towards the creature and start trying to chop its head off with my
pen knife.
Okay.
Because we need evidence to get paid and that's that's one thing I've learned
from pen itself.
You're hacking away at this creature's neck and working at that.
As you're doing that we'll go to Bizard.
Cavern shaking you see Bondan going up to the creature and trying to take a you know
proof that they that this has been what you found and thought.
What do you do?
Looking at can we still see part of the glow from the rift?
Yeah I'd say it's like peeking through in cracks like enough has fallen that it's
covered the main main source of it but you still see it peeking through.
A while ago I was tempted to but now I am going to take a moment stare study and try
to recall any studies of like extra planar magic or anything in that realm and see
if I recognize any kind of color association based off of what we've seen.
Roll a history or an arcana.
Arcana please.
Ah it's a 14 on arcana.
I'm going to say it looks familiar to you.
It looks like you've read about it.
It looks like you have a book that you know that you've read a passage about
about some sort of other dimension.
You can't place it in this moment be it the the panic the the stress of the
the case but you've committed this what you've seen to memory so that you can go back
and research this should you escape.
Yeah I know the book I need.
Yeah exactly.
That's what I do.
Okay penance.
Bonded has the he's got the right spirit but the wrong tools.
He's got the wrong tools for the job if only.
I'm going to from from my belt I'll have to hand axe and with that and my spiritual
weapon that still exists can can I help with some more serious like hacking to try and
behead this creature.
Now with the two of you going at this creature you are able to absolutely get through
neck snapped bond and already picking away and now your weapons coming in.
You were able to cleave the head off of this creature.
Fantastic.
Which brings us to Cav.
Cav sees the the carnage of the head being removed and the inquisitive nature on
Bazaar's face and he just kind of like slowly makes his way back towards the exit.
It's like come on guys we've got to go.
Packs away slowly.
Spacks away slowly into the crowd disappears into the shrub.
Bench sees what you're doing and although he's not very adept at fighting it's been
found out he does have a lot of muscle so he after you cleave that head off he comes
up and picks it up and starts pushing everybody through the entrance as stones
continue to fall down behind you.
Does it fit in the basket.
I was also thinking put it in the picnic basket.
It's a wicker basket so it's got some give to it so it's like it's coming out but
enough that he can use it to help carry it out.
So everybody now getting his head and running back out to the cave in is coming down
behind you and you're climbing quickly up the ladder you make it back to the elevator
and like there's this huge plume of debris and dust that follows behind you.
There's this reverberating echo in your ears as you're making your way back up the
elevator.
The cave in appears to have stopped on that lower level though and although you hear
movement from somewhere else in the mountain you feel like you're safe in this
moment and you make it back up to the top where you're all standing around with
this this monster head in the picnic basket and Bench looks to you all and says oh
well that was more eventful than the last time we were down there can we go home now.
I think that went pretty smooth honestly all things considered.
I would agree I mean if a world-renowned monster hunter thinks so then I would have
to agree and I do I do think so let's go get paid yeah let's go clear our names
cav because we did this yeah you certainly helped as you say that I'm taking my ear
plugs out and I'm like clear your names what do you mean.
We kind of got blamed for it's a long story we'll tell you on the way back
and you can tell me at the brothel.
We cut back to the patio outside the brothel where Bondon and Penance are sitting
counting their money on the table having been paid the 500 plus the 100 for the
one monster that you were able to kill and return proof of
hazard fee absolutely I'm counting out all of the coins I'm making sure that we
got paid right and I I count out 50 of them and I slide them across the table
at Bondon and I say that's for the killing blow you did good today kid.
Bondon enters the brothel comes back approximately three and a half minutes
later flushed and must and safe and that's where we'll end today's episode.
Dumbgeons and Dragons season four episode six starring Tom Laird as Kavlaranan Goldweave
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard with Russ More as your dungeon master
featuring special guests Christina Van Epps as Penance olive tree and Ryan Keely as Bond and Cove
they join us from I Seduce the Dragon make sure you go find and listen to their adventures
at istdpod.com dialogue editing and sound design by Russ More this episode featured music
from Epidemic Sound and Slipstream and sound effects from Epidemic Sound Boom Library and
Sound Ideas our amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garbutt and
a huge thank you to our supporting producers Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Cat Waterflame,
Jacob Madden, Christian Brown, Angaron Kiersen, Perry Matey, Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss,
LA Branton and Sarah Murphy. Are you enjoying the story so far? Well we couldn't do it
without you. In fact we'd love for you to join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
where when you sign up for a seven day free trial you're going to get access to an entire
other show two of them to be exact we've got the adventures of and cyberpunk rent we hope to
see you over there Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and maybe we'll see you in the community
we're over on discord you have a great week we'll talk to you soon
I'll give everybody one action moment before something happens I got one
oh are we I would like to help
maybe should we roll in uh for for initiative for order let sure let's roll it I was like
who's turn is it because I know what I want to do who's going first I know what I'm doing
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production