We're just on a lift on the way down.
Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
There is a sound of a very rusty elevator.
And all of you, the five of you,
yeah, I mean, last time we said we could only fit three in, but I feel like
we could definitely force five people into this very small rusty elevator.
All of you are packed in tight.
I'm a willowy young man.
Oh, then perfect. See, it's all making perfect sense.
So you're packed right in the middle there surrounded by everybody else around you.
There's the kind of sound and you're getting farther and farther away from the light above.
So how far down does this go?
Should I light my torch?
Like in time wise.
Wait, going down in time?
How long is this trip down is what I should be asking.
I can't, it's been a little while.
I can't remember if this was the, there's the first elevator.
And I can't remember if we keep going down on this elevator,
if there was a second elevator, but we'll go down.
There will be a floor and then there will be another one.
I think we went down twice.
Maybe it was the second one where we.
Was it the second one?
Riveting.
Yeah.
I mean, there was a lot happening.
It's hard to remember.
It's true.
I wouldn't like the, well, you could now, but maybe not.
If I hold it like up in between.
Okay.
Oh, wait.
Yeah.
I mean, I have a torch in my backpack just so you guys know.
Also, do you do, should we stuff our ears?
Well, they do do a fair bit of shrieking.
It's true.
I do have a method that would counteract that.
It just so happens that it would, for instance, bizarre.
If any of your spells require you to speak,
that's going to be an issue also.
Oh, that's.
Well, all of them.
So.
Yeah.
The, the quiet, quiet place spell.
The quiet place spell.
Yes, absolutely.
It might be something that when we,
when we come across these creatures,
we'll can figure it out then.
However, my method for allowing you all to see
is also a limited time thing.
Wait, you can do that, Penance?
I can do so many things, Bond, and you don't even know.
This is when you get further along in the course,
you'll really fully understand.
Well, cool.
If you can go ahead and take care of that,
that whole not being able to see in the dark thing,
then we wouldn't need the torch.
We wouldn't, I mean, the sound of the elevator alone,
I think is an indicator of something
encroaching upon their territory,
but it's going to be fine.
We have a very prestigious monster hunter with us.
You do.
How quickly were you attacked last time
and then you just ran?
You said you just ran.
It took a little bit and then we kind of,
we rode the elevator back up,
so it wasn't really a running,
it was like a standing in place while the machine moved us.
Yes.
And they followed you to the surface?
Well, not at the time they didn't.
That's right, they didn't.
That's where we're kind of thinking it wasn't our fault.
While I'm packed in between all of you guys like this,
I'm going to awkwardly still get into my bag
and I'm going to pull out my pen knife
and I'm going to cut off a corner of my robe
and then I'm going to shimmy up this little piece
and then I'm going to, in front of my face,
trim it down and to make myself some teeny tiny earplugs.
And then, because I'm strapped in between you guys,
I'm going to get her in.
And then my hands are kind of stuck up by my ears
and then I got to kind of shimmy my hands back down my body
and then after I manage to get them back down,
I'm going to act like nothing happened
and try to look really, really cool
and just pretend that you guys didn't notice me doing that.
I'm just going to imagine that Bonnet
is in the exact center of everyone.
So everyone was just like perceiving that whole thing.
And now I'm going to act casual.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast
and I'm your dungeon master Russ More, HeHim.
Also with me today, Tom Laird
as Kavlaran Goldweave, HeHim.
I know what I'm doing with it.
Kyle Klasset as Bizard the Wizard, HeHim.
But that's not a spell I've seen.
What is that? What did you do?
With special guests from I Seduce the Dragon,
Christina Van Epps as Penance Olive Tree, SheHer.
If I can hear you, everyone can hear you.
And Ryan Keely, SheHer as Bond and Cove, HeHim.
Are there still damage there? Can I see it?
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast
and you can join us today at patreon.com slash tumdragoncast.
There's a seven-day free trial
and a whole bunch of episodes for you to listen to.
We hope to see you over there.
And now, fuck it, let's play.
Bizarre and Kavlaran and Bench,
you recognize kind of where you are now
that you passed the first pathway,
which is where you found the mining equipment
down one direction and then the other direction was a cave-in.
You now recall that going down to the next level
was where you extended down and found a ladder
that went down further into the cave
where you came across what at the time
you thought was a dog-like creature,
which now that you've been attacked by these creatures in the city,
realize it was a youngling of this species.
Let me pet that dog.
Can Bondin and Christina see anything down these floors
as we're passing them in the elevator?
Not Bondin and Penance.
Bondin and me.
Me, specifically.
Did Penance cast the darkvision on those who can't see yet?
Not yet.
I think because I can only do it for about an hour,
so I'm holding it until we're a little bit closer.
But I do have darkvision up to 300 feet,
so if there is anything to be seen as we're going down.
Is there anything distinguishing that would be seen on these levels
or do they just look like average mineshaft levels?
They look like pretty standard mineshaft levels.
Bondin likely wouldn't be able to see a whole lot.
Kavlaran would only know this based on memory.
You can just see sweaty chests.
Exactly.
Penance, however, you can see down both directions.
You can see that there's a cave-in down one as you pass this.
You can see, because you've got 300 feet,
you can see the outline, dimly for your vision,
but you can see the outline of what looks like wooden mining equipment,
like a drilling device of some sort.
Okay.
So I'll leave it to you all if you want to stop there
or if you want to keep going
or if the others want to signal that you want to keep going.
Let's keep going down.
Take us down to the source.
Yes, the second floor we stopped at,
there was a ladder from what I recall
and that's where we encountered the first one.
Much smaller than the ones in town.
Hopefully easier to kill.
We're going to find out on top of the ladder
or at the bottom of the ladder.
I could. Could they climb ladders?
I can't remember.
They must have because they got up here.
I think they did.
All right.
So we will do something
when we get to the bottom of the second elevator level.
Right. You know, well, they wouldn't have been able to...
No. Okay. Yeah, let's go.
The elevator continues on
and after some time you make it down to this,
to the second level,
which the elevator shaft continues to go,
but it's a metal grate that you can see through
and Kavlaran would be able to see down as well.
It looks like there's been a cave-in further down
in this elevator shaft.
So this is basically the bottom of where the elevator can go.
Leading out of the elevator and down this far corridor.
As described, there is a rickety wooden ladder
that appears to be anchored into the walls.
There are a couple of broken rungs
and Pennin says you're...
Actually, give me an investigation as you're walking down.
Oh, boy.
And trying to find signs of anything.
That's a 17.
Perfect.
I have a minus one to investigation,
so I was expecting that to go badly,
but it didn't.
We're good.
So you see quite clearly with your dark vision,
you see big gouge marks of what looks like claws.
Now, looking at the, you know,
thinking of the drawing that Bizard gave you,
these line up very similarly with what you saw in that drawing
and what you've heard of the Howler.
They have four predominant claws
that would be able to make these marks.
And as you look down into this ladder shaft,
it looks like this creature is able to scale the wall.
Like it's not using the ladder itself,
it's scaling the stone beside it.
Oh, hell no.
Okay.
Terrifying.
Glad I haven't lit my torch yet.
Well, you're going to be horrified in just a second.
I pull out, I reach into my tunic
and I pull out a many pointed star amulant from around my neck
and I channel my holy power through it
and I will use my eyes of night.
I will expand outward my ability to see
up to four wing creatures within 10 feet of me.
So that's going to be Cav and Bizard and Bondin and Bench.
All of you for the next hour can see
up to 300 feet in clear color in the dark.
Damn.
So basically now like the lights just got flipped on.
Oh, shit.
Cool.
Wow, that's very cool.
You should have warned his penance.
It's awfully sudden.
I told you I could do something about this.
Yeah, look at these claw marks on the wall.
I don't-
That's not a spell I've seen.
What is that?
What did you do?
Oh, that's just a little blessing from my goddess.
So that's the power of divine magic.
Oh, very interesting.
Very interesting indeed.
Okay.
It's honestly kind of surprising that you guys can manage to not have this
and still function.
But for the next hour, you can see like I see
and hopefully that will aid us in this little journey.
I would say so.
So with that in mind, Bondin.
Yes.
I need to be able to watch your back.
Do you want to put a leash on me?
Okay.
Yes.
Do you want to attach a leash to my backpack when I go to the grocery store?
Sure.
With my mom.
Yeah.
Let me tie that onto you.
We can pull you back if you get into true trouble.
I'm going to be your guard here.
You're going to be going down first because you're the quietest and the smallest.
Okay.
It's going to be great.
And I have rope in my backpack.
So I'm going to tie it on.
Okay.
And this is your end.
We harness the boy up with some rope
and then I'm just going to hold one end to it and be like, you've got this kid.
Okay.
Can I go down the ladder now?
Absolutely.
Yeah.
Okay.
I start climbing down the ladder.
Bondin's going first, followed by Penance, I assume.
Because you've got the leash on Bondin.
Mm-hmm.
I'll go second.
Sure.
Great.
Great, great, great.
Who's following behind?
If he's not immediately eaten, I will follow.
Roger that.
How long is the leash that is tied to Bondin?
I'll go third.
Desire to go through.
Okay.
So it is the standard rope in my backpack, which is 50 feet.
So I can climb down 50 feet and look around for y'all.
Should I roll perception or acrobatics for climbing down a ladder?
You can climb down the ladder, no problem.
I would roll stealth, though, to see how quiet you're being.
Okay.
10.
That's with a plus too.
This is going to go great.
Yeah.
This is going to go so great.
This is going to be so great.
So you're going to go, Penance, are you going to allow Bondin to go the full 50 feet?
Yep.
Great.
Okay.
Cool.
Yep.
Unless I see something about to happen, I'll pull him back at that point.
But this is my old canary in our coal mine here.
Send the boy down.
Amazing.
Okay, so Bondin, you're going to go down.
I'm pink and shiny like a worm.
Bondin, you're going to go down.
Penance, you're going to see them.
They, you know, maybe continuously look back up at you and back down.
And once you kind of reach the edge of that rope, there's still a ladder below them.
So you would all have to, or at least you would have to proceed down the ladder for Bondin
to be able to reach the next floor.
Can I see the bottom of the ladder?
Yes, there's probably about another 25 to 30 feet below you before you'd be able to see out.
Okay, but I can see the bottom.
Yes.
Yeah.
And there's nothing moving down there?
Doesn't appear to be, no.
Okay.
I continue on with Penance behind me.
Yeah, I'll go the whatever distance.
I'll start descending a little bit down to make sure that the rope can keep going.
He can keep going.
Sounds good.
Okay, so yeah, Bondin, you make it down.
Penance behind.
Is everybody else hopping onto the ladder?
Are you going to wait for a call?
Oh no, I'll hop onto the ladder.
Yeah, I'll hop on.
They're blocking your exit, Penance.
I'm just saying.
I feel like that's against the rules.
I don't remember which module, but don't you want them to like, you know, make sure for safety
reasons?
It'll be fine.
Don't worry.
They're not, they're not one of them works in as a bureaucrat.
You shouldn't say it's a dirty thing.
Well, apparently not very stealthy, so you should be able to hear me up the ladder.
I was going to say this conversation is happening over 50 feet.
So like, if I can hear you, everyone can hear you.
It's a stage whisper more than anything.
With a stealth of 10.
So I hit the bottom of the, so I get to the bottom of the ladder and I jump off
and I look around.
Yeah, you look around.
So you have one direction to look.
You can look down the cavern, similar to the one that you just exited up above.
At the end of that cavern, which you can't tell the exact distance, but it's
give or take 75 to 100 feet down.
It looks like it branches off and rounds a corner, but you see a very dim glowing light
from down at the end of this corridor.
Can I roll?
I don't know if that's insight.
Like I want to know what color the light is and like.
Yeah, it looks bluish and purplish.
Okay, pennants.
Okay, so I'm here at the bottom.
I'm here at the bottom and there's a long, there's a long hallway.
And then there's a choice that we're going to have to make because there's two branches
to this path and there's a blue and purple light.
What do I do?
This wasn't in your book.
Wait for the rest of us.
Well, for the rest of us, I'm assumed climb down too.
As long as you don't see anything down there.
So that's moving.
Nothing's moving.
When eventually we reach the bottom, I will in a sort of
soto voice hushed say now what's important with monster hunting is that you have to
be able to discern monster tracks so that you can follow them back.
So now you remember there's the giant slash marks you saw.
Do you see any of them down here?
I look around.
Which is yeah.
Can we do like a little bit of a survival check or a nature or something to see if
we can find.
Yeah.
What do I want me to roll survival?
21 unnatural.
Dang.
Nice.
I only rolled a 13, but the boy is going to do it.
So it's fine.
Well, it's very, very recent in your mind, seeing those and being scared of them up
top, you know, having been shot into that light.
But you see the exact same claw marks that power.
Maybe you saw them all the way down.
They scaled up the wall.
They are all along the floor.
I look at the ceiling.
Are they on the ceiling?
Can they go upside downsies?
They are not on the ceiling in this in this corridor.
They're not on the same guy.
They go down in this corridor.
They go down the path.
Looks like they're coming in both directions.
I'm still going to be 50 feet ahead of the group.
And so I'm going to walk 50 feet ahead of you guys.
Still on my leash towards the light and towards we get until we get to the decision point.
We'll be right back.
It's the middle.
I miss starting with a song.
Well, it starts with a song every time.
No, you know what I mean.
With a Russ original.
With a live song performed for us.
Without any thought.
By Russ.
Without any thought put into it.
Well, I'm sorry to disappoint you.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
We're here now.
And this is just everybody's airing of grievances.
Shipping for stuff that's expensive.
Russ doesn't sing anymore.
Yeah, it's ridiculous.
Why aren't Amy and I even in this episode?
I'm not sure.
Yeah.
Wait, why aren't you in this episode?
We may have been busy doing something else.
That's right.
Maybe seducing a dragon?
Maybe.
Anything is possible.
We didn't.
Spoiler alert.
So Amy and Carla aren't in this episode.
But Christina and Ryan are.
And they are friggin' lovely.
And you should go listen to I Seduce the Dragon here.
Absolutely.
By the way, Amy and Carla are over in that feed right now.
Yeah, we are.
You get the full package.
They just had a live listen to the first episode of theirs.
Look at them doing more things than we do.
Thanks for being here with us.
Cool stuff.
They're great.
Proud of them.
I'm really proud of them.
I'd like to say, the next one's going to be in like two weeks minus a day.
I'm going to be there for that one.
Yes.
Put it in my calendar.
It's all happening during the day and I'm teaching small children at that one.
I don't think playing it for my class would be a good idea.
But they did ask maybe for a time shift.
So maybe we can make it work.
So we'll go back to Jess and figure it out.
But this has been a middle and a half.
A middle and a half.
What you do get with us is sometimes live things.
Sometimes live things.
But also you get an episode dedication.
Like today's patron, Wendy Bale.
Thanks, Wendy.
Thank you so much.
Thank you, Wendy.
So you can join us at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast.
You get The Adventures Of, which is the exclusive podcast over there,
which is six episodes deep.
And now once you get to season...
Six episodes.
Six seasons.
Doesn't seem like a lot.
Oh.
Six seasons.
Eagle-eyed listeners like Wendy caught that.
Oh, yeah.
Yes.
Thank you for catching that.
Six seasons deep.
And in season six, Kyle's there.
But it's like chosen three.
Zero context for a lot of things if you start with season six over there.
Yes.
Like we don't hold back on like in-jokes in that one.
So you got to start with one and then go all the way through with that one.
Yeah.
Also you might like Russ's character more than you should.
So you need to start back at season one to really get the whole effect.
Really be filled with that disdain.
And you're not really going to get why Kyle's character is having the effect.
He is on Amy's character if you haven't listened to previous seasons.
So please listen to them all.
They're very fun and quite silly.
They are.
Very silly.
We have a blast.
And thank you, Tom, for just saying yes to absolutely everything.
Of course.
Yeah, it's a lot of fun.
So we hope to see you over there.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Sign up.
Seven-day free trial.
We do hangouts.
We got this and a whole lot more.
Whole lot more.
Yeah, tons.
All right.
We'll let you get back to this episode where we're going down an elevator, baby.
Love you.
For nearly the whole episode.
So you can see that it's not Amy and Carla who have this effect on our group.
It's just our group.
Just take our time, OK?
Love you.
Bye.
Do I see anything 50 feet ahead of the group as I continue down this corridor?
So left, no light.
Right is the blue-purple light.
And as you get down to the end there, so everybody else is 50 feet back still, I presume.
That's why I'm yelling left or right, left or right, left or right.
Which way do we want to go, guys?
What do you see?
What do I see, Dungeon Master?
You look down to the left, which is the corridor that has no light.
And it looks to be like you see stone rubble.
If you take a few steps down, it branches further down and it looks like a cave-in.
I run back and then I go down the other one.
Looking back down the pathway that has the dim light, it appears to be getting brighter.
You see more of these scratch marks coming down from this direction.
You can't see the end of this corridor from your current position without progressing further.
I think the monsters came from this side.
All right. Well, if any of you have...
Jolly Sally forth.
Let's reel you back in and huddle. Let's do a quick huddle.
So we all huddle up and I say, all right, anybody who has any capability...
I take my earplugs out.
We're about... Oh yeah, that's true.
Anyone who has any capability of combat should get ready for that.
Okay.
Just in case, in case we're jumped, these things like to attack in packs.
If you see one of them, that means there are others you probably don't see.
Coyote logic, you know, we had to talk about that.
Bench.
Yeah.
I don't know if I asked what you can do.
Oh, well, I make a really mean sandwich.
Fucking true.
Yeah.
Should we carb up?
Oh, gotta carb up.
That's why I brought this pick and neck basket here.
So I've got sand, I've got pastrami, I've got a ham and cheese.
I got a vegetarian.
Anybody not like the meat?
No.
No?
No, here.
Okay. Well, we'll put that one back.
No. Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, I'll take it.
No, bizarre.
Oh, oh, you want it.
Sorry. I missed it.
You were speaking so quietly at the back of the cavern there.
I just have to plug in my hearing aid as well.
It's just what I need.
And then what else do we got in here?
We got a pepperoni sandwich, which is a delicacy.
I want pastrami.
Yeah, you want that one?
It's very good.
No, I want pastrami.
Oh, you want pastrami?
Okay, sorry.
Yes, yes, yes.
Okay, you get that one.
And everybody else gets what they get and they don't get upset.
Here you go, here you go.
Okay.
But I brought a knife.
That's good.
Oh, yeah.
Excellent.
Yep.
Very good.
It is a butter knife.
That's good.
Do you have any other weapons?
No.
It's better than nothing.
You can sharpen it on a rock.
Here, take this.
I pull out a dagger.
I say it's a little bit sharper than a butter knife.
But it works about the same.
So take that at least if you have nothing else.
Thank you.
I have a quarter staff.
I know Kung Fu and I've taken penances, olive trees,
correspondence course on how to be a monster hunter.
Sounds like you're ready to go then, yeah.
The first thing that we're going to do is that you're going to bench,
you're going to hold that knife, you're going to hold that dagger,
and if anything comes close enough to you to eat you,
go for the eyes or run.
Whichever you think is most applicable for your skill set.
Love it, love it.
I'm here for it.
We're going to start sneaking forward.
Kavlar, Kavlar, what are your skill sets?
Do you have anything on your person?
I've got this here hammer.
And he pulls his hammer off his back.
It's a war hammer.
I know what I'm doing with it.
Okay, okay, okay.
Bazaar, other than the power of dance and costume changes,
how are you going to help?
It's like a sword dance.
And I pull out a scimitar and so a sword dance.
And of course, a little bit of the magics here and there.
You can't overuse it.
Otherwise, you know, it hurts.
But the sword dance works out fairly well.
How does it hurt?
Your feelings?
No, like physically.
You see the gray spots in my eyes is kind of that.
And I get a little trickle of blood out of the ear sometimes.
Last time we fought these, I used so much magic,
I vomited blood when I got home.
It was great.
So yeah.
I'm trying to stare into your eyes like way too intensely.
So I really want to like,
I'm just like trying to see the eyeballs.
Like, are there still damage there?
Every little spell, just a little bit of the green goes away.
So speaking of which, I'm going to cast Armor of the Weave on myself.
And of course, there's a little crest of a Bernhardt Swan school on there
because that's how you have to learn the spell.
It's their own copyrighted version.
There's a watermark on the spell.
Sorry, you only have a license for one Armor of the Weave.
You can't teach it to anyone else.
Was this Adobe Creative?
Come on.
Yeah, pay your subscription fee for your freaking spell.
But no, I'm ready to go.
Should I continue to go for us?
Yes.
Go for us.
Again, stealth.
Quiet.
Okay.
I stuff my earplugs back in and have my quarter stealth.
Perfect.
You want me to roll for stealth?
I will give you another stealth here.
We've made it pretty far.
Like, let's re-up that chance to be a little sneakier from this point.
Although, we've made a lot of noise to this point, so.
They're sandwich eating.
We stopped to have a picnic.
Yeah.
Well, you got to.
You got to carb up, bro.
It's what they brought me along for.
Right?
You can't be encumbered by picnic basket weight.
No, no.
We're going to leave that.
Maybe we could use it as a distraction.
I'm going to bring it with us and just see.
Smart.
13.
Unnatural.
Got an unnatural 20 on stealth.
Maybe he should go for it.
Beautiful.
So everybody behind you is much quieter than you.
Okay.
You're going ahead still with leash on.
This corridor gets increasingly brighter the longer you go down it,
but you walk down for 100 to 150 feet before you are able to see an opening.
And it opens up into what you can see from a distance.
I'm not going to place you right into this room yet,
but it opens up from into this huge cavern.
And inside of this cavern, you see a crack in the far side of the wall.
And it appears to be where this light is coming from.
And it's this shimmering luminescence that looks like no light source you've ever seen before.
I would like to roll investigation on the crack.
What is it that you're looking for in the crack?
I want more specificity about the crack.
Okay.
Yeah, give me an investigation roll.
It was 14.
14, okay.
Like, like, like, like where?
Yeah.
Yeah, so it is.
Okay, yeah, it is on.
So you're standing, we'll say 15, 20 feet back from the opening
so that you're not directly in this room.
But it is on the far wall, which is going to be another 50 feet beyond that.
And it extends from the floor up above from where you can see.
So you can assume that it's going to the ceiling.
And it's almost like it's pouring out like a liquid.
You can see the floor itself.
It's not, there's nothing pooling there.
So you can rule out the fact that it is liquid,
but that's what the illusion that it's giving your eyes right now
is that there's something coming out from somewhere beyond that.
Can I see the ceiling of this room?
Not without getting closer to the entrance.
I would like to walk up to the entrance of this room
and look around it, including up.
Okay.
You proceed forward another 15 feet or so.
What's your passive perception, actually?
12.
You're focused on the light and then you're following it up to the ceiling.
And as you approach the entrance out the corner of your eye,
you see not swift, but you see movement often to your right,
which gives you pause for a moment.
And there's a scratching sound that you hear next.
And it's almost like one of these creatures, much like a dog,
like flops to the ground and you hear this rumbling thud.
Do you poke your head around the corner
or does that give you pause to go back to your point?
I would like to run at it and hit it with my stick.
I will say, if he starts running, I'm gonna pull back on the rope.
I'm not gonna let the baby go too far off the leash here.
Are you holding at that 50 foot mark, Penance?
I am.
Okay, so I'm gonna run and with my...
Your Penance is gonna see me grab my staff and get ready to run and strike
and I'm gonna run full force and then I'm gonna be stopped
by my leash that I forgot about and fall back into the hallway.
I think you maybe get one, maybe two feet
and then yeah, you retract like Scooby-Doo style,
like bounce back into the hallway there.
Oh boy, here we go again.
I start reeling him back and to everyone else,
I'll start moving forward a little bit quicker and say,
it's go time, everyone.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season four, episode five.
Starring Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard.
Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Featuring special guests, Christina Van Epps as Penance Olive Tree
and Ryan Keely as Bond and Cove.
They join us from I Seduce the Dragon.
Make sure you go find and listen to their adventures at istdpod.com.
Dialogue editing and sound design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and Slipstream
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garbutt.
And a huge thank you to our supporting producers.
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babiak,
Kat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown,
Angaron Kiersen,
Perry Matey,
Old School Gamer D,
Craig Zeiss,
L.A. Branton,
and Sarah Murphy.
Are you enjoying the story so far?
Well, we couldn't do it without you.
In fact, we'd love for you to join us at patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast
where when you sign up for a seven-day free trial,
you're going to get access to an entire other show.
Two of them, to be exact.
We've got The Adventures of and Cyberpunk Red.
We hope to see you over there.
Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
And maybe we'll see you in the community.
We're over on Discord.
You have a great week.
We'll talk to you soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.