Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment. All of you have gathered in Everbane's and Bonwyn
and Bizard, you in particular right now, are heads inside of the forge taking a look at the entire
situation.
Well, so you tried everything that you've been taught. You found this note.
Mm hmm. Yeah, I mean, to be totally honest, the forge is basically constantly running. I mean,
we'll let it go out, you know, when I take my two weeks in the summer and Thane goes back home
to visit his family. And otherwise, it's just, it's just going for the entire year. So
okay,
you know, roll Arcana or Investigation.
Let's go with Arcana.
That's 14.
14 for me too, for investigation.
Bizard, do you want to roll with Advantage based on Bonwyn's roll, please?
Yeah. Oh, it was less.
Great. Cool beans.
Yeah.
He actually got dumber when I came and stood beside you. Sorry.
Yeah, I can't believe you can't find it.
My normie vibes were like, just like sinking into your magical skin.
Bonwyn, when you back out of the main area and you're going to check other
components around and Bizard, you are, I mean, you're looking intently in here,
not really sure what you're looking for exactly. But as you like scoot away some
ash off like the, the, the bricks or stone, what is it made out of? Stone or brick?
I literally was just googling images of forges to be like, what does this look
like?
Mostly probably like cement, what I would assume.
Yeah.
But in an old timey world, probably like, just like a hearty stone.
Yeah. Yeah. Some river stones, you know, maybe.
Yeah.
Oh yeah. If you Google forge and look at images, this is all exactly what I was
mixuring. It's like stone. It's open, but also has a top.
Excellent. Okay. So we're all seeing the same thing.
Yeah.
Of course. Got to have the chimney.
I mean, I don't know. I'm seeing a very handsome fellow in a yellow and
blue outfit with an X-Men tag next to his name.
Your search history is very different.
I feel like the rhythms are not aligned.
Oh damn.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D and D actual play podcast.
And I'm your dungeon master Russ More.
He, him also with me today is Amy More as Alydin.
She, her, and if that doesn't work, you're here.
Carla.
Max.
That is Bonwyn.
Everbane.
She, her, when rolls her eyes like you can when you're an adult at your
parents, Tom Laird is Kavlarananan Goldweave.
He, him.
Look, sir.
We've just been politely watching until this point.
And Kyle Claset is Bizard the Wizard.
He, him.
Oh God.
What did I do?
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast, and we'd love for
you to join us over at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast right now.
When you sign up, you'll get a seven day free trial and instant access to
so many amazing bonus episodes, more of what you love.
Come find it today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And now fuck it.
Let's play.
Okay.
So you scoot away some ash away from the mantle of the forge and your
fingers run along something that, that feels out of place and taking another
look at it, you see that there is an etching that's hidden behind like the
hearthstone, like right in behind there.
I'm going to look around for like a brush or something to really like
clean out the cracks and see if I can get a better definition on it.
This is a full one of those nice fireplace kids right there.
That's what he thinks about your brush.
Yeah.
Not a fan.
Okay.
Oh, just a standard brush.
You're a wizard, man.
Come on.
All right.
Fine.
I'll cast.
I'm kidding.
Cast gust and get ash and soot everywhere everywhere.
Hey, I just can't make your dogs happy, dude.
No one can, anybody want them?
I've told you, no, I have my own.
Yeah.
So they get everything they want.
And yet maybe that's the problem.
Yep.
Yeah, probably.
Uh, okay.
Whether you gust or whether you brush.
I don't have gusts, so it's brush.
Okay.
What about May's hand with a tiny brush?
Yes, I can do that.
In fact, I do.
Just so you don't get any shit on you.
Because I have other things that I need to look at anyway while it's being cleaned away.
So go ahead.
Yes.
Uh, you, uh, are able to see this etching now.
And it says to the flame, grief is the shadow of joy.
Both burn bright in its heart.
Bonwyn, have you ever noticed this etching?
Uh, no, like the manufacturer kind of thing on the inside.
Uh, I, it may be it's from the manufacturer.
I know it doesn't look as a manufacturer.
I would say no.
Okay.
Well, no, I can see where you're touching now.
That's not it up on the side there.
You can see the thing.
And it also is just the EB that my dad did.
I don't know why I said the manufacturer.
Cause obviously my dad just built the forge, but you know, it was, it was an
upgrade one from the one that like great, great graded me.
And he thought he could start a new business making forges, but were
the only blacksmiths in town.
So I'm not sure.
Forge forgers.
Oh, that could be something.
Fane, write this down.
Yeah.
Okay.
Forgers.
Forge forgers.
Are we making forges now?
We might make fake forges.
Why would we make fake forges?
You mean forging forge forgers?
The best part of waking is forges in your cup.
You know, I was thinking Folgers a second ago and I was like, how can this work out?
He just went for it.
I don't wait for it to work out.
I just, that's right.
You just make it happen.
If we learned anything from the business meeting before Russ got us all horribly
sick, it's that we're just going to take those shots.
We should just go for it.
Exactly.
Definitely.
You don't know what's going to land.
Yeah.
Um, no, I don't.
I never noticed, uh, I never noticed an etching in here.
It aligns with the note that you got, uh, to the flame.
Grief is the shadow of joy.
Both burn bright in its heart.
Okay.
Grief is the shadow of joy.
Both burn.
So does that mean it wants, it's like the two sides of a coin.
So it can have joy or grief.
Let me look at the note again.
I mean, you know, when you.
Joy and grief remembers the truth of the hand that stokes it.
Blood and purpose, joy and grief.
These are the sparks it craves.
I think I understand, you know, that being the two sides of the
same coin and the shadow, you know, you.
Sometimes a shadow can, uh, diminish an actual person.
You know, at, you know, at evening time, your shadow can be
much larger than you actually are.
Right.
I think that's a good metaphor for how, you know, grief can
overshadow the joy in your life.
Oh, that's really, that's, that's quite beautiful.
Sorry.
How that relates to you.
I don't know how that forage.
I don't fucking know.
I don't know either.
The thing is my business, the opposite of yours is very much,
uh, a hands-on touching, doing, thinking when I'm creating my weapons
and being creative in that way, but otherwise it's very.
It's not esoteric, you know?
So that must've got lost between great, great, great grandma,
Malin and me.
Yeah.
What's something you can't live without?
And you can't say the forge because, well.
Um, gosh, I don't know.
Uh, well, I mean, up there on that shelf, you'll see there's
like a really quite poorly made a dagger.
That's the first thing that I ever made myself.
And I put it up there to remind me to keep progressing and that I can do this.
And it's like, it's really important to me.
So it's not, you know, on the scale of things, I'm willing to give up.
I guess it's, I don't want to give up, you know, someone I love, but that
is a thing I love and that is important to me.
A lot of sentimental value.
Absolutely.
So.
It was just something I imagine, you know, your father guided
your hand on this graph.
Of course, of course.
Important memory as well.
So many memories of, of, yeah, just time spent as a little one beside my dad
working and, and him helping me.
And yeah, but this was the first one he never laid a hand on.
He just watched and, you know, corrected me if need be, but I did it all myself.
So, oh, did he, did he do that thing where he comes by and goes,
interesting and walks away?
Yes.
Oh, that's how you're going to do that.
Huh?
Yeah.
What the fuck is that shit?
I mean, that's why part of me was glad when him and mom retired out to the
lake, because he would still do that.
Even though, and I would never tell him this to his face.
I am like 10 times the Smith he is.
Have you seen the things that I've made?
The weapons, the intricacy, the commissions that you have.
He was a very good Smith, but yes, exactly.
It's just, it's, but he's still like, Oh, okay.
Sure.
Yeah.
You could do it like that, I guess.
Okay.
Follow up question.
What's more valuable to you?
Cause like, you have to think about what you're offering here.
That you give that up.
There's a potential of lost memory.
Uh, you know, they talked about how they lost their voice.
So, you know.
Yeah.
Is the loss of that memory, uh, worth relighting the forge to you?
I mean, I need the forge.
To, to, for my livelihood, to make money, to help the kids, for Thane's employment.
I mean, there's a lot counting on it.
Not to mention, you know, like the pressure of legacy and I can't be the
ember bane that lets the forge go out forever.
So I guess it is.
I think it's worth it.
I'm going to tell you this and I totally respect your decision and your view on
this as somebody who was raised in a house expecting to take over a business.
You don't have to.
You can do your own thing, but if you love this, keep doing it.
Obviously.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's a really good point.
Thank you for that.
Yeah, no problem.
But no, I had a wonderful, happy childhood.
So I would like to take over that.
Fantastic.
I'm happy to hear that.
Small, just minor judgments, but yeah, no judgment, just obliviousness.
Just, I kind of pictured when you were shit talking your dad, that Russ was
going to like pan the camera over and he was going to be right behind you.
I mean, you did ask him to come to town.
I did ask him to come to town.
Knock, knock, knock.
But he wouldn't know, he still thinks it's his home.
No, it's not dad.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
We're so happy that I didn't hit record.
I hit record on my local and I was like, well, I guess I'm the only one talking.
You went from, I'm not going to talk a lot to now you're the only one talking.
Welcome to the middle only with Russ.
I'm not going to talk a lot, but let me just start off talking.
Anyway, we're in the middle.
We're in the middle and we're bullying Russ because we don't talk very well.
Because he's sick.
Come back, it's okay, we're not trying to bully you.
He actually has left the room now.
You know what I think about Russ, guys?
Tell me.
He's really hardworking and smart and kind.
Oh my God.
He works so hard.
I agree with all of these statements.
He's like genuinely a good person.
It's, it's crazy.
Am I right back?
Yeah.
Point of sale.
Real cash register over here.
Um, what are we talking about?
Everybody?
You, you, nothing but terrible.
Nothing but mean things about you.
You'll find out when you, when you listen back.
There's only mean things to say about me.
So I get it.
Uh, another thing Russ is, is prepared because, uh, we have patrons.
You see, you can become one at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And as part of that, you get a bunch of stuff, including like
special extra episodes of like a million extra episodes, I think approximately.
Yeah, just a little other show and all kinds of fun stuff.
But another thing you get is an episode dedicated to you.
Here he comes.
The star of the show.
Russ More with today's patron.
Zombie army.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, wow.
That's probably our most terrifying patron.
Thank you.
Zombie army.
Please stay with us happily.
It is singular name, not even a hyphen or share situation.
Nice.
Well, if there's going to be a zombie army, zombie army, zombie army.
Army.
Yeah.
Love it.
We got there.
Yeah.
Thanks on the army.
Stay on our side.
I love it.
Yeah.
No, it's great to have you.
Um, I don't know what else we've talked about.
So if we feel like that's like great,
I think we've done it, you know, don't worry.
We did a great job.
Well, you know, you always do a great job.
That's why I left you with confidence to go deal with the screaming
dog in the background.
That was fine.
Yeah.
Well, it's good to see you all for that brief period of time.
Let's get them back to the episode now.
Okay.
Let's do it.
Love you all.
Bye.
The door burst open and your father enters.
Is it broken?
It's not broken.
It's not working, but it's not broken.
Come look, look for yourself.
I've tried everything.
Come and grabs a hammer off of a, uh, I'm going to watch him do like, just
watch a montage of him doing the exact same thing I did in the previous
montage, cause you know that like, but that's tapping it, he's looking at
it, he's trying to throw fire or he gets you to run through everything
and he stands right over your shoulder.
Yeah.
Right.
Interesting.
Just sharing significant looks with Bizard.
He looks at it and he's, he's perpLexed.
And, and then you notice that there's like kind of, uh, some
glint of recognition.
Where'd you say you went?
Well, um, I, we were, I don't know.
What are we telling people, Bizard?
Uh, to, uh, to find people in the woods.
Yeah.
Alydin and some kids were missing and that's sort of why to help.
And we went somewhere weird, dad.
I don't know what it was.
It was a weird place with scary things and monsters and a whole
bunch of children who we rescued.
So that's good.
Why do you ask?
Well, the Forge hasn't really gone out in a, in a long time.
Your mother mentioned you found like a letter.
Yeah.
I found a letter from Malin.
So my great, great, great grandma.
And it, it's, um, it's pretty woo-woo about beating it.
What do you mean it's woo-woo?
Well, here you can, you can read it and also you probably already knew
this because you know this place inside and out, but Bizard found
an etching inside, uh, the Forge.
Yeah.
You know about that one?
No.
Well, I mean, when we rebuilt it, we used a lot of the, the, the
material stone, of course, from great, great grands, uh, grands Forge.
Um, and, and yeah, I mean, it's never been, I've never had to
relight it, my father's never had to relight it.
His mother never had to relight it.
This is not to say, this is not a guilt trip.
Let me just preface it there, but this is to say that your great,
great, great grandmother Malin, how many times can we say great?
Yeah.
He's looking at the letter.
She made it, at least it's how it was told to me, is that she made
an offering through some sort of ritual so grand that it was to
keep the Forge lit and have her soul guide the hands of
everbanes throughout eternity.
For that to go out, are you sure you were just looking for kids in the woods?
Well, we were definitely just looking for kids in the woods.
Um, a lot of things happened.
There was instruments and they were attacking us.
There was a man made out of a banjo, um, sort of he had a banjo
and then it, we were floating in memories in space.
This all sounds like the nonsense I was saying after that one weekend
in high school when I was away for the night camping and I came home.
I know that, but this really happened.
Yeah.
Uh, the, the way you just explained it sounds very familiar and it was
exactly the situation we were just dealing with.
Somebody was under or made a deal with this other, other planer being.
And, uh, it just kind of backfired on them.
And so we wound up in that realm.
I think the, the Feywild is, maybe it could have been the shadow
fell as creepy as it was, but that's, that's where we were.
So I'm just, yeah.
My G G G G ma no G G it.
That's not easier.
I thought that might be easier than we could just call her grandma.
Malin.
Let's just call her Malin.
It's easier.
Um, you think she made a deal with the same thing that the
banjo man made a deal with?
I mean, you're right.
And we're talking, this is two, this is a coincidence.
Everything that I've heard told and it's, it's piece by piece
kind of slowly coming back is there was nothing nefarious in the rituals.
She's she did to keep it lit and as, as it's, as it's, I mean, it's
as it's outlined here and as it, as it was told, like she did it for good.
Yeah.
I read it like she gave something to the fire as opposed to making a deal
with a outside scary entity.
But I don't know how to give a thing to a fire, especially if the place
can't be made to hold the fire.
Exactly.
As I've never had to or seen, I don't have a lot of like firsthand
information on when rolls arise.
Like you can when you're an adult at your parents.
Look, I've got an old, I've got several old boxes of books that have
been passed down that are just collecting dust.
Like maybe there's something in there.
Maybe there's more journal entries from Malin.
Maybe, maybe there's something that can give us a clue back at the house.
Great.
Thank you.
I don't know if this being an other worldly kind of situation or, you
know, something mystical, perhaps something from another plane could help out.
I kind of had a realization dreaming the other night and woke up with a
spell in mind.
And with the adventure that we went through the, you know, those portals
and everything, summoning came to mind.
And I will hear easier to be shown.
And I begin drawing an outline, a chalk circle on the ground, a lot of
squares, triangles, concentric, it's amazing.
It's like he's, it'll blow your mind.
Okay.
And in the center of it, kind of the elemental symbol for the fire plane.
And I sum it up, I sum it up a few mag or a few magma methods.
Whoa.
Which, what, what's happening?
Just seeing if perhaps this could wind up getting things started again, kind
of breaking the idea of what's being said, but maybe we can just, you
know, force it, uh, with a little, little devilish magic.
So, okay.
Oh, okay.
Uh, you don't want to read the books.
You just want to bring in fire monsters.
Okay.
Cool.
Yeah.
I mean, that's one way to do it.
No, that's so interesting.
Yeah.
I just totally dad commenting on your magic never done it himself.
No idea about it.
What, um, Kyle, what, what do I, what
are we looking at?
So we're looking at four of these little imp like creatures.
They're having, uh, they look very slender.
They're flying with like very like kind of flamey and magmas
dripping off of their wings and off of their chin.
They're a lot.
Their tongue is just like lava dripping out of their mouth.
Um, really sharp claws and nails and they're just kind of
floating there like, Hey buddy, what's up?
And, or, well, Russ, you can do whatever.
Yeah.
No.
You've just summoned four methods into the space.
You don't have any control over them, right?
No, I, I do.
Yeah, you do.
Yeah.
They're friendly to me and my companions.
Got it.
Yeah.
It's not.
Oh yeah.
It's not like summon minor demon or whatever.
I'm actually conjuring minor elementals.
So they're actually elementals, not devils.
My bad.
Got it.
Yeah.
How could you explain element?
You're trying to dumb things down for me.
They look like they're from hell.
Yeah.
Sure.
Uh, how fun.
Okay.
So maybe, um, maybe Bonwyn is like, sure, those are all of this.
And, and we'd obviously cleaned out the forge of everything to your, you
know, and I start like kind of getting some kindling back in there and trying
like, okay, can you, yeah, try.
Yeah.
Uh, okay.
Uh, jab, jab, jab, jib with a Y.
Go on in there and, uh, they go in there and they stand, you know, in a
circle around each other and, uh, they just exhale their fire breath
right into the center of it.
From the outside, you can see like this big burst of flame.
You hear them kind of cackling to each other as they're trying to light this.
You, you hear the crackle of wood.
Um, and then everything is quickly extinguished and then like a plume
of smoke pours out and the methods come.
What if I put this in there?
Should I put, I'm going to put this in there and, and I, I take that
little dagger that I, that I had made and my dad doesn't know what's going on.
It's fine.
What, what are you doing with the, what, what are you doing with the dagger?
Well, I said I needed to, you know, give something and need to lose something.
And this is really valuable to me.
So I thought maybe this could be a small sacrifice to the, to the flame in the
forge and if that doesn't work, you're here.
Who's the creepy child in the corner?
Look, sir.
We've just been watching until the window.
Yeah.
No, that's, that's fair.
I mean, it's good to see all of you again.
Um, okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um, that is a recharge ability that I have to do.
So I rolled four D six and I got three out of four sixes.
So three of them can do it quickly again.
So is it Jim with a Y that can't do it this time?
Yeah, poor Jim with a Y.
Okay.
The three of them pile back in, uh, with the dagger and same thing goes.
You're watching from the outside.
You see like a wood spark, um, around the blade and then same thing.
Everything seems like it gets like sucked into a place and then smoke
shoots back out, um, the dagger remains.
Um, and then the three of them pile back, or I guess four of them, because
they would have tried to go, all go in, four of them pile back out.
Thank you for trying to take some Tom's and grab it just in case it's
hot and I put it down.
Yeah.
Um, y'all, y'all, y'all are dismissed.
Y'all can, y'all can head on back and I break concentration on the, on the spell.
Uh, at the same time, like, uh, there is a loud ringing in my ears as blood
just begins to pour out of them.
And I'm saying, Oh God, what did I do?
Oh my Bizard.
Oh my God.
Is your friend okay?
What's Oh my God.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
This, no, this is clean.
Let me, it's okay.
It's okay.
Everything's good.
Shh.
Well, I'll just, okay.
I'm, I'm going to get a napkin.
Is he okay?
I don't know.
I don't, I feel like I don't know anything anymore, to be honest.
Why don't we go take a look through some of those books?
Okay.
Maybe we'll find something.
Maybe we can, maybe your mom will be back and she can patch up your friend's
head, uh, summons fire monsters, bleeds from his ears.
I actually really want mom to meet his mom.
Cause I think they'll hit it off.
Uh, who's his mom?
Her name's Clara and she's, she's taking over.
Yeah.
No, Claire has been down for lemonade a couple of times.
Oh, Justin.
Okay.
Wow.
Even though she was kind of redoing the whole store.
Yeah.
She's been very busy.
I helped her with some of the shelter in there.
Wow.
Okay.
Great.
Did they like each other?
Oh yeah.
They hit it off.
Uh, they're starting a canasta club.
Of course they are looking for new members and he's pointing to cav.
Is cav been there this whole time?
This whole time.
Just quietly sitting in the corner with Alvin.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm in there.
I did not know.
I did say you were all there at the beginning.
Did you?
Yeah.
Oh, I missed that.
Cause that's where we left.
It was like, well, we're going to try and fix the forge.
So we all went there.
Whoops.
That's okay.
This cav in is two guards.
Yeah, like two guards.
Yeah.
Have I not paid my like peace bond or anything?
No, they're there.
Yeah.
The guards are waiting outside, but they, there's one at the
front, one at the back.
Good thing they don't know about the tunnels.
I think everyone knows about the tunnels now, don't they?
Pretty wide knowledge now.
Maybe they don't know we have one.
I don't think we want to go in there though.
We cut down to your parents place and your dad leads you into his
workshop and you see that he's been building lots of chairs and what
looks like bed frames, a lot of different pieces, presumably.
For the school says that, but just mind yourself.
Don't, don't step on anything sharp.
They're here.
He grabs a couple of things and puts them up on the table.
This is this, this kind of production level is so much, makes
so much more sense for stuff for the kids than just like pumping
out canoes like you were.
So I'm glad I've really perfected the canoe.
Uh, you know, they started, you know, the business is booming.
Actually, there are lots of people trying it.
Uh, they're gorgeous, but this is like.
You're really making like a real material difference for those kids.
So thank you.
Oh, of course.
Of course.
Uh, here, give me a hand back here and he goes and goes to the back
and there's this huge stack of boxes.
It's gotta be one of these.
He's trying to reach up to the top there.
Hey, uh, you, you, uh, Kav was it right?
You're going to come help me with the ones up top here?
Sure.
Yeah, absolutely.
Right.
You start handing them down, passing them out and it's opening up boxes
they're coming down and maybe this one shuffles one to you.
Bonwyn, uh, there's old journals in here.
I don't know how far back they go.
Oh my God.
Not mine.
I hope.
Well, maybe this one's got the unicorn on it.
All that might.
Okay.
Nobody read that.
None of you.
Uh, we'll just put that back in the box.
Whoever finds it finds it and he passes it over to Bizard.
Um, everybody's kind of looking through and trying to find what, uh, trying
to find anything of any value.
Everybody want to roll either an investigation.
Yeah.
Probably just investigation.
Not one.
I'm too embarrassed about the thought that someone might read that journal
that I wrote when I was a lot of years old.
You are very distracted.
Snatching things from people's hands at this point.
Yeah.
I'm just going around looking like, yeah, yeah.
No, no, not that one.
No, no magic shit in that one.
Nope.
Nothing.
There's nothing important in that one.
Don't worry about it.
1813.
22.
Oh shit.
Ooh, ALex.
Do I have to roll a disadvantage?
Wait, can I see out of my other eye?
Yeah, you can see your eyes.
I feel like I probably makeshift an eye patch or something.
So as to not concern people around me, I'm tired of getting asked
questions, but my shiny eye.
Which has actually been like counterproductive because now they're
asking, what did you do?
So many questions.
I'd just be like, I'm hooked it.
Mind your business.
Alydin, you're tossed a small box and you're filtering through.
There's only a few books in there.
There's, I mean.
I'm good if it got tossed at me.
Yeah.
Surprisingly.
A huge heavy box of books gets thrown at the child.
That's right.
Make a dexterity saving throw.
You pick out a book and something about this book reads like fairy
tale, but another part, there's a familiarity to it based on books
you've seen at Bizard's.
The title of this book is Flames Beyond Fire.
Sounds like a romance novel.
Is there a shirtless man on the front?
Some sort of firefighter, I'm sure.
Tom, write that down.
It's so good.
Instant bestseller.
Yeah, that would be.
I want to flip.
I want to flip through it.
This looks important.
Yeah.
You flip through it and you start to see things.
I mean, you don't know what exactly they're telling you, but there's a way
in which this book is written that leads you to believe there are magical
components to this book.
Like it's very familiar from tomes that you've read of Bizard's and
spell books and that sort of thing that he has at his shop and just the
way it's laid out, like this is jumping out to you, there's little
notes in some of the ledgers.
Bizard.
Yeah.
I waved the book.
I think I got a good one.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Check it out.
I'll open it up and flip through it.
What's it called again real quick?
Flames Beyond Fire.
A Coral Between Lovers.
The fire's in my pants.
Something about burning loins.
Okay.
Who's the author?
There is no author of this book.
Anonymous.
Okay.
Keep your secrets.
This is the best, most dangerous books.
Yeah.
Make an arcana roll as you take a look through this book.
That's only a 10.
Does anybody else have Reading Rainbow in their head?
Yes.
So much.
You, as you begin flipping through this book, have a very, very
vague memory of like just a little side class that was put on at Barnhart Swans.
Speaking of which, you can get the shirts now on our store.
Save it for the middle.
God damn it.
We're not going to have anything to talk about now.
Oh, we're going to be fine.
It'll be all good.
You have a very faint memory of this very rare form of magical influence.
It was referred to you as Anima Bound Fire.
The concept is flames tied to identity and memory.
Without further investigation, that's kind of where you're left based on what
you're seeing as you're flipping through.
Anima Bounds is the main character.
I am just writing a romance novel in my head.
Yeah, right.
I mean, yeah.
Yeah, this is, I'd have to, I'd have to spend more time.
I'm right though, it's important, right?
Huh?
It's important, right?
Yeah, you know, it's a, it's a good find for sure.
Um, it talks in here about an Anima Bound Fire where, uh, specific
fires and flames can be tied to like identities or, or memories.
Um, shit.
Swear jar, and I hold up my bucket.
Hold up three fingers, three silver.
I'll get you later.
Um, I mean, that kind of confirms like the, like the loss of the memory.
Uh, like, do you remember seeing what the memory that was lost?
What was inside there?
What was going on?
I can't recall right off hand.
The one that Bonwen lost?
The one that Bonwen lost.
Yeah.
It was just, just Everbane's and there didn't seem to be
anything super special about it.
It was empty, um, except for, you know, the things that are around.
He was smashing stuff, like picture frames and, and things like that.
I was just wondering if it's like a specific memory or the
idea of Everbane specifically.
Like, I don't know.
Maybe we got to go fix it.
I don't know.
Shit, I don't know.
That's not the one.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season two, episode 29, starring Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwen Everbane, Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design of today's episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound and sound effects are from
Epidemic Sound and Boom Library.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
And we'd like to say a huge thank you to our supporting
producers, Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Cat Waterflame,
Aguron Kierzen, Perry Matey, Jacob Madden, Old School Gamer D, Craig
Zeiss, L.A. Branton, and Chibs1012.
Have you been enjoying your time with Dumbgeons and Dragons?
Well, thank you so much for being here.
If you're looking for more of what you love, come over to
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where you're going to get a
seven day free trial.
And when you're a patron for at least three months, we're going to
send you some merch based on the tier you're at.
Come on over.
We hope to see you over there.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Have a great week. We'll talk to you soon.
Yeah, that's right. You tell them, Loki.
Paisley, don't everybody calm your shit.
I just hit record and said we're going to play.
Yeah, that's the those are the words they heard you saying,
I'm going to record.
And they were like, now, now scream, pull the cords off the table.
How do we make that fuzz sound happen?
We know they've been doing it.
There's like a tiny and quite ill made little.
Oh, my God, words.
Small knife, the word is thank you.
What I'm here for.
I appreciate it.
What the banjo man took from you.
That's right. The word dagger.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production.