Welcome back to Dumbgeons and Dragons. We'll begin in just a moment.
The words crawling across its body slow then freeze mid-letter. Ink bleeds backward into
the seams of parchment and stone as if pulled by an unseen hand. The quill blade softens,
collapsing into loose pages that scatter across the floor and fade into dust.
For a moment, there's nothing. Then, the room exhales. The shelves grind once more,
not in threat, but in retreat. Stone books slide back into the walls, titles erasing
themselves as they vanish until the chamber is bare save for the far wall.
Where a door should be, there is only stone, unbroken, unmarked. A pause stretches for too
long and then the floor shivers. Fine lines etch themselves outward from a single point
at the chamber's center, not cracks but deliberate marks. A diagram emerges, circles,
angles intersecting paths carved with impossible precision. A map. Vintersmouth sits at its heart,
not centered but pierced through as if something passes through the city rather than rests within
it. Three lines extend outward. Two are still. The third flickers, its edges blurring,
shifting by the second, sliding across the stone like a shadow that can't decide where to settle.
As you watch, the line drifts slowly away from the city, away from here.
The air grows heavy. Pressure builds behind your eyes like a thought trying to finish itself.
You understand that this was never an entrance. It was a marker. A false
index. Perhaps a test. A way to see who would come looking and how they would read the record.
Behind you, faint and distant, the sound of quills resume. Not here but somewhere else.
Ink hesitates before writing as if considering you. The words appear uneven,
pressure changing mid-stroke. Seeker accepted. Then, after a pause, entry requires contribution.
One final mark bleeds through the stone.
Not words but a name-shaped blur, half-formed and familiar.
The stone walls around you begin to rattle and shake.
Alistair runs over to the map on the wall and begins sketching, as furiously as he can,
onto parchment. We have to get as much information as we can as stones begin to
fall around you. You look back and the way you came in, the long hallway has reappeared
and you see daylight down at the end.
Quick Alistair, rub it hard.
Dumbges and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast and we'd love for you to join us today at
patreon.com slash dumbdraggingcast. You'll get a 7-day free trial to check things out.
And now, let's get right to it. Fuck it, let's play.
Quick Alistair, rub it hard.
Do the rubbing real hard.
Is he doing a rubbing or is he drying?
Because if he's drying, we're rubbing.
We don't have time for me to watch.
Kyle set the tone.
Yeah, that's great.
We're in danger.
Yeah, it's a problem.
He was sketching it, but perhaps he takes Bizard's cue and instead rubs the engraving,
which seems to be working a lot quicker for him.
He grabs it and looks at it and he's like, I think this will do.
All of you book it down the hallway.
You hear stones filling the room behind you
and the hallway collapsing in on itself.
You feel dust and air pushing you out into the street as you all leap through the door
at the last moment and fall onto the pavement where onlookers are blasted by this dust
out into the air.
They're coughing and looking and there's a bit of panic and confusion
and you look up and you had gone in.
It was evening.
You heard the call of the bells as you were at the bird awakening
and now it appears to be morning.
Is everyone okay?
I think so.
Yeah, yeah, I think so.
Because like I kind of thought we might die.
Oh, always at this point, right?
I mean, yeah, a little bit.
Yeah.
Where's Alydin?
Shit, where's Alydin?
Can we look back?
Is everything just destroyed?
Everything is just destroyed.
Okay, no, no, no, we need to get back in there.
Okay, but like, how do we get back in?
I don't know, but we can't just leave Alydin in there.
It's Alydin.
She's just a child.
I'm going to pull out the thread and I'm going to walk right back to the center of that
and I'm just going to start unspooling it.
It was like, you make a fucking door right now.
You begin unspooling, like pulling at the thread and as you pull at the thread,
like the little bit that you're able to get at just spins the spool on top of it.
It's like you're not actually pulling the string off of the bobbin.
Okay.
It's just revolving around and you hear a faint cough from somewhere in the rubble.
There's a bit of movement off to the side and
like some stones, small stones kind of push their way out and Alydin reaches a hand out.
Okay, I mean, I'm going to go help dig.
I'm not just watching the child dig their way out of the rubble.
No, I'm not watching.
I'm just listening to your beautiful description.
No, I imagine we were like pawing at the rubble.
Indeed.
You pull her out and she coughs and then you hear a call from across the courtyard.
It's the voice of June.
Alydin, what the hell are you doing over there?
You're supposed to be in school.
Alydin picks herself up and brushes herself off.
Do I have to go to school right now?
Are you okay?
Are you broken?
I'm like giving her the once over, make sure no bones are broken.
Doesn't appear to have any broken bones.
She's got a couple scrapes, but more or less she's just covered in dust and dirt.
I mean, after that, I'd say, yeah, you need to go to school.
School's a much safer option.
I think that's a great idea.
We love you and we value your education, so it's probably best if you go with June now.
Absolutely.
I love you too.
It's true.
Don't do anything fun without me though, okay?
Nope, definitely not.
We wouldn't dream of it.
June comes over and grabs her by the arm.
And what were you doing in the rubble?
Come on, we've got some things to learn.
Alydin looks back at you and just waves solemnly.
She heads off towards school for the day.
Sometimes I forget she's just a kid and then something really dangerous
happens and I feel terrible.
Yeah, that was terrifying.
That was so bad.
Yeah.
Thank God for school.
That's what I'm always saying.
It's a good cold open.
We end on positive education.
There we go.
And we worked hard to get those schools back for this town, so like...
Yep.
It's true.
We worked hard to get schools back.
The four of you are standing there.
Alydin has just walked off.
Everybody hears a very familiar voice come down from the city hall stairs.
And it says, Kavlaran, are you back from leave?
Oh, good.
This is a disaster.
We need somebody to watch it.
Thank you for saying yes.
Okay.
Yes, no, we just need somebody.
There's people putting up barricades around the rubble.
You just need to stand here.
Don't let anybody near it.
It will be perfectly fine.
We'll come back and check on you in just a moment.
Everybody else, get out of here.
We need to take care of this.
Kavlaran, don't move.
Sure, I'll staple to the spot.
Don't worry about it.
Could somebody tell us, I don't know, what time it is?
Well, it's morning.
What do you mean?
What time is it?
Did you not wake up this morning and then come here and...
Well, no, I was inside the...
Oh, you went inside.
In there and it was night when we went in.
It seemed like we weren't in there for that long.
How was it inside?
Oh, dangerous at the end.
Yeah, a lot of this kind of situation.
This rubble, this...
Yes, well, no reason that Kavlaran should stay here,
remain on site, deter curiosity,
and record any changes that happen.
Okay.
Yeah, I'll do that.
Nina hands you a notebook.
Kavlaran, are you excited to see more paper?
Always.
Oh, you know, it's like...
How amazing.
Number one for me.
And I just walk around with like the clipboard,
and I say, nothing to see here.
Nothing to see here, anybody.
Nothing to see here.
He's really kind of doing well with this new role.
I wasn't sure.
It seems outside his normal thing,
but he's doing pretty good.
He should try yelling at people more often.
Yeah.
You see Alistair writing in one of his notebooks.
He's mumbling to himself, is it daytime now?
We went in there, it was nighttime.
We weren't in there for that long.
Were we in there for that long?
You fall asleep on a regular basis.
What has time lost to you?
Well, I don't know.
I don't think I fell asleep very much in there, did I?
No, not much.
Not as much as usual.
Maybe the air in there is different.
Actually, I don't think you fell asleep at all.
Well, that's interesting.
We're going to need a copy of that map.
Oh, yes, of course, of course, of course.
He holds up the map.
Here's the rubbing.
I rubbed all over it, just like you said, Basar.
Excellent. Great job.
Thank you.
Do you have work to do, Kavlaran?
Should we go and get you a snack or something?
How long you think you're going to be here?
You didn't really get a lot of warning.
Yeah, there wasn't a lot of details.
Let's take care of this for you.
I pull out a different spool of thread.
It's like this silver thread and I start putting it around where the door was
and I'm going to ritual cast alarm.
So if anybody crosses over it, we know it's happening.
And that way we can fuck off and do whatever we want.
And Kavlaran doesn't have to listen to Nina.
Breaking rules with wizardry by Basar.
Love it.
That's right.
Okay, so snack, though?
I mean, yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, you know what I was going to say,
or should we like get into this whole thing?
But no.
Well, we can do that over the snack.
And honestly, if I've learned anything in the past few months,
it's that if you have an opportunity to eat, bathe, go to the bathroom,
you take it because you don't know when the next opportunity is coming.
You don't know.
So are we going to go eat first?
Are we going to go to the bath houses or what's the order here?
I mean, I say eat.
I mean, they used to have that buffet over at the bath houses.
Do they still have that?
Yeah, it wasn't that good, though.
Remember how sick you got that time?
Yeah, well, sure.
But I get sick at most buffets.
So I ordered the soggy waffle and I was not happy about it.
It was too soggy.
It was as described.
I mean, yes.
Yeah, yes.
Yeah, probably just like them buns, though.
Sure.
Them buns, though.
My treat.
We're going for snacks.
I don't know what you wanted us to do, Russ, but we're going for snacks.
You can do whatever you want.
This is a world where you have complete control over what your characters do.
Tried to get Kavlarne to work.
That didn't work.
So nope.
They 86'd it so fast.
Didn't want to leave.
We already lost Allen.
And why are we just going to leave Kav milling around the center of town?
We want to stay together.
We're best friends.
It's a business owner episode.
Yeah, Tom, just sit there quietly.
You're guarding something.
Just kidding.
We kidnapped you with us.
That's right.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
No, I don't even want to talk about Fred Durst.
I mean, it's kind of a nod to once you start doing it, you just kind of start rolling with it.
Yeah, the idea of Fred Durst into the middle.
Yeah.
And then, of course, everybody will sing the famous song in their head to themselves.
That one, they did it all for it.
And that's when we just transition into something else.
Like, how awesome you are for being here listening to us.
I mean, so true.
Oh, the best.
Very, very true.
You know what I did is I put the memory card in.
And then I didn't actually hit record.
So as the quality on our track changes, that's what happened.
Just so you know.
Yeah.
I love that.
It's a little adventure.
It's good now.
Yeah, it's good now.
Oh, perfect.
You weren't rolling.
Well, we're past it then.
I was not rolling.
But now you're rolling.
That's terrible.
What?
You did it on purpose.
Just play it off like you did it on purpose.
Oh, yeah.
Look at you.
That's right.
Yeah.
It's a good time.
Good stuff.
Let's never mention Limp Bizkit again.
Unless they happen to ever be our patron.
Oh, wow.
In that case, we would mention them because they would get an episode dedicated.
And they're part of the $30,000 Limp Bizkit only tier.
Exactly.
Or if you just want to make your username Fred Durst.
You could say, hey, supported by Fred Durst.
Just flag me when you do.
Jess, don't do it out of principle.
I can see Jess typing.
Like, is this something that people could just sign up for under famous people's names?
Absolutely.
Look at our listeners.
Literally, we have names that are not names for whatever you want.
I'm going to come in tomorrow as this is released,
and everybody's going to be Fred Durst.
That's what I love about her.
Or any other member of the band.
I'll have to look it up.
Yeah, we all know the other member's names.
Yeah.
Wes?
Wes Borland?
Wes Borland, that's right.
Fucking son of Al Borland.
Son of Al.
Richard Karn's figment.
I don't think so, Tim.
But no, you do get an episode dedication to you when you are a patron.
If it's Richard Karn, I'm going to lose my mind.
God, I fucking hope it is.
But if it isn't, I'm going to love them just as much.
Yes, it's not Richard Karn, but it is Alexander Wright.
Thanks, Alexander.
Thank you so much.
If you're having just one of those days you don't want to,
then we hope we can turn around by shouting you out
and telling you how much we love you.
Absolutely.
We appreciate your support.
Does anybody remember the hook of Chocolate Starfish
and the Hot Dog Flavored Water?
I mean, that was the album, wasn't it?
That was the album title.
I'm pretty sure there was a track named that, too.
I did not have the album.
There might have been a title track situation, is what you're thinking.
I had the album.
Sorry, everybody.
It's okay.
I had the album, too.
You had somebody sending you CDs.
Yeah.
Was it Columbia House?
Is that who was sending you CDs?
No, I had family who worked for Warner and Universal.
And they were just like, here's Christmas.
So you got the CDs with the notches out of them.
The promo CDs.
That's fine.
Yeah, you ask for one rap album one time,
and you only get boxes full of rap albums, which are great.
Love the genre, but you got to mix it up a little bit,
like throwing some Dolly Parton every now and again or something, right?
Yeah.
So thank you, Alexander, for being here on this journey.
Thank you.
I keep forgetting we're in a middle, like, seriously.
We just had the gook hang,
which if you are awesome like Alexander
and you come on over to Patreon.
Yeah, come to the gook hangs.
You can join our monthly gook hangs,
where we do a kind of shoot the shit and talk about random stuff.
I feel like we should explain what we did.
So gook hang makes no sense.
That's not a word.
It is so far from that, yeah.
Yeah.
We used to do it on Google Hangouts, guys, when that was a thing.
And we called it the gook hang.
That was 10 years ago.
We still call it that.
So now people are like, I don't know what that is.
I'm not going to that.
But we just hang out and have a little chitty chat.
And we played a really fun game.
It's true.
We host on Discord.
And they did try to change the name multiple times and I wouldn't.
It's gook hang forever.
Yeah, always has to be.
I only remember it's weird because Aidan was like,
hey, what are you guys recording tonight?
And I was like, oh, we don't record.
It's the gook hang.
And he is like, the what now?
And I was like, oh, right.
I normally translate that from us to you.
I'm sorry, the what?
That just gave me the outside perspective of someone being like,
not tonight.
It's the blibli borp.
Yeah, exactly.
He was like, I don't know what you're saying.
Like, we're saying it like it is a real word and it's not.
Yeah.
Don't worry.
We're having fun and we're not doing anything dangerous.
Bye.
Anyway, if you remember, you should come because it's really fun.
We played Monster Dating Game.
We did.
And maybe it'll be a different game next time.
Maybe.
We got a list of them now so we could spring on any improv game at all.
Please do.
I love it.
Okay.
Patreon.com slash dumpdragoncast.
Join us for all the fun at the first Tuesday of the month.
Did we say first Tuesday?
No, we didn't.
I yelled it out.
That's the gook hang first Tuesday.
I would have caught it in post.
But yeah, thanks for being here.
Love you.
Have a great week.
Bye.
Love you.
Cut to them buns though.
You've got a lovely beverage, a warm beverage, hot chocolate or coffee,
whichever you prefer.
There's fresh croissants because it's very morning as previously described.
The freshest of baked goods have been laid out before you.
You've got the little egg bites too that everybody's raving about.
That's laid out and Alistair puts the map out onto the table.
So this is this is what I got.
You know the town in the area the best.
And he kind of he's looking at the map.
Then he kind of spins.
There was one glowing, wasn't there?
Yeah, kind of flickering.
Yeah, I only had one color, so I didn't.
Was it this this one?
And he points to one pointing off into the hills.
I don't know.
Do you guys remember?
That looks like is that going up to the mines?
Yeah, I have eye for detail so I can.
Really, it's to find a hidden creature or object,
but it's got to be good for looking at maps, right?
I mean, I would have to think so.
Roll investigation.
Bonwyn for your eye for detail.
You can roll photography.
Well, there is sometimes you have like map makers to it.
That's true that but I love when that shit comes into play.
Thank God that was with advantage.
That's a 23.
OK, you're looking at them.
Otherwise it would have been a seven.
You're looking at the map and Alistair's like spinning it around
trying to remember and you take it from him and you just take a minute.
Kind of correct the map in front of yourself
so that ventures myth is oriented in a way that makes sense for looking at this map.
And there are three lines.
There is one that goes off through the hills towards the mountains,
which as previously mentioned, may be in the direction of the mines.
There's one that heads down into the south
and then there's one that you distinctly recognize as being the glowing one,
which is heading off into the north.
In the sketching of the map,
you see some symbols which could be the forest and then it continues to go off.
And your long experience here, Baldwin,
you know that somewhere off in that direction,
you can't exactly remember how far, but there's a ghost town.
The river diverges and it's a dry like a dry bed.
Why the town, at least why you were told and through history of the town,
why it was abandoned and ventures myth was made more into the port town that it is.
But that line, you distinctly remember being the one glowing in the
in the cave area that you were in and the library that you were in.
And that's the direction that it's pointing.
So player knowledge, this is like heading through the verboten forest to like
back in the olden times when we made our hilarious penis maps.
Exactly.
Perfect.
Alistair, do you have a different color of ink?
Because this, this line here, that one was the one glowing.
Sure.
Yeah. So if we could.
Filtering through his bed.
That'd be amazing.
Pulls his, here you go.
Thank you. So I don't, you're all sort of newish here.
There's like a ghost town over here.
It was like the original settlement.
You're like, you know, generations ago.
Wasn't that what the sheriff was talking about in the goblin caves?
Maybe.
Oh yeah, that rings a bell.
Yeah. So there was a settlement there,
but I think like the lake or the river dried up because they're,
you know, it kind of split.
So I don't know.
I mean, you know, the school's closed down.
I don't remember exactly if we were ever even really taught that.
But yeah, ghost town.
And that's the one that was lit up.
That's the one that was glowing.
Which tells me, warning, don't go there,
which secondarily tells me that's probably where we're going to go.
Yeah. Unless there's no point in deactivating something that can't be deactivated
and we need to prevent.
But I wonder, I wonder if we deactivated this one.
Does this this looks like it goes up into the into the hills.
It does.
I wonder if we deactivated that in a sense.
Oh, and that's why that one's not glowing.
Oh, interesting.
Russ, thinking back to those monsters,
like I'm trying to draw a connection of like appearance
and they're like the way their body was manifested,
if it was like inky in any kind of way,
if there might be a connection to their biology.
There wasn't specifically anything inky about them.
They were definitely more like muscle bones in you,
like a traditional monster that you'd thought of.
Aberration monstrosity.
There was, as you went down into the mines,
like there was a portal effect that you did see.
In fact, Bizard contemplated going through it at the time.
Actually, I took a memory of that.
Like I saved a memory of that portal.
Yes, yes you did.
And did that happen to look anything like the door that we just went through?
What does it look like when you're calling upon that memory?
So I know the spell is kind of odd, but like I encode thoughts.
Duration is only eight hours,
but if you cast a spell while concentrating on the spell,
let's see, through this charge,
I can literally just pull the memory from my head
and like view it.
So again, it's another one of those things
where I just pull like this strand out.
I'm just going to do the magic thing of dropping it into a bowl
and saying, oh yeah, like this is my soup, whatever.
Okay.
Was anyone else picturing like the magicians
like tied up handkerchiefs coming out of his head?
That's right.
Yeah, I have a good chicken noodle soup going on
and it literally depicts the memory in the noodles.
I love it.
Okay.
Okay, yeah, I like that a lot.
So yeah, you pull the memory and lead it into this bowl of soup that you have.
And before you, like instantly you and Cav are teleported back there.
Bonwyn, you hadn't seen this.
You weren't there.
You weren't present for that.
But the two of you are transported back to that moment
and the four of you, five of you are in the caves.
You see this, it looks more rift-like,
more like any portal you ran into with the banjo man.
Oh, okay.
So going through the trees,
going through different doorways,
transporting, you know, ending up in different places.
There's more of a direct connection there.
That said, now that you're analyzing this memory,
what you perhaps didn't notice in the moment
as things were falling down around you
and monsters were trying to eat your face off,
is that there are distinct runes that are present.
It's not like they're written in some sort of phrase,
but you see them scattered throughout the space.
A lot of them very faint and worn down, worn over.
But roll a history, roll a history check.
Got a 12.
Bonwyn, you can roll us too, because you are seeing this memory.
A seven for Cav.
19.
Ten and up, you're making the connection.
Is you, the runes you see,
so the portal you see very similar
to your banjo man experience,
to going to the fey that way.
The runes, however, aren't as similar
as those that were along the pathways
that you were walking, anything you saw in his house.
They're more similar to some runes you saw
just in this library area, in this false entrance.
And there are distinct differences between the two.
Can I do my cool move, like I pulled in the library,
where I can use my stone cunning
to check history, the origin of stone work.
I'm proficient in that, to see if it will,
I don't know, give me any info other than,
like last time it basically just told me
it was like ancient and hadn't been used in a long time.
But, you know, something like that.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, we pulled that in, and like it told you
that there was definite dwarven work
that went into this.
Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
21.
Looking at this memory that Bazaar just pulled,
it's on a loop.
He pulled a specific set of time,
like you see monsters jumping out,
you see the portal, and then you see a collapse.
Looking at the carvings underground,
like this is different.
This is a very different space.
This is mining carving.
Like, there's no real distinction of who did this.
The reason why is that they were mining for minerals,
for ore, for any number of things.
The runes, however, you don't draw any historical significance
to you in terms of specific stone.
Can I also, what would I try to see if I know the runes?
Also history, or like?
Could be history, or religion, or arcana, if anybody.
Arcana might be a little more along those lines.
Yeah.
No, OK.
Well, just kidding.
Love that.
The distinction you see is that although the spaces
are different, the portal mechanisms are different,
like the general vibe of them is different,
there are those same similarities.
So there is a connection within those specific
runes that you're seeing.
OK.
So not totally dissimilar.
No, seems like the two are connected,
and it seems like we have the actual archives,
and then this was a, it said it was a false index.
So we could just call that, like, what, the fee?
F-I?
Oh, sure, yeah.
Yeah, sure, yeah.
I've read about false indexing.
I don't, it's, they seem to pop up in the texts
as more of a, as more of this, as more of a marker,
as more of it testing the space.
He puts his head on his hands, and he's just like,
you notice after a second, you think he's in thought,
but he's in fact falling asleep.
So to his point about testing a space,
the old city that dried up is lit up.
What if they failed?
And then that destroyed the town?
I mean, it could happen.
Yeah, I mean, nobody, like I said,
there always is just kind of like,
yeah, people used to live there, now they don't,
river dried up, blah, blah, blah,
but I mean, it could be anything, right?
Could be that.
I'm gonna go on the very, very extreme and say,
what if the people were indexed to be goblins,
and they moved into the caves,
and that's what happened to them.
I mean, that's an extreme, like,
woe out there kind of theory.
But they did have like that whole civilization,
the goblins.
Yeah, I feel a little bit worse.
Yeah, were those like, had been, huh,
I think it's maybe best not to think about that.
How could I have known?
You couldn't have known.
We were in danger.
It's true, but pretty wild and out there shit,
if that's what's actually happening.
I don't know, what are y'all's thoughts?
Well, I mean, I feel like we kind of
have to follow this path, right?
And at least see what we can see,
not just at the end, but also the journey there, right?
If there are signs of anything and-
Right, like clues to pick up along the way, sure, yeah.
Exactly, clues.
Should we go now?
Bonwyn, does anybody know how long it's been
since that town was abandoned?
Do your parents remember by chance, or?
I mean, this was so long ago.
Like, generations and generations ago,
even they wouldn't know.
I mean, there's a chance.
You know, before the schools all shut down,
there was a pretty good library.
There probably still is on the noble side.
I mean, there could be something there,
like an actual history.
You know, we've been kind of,
kind of living in the moment for a while.
I think we utilize our resources,
and Kav, you have a fantastic resource up at City Hall
who could go and be a gopher for us
in getting texts that are like-
Yes, an expert at finding information in books.
Exactly.
He's the best.
We have more important things to do.
Oh, great idea.
Oh, perfect.
Plus, I miss the little guy.
I wonder what he's been doing.
We haven't seen him in a while.
We haven't seen him since you went away.
It's been a minute.
Probably just putting lotion on his mom's feet from what I hear.
Probably been doing that.
I mean, I've missed him.
He's a good dude.
He's a sweet guy.
Yeah.
Do we go to City Hall?
Is that rude?
I mean, that's where he's going to be, so.
Yeah.
Maybe you should wait outside, though,
because you are supposed to be explicitly at that.
But I mean, you know, that's close to City Hall, right?
Yeah, I'll just head over there and tell people that there's nothing to see here.
And you guys hit up City Hall, and we'll meet back up in like an hour?
Yeah, I don't think it'll take us.
I mean, he'll see us, right?
Yeah.
We'll just tell him to go do the job and then meet us for dinner tonight.
Yes.
Perfect.
And then, as an extra little treat,
in case he's not super inclined to skip out on work to do it with us,
he knows he has a dinner with you at the end of the day to look forward to.
Who could resist?
And a paid dinner at that.
Indeed.
Love it.
Okay, I love this.
Are we bribing a government official?
I think we are hiring someone freelance to do a research project.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 4 Episode 52 Starring Amy More as Alydin, Carla
Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave, Kyle Klasset as Bizarre
the Wizard, and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue, editing, and sound design of today's episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babiak.
Music is from Epidemic Sound, and sound effects are from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library, and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garba.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers, Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babiak, Angaron Kierzen, Perry Matey,
Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Old School Gamer D,
Craig Zeiss, L.A. Branton, Chibs 1012, and Kudzu828.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast,
and all of our amazing community help make sure that we have adventures for you every
single week.
Come join us today, patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
We hope to see you over there, and you have yourself, right now, a great week.
Yes, and we'll talk to you very, very soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.