Looking for Dumbgeons and Dragons? Well, you found the right place. We'll begin in a moment.
We see a picture of this quaint little home with a white picket fence sitting in the
middle of an open field. That house begins to shake back and forth and sound emanates from
it and windows smash. We see fire pouring out of those windows. Inside we see Bonwyn rushing
room to room lighting anything she can on fire as Bizard walks down the seemingly endless hallway
being chased or at least slowly cornered by more and more of these instrument monsters that
have come to life. Upstairs Kavlaran you've knocked down Alydin's parents and Alydin you
sit up in bed and throw your legs over and go to stand up and you stumble and fall forward.
Kavlaran make a dexterity saving throw please or no not a saving throw because you're not in
danger. Make an athletics or make a don't let the child hit the floor. Gotcha.
Operation continue saving Alydin. She didn't even expect to see me here.
Right and then she totally wasn't even stoked when I busted in the door like what the fuck.
Oak would have been so happy to see me. Maybe it's Kavlaran the heroic, Kavlaran the magnanimous,
like now it's a whole different thing. He's saving people. Kavlaran the ever giving.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master Russ More
he him. Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin she her. Do you want to kill them
before we go? Carla Maxstead as Bonwyn Everbane she her. You would recognize that booty.
Tom Laird is Kavlaran Goldweave he him. Cav used to be a touring musician so he's
well familiar with destroying hotel rooms thank you. And Kyle Claset is Bazaar the Wizard
he him. This is a problem. Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast.
You can join us today at patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where you'll get access to
hangouts backstage access recordings a whole lot of extra episodes and we know you love those
so come come give it a try plus when you sign up before the end of April 2025 you're going to
save 25% off your first month or your first year 25% off your first full year is a pretty
great deal if I don't say so myself patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast we hope to see you over
there and now fuck it let's play uh that is a 13 to acrobatics okay yeah you like catch
her arm as she falls forward Alydin you feel weak like you you felt this these waves come
throughout your stay in this ethereal home um but you feel like walking is difficult
at this moment like you're trouble grasping at things I think I'm as you go no you go ahead
uh I was gonna ask like Russ uh is there anything like is Alydin saying anything like mumbling and
coherently or just quiet or will Amy take it away Amy is Amy is still in full control she
just is losing yeah so yeah sorry I think I'm gonna just need a little help or like a sec
I don't I don't want to stay can I can you help me get it I need to get out yeah we have to get
out of here 100 kid uh let's get out let's do it desperate to know if Alydin lets that kid
pass because she's in a weakened state or points it she does she lets it go
oh wow okay it's not the time it's not just maybe not but I'm filing it away yeah
you only get so many thank you something calves not used to a big check mark for the knocking
down the parents and rescuing but like a small negative for the kid yeah Alydin will remember
this you're on the list condescending twice on the third time it doesn't go over well for
anybody okay um and you russ you mentioned I saw a glint and I thought it was in music box
or did I just fill in the the background yeah so uh just to reset that part of the scene so on
the dresser there is a music box that is continually playing it has been for as
long as you've been in the space um below the dresser it looks like there's a broken
floorboard and something metallic caught your eye underneath this floorboard okay and that's
below the dresser yeah like yeah it's like the the leg of the dresser is like on top of it
a little bit like kind of leaning in a little bit yeah all right um as I as I catch Alydin
and say that we should get out of there um I take a bit of a closer look at the
parental figures I guess do their music boxes like kind of match the one that's on the
dresser like their music box heads uh like design wise just if they have like any
yeah um yes there are definite similarities like in the style of of wood that appears to be
making up whatever the head structure is um a lot of the engravings and carvings along the
side appear very similar to the smaller box and they both have the same spinning uh we say
ballerina yeah we both have the same spinning ballerina and as you've knocked them down
all three do have the same winding mechanism just obviously larger in scale okay um as I see
this on the two I knocked down and on the dresser I like with my other free arm that hasn't caught
Alydin I want to like pull the dresser over and like throw it to the floor sort of thing
okay uh make a strength check please you're fucking trashing my room absolutely
actually even though Alydin spent all the day before just just trashing the room just
trying you can't be a touring musician so he's well familiar with destroying hotel rooms thank
you yeah uh oh and you said strength yes please 16 okay uh yeah you pull Alydin out
of the way and throw this down um which um drawers start to to pour out but yeah
crashes down to the ground that leaving that floorboard open if that's what you were
yeah I was kind of wondering if the floorboard like springs open at all like it was holding it
down or kind of what's going on yeah like pulling it forward like it even cracks into
the floorboard more and then the leg itself pulls it up uh like splintering the floorboard
which does appear secured closer to the wall um but yeah splinters it open so that you can
see further inside um and it looks like there is a how musical is how um would he know what a
tuning fork is or do you want me to describe it as Kavlaran would see it if he doesn't know
what a tuning fork uh Kavlaran thinks it's like a fancy hot dog roaster yes exactly
just a really short one yeah just like a really small one yeah like a travel size yeah
so yeah the small and he's gonna grab it okay what are you doing I think like this
caught my eye I think we should take it well then I'm like you know I like shiny things I'm taking
I kind of lean that awkward thing where he's holding me up by my arm but I'm reaching in
the opposite direction like like an a-hole um and I want to pick up which I'm assuming the music
box that fell off of the dresser didn't break no no of course it didn't I want it landed
actually pristine on the bed which was just equidistant from where the dresser had fallen
it is made of wood there's a lot of fire in this house yeah I'm
I assume I can smell that smoke yeah yeah I think we need to take this stairs yeah
uh okay you grab the music box you grab the tuning fork um do you want to kill them before
we go I just wasn't expecting that yes I don't know I think we should just go
oh okay
disappointing fine another strike
jump back into initiative order downstairs bizarre this hallway is not ending and now everything
that was in the hallway so all of the violins the trumpets um the cello is still trying to
track down Bonwyn so yeah the trumpets and the violins are like climbing the walls and the
floors making their way towards you you still have mage hand holding your tuning fork down
closer to the door my my mage hand's just gonna move to me and I'm gonna take possession of
the actual tuning fork uh and before striking it or I'm not gonna strike it this time how
many how many violins are there I think we said three there are three violins
perfect then I am going to uh I'm going to take my blade and I'm actually gonna like
run the uh run the tuning fork along the edge of it creating a spark and using that to launch
scorching rays cool and uh so I'm gonna do a do a ray at each each one okay love it well
roll that that's a 12 to hit on the first one 24 on the second and 15 on the third
all three of those hit beautiful the first one takes 10 damage second one takes
eight damage and the third one takes nine damage that seems like a lot that does seem
like a lot of damage yeah scorching rays go um and like um all three of these violins as they
are their strings are moving them down the hall like they light on fire and like continue
to move their way down the hall towards you that was my action I still have blades ongoing
uh I am going to I'm gonna stand my ground okay yeah I'm gonna stand my ground and wait
right where I am okay Bonwyn you're in the dining room uh the cello is making its way
down to this this doorway that you are in there are no more egresses you've reached like the end
of end of the house as far as you're concerned um so dining room table there are three chairs
looks like it was set for a another set for a meal um there's a sideboard in this room a
window outside which as you look out it is um like pitch black night like you can see the
faintest wavings in the trees um and as you look into those trees you see the moonlight
glint off of the mannequin children that are all lined up along the tree line what about
those guys they're made of wood too oh what have I done stay there you turn back and face
the cello and um the table is set make and what are you better at investigation or perception
oh probably neither let's see um investigate oh definitely investigation okay roll investigation
please roll perception something looks off 23 okay yeah something looks off and you're
looking and there's there's perfect table setting for two of two of the three settings
the final one where there should be a fork you see a tuning fork which I think you know
in asking cav that question valid but Bonwyn would know because you could have made them
could have made them yeah I get a lot of magazines with all kinds of different
metal working in it so I've seen lots of different projects yeah so you see where
on this third spot there is a tuning fork where the fork would be normally placed
cool and cello straight out the door in front of you kitchen on fire
well my main plan was light everything on fire and I've done that I came here to
save Alydin and light some fires and I haven't found Alydin so you also would have heard
bizarre's first attempt at the tuning fork down from the front entry like
well that's what I was gonna say like I have been presented with a new thing to do
so I think I would I would um do that and maybe just uh like I said I have that that
little hammer so I would take it out and like you know try and get get a good ring off
that tuning fork all right off a piece of metal so you run you run over rush over to the table
not run it's not a big room so you rush over to it grab it and and make it ring make an
arcana or performance check please 10 same better than what I did same as I had previously
described for bizarre so you strike it and this note rings out and it's like visually like
there is a um expansion of energy that comes out from this which is unlike anything you've
ever seen look at all the house around you none of this is normal everything is yeah it
moves out into the space and and as it moves out into the space like you see the cello be
pushed back and against the wall and then it sucks back into the tuning fork and finishes
its ring how far is the cello from me uh and it's like between me and the door obviously
because it followed me in there yeah it was coming into the door so like you pushed it
back out into the hallway so um let's say like 15 15 feet because this is okay so it's always
space yeah what would on when do everything's on fire she tried the tuning fork
she's trying to see like what else have I got here oh how about this guys it's a classic oh
it's a classic oh the cello's back in the hallway yeah so you're alone in this space really
the only person can you just duck down when the cello comes and looks back in it's going to be
like oh she's not here oh yeah that's actually hilarious i'm going to open the window okay
and then i'm gonna i'm gonna duck under the uh the table i don't know how this thing sees
if it just senses me i don't know sure but um for now because in case it like wanders away
i don't need to engage with it i might just be able to like sneak out behind it
i don't know what it's gonna do it's fine it's fine i got you yeah okay so cello knocked back
out you're going to go slide open the window uh make a stealth roll stealth check i am actually
good at that so that's a 19 okay cool so you are hiding under the table the table has
a tablecloth on it um so yeah it provides you a little extra cover but that is a good roll so
we'll check in when the cello gets back around and that's where you are holding for now
yeah i think so because i definitely like clearly saw something happen with the tuning fork so i'm
just gonna try that again got it unless something else crazy happens which seems likely
some weird weird shit happening okay weird shit going on
welcome to the middle everybody thanks for being here
hey this banjo man he's he's kind of scary he's definitely a thing i don't like him i don't you
know what amy i don't like him either i don't say that a lot no but i do not like him or
this song that i i literally just imagine poor Alydin has been hearing the same like
how am i not taking psychic damage right how am i not just bat shit crazy like it would
i guess you would eventually just tune it out probably because that's what we do as humans but
my goodness well and as a child though repetition is something that that's right you know see i'm
more into early banjo man this new stuff yeah that's fair before he signed to that major
label got kind of commercial yeah yeah totally totally get it um but yeah no it's it's a great
time and we're having fun uh we're we're live live live streaming to some of our patrons
over there we do that that's a lot of fun um and i mean becoming a part of the community
a lot of people have been jumping on board because we've got that 25 off your first month
or first year yeah that's a great deal it's a no-brainer uh i think so i think many people
think so uh so patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast come on over have some fun have a great time
you get an episode dedicated to you like today's patron donna newton thanks donna
god i love the name donna i know we mention names every time
um but i just like it i like it too i i think it's kind of due for a resurgence don't you think
i also i think so yeah i bet in like five years it's going to start happening again
with babies because it hasn't been in a while yeah true all right let's put it out there
we're bringing donna back uh or donna's bringing donna donna's bringing donna back
we're gonna thank you for bringing yourself donna yeah appreciate donna we appreciate you
all i can think is she's bringing donna back yeah anyway thanks donna thank you for being here
donna we hope to see you over on patreon patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast 25 off
until the end of the month uh come on over it's a great time uh but now we'll get you back to
the episode and we'll talk to you very very soon love you bye love you bye trumpets turn
they are have stopped moving the trumpets they're close enough so they are going to
let out that same ear-splitting swell and burst so can i get a constitution saving throw from you
bizarre this is a problem no no violins that's a five yes okay in a 30-foot cone this swell and
burst of compressed air flings itself towards you uh you're going to be shot backwards 10
feet and take four thunder damage as you are knocked back uh make a dexterity saving throw
to avoid being knocked prone all right that's a 21 okay so yeah you managed to stand your
ground but yeah you have been moved back 10 feet the violins that are on the walls also
had to save against this because it covered everything the fire that you lit extinguishes
on them but they are tumbled forward and two of them break apart um and you see their their
strings trying to like reach for the parts and pull themselves back together um one the final
one is like crawling now on the ground towards you piano stuck in piano room uh we're not
going to worry about that uh however it is the cello's turn piano had to be built and
airlifted into that room yeah i think the piano was assembled in that room right like how
wide is the door yeah the cello moving itself back into the room um you hear it like stomping
it's on its foot and like the strings are like holding it's propping itself up as
it moves into the space and over to the window it's going to turn back into the room
and let out a deep vibrating note all creatures within 30 feet that's you Bonwyn must make a
wisdom saving throw but with advantage right because my because my earplugs nice with advantage
uh sorry you said wisdom wisdom yeah okay that one was a 15 and that one was also a 15
so it's a 15 so you are under this table you've got the the tuning fork in hand um the cello lets
out this deep vibrating note that shakes the bones in your body and even though you have your
your ears plugged like you feel this what can only be described as like a paralyzing
nostalgia come over you and you feel a sense of dread for a moment you see visions flash quickly
of childhood homes and loved ones and all these places where you feel safe and then they all
crumble splintered into wood and churning darkness but you saved so all of that disappears
as you come back to the space Alydin upstairs Kavlaran has you by the arm but in like a nice
way in a supportive way yeah yeah of course you've got the two parents behind you door in front of
you chaos sounds like it's coming from downstairs did you guys find cedric
which one was cedric again
i mean you gotta be true to character right no i i don't know i i don't have all you kids
look the same i'm sorry i'm just leaning into it now i love this like awkward uncle
never been around kids i don't really know how to act around kids i love that it's so good
that's awesome Alydin kind of gives him one of like these what like look at him just like
cedric has a very unique appearance you don't yeah i don't think tom was actually
face blindness so it's totally fun yeah no i love it i love it you're never gonna find gorsh
again no gorsh was he doesn't have but blindness but he doesn't he has face blindness he
remembers those cheeks and he would recognize that tight peach yeah all right
whoa this is a scary place sorry nope if i took one thing away from the business
yeah it was more gorsh more gorsh gorsh spin-off episodes yeah um okay so she's just gonna
blow right past that and we'll also sorry we'll also bump Kavlaran up to yours because you guys
are kind of together so it doesn't really make sense to have you do something but he's supporting
you so two of you collectively can kind of figure out what you're gonna do cool who who's
here uh we uh bazaar's here Bonwyn's here i'm here you're here and we all gotta go she like
like brightens up significantly to hear that somebody else yeah anybody anybody am i
preferred anyone else could have said fucking ignatius at this point
i mean um but yeah she definitely brightens up hearing that um bazaar and Bonwyn like she's
you know like yeah these two don't know each other that well like this is what being cared
for looks looks like so okay we have to leave because this place and it'll it'll put you to
sleep and the and nothing is right and i i can't leave you can't leave not yet okay but maybe
maybe
something burning oh yeah that's probably uh yeah well um yeah we we need to go is the
the short story there right she she nods and is like okay yeah okay all right what's the best
way out of this place she she looks back at cav and is like front door i only came in i've
never gone out okay cool we'll try the front door let me start hustling towards that door russ
okay so you're gonna go you're gonna make your way down the stairs you can make it to the bottom
of the stairs and part way down the hallway which is back towards the door as you get down
there Alydin you're now seeing a lot of this for the first time uh Kavlaran more things
are on fire um naturally be weird of less i mean i would hope more things were on fire
yeah as you get to the base of the stairs looking down to your right you see these
instrument creatures these trumpets like moving along the ground vile one single violin moving
down but also the shadowy outline of who you recognize as bizarre who is an inexplicably
long way away from you in this space you see into the dining room um make a perception
check you see me i was gonna see with my tuning fork and my lit torch under the table
cello didn't see me he just guessed 17 and i've got a plus zero okay i was uh 15 after uh after
bonus all right so neither of you see Bonwyn because you rolled a 19 i believe yeah yeah but
you look into the room and you see this cello figure um on the other side of the room and an
open window um the kitchen's on fire the dining room's on fire um you're halfway down the hallway
but that's as far as you can get this turn is there anything else you want to do uh well i
think at seeing bizarre uh Alydin would go bizarre good good she's safe run just fucking
run wait was that you with the tuning fork you mean this hot dog roaster
that's hilarious but not right now there's a time and a place
and now i'm hungry damn it it's actually bazaar's turn now so that
works out we can just flow into that uh yeah seeing Alydin like i i'm very very angry and
upset in this like encounter like i really want to find this fucking this dude but he
disappeared so like bazaar's pissed in his own way so like he is going to push forward just
walking right past that poor little violin on the ground not even getting it the time of day
and he is going to push towards that uh that mess of trumpets and other bells and give two
attacks to it and then move past it okay like just going in yeah brutal attacks love it
see that is an eight on the first one and a 20 unnatural on the second and the dirty 20 will
hit yep dope all right and that's going to be seven slashing damage cut it up yeah your blade
cuts down through them lets out this muted horn sound as it's knocked against the wall
the other one and as you continue to move past it because i assume you're going to
use your full movement yep yep it doesn't really have like a effect it yeah no that's not going to
work uh so yeah you you're able to insult you insult you hey fucker that's what i imagine
when you're like slashed at the trumpet that's totally all i was picturing too
all right so there's going to be a lot of trumpet falls
uh and you can make your way um i mean you walk what feels like 30 feet but you've been backing
up for some time but by the time that you reach that distance um you find yourself at the base
of the stairs and unless there's anything you can do it's Bonwyn's turn since cav showed
showed me his i'm gonna show him mine and be like i have a tuning fork too found one as
well Bonwyn from under the table you see um Kavlarne and Alydin rush down the stairs that was
going to be my first question was if i saw them amazing cello still in the door uh cello moved
behind towards the window so yeah you've got a clear shot to the door like hey where did she
go where did she go i don't know why i did a violin thing just so you guys could see it
anyway you're it's a very tall person playing it it's right
um i am just gonna like book it for my friends like Alydin i'm so happy that she's there and
we found her and she appears to be like whole and i'm probably just gonna run up and hug her
here i'm sorry i do not ask but i'm just so happy to see her i'm into it and then i will
try to hit that tuning fork again so you're all four of you are back together now
gangs all together again you're you pull out your tuning fork like let's
like oh yeah so we all have them out now in our hands so let wind yes i know that's what
i was gonna say like this is an initiative order but can we like yeah yeah yeah kyle tip to tip
with the tuning fork cheers like uh so yeah you rush out uh you've got your tuning fork
the trumpets of what's left of the trumpets have turned around the violins are piecing
themselves back together i drop my burning torch on them they run past cello is like
getting ready to make another one of these blasts and you hear the stomp of the piano
in the other room as it's on fire trying to just make its way out the poor fucking piano
god it's just trapped in there i know i can't think about it too much or i'll feel guilty
about this evil piano that i lit on fire but it's crazy the banjo man made me evil i just
know this is really good pay that's what you see around you that's what's happening around you
three of you have these tuning forks out what are you gonna do with those
i didn't work the first time mine didn't work either but i probably yeah i think that i have
like a small just like piece of metal that i like maybe can hold out and we can all
and i'm like uh we can all try and hit it at the same time love it yeah let's do it
what happens what do we roll group uh performance or arcana role you can choose
a better role team party kill you can roll yeah yeah all four of you they're cheering us on
all right it was arcana or what russ or performance 19 17 18 in performance 19 crushed it oh we're so
much stronger together guys at least two yeah all together what it is uh let me scroll ahead here
hold on he did not see us succeeding so he's gonna pass some stuff here yeah i was just
still hovering on the monsters yeah you strike each of these three tuning forks and the energy
wave amplifies and rings out and you you feel the entire house shaking this wave passes by
each of these monsters that begin to vibrate and fall apart and collapse and just become
lifeless instruments as this music fades into a soft melancholic tune
as the final instrument shatters or falls silent you hear the front door burst open
and stumbling in is the banjo man as he staggers in his fingers twitching as if
struggling to keep playing and he says no no no no the song's not over yet his voice cracks
almost pleading he screams out in frustration gripping his head as the discordant magic
begins to fall apart the clearing that you are in begins to tremble as the banjo man's hold
on this dreamlike realm begin to weaken a window of glowing golden light bursts
open behind you on the opposite side of the banjo man in the space between worlds
Alydin you're the first one to see it because of how we're all kind of standing here
everything around you at this point everything around everybody begins to disappear the house
disappears the parents the illusions all gone and Alydin as you look back and see the banjo
man for the first time yet have this odd recognition of him all of you see his eyes
flicker with something unreadable is it regret rage perhaps despair the silmarillion the
silmarillion and then his bones begin to crack his arms begin to extend his strumming on the
banjo becomes fractured and this these notes begin to vibrate and move and in this new form
with his monstrously long limbs and sunken in eyes and jagged sharp teeth wings begin to
sprout from his back he digs into the ground beneath him and charges towards you pushing you
towards this glowing window as the energy that surrounds him is moving towards you
Dumbgeons and Dragons season four episode 22 starring Amy More as Alydin carla max dead
as Bonwyn everbane tom laird as Kavlar in gold wave kyle Claset as bizarred the wizard
and russe moore as your dungeon master dialogue editing and sound design of today's episode is by
russe moore our community manager is jessica babyuk music is from epidemic sound and sound
effects are from epidemic sound and boom library our amazing cover art is by matt garbutt and
we'd like to say a huge thank you to our supporting producers including gabriel lynch
jessica babyuk cat water flame jacob madden anger on kiersen perry matey old school gamer d
craig zeiss and la branton we'd love for you to join us over on patreon at patreon.com slash dumb
dragon cast and when you sign up by april 30th 2025 you're going to save 25 off your first
month or your first year that's huge bonus episodes hangouts backstage access we've got it
all over there so we hope to see you over there okay you have a great week we'll talk
to you soon Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production