Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment. The door chimes and your senses are filled with the sweet aroma of all the great things that you find at. I just said the words. Sweet Apothecary. Sweet Apothecary. I even said the words after the fact. There's cinnamons. There's tamarins. There's rosewater hips. Probably.
Mint, mint, lavender, chives, onion, patchouli, bed, bed. It smells like bed. It smells like bed. It smells like comfort. That's what Amy means there. Yeah. Any time. The four of you. Now, I guess the question is, because Alistair has been kind of off doing his own thing for an adventure and a half year. How much does he get done doing his own thing? Well, I mean, it takes him a while to do anything. Yeah, it does. I'm just curious. How much does his own thing cost?
How much does this guy get done? Has he caught up with you at this point? Are you still just like getting your stuff and then you'll swing back and get him and be like, all right, we're going now. We decide we're taking him? No, yeah. He's got all like. Okay. Bizard said he wanted to like throw him over the threshold and make sure that nobody else got. I said we need to test her. Yes. We should just get. We should bring a wagon for him. Hey, we can't have him slowing us down. He is going to slow us down. You think he could pull a wagon?
Not efficiently, Kyle, no.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon master, Russ More, he him. Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she her. Magic Daddy, what's my budget? Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she her. Now I wait to see what sort of family we are.
Tom Laird is Kavlaran Goldweave, he him. Oh, there's always a bud. And Kyle Clastet is Bizard the Wizard, he him. Damn.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported show and right now we have a survey going on at patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
You can join our Patreon at any of the tiers or the free tier to give us your feedback on what you want to see as part of the community. Thank you so much for your time, effort and energy. We can't wait to do more with this amazing community.
And now, fuck it, let's play. As the bells chime, from the back, Ursula Major and Ursula Minor come out to greet their guests.
Oh, who do we have here, sister? Hello, friends. Sister, we haven't seen these folks in so long, have we, sister? It has been a long time, sister. Welcome. What do you need?
Oh, um, well, we're going to be venturing on the road. On the road? Yeah, a little road trip. Where to?
Oh, top secret, sister. They don't want to say. We have some secrets of our own, don't we, sister?
Well, how about we tell you and we return for secrets of your own? Oh, we'll consider it, won't we? Secret secrets are so fun.
Maybe we will. Um, so what do you think you need for your little road adventure?
Gav, any thoughts? Well, I mean, I don't know about you, but I'm always getting banged up when we're out adventuring, so I guess something in like the healing potion department.
Healing potion. We have just the thing. We have that really great salve. Oh, I love a salve.
I think there's one in the back. Yes, it smells beautiful. Bergamot. You'll love it. Oh, OK.
Yes, some of those healing potions will do quite nicely. Oh, do you have anything? We might be joined by a fellow who has trouble staying awake.
Oh, so if you have anything like I've heard, there's something called caffeine that can help with that. We do have a special tea, a special morning thunder tea. Oh, we do.
That might help. I think so. I think that might help. And maybe a little dark chocolate. Oh, delicious too. Yes, wonderful idea.
Antioxidants are fantastic for your skin. He's just bustling around the store and I'm putting things in a little basket.
Now, do you think any of you who are not blessed with being able to see in the dark may need to be able to see in the dark? Because we do have something for that.
How's it going? That's me. Oh, you get one of those potion of Twilight Sight, sister. We'll need that. Twilight Sight. Here we go.
The last one. Dim light will become bright. Things won't be perfect, but it will it will assist, certainly.
OK, thank you. What does it taste like? Oh, what is that one, sister? Peppermint?
I think peppermint rosemary, I think. Oh, a little savory twist. You know, sometimes we like to mix it up.
OK, so it's not vile. I was just kind of bad at the potions thing, so I've never. Oh, did you try one of these yourself?
No, I never. I don't think I really got this far. The healing one's kind of where I was told to stop. Yes, yes. It can be a tricky business.
We do specialize in unique flavors and scents here. It is a sweet apothecary, so indeed built in.
Excellent. That black one swirly one up there on the shelf. What's that?
The ink blood tonic. This one here. We don't sell many of these, do we, sister?
We do not. This one. Oh, this mystery road trip becomes more intriguing.
This is going to allow you to see faint magical inscriptions in stone or in the air.
But be careful. You're looking to get a little sneaky. It's harder to lie with this one around.
Harder to lie, but none of you would ever lie anyway, so don't worry about that. Won't even bother you.
Yeah, I'll definitely take that one. That seems like that'll be useful.
So if we were going somewhere, jeez, if we were going to meet someone who was sort of strange or maybe not, maybe local, who was powerful and we wanted to not be susceptible, is that anything?
I do have a little something. Let me see if I can find it back here.
She bustles behind the desk and is shuffling underneath. Oh, OK, so I have this fey dampening cordial.
Oh, yes, sister, that is the one. It's made. Remember that cherry harvest two and a half years ago?
Anyway, this will make you a little less likely to have the pants charmed off of you, so to speak.
Indeed. This one is we really don't get a lot of requests for this, do we, sister? Oh, my curiosity is really getting the better of me.
I can't wait until you return to tell us all your secrets.
Well, usually people want their emotions heightened to feel a lot more, but this one will bring it way down, way down, way down for an hour.
I'll give you a little card and it's got all the instructions, just everything written right on it.
As we discussed before, we don't have unlabeled vials just laying around. Everything's very clearly marked.
That'd be so dangerous, wouldn't it, sister?
So silly, never. So there's no like discount mystery bin.
Oh, well, well, I mean, we didn't.
Are you feeling a little risky? You might like to take a little gamble.
I mean, it depends on how much that gamble will cost me. Oh, wonderful question, sister.
You're looking for a deal. For Kavlaran, what do we think?
I don't know if you ladies know this, but I'm currently on leave from my job looking for a fun time.
I mean, I went back to work for like three hours, but it was just guarding this weird tunnel collapse thing.
So I don't think I'm like back to my normal job yet.
I see. So you're looking for the early retirement discount.
That would be great if available. Yes.
OK, well, sister, what do you think?
I want to do it just so they'll tell us more about their adventure when they return.
I have to say I am intrigued. OK, well, we have to do it a fun way, though.
So maybe we'll just, sister, let's just gather a few things.
Don't look. Oh, OK. And then you can just reach in and just grab it.
Just grab the one that your heart calls to you. But they'll only be fun.
They'll only be fun. Retirement. Yes, yes, yes, yes.
We would never put anything dangerous. We don't sell anything dangerous, do we, sister?
That's right. No, sister, we do not. Certainly not a whole cabinet in the back.
Not if you, you know, know how to use them.
Nothing, darling. OK, perfect.
Now turn around, as I said. OK, yep.
OK, no one look. Clink, clink, clink, clink, clink, clink, clink, clink, clink, clink, clink.
Jingle jangle. Hey, sometimes, um, like, do you guys have anything like that could make somebody not forget stuff?
Hmm. Now are we thinking homework or something deeper?
Hmm. Um, she looks over at Bizard and is like, remember when I was like in the house and then I was like forgetting stuff?
Oh, sorry to overhear. So not homework. You're probably very good at your homework.
You don't need any help with that, do you? Oh, absolutely.
No, I always get my homework done at school, so I don't have it, and it is then just schoolwork.
Well, young lady, I think we have just the thing for you.
Now you will forget, but then you can remember.
This is a memory salt suspension. You actually will smear it on your temples and you'll be able to recall something you've forgotten,
or at least you'll have a better chance of recalling something you've forgotten, but it will have to be within the last 24 hours.
OK. And as I mentioned, we do have very specific scents here at Sweet Apothecary in this one.
You will smell lake water for the rest of the day, so don't be alarmed by that scent. It is intentional.
I like that smell. That's OK. It is a nice smell, isn't it?
Sort of chlorophyll and fresh water. Yeah.
Bizard, what's my budget?
Uh, don't worry about it. Magic Daddy. Magic Daddy, what's my budget?
We're also going to be getting everyone some healing potions, make sure that everybody's stocked with at least one.
I mean, I think between Bondwyn and myself as business owners, we...
Oh, certainly. Don't worry about it. We need to be prepared for this trip. Absolutely.
Yeah, so I believe just making sure that we're set on those.
Alydin, this potion of Steady Hand, I want to get that for you in case because I know you work with your hands
and I want you to be ready in case we have a jarring situation.
And I believe in you, but I want to make sure that we're ready.
OK, I'm going to try not to read too much into it and let it affect my confidence.
I think we all need some help. For example, I see this bottle of anchoring draft and that seems like a good idea.
No, you know, if there was perhaps some sort of portal, portal, portal, we might be able to avoid being, you know,
that seems like hopefully doesn't come up. Portal, portal, portal.
Sister, did you hear that? Three portals.
The book. Have you read the book? Portals, portals, portals.
You have the pocket copy.
Now you, young sir, are you ready for your mystery potion?
Absolutely.
Roll a d6, Tom.
OK.
Thanks, Russ. You made it so beautiful. He put little icons and everything.
Four.
This is funny for Cav.
For you. Oh, yes.
And Cav's pulled out sort of a cloudy pale blue liquid.
This one, we call this the R&R tonic, the recall and revision tonic.
So for 10 minutes after you take this, you will be just a little bit smarter.
And you may in fact be able to, let's say, rephrase something that you said in the last minute.
The world, this isn't time travel, of course.
But people listening to you will remember it as you restate it.
Oh, interesting. OK.
But. Oh, there's always a but.
There is always a but when we deal with the Weaview.
We'll maybe perhaps momentarily forget a minor detail.
Just something trivial. Just something small.
Indeed. I wouldn't worry about it and you'd only momentarily forget it.
So don't be willy nilly with this one.
But if you have you put your foot in your mouth, this may help.
OK. Quick question.
Could that minor detail be something like forgetting to use the restroom?
Oh, interesting question.
I wouldn't. I mean, I don't think so.
Sister. It doesn't sound.
I know an odd question. I understand an odd question.
Because it bears asking considering things.
That's more of a physical need as opposed to something in your brain that you would recall.
Fair. That is a fair.
Your body would be signaling to you that you needed to do that.
So you could have had the thought, oh, I should I should visit the restroom.
But then that thought may disappear, but your body will still be telling you.
So I wouldn't worry about that.
You won't need any diapers.
Are you worried about wetting your pants at any given moment?
Good. I can leave the diapers. Good.
Yes. No diapers needed unless you need them for another reason.
We never judge, do we, Sister?
No judgment.
This has been a blast. Great shopping experience. Great service.
Always the best service here.
Well, we do love what we do, don't we, Sister?
We absolutely do. And you know what?
If you do what you love, you never work a day in your life, do you, Sister?
That's what we always say.
We cannot wait for you to come back from your little road trip adventure
and tell us everything about it.
And of course, we'll see you at the next business association meeting.
Of course. Of course.
Lovely to see you. Be safe.
Take care.
Welcome to the middle.
This is the middle.
Is the adventure within the adventure.
You have arrived.
There's a long and winding road before you.
And at the end of that road, what do you see?
What is it?
Is it a survey?
It's a survey.
I had to squint a little bit, but I'm pretty sure it's a survey.
The best thing you could possibly find at the end of a long and winding road.
Yes.
Everyone's favorite thing.
Exactly.
We are doing a survey for our patrons
so that we can make sure that our Patreon community
And the rewards that we offer are really exactly what you want.
We want you to be satisfied.
Yeah, absolutely.
It's been a while since we've done a good update to it,
so it feels like it's time to freshen her up a touch.
And we want your feedback.
And not only, like some people are thinking, well, I'm not a patron,
but there is this free tier that you can join over at patreon.com
and when you are a member of the free tier
and you fill out the survey, give us your feedback,
your name goes into a draw where we're giving away five chances
at a month free of our supporting producers tier.
Heck yes.
So if you've been thinking about it,
join the free tier, fill out the survey,
maybe you get to join at like a good mid-level.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
See what we have to offer over there.
See if you like it, see if it tickles you.
And if you are a patron, tell us what's up.
Be honest.
We want to know.
Look, we've had several respondents already,
which I've already said I need to like not look at it till it's done.
They're not.
It's only helpful in the aggregate.
It's a small sample size.
It's anonymous.
Be honest.
It's totally 100% anonymous.
But don't be mean because we are sensitive.
Like we are fragile little things.
Constructive criticism.
Absolutely.
But I will cry.
I can't imagine any of our patrons would be mean.
No, I don't think anybody would be mean.
Don't be mean.
Okay.
Please.
Don't make me cry.
I will filter it before it gets to everybody.
But yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Unless it's deserving.
I know.
I was going to say if we've made you so upset that you feel like maybe you
have to be mean, then I actually feel like we should.
Join the patron to tell us about it.
We probably need to hear about that.
That's the only way it's going to sink in.
I get it.
We're setting up too much of that.
So patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Come join the free community.
Lots of things that we're trying to make happen over there.
And I stipulate that because we're trying to make it happen right now.
Like this is the process.
We're building it out.
Trying to make it so that like this is the place.
The world is nuts.
Social media is mostly bots.
We don't know who we're talking to half the time.
So if you come join us, then we know that we're talking to real people.
And we are real people.
And thank you for supporting us.
Real people.
We're here making some funny, funny, silly, silly adventures.
And we want to keep doing that.
And your support is what helps us do that.
So that's going on right now until June 30th.
Make sure that you are doing the thing to come join us.
Oh, and by the way, it's quite short.
It's not one of those surveys where you click and it's like 400 questions.
Oh my God.
When you do a bunch and then it's like 3% complete.
Yes, exactly.
It is not that.
No.
Like there's different kind of tracks that you can go through,
but less than 10 minutes for the longest of the possible questions.
Unless you spend time on the long answers.
Like that's on you.
Hey, you want to write us an essay?
We'll read it.
As long or short as you want it to.
Exactly.
100%.
So patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Come join the free community or, or, or the, or any of the tiers as well.
And fill out that survey.
It's pinned at the top of our Patreon and we hope to see you over there.
Now, Loki's making complaints in the other.
Loki is making complaints and saying, because who's supporting this episode right now?
Who gets the shout out?
Sorry, I got so wrapped up.
Today's patron.
Loki is a professional.
And he knows that we are missing out on today's patron.
And he would like you to see he stopped whining because he knows we're back on track.
That's right.
So when you are a patron, you get an episode dedicated to you.
Like I've been so lovely.
Everybody's been so lovely to remind me.
But that patron is Matthew Miller.
Thank you so much, Matthew.
Sounds like it's another like superhero kind of name with the double.
Or like a cool noir detective.
Matthew.
Yes, that's what I had in my hand.
Matt Miller.
Or an artist, Matt Miller.
I could see that.
Oh, yeah.
Whatever you do, Matt, you're great at it.
And we love you.
Thank you for supporting us, Matt.
Absolutely.
Or Matthew.
If you're Matthew, if preferred.
Fair enough.
Or if you're a sports person, just call you Miller.
Oh, OK.
Good old last name.
And if we get one of those surveys with I prefer Matthew, then we know.
We will.
That one will not be anonymous.
We'll know for sure.
So, yeah, Hunter is in.
We'll make a correction at that point.
Thank you, Matthew.
And everybody else for filling out the survey.
We really appreciate it.
Your feedback means a lot to us.
OK, we'll get you back to the episode, though.
Love you.
Bye bye.
Bye.
Everybody heads back out.
You've got all your potions in hand.
Please note them in the places where you note your potions, because it's up to you.
If you remember, you have a healing potion.
Not me.
Only you can prevent not using your potions.
That's right.
Just don't delete anything from that document yet.
I will copy and paste from it later.
Sounds good.
And as you exit back out, everybody has a lot of things.
But, Bonwyn, you've been taking some time since a lot of these events have been happening.
And you've been spending that time in an attempt to connect more closely with the powers behind the forge.
Ashutra, to be exact.
Yes.
I don't believe perhaps you've mentioned this to anybody, but I'll allow you to perhaps transition to back to Everbains now.
Oh, yes, yes.
Everyone come in.
I made tea.
Come in.
We're heading on our adventure very soon, and I hadn't mentioned it to anyone.
But you know, after that trouble with the forge, you know.
Yeah.
And then being in that chamber and the book and putting that down.
And I thought it would be important to sort of spend more time attuning to Ashutra, who is, of course, my patron of the forge.
So what does that mean?
Well, we mostly commune via creation.
So like making stuff?
Exactly, Alydin.
Exactly.
So I've been using my own imagination, which, as you know, is always kind of tended toward the martial and some of Ashutra's higher being kind of thoughts.
And I've created something for each of you.
Whoa.
OK.
Yeah.
And I'm really excited.
And I hope that you like them.
I mean, I've seen your work.
You're so talented.
Of course we'll like it.
I've done the whole thing like I normally do for my regular clients, where it's in like a very fancy box and it has a ribbon and the whole thing looks just absolutely gorgeous.
And I place something in front of Kavlaran and Alydin and Bizard.
And now I wait to see what sort of family we are.
Are we a family that takes turns opening presents or are we a family that all opens presents at the same time?
Carla also wants to know.
I mean, look, when there's multiple presidents, I think everybody just free for alls.
But like one person, maybe we go around.
I don't know. I don't know.
I'll say this Bizard probably takes a moment and like just kind of like appreciates it.
So he'll he'll probably just take a moment.
So you'll do what you do.
And he's probably like maybe tearing up a little bit.
Alydin's already opened.
OK, that's fair.
This is a child.
I mean, not a child, but a child, a child.
OK, so Alydin opens.
Bear with me.
OK, Alydin, this is something I've never made anything like this because it is a dagger, as you can see.
But it's not it's really more like you would use this for calibration more than for stabbing.
So the edge, it's very narrow and precise.
And there are metallic harmonics tuned to a magical strain.
What?
When you hit a construct or a magical object or a ruin or a barrier, you can use this blade to learn about that thing.
Do I do I have to stab it with?
No.
No, no, because you don't want to just don't damage it.
I mean, it is it is a hearty weapon.
But still, you also if you find something magical, an object or a barrier blocking your way, you can use this to stop one of its magical properties.
How did you do that?
Well, it involved a lot of late nights at the forge and a lot of deep introspection and communing with the spirit of my long dead great, great, great, great, great, great grandma.
So Alydin is just like, how do you run the waist?
Thank you so much.
I love it.
For Bonwyn in this, like there's a lot of magical components that are imbued within these items.
And we'll obviously get to the other ones like Bonwyn herself, not inherently magical.
So how I picture like these abilities coming into these like the forge in and of itself, whenever you you you create something with it, we had determined like it gives up plus one to certain aspects of the of the weapons ability.
But you have been able to really, as you mentioned, commune with Azhuthra and you feel like you are like her vessel for placing these abilities within.
That's what I was imagining too.
Like I like commune with her and she is able to like work her magic through my hands slightly.
Exactly.
Cool. Cool. Cool.
Kavlaran looks like someone's an only child and you've opened your present immediately.
Well, you can't hand me something and expect you to not open it immediately.
I wanted you to open it.
I wanted you to be happy and open it.
And Kav, what you see is a big war hammer.
It's sort of like layered on each of the faces and it looks almost like overbuilt.
It's like so big.
It looks like you could hit it against over and over and over again.
Does it look like I could get the like thing up to the top at the county fair?
Oh, for sure. For sure.
Absolutely.
So this is not enchanted to negate magic, though.
It is forged to introduce counter pressure into imposed systems.
So you will get, you know, it's it's very dangerous.
You will be extra strong on on your attacks and when you create damage.
But when you hit a creature that is magic or affected by a magical effect,
you can suppress one minor magical effect on that creature.
Oh, so say they've cast. Oh, goodness.
They have a shield of faith up in front of them.
You might be able to disarm that momentarily.
Very cool.
And if you strike a surface, you will introduce structural contradiction,
which means in a 15 foot radius, creatures cannot be forcibly teleported.
Magical classification or tracking effects fail
and charm or fear effects originating from system based magic are suppressed.
So it doesn't cancel spells, but it prevents structural enforcement.
Like a little momentary reprieve.
Indeed, indeed.
So if we're in a scary cave, I think the cave itself can't.
Plus, you'll be more persuasive, more insightful.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Oh, my pleasure.
And for all three of you, you will, of course, have to spend some time
practicing and getting attuned to these new new.
I hesitate to say weapons, but let's say weapons or just like game changers.
Oh, that's really sweet of you.
That's very sweet of you.
Bizard, are you going to open yours?
Yeah, I am.
I wouldn't say thank you, Bonwyn.
Growing up, gifts were something that were rarely received.
And when they were, it was always experienced from a place of love.
And I just thank you so much.
Not since my mom or one of my mentors, Darius Rucker, back at the Academy.
Well, Cav, you remember.
So, yeah, I start opening up the box.
It's my pleasure.
And I did make it with love.
I put so much thought into making these just precisely for each of you
because you've all come to mean so much to me.
Bonwyn, you're going to make me cry.
So, Bizard, when you open your box, inside is a very rare, wondrous item.
Ashutra's Margin Quill.
So, it's forged ironwood bound in ember-threaded metal,
and the tip is engineered to channel arcane flow with minimal turbulence.
So, you have reinforced arcane focus.
The quill stabilizes spell vectors as they form.
You have editorial flow control.
When you cast a spell of first level or higher, you get to apply an adjustment,
one per spell, so you can exclude up to two creatures.
You can increase or decrease the duration.
You can extend the range, or you can change the damage type.
Damn.
This shit's dope.
Fuck yeah.
That is...
Structural insight.
If you cast a divination spell or identity-like effect,
you get advantage on associated arcana checks,
and you can ask one additional structural question about the system sustaining the magic.
And red line reality.
When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your spell
or a magical effect attempts to bind, categorize, or relocate you,
you can force a reroll or reduce the effect to partial.
It's the best fucking pen in the world.
And the air will smell like heated ink when this occurs,
because you got straight fire going through that quill.
That's insane.
That is so...
Damn.
That's a good list of shit, and I love it.
And for all of us, you'll notice each hilt,
and I think it was more clear on yours, Bizard,
but there's this faint metallic thread.
And that's for all of us.
We all have that, and when we are all together with these items
within 20 feet of each other,
we will gain advantage on a saving throw against force movement,
planar displacement, or magical classification effects.
So we're better together and stronger together,
just like we know that we are.
Earth!
By our powers, come by!
I mean, I must be fire.
Of course. Wind.
Wait, no, it's air?
What's the magic?
Air.
Air?
I also made myself a dope item called Load Bearer's Edge.
This is a rapier,
and it is forged in a shoethrous heat
using interlocking micro-lattices layered through the steel.
So this blade was not made to cut flesh.
It was made to find fracture.
So I get some pluses,
and it has a structural stress reader.
So when I hit a creature that is adjacent to a wall, pillar,
large object, or architectural structure,
or inside a magical construct, barrier, ward, or rune circle,
I get extra damage.
And this is so cool.
I'm reading this as I go, Russ, and it's blowing my mind.
Anchor the fracture.
When a structure, portal, or magical boundary within 15 feet
shifts, collapses, or destabilizes,
you may stabilize it until the end of your next turn.
So it can delay force teleportation, structural collapse,
or magical displacement of the structure.
So sick.
Baller.
I also have some forge instinct,
my stone's wisdom,
where I can know about things just because of my innate knowledge.
So with this and the potions that we got
from those, the major and minor,
and the sweet apothecary, I feel like we have...
We're going to kick some ass.
Yes.
Absolutely.
Or read books.
I'm not...
Well, you have to do both.
Yeah.
Studies don't stop just because we're on the road.
That's right.
Well, then are we getting a wagon?
Honestly, if we're going to bring Alistair,
we might want to bring a wagon.
I'm pretty sure we can secure something.
I don't want to carry him.
Please, Magic Daddy, can we get a wagon?
Yes.
Yes, we can get a wagon.
We hear, as we fade from this scene,
we hear the sound of...
Coconuts?
A slightly...
Why would a wagon have coconuts?
I don't know, because I thought maybe it was a horse.
Exactly.
Just the way you put your hands together
is like, coconuts, I get it.
You got it, yeah.
We hear the sound of just one slightly squeaky wheel
as we see Alistair being pulled in this wagon
and the four of you heading off into the Verboten forest.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 4, Episode 60,
starring Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane,
Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard,
and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue, editing, and sound design of today's episode
is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound,
and sound effects are from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library, and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok,
Angaron Kierzen, Perry Matey,
Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss,
and L.A. Branton.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported show,
and because of our Patreon supporters,
we get to keep telling bigger, weirder,
more heartfelt stories in this world we love.
And honestly, that's something we will never take for granted.
Join us today at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast,
and help us tell the stories that you want to hear.
We hope to see you over there.
Have a great week, and we'll talk to you soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.