We're back! Season 4, baby!
Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
There's a thud from underneath the table and the anvil moves and falls to the floor
and we see Bonwyn run out of Everbane's.
As we pan back, there's another huge crack as the wood to the door underneath this table splinters.
Another. And the table above it is thrown to the other side of the room.
And we see this huge claw reach up and out and drag along the ground,
these enormous claw marks along the dirt floor.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More,
he him. Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she her.
But I do want to say, I think I'm in a gang.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she her.
The thing that was under the thing is now, it's emerging.
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave, he him.
Can't believe he found the actual books.
And Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, he him.
Do I recognize this sound at all?
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast and you can join us today at Patreon.com
slash DumbDragonCast. There's a seven-day free trial and a whole bunch of episodes for you
to listen to. We hope to see you over there. And now, fuck it, let's play.
Bonwyn, we see you running through the streets towards the guard tower.
I'm going to say Bonwyn not a runner. I'm going to say Bonwyn is walking very briskly,
like hands. Yep, exactly. We all started doing power walking, hand movements.
One foot always on the ground? Are we doing an official power walk here?
I don't think so. But just like trying to be as quick as possible. But realistically,
Bonwyn's not a runner. But moving at a jaunty pace and I think just focused.
Maybe scanning to make sure there isn't like, you know, a random small child out in the
middle of the night where the monster might be. But otherwise just like, got to go get help.
Got to figure this out. Need more people to solve this problem.
So it is, you know, based on the fact that you were all running a heist not too long ago,
the streets are pretty bare. Like at most you see somebody stumbling out of a bar
or tavern. That's all the people you see. You make it to the city guard station,
which is on the other side of the river. So you've had to go quite a ways to get there.
The door bursts open and inside is Dace with his, he heels up on the main desk
and one other guard who looks like he's just reading a newspaper.
And the door bursts open and startles Dace. What? What's happening?
Oh, hey, you. Come on. We got to go. Get all the weapons.
Whatever weapons you have. Get all your weapons.
Get all the weapons. Okay. What are we doing?
Whoever's here. I don't just, we got to go because the thing
is now it's emerging.
The thing is emerging. Great. That sounds fun.
Let's go. Let's go. Hey, Dace grabs his sword and a couple other weapons and yells,
go sound the alarm. Get down to the military barracks.
And then follows you quickly out of the station.
We cut to the stable. Alydin, you've just returned not too long ago and everybody is
asleep currently. Tali has one eye open as she sees you walk in. She says,
how did it go? Really good.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
How was the food? So like you went, you went in, you went actually into the tavern and like
they, they, did you bring any back? Not from the tavern, but I got these from
city hall. You went to city hall?
Shh. Sorry. And I show her the inside of my bucket.
And then also my big pockets and it's just filled with like pastries and you know,
like the treats up here, like granola bars. I don't know. Whatever's out there for the
staff to have. That's so amazing. Why did you go to city hall?
Shh. Sorry. Sorry. I'll bring it down.
Well, cause if you wake them up, they're going to eat them all right now.
And I need to, I need to scroll them away.
Of course. So that we can just parse them out.
Yeah, absolutely. Listen, I know I tell you a lot of stuff,
but I don't think I can tell you this, but I do want to say, I think I'm in a gang.
You're in a gang. Sorry.
And like, it's pretty cool. I'm like, I'm like one of the, I'm like a grownup.
Well, I mean, you are the oldest, so that makes sense.
So here had to happen sometime. Oh, thank you.
Shh. Eat it quiet and go back to sleep. It's late.
She lies back down and puts her head on her straw pillow and quietly eating.
This is very delicious. Thank you very much.
You're welcome. Where are you squirreling away your supplies?
There are some empty crates and flour or grain sacks that are around that I use too. Inside
of the crates, I'll put the unwrapped perishables, I guess, like the muffins and
things like that. And in the sack, I put in some of the like dried meats and cheeses that
are packed up in like a cheesecloth. And I kind of put those away in there and then put them on
top of a crate. Cause you know, you don't leave food on the floor, not feeding mice.
As you're putting these away, you pause for a moment because you think you hear a sound,
like a sound of some sort of scratching noise.
I do a quick scan in the really dim light to see if any of the kids are stirring or waking up and
they're gonna find out where I'm hiding the food. You look around and anybody you can see from
your current location, most you see is like somebody turning over and nobody appears to be
awake. And you pause for a moment and you don't hear the sound again. Go back to doing
what you were, you know, putting away all your things. And as you go to lay down yourself,
you hear like this soft distant echoing sound, a bit like a howl mixed with like this guttural
growl. It sounds like it's coming from the storage room. I slowly roll over
to tally poker awake. I'm sleeping. No, you're not. Did you hear that? Hear what?
It was like a growling, like a... You pause for a moment and the sound
rises above the silence again. And it's a little louder this time. She says, I hear it.
I hear it. Maybe it's those goblins. Oh, maybe. Okay. Didn't you say they were kind of
friendly though? Well, I thought so, but I mean, like, I don't know, like, shh, shh, bizarre,
like murdered a bunch of them and stuff. Like I've seen stuff children should not see.
Well, it's a good thing you're an adult now. Right? Okay. I think they're good. I think it's
in the tunnels. They're in the tunnels. We have to leave. You have to wake up the kids
quietly and I need you to take them out into the street. Oh, okay. Okay. Okay. Tally's
scrambling up and like gently stirring everybody awake and they're all delirious and confused
about what's happening, but trying to usher them away and you hear like this cracking sound from
down in the cellar. And then far off in the city, you hear the sound of the town bell.
Fuck it. We're not being quiet kids. Let's go. Let's go. Let's go. Everybody move.
Cav, you open the door to your, what did we say? You're in a bit of a hotel.
It's like a long term rental situation. Yeah. You open the door to your room and
for auditors and the newly divorced is what it says on the sign outside.
I mean, that's what it is. It was very, very, very specific clientele. Find the name of this
place and get a sign made or something. Cause that's, I know you didn't.
That's the t-shirt you can buy. You open the door to your room and go to set the books that
you've you and the team has found down on the table and get yourself cleaned up and ready
for bed so that you can all think about this in the morning. As you're passing over
to your bed, you have another look at the books and you even reach down perhaps and
flip them open. Like everything you've been looking for to explain why the money isn't
adding up appears to be evident in these books. How does that make Cav feel in this
moment? Like what's going through his mind? Kind of almost disbelief. Like he can't believe
he found the actual books and it seems like a little too good to be true, but also at
the same time, he's like, holy shit, like I'm good at my job. Maybe
you're just riding on that cloud. You, you close the books, you, you may me perhaps even
tuck them away somewhere safe. Oh yes, I will be hiding them. Perfect. You hide them away
and you're climbing into bed and as you, as you snuff the candle and put your head down on the
pillow, you hear a sound that you haven't heard in this city before. It's close to you because
you're on the noble side of the city. You hear the sound of this large alarm bell that begins
echoing slow and pace at first, but then it picks up. Okay. I immediately a cab thinks that
it has to do with the heist. So, cause why wouldn't he? We just stole something very
important and now all of a sudden the city alarm is going. So some quick thinking,
he grabs like his messenger bag and puts the books in it because he doesn't trust that they'll
be safe. Even though he's hidden them, doesn't trust they'll be safe in the room. So he grabs
that grabs like a coat and just heads out into the kind of the, I guess courtyard of this place
and sees other people kind of setting up shop there. So goes and talks to some of the
divorced dads to see what's up. I'm imagining you looking like, like, like a Christmas carol,
like you were in a white sleeping gown, a sleeping gown. I mean, can for sure would wear a sleeping
cap. Absolutely. Yeah. You, you walk over to a couple of people who you've seen in passing at
the continental breakfast some mornings before, and they nod to you as you walk up and they too
are in their night gowns and are looking around and you see as you walk up to them,
you see a group of military soldiers like rush past the opening of this,
this courtyard and off towards the bridge. So what's, what's going on? Oh, I don't know.
I heard the, I heard the, I was washing a dish and I heard the bell and I came down.
Yeah. Yeah. I, me too. I was, I was, I was down in my basement suite and I heard,
I heard the bell when I came out. That's not what you told me.
Oh, that's not what he told me. Okay. Well, tell him what you told me. Okay. Well, I was,
I was sleeping and I, and I heard, I was stirred awake by the sound of the bell.
And then I came out. I wasn't. Yeah. I mean, it was, it was pretty close.
It was pretty close to what I said. I just wanted to give a little more flavor to the
story. Anyways, I don't know what's happening. It looks like there's a whole military thing.
Maybe somebody's being attacked and a couple of them walk out. And one of them walks out to the
out to the entrance to the courtyard. And as they do a few more soldiers kind of step
in front of them and bar their access so that they can't leave and they stand back
and they walk back to you. And I don't, I don't know what's happening.
Okay. Weird. I guess we'll just sit tight till they let us know.
I guess so. This is, this is a first.
Hey friends. We're back. I know it's been so long. It hasn't really been so long.
We've had those lovely mini-sodes, which if you haven't listened, we highly suggest you go
back because we've created a whole bunch of stuff that we can now pull upon for this,
this upcoming season. We are so thrilled to be back for season four, which I gotta figure out
a better way to classify the season so that it makes it easier for people to share. Obviously,
campaign one, season one and two, campaign two, season three and four, and however far
into the future we go. We are really excited for what we have, what I, I am really excited
for what I have planned. I'm also very excited to throw those plans out the window as everybody
else decides what they want to do. You know how games go. That's probably what's going to happen.
We have a few episodes. We, so two big action sessions that we recorded, this one
and another one, I think, and we're going to split those up into smaller episodes,
into smaller little, little action-packed, exciting adventures that we have going on.
And then we have a couple lovely guests from I Seduce the Dragon coming up in,
towards the end of the month, and we're going to have surprising adventure, shocking turn of
events, and who knows what else we're going to have. What we do have is a wonderful community
over on Patreon, where when you're a member, you get an episode dedicated to you, like today's
patron, Clint Peacock. We're thrilled to have you here, Clint. Thank you so much for being
here. Hopefully, you're enjoying the, all the great bonus episodes. I'm catching up
on the adventures of, Cyberpunk will be back in release. I know we just dropped
one main episode, more coming. Summer was buck wild. Let's just say that. Hopefully,
yours was chill. Mine, not as chill as I thought it was going to be. But we're going to be
catching up here over the next little while, back into regular release, and we're excited
for it, and we hope you are too. Come join us over on Patreon, Patreon.com slash dumb dragon
cast, seven day free trial. You can come to have a little taste, see what you like about
it, which is probably going to be more of us. We're there all the time, having hangouts,
putting out new episodes of The Adventures of, and Cyberpunk, and all the little fun
things we do as well. And then join us in the Discord community over there, amazing people
talking about not just the show, because there's only so much to talk about with the show.
There's lots to talk about with the show, but also friends are being made over there,
games are being played, things are happening, and we want you to be there too. Again,
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast. We hope to see you over there. Okay, let's get you
back to this episode. We will talk to you very, very soon. Love you. Bye.
Bizarre, you make your way back to the shop after the heist, and you get in and lock up,
and you're heading upstairs to get ready for bed, and you reach into your pocket as you're
cleaning up and putting things away, and you hold in your hand the vial that Kinney gave you.
Based on how tonight's gone, where's Bizard's head in terms of
needing to use this, or Kinney in general? Bizard feels conflicted. He's, you know,
he's made a deal with a very dangerous man and was able to resolve the problem,
technically, without his assistance. But he's at a point of like, okay,
I don't have to worry about the people I've begun to work with and become friends with.
I only have to worry about myself and what may happen. But knowing Bizard,
he's considering, like, could I go back to Kinney and could I say, well, I don't want
to not follow through on something. So we resolved the issue, but he's very doubtful
that that would work too. Just feels kind of, like, stuck. He's probably just sitting on his
bed just, like, staring at it, like, the hell am I gonna do? What have I gotten myself into?
And he thinks for a second about his mom. He's just like,
shit. And he pulls out a, you know, a quill ink and a piece of paper and he starts
just kind of writing his thoughts out. You sit and you write this and you get a
couple paragraphs in. And you stop for a moment just to collect your thoughts before
you continue writing. And you hear this, what sounds like an eerie wind begin to permeate through
your home. Doesn't sound natural. Sounds almost animalistic. And it's coming from
somewhere far off in the distance as far as you're concerned.
Do I recognize this sound at all? Can I place it to, like, an animal or some kind of,
you know, maybe magical creature that I encountered at school?
Make a nature check.
Dope. I'm alright at those. That's gonna be an Unnatural 20.
Ah! You, nothing from school, nothing from any, you know, roving out in the environment around
Kingstown or any small excursions that you've been out on. But it immediately gives you
a feeling of being back in the mountain, down in that tunnel, down in that cavern,
on the adventure that Ignatius brought you out on. Like, you didn't, like,
almost like you didn't register the sound when you were down there. But now that you're
hearing it here, it gives this, like, shiver down your spine that it's eerily similar
to a sound that was present in that cave system.
Immediately sits upright once that thought comes to him. He says, oh, there's no time for writing
a letter right now. And he actually takes it and he kind of, like, crumples it up,
throws it in the bin, says, Mom wouldn't want to hear about that anyway. And then
gets his clothes back on, like, you know, gets out of his pajamas. And he's like,
I feel like I might need to be ready for, God forbid those things show up in the city.
And then you hear the alarm bell from the military barracks begin to ring across the river.
Well, I can do math, walks downstairs and makes his way into the into the streets and
where would he go though? Oh, I know where he would go. He would try to go find Alydin
and the kids. Well, you're going to meet them halfway because Alydin's first thought was,
I have a key to a place that doesn't have a tunnel that I know. Oh, please. She's gone up
and down that place. If there was one, she would have found it. But yeah, she's got like
nine kids in tow and they are running through the street to the magic shop.
Bonwyn and Dace, you round the corner into the hot block. You immediately see that the
front of Everbane's has been blown wide open. Like some large creature has torn their way out
through the door. There's rubble in the street. There's tools and raw ore that's been
kicked about. And you see huge claw marks that have dug into the road and the pavement
and even up the side of a building on the other side of the street. Okay,
I'm going to start like pounding on doors. This is my neighborhood. I know everyone that lives
here and just shouting, wake up, wake up. You've got to get out of here. You got to get out
of here. Dace is doing the same and he's doing it as he's walking towards the footsteps.
He's checking inside of Everbane's first to see if there's anything still in there.
You knocking on doors see him from a distance. He turns away from Everbane's presumably because
he doesn't see anything and is making his way over to the wall and see if he can follow
where the creature went. You see him duck down between two buildings in the direction that the
footprints are going and he goes out of sight for a moment. What do you do? I think once
some people start coming out, then I say, wake everyone up. There's something on the loose here
and I'm pointing at these enormous claw marks that people would presumably be able to see.
Get to safety, get wherever you need to get and make sure everyone's awake. I'm going to
run into the shop and grab some fucking crazy weapon that I'm working on because I'm always
working on one and then I'm going to follow Dace when I know that I have delegated the
task of waking everybody up in the neighborhood. Yeah several people come out and they get this
direction and they you know rush back in get a couple essential things, clothes primarily
and then come back out and are working to clear everyone out of the hot block and as they
do that work their way back towards the noble side of the river as well as the military
barracks. Oh no all the poor people are coming across the river to the rich people's side.
It's a real problem. Yikes. Gross. That's where we leave that group. As you follow Dace,
you head down this alleyway and you you lose sight of him because you know there's a little
bit of a distance there but you hear footsteps around a corner and as you poke your head
around you see him and he sees you and he puts his finger to his lips signaling for you
to be quiet and as he does so you hear the sound of the bell on the other side of the city.
You hear this like rattling sound like a if you think like dinosaurs in Jurassic Park like the
throat rattle from up above where Dace is standing and you see like this shadowy figure
disappear over the edge. You don't have to make any saving throw on this because it's
not facing you but you hear this what would be a deafening howl that comes out of whatever this
creature is. You can feel small stones shaking free from the buildings around you and loud
crunching noises as you see it leap through the moonlight to another building as it's
moving towards the sound of the bell. And now that I've seen it or at least the silhouette
of it is it confirmed to me that it is the thing that we saw in the mineshaft?
Definitely has the same body type it looks bigger than the one that you saw in that cave.
For sure because that was like the size of a large dog right?
I think we said a large dog yeah.
Yeah.
Okay cool so we just saw the baby maybe.
Dace looks at you sees that you've got a weapon and he says are you coming with me
or you helping people out? They're on top of it I'm coming with you.
Let's go. You head back down these alleyways following it's moving much faster than you are
but it's leaping from rooftop to rooftop you're losing sight of it but you can still
hear the sound that it's making as you are chasing it towards the bridge.
And I think I guess the bell's going now but I'm still yelling as we go
to try and like rouse as many people as we can.
We cut back to the courtyard and Kavlarananan you're seated with a few others more people
have come down at this point the two guards are still standing outside the courtyard they
don't appear to have given any direction or information to anybody who's gone up and asked
them they've just been told to stay here and they will be safe if they stay here.
What do you do? I look for somewhere to slip out during some of the chaos.
Okay make an investigation check please. I can do that.
See on the ground floor like does he have a little balcony on the other side that he could
just like step over the gate. Right all right investigation that's a 12.
The courtyard appears pretty locked down three stories what story is Kavlarananan on?
We'll say second. I guess to Amy's point you would
have a balcony from your room that does have a fire exit like a ladder that extends down
in case of emergency. We're very safety conscious here in this medieval town.
Absolutely on this side of the river.
Yes there was the big fire in the in the in the rich district.
That's right. So they've built all the safeguards in.
Yeah okay head back to my room and scope out this ladder on the balcony and like
shimmy down and try to get out the back way.
Yeah you so you get out on the balcony you see a lot of movement down on the street.
There are some guards but nobody's looking up at you and
nobody's paying attention to you. You still have bag in tow?
Absolutely.
Okay great. You pop the ladder down and make it down to the street.
You're caught up in a bit of chaos which kind of rushes you along.
There are a couple guards behind this group that you've been swept up into.
It appears that they're moving this group down to the military barracks.
Is that where you want to continue to go?
Not not my first choice with state secrets in my bag.
Some light espionage yeah some light treason.
Yeah I'll make my way I guess toward Everbane's.
Okay.
I have a feeling that's where all my crew will be.
Okay make a stealth check to see how successful you are getting away from
the guards in the vicinity.
Stealth roll so that's a 15.
Okay you go with them for a couple blocks but then find a good position to just sneak
off into an alleyway. You do so and you wait until this main group passes and a couple guards
ushering people along behind them and then find a break where you're able to
make your way back to the bridge.
So we see Kavlarananan weaving through any chaos that's happening of people being ushered out
and making his way over to the artisan district.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 4 Episode 1
Starring Amy More as Alydin Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard and Russ More as your Dungeon Master
Dialogue Editing by Carla Maxted and Sound Design by Russ More
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and Slipstream
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garbut
and a huge thank you to our supporting producers
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Christian Brown,
Angaron Kiersen, Perry Matey, Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss, L.A. Branton, and Sarah Murphy.
Join us today at Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast
where you'll be able to join the community over on Discord,
get access to a whole bunch of amazing episodes that we've played and you're gonna love
and so much more like all the great hangouts.
Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast we hope to see you over there.
But that's it for me right now.
We'll be back with you hopefully very very soon.
You have a great week and we'll talk to you soon.
Say soon once more Russ.
Soon!
Bye!
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Everybody move!
And they do.
Because I'm a grown up now and they listen to me.
You're their fearless leader.
That's right.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.