Really cutting it close, getting in under the wire.
The party's still happening, but the ceremony's long gone.
That's okay, we've got more for you.
Coming up in just a moment,
Dumbgeons and Dragons will be right back.
The bridal parties filtered back in
and taken their seat at the head table.
Everybody's, some appetizers have been served,
drinks have been flowing.
Certain people are perhaps getting a little sloppy,
being that the drinking started
well before the ceremony of this.
Not only started, was encouraged.
Was thoroughly encouraged and pushed to keep everybody,
which is counterintuitive, but we did it anyways.
That's a Goldweave wedding for you.
That's right.
Kavlarananan, you, some time ago,
well before the bridal party had come back in,
had gone looking for your father's fourth wife.
Dame Corvella, who you saw enter
from her distinct attire, which was all black,
big, long, wide brimmed hat, black veil of her own.
I mean, there was an air of coolness as it entered,
and by coolness, I mean coldness.
You've disappeared down the hallway
and you can't find her anywhere.
You've headed back out towards the seating area.
You see that everybody's kind of milling back in,
but you know, there's a bit of tension within you.
You catch your father's eye and he looks over to you
and gives a smile and another thumbs up,
like things going, oh.
Given the old neck, not good sign.
Yeah, he leans over to his new bride, Guendevere,
and you see him whisper something
and he excuses himself and gets up and comes over to you
and says, what seems to be the problem?
She is here somewhere.
Somewhere.
Somewhere, not sure where, lost her.
It's not a large place, Kvlarne, what happened?
Well, you see, I was, oh, by the way,
Mom, Eloan, and Lady Emma are all like a team now,
so that's a thing you're gonna have to deal with.
Anyway, moving on.
I saw her come in and I was busy with the team,
team X mom.
Yes, yes.
And I saw her come in and then she kind of disappeared
into the back and I went and looked for her,
but I can't find her anywhere.
Great, well, we'll all keep our heads on a swivel.
Nothing good comes when she disappears.
How did she look?
Did she come dressed appropriately for the wedding?
Funny story, totally dressed in black
with a huge hat with a black veil on it.
Yeah, no, that's what I completely expected.
So I guess she's dressed appropriately then.
Yeah, no, 100%.
I'm glad she took that to heart
and that's how she came.
All right, well, you let me know if you find her
and I will do the same.
I'll give you a signal, signal, signal, signal,
like a caca, caca, tuky, tuky.
I think it's perfect.
Perfect, absolutely the best choice of action there.
That's what we did when you were a kid
and it's what we will do today.
So if it's looking bad with, what did you call them?
The X squad, X team?
I call them like the X moms.
X moms, X moms, I like that.
So the X moms,
if they look like they're getting unruly
or we see Corvela making a move for any cutlery?
Any cutlery? Sure, sure.
Question for you, just,
because I see there's like a couple,
like kind of balconies up across the way.
How good of a shot is she?
Just out of curiosity.
Well, she did, she was, you know,
top of the, top of her class.
Cool, that's great info to have.
Yeah, she doesn't have any problems with you.
We did reinforce the glass here.
It is a lot of glass, this is,
but I mean, you saw her come into the building.
So why would she be across the street?
That's not, that's not something that people do
is come in to distract and then leave.
Look, I mean, you always called her a witch.
Does she, like, can she do magic stuff?
I didn't always call her a witch.
I called her a witch. Okay, at the end,
you always referred to her as a witch.
She was a loving,
Is there any fact in that?
I don't think so.
She did have a lot of,
Let's see why you guys didn't make it.
She did have a lot of pots.
Don't know a thing about her.
She had a lot of pots.
She made a lot of brews, a lot of stews.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
So, you know, thinking back on it.
Were there a lot of jars with names like
Eye of Newt and stuff like that?
There were a lot of jars,
I couldn't necessarily- Coriander.
Cilantro.
I didn't know the names of all of them
or read all the languages that they were in.
Oh, they were different languages.
It was international cuisine that she made most often.
Okay, in like a big soup pot?
Yeah, it was large.
Yeah, like, are you saying like cauldron?
Is that the word you're looking for?
Cauldron, that's the word I was looking for.
She had a lot of definitely a witch then.
That's great.
This is just, it keeps getting better.
Yeah, no, you're doing a great job.
I love this for you.
Hey, have you seen Gary?
He's supposed to start the speeches.
You need to keep track of Gary.
Look, I realize-
Yeah, Cav.
Thank you.
No, you're right.
I gave you four people to keep track of.
I just need to keep track of Gary and-
Thank you.
And my wife.
Where is she?
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast
and I'm your dungeon master, Russ More, He-Him.
Also with me today is Tom Laird
as Kavlarananan Goldweave, He-Him.
Got him.
Got him, found Gary.
Gary's here now.
Carla Maxted as Lady Marison the First.
This is actually pathetic.
I can see why you don't care anymore.
Amy More as Eloin the Second.
This is my time.
And Kyle Claset as Baroness Yiselle the Third.
Oh, no, no, no.
You're not getting out of it that easily.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast
and we'd love for you to join us today
at Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
You'll get a seven day free trial to check things out.
And now let's get right to it.
Fuck it, let's play.
Where is she?
And he turns and looks and Eloin,
you're standing right there.
Oh, hi, Eloin.
Lovely to see you.
Thank you for coming today.
You should try the pastries.
I'm gonna-
Do you have a minute?
Oh, we are about ready to start some speeches.
Yeah, we're a little bit behind schedule here, Eloin.
This'll just take a minute.
We're just gonna have to hold that for the end.
All the questions will be held
for the end of the event.
Don't let him deny you.
Say what you need to say.
Oh, that's emboldening.
I see you've all decided to-
Well, we have a lot in common.
Yes, no, you do.
I have no disagreement.
Yes, of course.
I have some time.
I haven't found Gary yet.
Gary's the one to be the emcee,
so if we don't find Gary, we can't.
He gives like a wink to you, Cav,
and you'll be like, maybe you find Gary.
So you're stepping on my foot repeatedly,
like, find Gary.
He's not finding Gary.
But now he's connecting find Gary
to fix this wife situation,
so now it's back in his court.
Yeah, that's true.
Oh, he's a sneaky one.
Smooth operator.
He's a manipulator.
Light bulb goes off.
Cav scuttles away to try to find this fucking Gary.
All right, you've dispersed.
You're gonna go find Gary
and keep an eye out for Corvela.
Why?
What happened between us?
Well, Eleon,
sometimes two people
no longer see eye to eye,
and drift apart.
I fear that's what happened with us.
What do you mean you fear that's what's happened with us?
Well, I'm a poet and I didn't know it.
I appreciate you being here, Eleon.
We've discussed this many times.
No, we haven't.
Well, at least once, I'm sure, right?
Yes, all that time together,
and you're right.
I should be just satisfied
with that one conversation we had
as to why you think
that we're done.
Well,
yes.
Well, I did think that we were done.
I thought that perhaps,
you know, you would be better off without me.
It's not you. Oh, please.
It's me. Jeez.
Please.
Obviously, it's you. You're embarrassing yourself.
Obviously, we are at your fifth successful wedding.
If we could just keep our voices.
Oh, if we could just keep our voices, of course.
I appreciate that you RSVP'd.
What?
What did I do wrong?
I can change.
Nothing.
No.
You don't have to do that.
You don't have to change.
Nothing to change.
He's terrible.
I'm terrible.
Do you need to change your drink out
and I switch the drinks?
Yes.
How are we enjoying the specialty?
Oh, no, no.
You're not getting out of it that easily.
Yeah, no.
Also, it's gross.
Back on topic.
If our love didn't mean anything to you, just say it.
Our love did mean.
No. Yes.
Because when love is real,
you can give somebody a good enough answer
so that they are not tearing themselves apart
every single day through countless weddings.
You know what?
I'm sorry. One of these times,
I'm not gonna show up to your wedding.
She bustles away in a big swirl of her skirt.
Swirl is a word now.
That's right.
Cav comes running back in with Garry,
fireman carried over his shoulder
and dumps him in front.
Got him.
Found Garry.
Garry's here now.
Lovely to see you, Garry.
We're just having a word with Harrison.
It'll just be a moment.
Garry, if you could please prepare the speeches.
I...
Congratulations on being promoted to best man.
Good for you.
Oh, thanks.
Good job.
Yeah, I know.
Sometimes a demotion.
Sometimes you get back up and...
Garry, go get Garry.
No, yeah, no.
Of course, I have one job.
I'm gonna go do it.
And he heads off.
Look, I...
It's a part-time job.
He's right in it.
Splish it.
Semi-pro best man.
He also works for him.
He's been working his way up the company ladder
every time somebody dies.
I...
Are a coward.
Am a coward.
And...
Yes.
I don't know if I have...
An honest bone in your body.
Thank you.
A spine to say what you mean when you're...
A good enough explanation for why I love the way I do.
It's...
Poorly.
Yeah.
Yes.
I'm surprised I have a kid from you
considering the lack of balls.
Okay.
Ellen's over at the bar, but she even heard that
and was like, damn!
Snap!
All you hear is like, yes, queen!
In the background.
I owe you more than what I've given you.
I do.
All of you.
And looks over to Ellen.
I know that, and I am sorry.
I loved...
This is actually pathetic.
I can see why you don't care anymore.
Exactly.
Every conversation like this has happened, you know,
after we split, picking up Cav, dropping him off.
Oh, you must have had to deal with him constantly.
I'm so sorry.
It wasn't even...
Co-parenting with him?
Exactly.
Oh, I dodged a bullet.
You did.
You absolutely did.
Oh, I'm so glad Four's here.
Where's Four?
It's a great question.
At that, you turn and look,
and like, Harrison was there for the...
You did, but then you look for Corvela
and don't see her, and he's...
Of course.
Back at the head table.
He is a coward, as you can see.
100%.
This is not surprising.
You hear Gary, like, tap the microphone.
The microphone.
The thing that's right in front of your face?
The...
Sorry, this is the best word to forget.
The one my whole life has revolved around for 20 years.
I got it.
It's not our glass, let's get it together.
You hear Gary tap the microphone,
he says, if everybody can take their seats,
we're gonna start some speeches.
And it looks as if, well,
we have the usual, the best man's speech,
which, he kind of covers it.
Am I doing it, or is Cav doing it?
Cav's already done one tonight, I guess.
I guess you, Harrison shrugs.
So, the best man's speech, and then it says here
that we're supposed to just pass the microphone around
to anybody who has things to say.
Oh, Eloan Perks, up.
So, take your seats, just, you know,
find a buddy, grab another drink,
and we'll start in just a moment.
Dad, dad, who planned this wedding?
Gwendovere.
Benny Benson.
When Gwendovere got together with Benny,
and they just went to town and said...
You know, ever since Benny split from the Jets,
hasn't been the same.
It's really gone off book, yeah.
Everybody grabs some food, and they grab their drinks,
and everybody sits down, and Gary gets back up to speak,
and he says, well, I've known,
I've known Harrison for three weddings now.
Me too.
Thank you, Yuzel.
Yes, yes, it was a lovely day,
and Harrison's given the same stop now hand signal.
But we're gonna move right along.
Harrison's a great friend who treats his friends like,
well, like they're the best man,
and look, he's a guy, he's a complicated man,
and I've run out of nice things to say, sir,
and yeah, he works for me.
I have one nice thing to say.
One.
Which was, he's a complicated man.
Yes.
Yeah.
You know what, I was demoted.
Kavlarananan, perhaps you would like to take over.
I'd love to, Gare, thanks, thanks, bud.
Have all of the controls.
Welcome to the middle.
You can do whatever you want.
In the middle, it's whatever you want.
Welcome to the middle.
Russ just declared that he has all of the controls,
so nobody else is in control.
That's right, no.
I mean, if you're playing the home game,
you know he's had all the controls the whole time.
Obviously.
So it's fine.
That's right.
But also, he's married to me, so he.
Really, this has been Amy's long con
to have this game run.
That's right.
This is just a project that Amy wanted to do
that Russ has been enacting for the last 10 years.
I love it.
I mean, sounds like me.
How many podcasts can I give him to make?
I guess I owe him maybe $10.
To trading places, here's your dollar.
This middle that you're listening to
is in this episode that you're listening to,
which comes out at the start of our Patreon sale,
or very close there too.
So right now, when you visit Patreon.com
slash dumb dragging cast,
you can save 50% off your first month
or your first year membership,
all in celebration of our very own Carla Maxted.
Not really, but that's pretty exciting.
50% off a year?
That's a great deal.
Yeah, that's really good.
That's crazy.
Do it, I know.
Does that make them a member?
Well, yeah.
I mean, I already had every record,
but should I?
Now's the time.
What's the time?
That's wild.
You're gonna save boatloads by just signing up today.
Yeah, Carla, you're being very humble.
We actually, listeners, we actually asked Carla,
what do you want for your birthday?
And Carla was like,
give a discount to our sweet, sweet patrons.
Very altruistic.
Very altruistic, absolutely.
I want more of them to join us
and see how dumb we are.
There you go.
The world deserves to know just how dumb we are.
You deserve to know how this sounds unedited.
Yeah, one hundo.
There are some things that still get cut out.
We're pretty good now,
but yeah, no, there's still some wild stuff
that doesn't make it fair.
Yeah.
I believe it.
But if you've been thinking about it,
that's a good deal.
Even if you just wanna dip in for the month
and listen to some bonus content, that'd be great.
And even if you do that whole month,
you still get that one sweet bonus
that everybody gets whenever you sign up for a Patreon.
And that's a monthly, that's an episode dedication.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah, we've got a special one right now
and we can get so many more with this sale coming up.
Carla, thank you again for being so altruistic.
But now we're gonna have them lined up
for way through 2030,
which means we can't stop doing the podcast
until we get through those names.
So looks like you owe Amy 20 bucks.
Commitment.
That's right.
And yeah, don't wait till my birthday.
My deal's not gonna be as good as Carla's.
I am not as nice as she is.
So you should probably get in on it now.
Fair. Y'all are giving out deals too?
Untrue.
I'm killing Jesser.
You know who's got the best deal right now?
Who's got the best deal?
Who's got the best deal of the month?
The best deal of the month is what we're talking about
when you get that Patreon dedication.
Today's patron, the fashionable wizard.
How delightful and elegant.
I wish the fashionable wizard had a 50% off sale.
Oh my God.
The capes I would buy, the hats, the jeweled items.
My wand would be huge.
That's not the only sale we have going on
for fashionable people though, is it Russ?
It is not.
You are correct.
Oh, well how apropos that the fashionable wizard.
If you're a fashionable wizard,
you need to bedeck yourself in some high class items.
Wait. Bedeck?
Yes, that's correct.
You need to bedeck yourself.
Bedecked, bedazzled.
I'm not even gonna, I can't even look it up.
I'm not gonna disrespect Carla like that.
Bedeck is a thing.
You've never got into bedeckery?
I've never bedecked.
Bedeck yourself and save some money in our dashery store,
dumbdragons.dashery.com,
where you can save a percentage off of different items.
Like a t-shirt is how much usually?
$22.
And now it's gonna be.
$16.
Whoa.
That's a hell of a bedecking.
Good deal.
That's a pretty great deal.
We got some old school looks.
We got some new school looks.
Also guys, I looked it up real quick.
Bedeck is a word, not crazy.
No, I knew I wasn't even gonna question it.
I questioned myself.
It's just, it's not very commonplace.
What if I told you that the kids are saying it?
They're not.
Oh god.
You know what?
The kids are saying it.
I don't trust them, okay?
Bedecking slaps, guys, is what I'm saying.
Love it.
So be like the fashionable wizard
and sign up at Patreon.com.
Yeah. That's what it is.
Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast
where right now you can save 50% off your first month
or year.
And then just head on over to our dashery store
and get yourself some sweet, sweet merch
that you can show off to all the other cool kids
that hang out.
In our Discord.
In your neck of the woods.
Or in real life.
We need to be fashionable.
Yep.
All those great things.
Thanks for being here with us.
They're gonna save so much money.
Save money on the account.
Save money on the clothes.
They can go buy bubble gum afterwards.
Yeah, love it.
Happy birthday, Carla.
Thanks, friends.
And if you do sign up, thank you so much for signing up.
Or can't sign up, zero pressure.
You're still here listening to us
and that is thanks.
Love it.
This middle's been forever.
So you're a trooper, thanks.
Yeah.
We want you here.
Your finger got tired from hitting that skip button
and now we get to say goodbye and we love you.
We love you.
Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
We got you again.
Bye.
Love you, bye.
You know what?
Let's just do that thing
where you're gonna pass the mic around.
I'm into it now.
Sounds like a great plan.
Who wants first dibs?
Oh, Eloin, the back.
There's a few people who stand up
as you're putting your hand up
and are moving towards the microphone, Eloin.
What do you do?
All right, Lordbucket, we're gonna go with you
and then Eloin, you'll be next.
Yes, Lordbucket here.
Thank you for coming everybody
from well as far away as Vintersmouth
and probably up in the Me Mountains there.
I was just there last week having just a grand old time.
We saw some wild fauna and flora
and it was really quite an adventure
and I think that's what I'm gonna do more of
in these later years in my life.
A marriage is like a sunset.
Tell us about your current grandson.
Oh, have you heard about my grandson, Marklson?
He is really just the sunshine in my life.
And well, as I was getting back to the point,
I hear you, Ezell, I'm moving on, don't worry.
As I was saying, a marriage is like a sunset, sunrise.
Things are good, things are bad,
but you do it all together.
And well, if anybody wants to take a look
at my slides after from the Me Mountains,
I will be showing them as well as a follow-up
group of photos of Marklson.
He should be making an appearance after his nap later.
If anybody wants to say hello, you come find him.
All right, it's bold move to have a former wife here.
Eloin?
Four former wives.
Yes.
Thank you.
Love is important.
Marriage, she's had a few to drink now.
Marriage is not a way to say I love you.
You look over to Harrison's face
and he's got a very quizzical look about him.
Like he didn't understand what you just said.
Of course he didn't.
He's stupid.
Marriage is supposed to be sharing
with everybody you know, all your important people
that you love someone so much.
But that's all it is to you.
All you want to do is flaunt a temporary love
and spend ridiculous amounts of money.
Think of the colleges you could have put Cav through.
Okay, Cav did go to college.
I said colleges.
Get it.
Sorry Cav, do you want to go to college?
Is that what this is about?
This is my time.
It's a great, and actually speaking of that,
we've hit our three minute limit
so we'd like to move on.
We can come back to you.
Oh man, Bucket talked for like 17 minutes.
No, that's just, he's just the most boring person
in the world so it seemed like it was that long.
Listen. Let her talk.
All right, round two, Ellowin, let's do it.
Love is not just something that you put on like a costume
and parade around in front of people.
Love is deep and love, and it hurts
and it makes you do crazy things.
And you, ma'am, and she points to.
Gwendolyn.
She points to Gwendolyn.
Points to Gwendolyn.
I love him.
But you can do better.
Yeah, you can.
And then I drop the mic and I kind of stagger off
with my little bottle of brown liquor.
Okay, probably won't be getting the deposit back
for the AV equipment.
Not a problem though.
Lady Schneiderhound, you're up.
Cav, Lady Schneiderhound is giving her speech
and you clock the silhouetted figure of Dame Corvela
who doesn't enter the room
but is just like standing off to the sides
looking straight at you.
And then after Lady Schneiderhound kind of wraps things up
and there's a small clap for what she said at the end
which was all you need is love, da, da, da, da, da.
She.
No more than that because we don't want any
litigious actors coming after us.
Exactly.
I'll take on Daphne, I won't take on the Beatles.
Fair.
She heads back down the hallway.
You see her turn and like signal to you this time.
Okay, that was the excellent Lady Schneiderhound.
We're gonna throw it over to my dear sweet mother.
Take it away.
Welcome, take the mic.
Thank you so much, my darling Cav.
It is wonderful to be here to witness the third wedding
of my only son's father and ex-husband Lord Harrison.
Is an absolute delight to be here to witness
all of the great women that he's been with
and the taste he has cultivated over the years
for younger and younger vintages of wine.
Vintages, so young, well, how young are they?
So young, they're still being pressed.
I don't know.
He's not.
No, but.
He is just like, why'd I pick this analogy, damn it.
But truthfully, it's great to see another
lavish event to celebrate love,
and I can't wait for the next,
what'd you say, Cav, where'd he go?
I think he said it's gonna be three more times.
Three more times.
And if they all do it right,
Ellowin, you're right, love does hurt,
and you can do some crazy things.
I'm sorry that you didn't do them in the fun places.
And I leave the mic there.
It's an awkward clap through the crowd.
Ellowin, ruckus, cheer.
You look for Cavlarn, who, yeah,
he's nowhere to be seen.
You saw him sprint out the back.
Lady M, would you like to give a speech
before we check in with Cavlarn?
Why not?
Well, nothing to say to you,
Harrison, but Guinevere.
You see him pull at his.
Welcome to the club.
Thank God.
Welcome, welcome.
You'll join us soon enough.
And I think we're quite a bit of fun.
Let's do shot.
One of us.
Goobel gobble.
All of you, you get up and move towards the bar.
There's a confused, like a bit of excitement
from some people,
cause they're not entirely sure
what the vibe is anymore.
Harrison's like pulling at his shirt collar,
looking around for Cav.
Like you can't see you.
And Cavlarn, you had booked it down the hallway.
You hear kind of the end of Yiselle's speech
and Lady M get up and start speaking.
And you're like looking in every door again.
And you get down to the very end of this hallway
in this dimly lit room.
There's a couple of candles inside and you enter
and you see the same silhouette standing by a window.
Very clearly, Dame Corvella.
You've met her several times before.
What'd you have to do?
At least twice.
At least twice, yeah.
Well, yeah, I mean, she would have
at least partially raised you,
depending on the timing.
At least been there during a raising.
Anyways.
She was your only technical step mom.
True, true.
Yeah, we were like pre-step moms.
Yeah.
You enter and she doesn't say anything,
but you see her standing there.
What do you do?
How are we feeling today, Dame?
She turns and with a coldness in her voice says Gavlarne.
We're doing just fine today.
Good, good.
Normally has a bit of a sneer about her,
but she doesn't this time.
Couldn't help but notice the attire.
It's a bold choice.
I dressed for the occasion.
It is a wedding.
Exactly.
It's where love goes to die, Gavlarne.
Oh.
Give her the mic.
Yes.
Gavlarne.
My lapel mic's been on the whole time.
Hey!
Fucking lapel mics.
Why did we put them on everybody?
I don't know.
I have not come to give a speech.
Okay, that's probably good.
Anything profound.
I stayed quiet because noise makes liars sloppy.
She sits down, folds her hands.
She says, come in, have a seat, close the door.
Sure, yeah, I'll be right there.
The sound of the party, which has kind of picked up,
people have stopped giving speeches
and there's more just like,
shot, shot, shot, shot, shot, shot, shot.
You close the door and which dims
everything happening outside and says,
your father believes he has simply been unlucky in love.
Oh, well, we both know that's not the case though, right?
No, of course not.
It's not that he chooses poorly
or that hearts are fragile things.
The small humorless smile comes across her
very stoic face and that is not what happened.
She noticed you sat a little further away from her
and she gets up and pulls her chair closer to you.
Not getting a threatening vibe,
but she's coming over to you for certainty.
She says, years ago, before you were grown,
your father signed a document that he did not understand.
I mean, I do not think that is the first
and only time that has happened, but please continue.
No, yes, it was a civic agreement.
You're right.
He has signed many of them.
It was a consolidation of authority,
something boring to him, you know, Harrison.
Okay.
Something men like him never read closely.
She looks to you knowingly
the words did not stay where he put them.
They were taken, preserved, filed.
I do a lot of filing in my job.
Well, in my old, well, I didn't do it,
but like I was around while it was done.
So I'm with you so far.
She lifts the brim of her hat, even removes it.
So you can see her eyes.
They were filed in the Weeping Archive.
Oh shit, I've actually heard of that.
Every marriage after that was not chaos.
It was containment.
Each wife placed near him by coincidence,
by council, by recommendation.
Families with scribes, record keepers,
people who knew how to erase a just delay.
He thought he was protecting himself.
The Archive thought it was indexing him.
That's why he forgets things that matter.
That's why records vanish.
And that's why Vintersmouth
keeps surviving scandals it should not.
Your father is not powerful, Kavlarananan.
He is footnoted.
She stands up.
I waited to see what kind of man you were before telling you.
Whether you could carry truth without turning it into a weapon.
Now you know where to look.
The Archive already knows who you are.
She turns to leave.
She opens the door and the sound of the party picks up again
as the door opens.
As she exits, she adds without turning back.
If you ever read your father's name in ink that won't dry,
don't touch the page.
Okay, noted.
She turns the corner.
As you get up to follow her, she's gone down the hall.
It's weird that every conversation I have with her is like this.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season four, episode 48,
starring Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave,
Carla Maxted as Lady Marizon the first,
Amy More as Elluin the second,
Kyle Claset as Baroness Yselle the third
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue, editing and sound design of today's episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound and sound effects are from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Angaron Kierzen, Perry Matey,
Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Old School Gamer D,
Craig Zeiss, L.A. Branton, Chibs 1012 and Kudzu 828.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast,
and all of our amazing community help make sure that we have adventures
for you every single week.
Come join us today.
Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon Cast.
We hope to see you over there and you have yourself right now.
A great week. Yes.
And we'll talk to you very, very soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.