Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment. The door to your motel room opens, Kav, and you step through two guards.
I'm in the motel room?
Yeah, but you got an ankle brace on.
You're back at the divorced dad's hotel.
It's the divorced dad's hotel. Yeah. The door to your hotel room opens and behind you two guards lead you in and then kind of step back and are standing guard.
Outside of your room, the door closes and you find yourself in the room that you left.
There's a slightly thicker layer of dust over everything.
They clearly haven't sent housekeeping because you've left the do not disturb on there.
Oh, it's the original sheets.
Yeah. Yeah.
Look, as someone whose husband works in the hotel trade, I respect the fuck out of the DND.
As you enter though, and as the door closes, your foot knocks into a folded up piece of paper on the ground.
I grabbed the piece of paper.
You pick it up. It looks like it was hastily folded and you open it and there are three lines written on it.
It says, they're rewriting the truth, friend.
Vintersmouth might forget, but I won't.
Watch the stars. They're moving too fast.
Someone as high as fuck when they wrote that.
I miss our simple little town guys. Everything's so complicated.
Everyone speaks in riddles now.
Since when, too? Like this feels new.
Oh boy.
About three weeks ago, they all decided we weren't there for them.
Everyone took a vote.
Let's just be kind of more like Wacky now.
Damn it.
Let's give it a whirl.
It's all that Wacky Wand Wednesday business.
They have no idea.
That's where it all started.
There's catamine on the wands.
Of course, that's it.
That's it.
The town's just a giant K-hole.
Mystery solved.
Oh God, you're going to have to have an age restriction now on that.
K-hole was Cav's nickname in college.
Oh God.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast,
and I'm your dungeon master Russ More, he, him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
Not a kid. 14.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she, her.
I did say I gave really good strong hugs, so sorry.
Do you want me to roll damage?
Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave, he, him.
No, not like on the network sitcoms.
And Kyle Klasset as Bazaar the Wizard, he, him.
Escorts dressed up as guards.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast,
and we'd love for you to join us over at patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
Right now when you sign up, you'll get a seven-day free trial
and instant access to so many amazing bonus episodes,
more of what you love.
Come find it today at patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
And now fuck it, let's play.
Watch the stars.
Friend.
Well, I mean, Oak's a friend.
Bench is a friend.
Bonwyn, the kid, and Bazaar are all friends.
Somewhere, Alydin's ears are parking good.
Not a kid. 14.
Now, Russ, do I get the impression I'm free to leave the hotel room, or?
Are they just going to follow you and that's fine?
Or is it like a don't leave town kind of thing?
Yeah, like am I a flight risk, but as long as I don't go,
like they give me some leeway.
Yeah, they're allowing you to kind of go between places.
Obviously, you've been told by the guards
that you're to go nowhere near the mayor's office.
But you are a problem.
Barely did when he worked there, guys.
At this time, free to roam the city with escorts.
So stop by the quivering hills.
Go by the quivering hills, yeah.
Guards.
Oh, well, those are two very different things.
You mean escorted?
Being escorted around the town by armed individuals.
Escorts dressed up as guards.
Halloween, baby.
Cuff them.
All right, I would like to make my way to the Brood Awakening.
OK, yeah, you clean up whatever you're doing
and head back out with the two guards.
They don't say much of anything to you
unless you direct question or comment to them.
Who are they required to make small talk
if you make small talk with them?
Or what's their directive?
Are you trying to win them over?
Contractually obligated?
Contractually obligated to make small talk,
but they will not initiate small talk.
So is weather, hey.
You know what, though?
That's fucking ideal.
Perfect.
And you make your way to the Brood Awakening.
It's before it opens.
So the door is locked as you sidle up there.
I do the super secret knock that Bench and I agreed upon.
That's just three slow knocks.
It's almost instantaneous.
As soon as that third knock hits,
you hear a back door burst open
and quick footsteps running towards the front,
and the door swings open.
You see Bench's huge smile on his face.
You're here.
You came back.
He goes in to give you a hug,
and the guards kind of like
grab their handles or their swords.
It's fine, guys.
It's fine.
Come on in, everybody.
I assure you, too.
Come on.
It's good to see you.
So I don't need the full explanation,
but it's great to see you.
Would you like a drink?
I would love a drink.
Thank you.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Have your taste changed in the last three weeks,
or would you like the oatmeal stout?
I mean, I'll take anything you want to give me,
because it has been a hot minute.
Okay, okay.
Well, we'll put this little meat on your bones.
He pours you a stout.
I think I've got some...
I don't have anything hot whipped up yet,
but I've got some...
He looks under the counter.
I've got some pretzels and some beer nuts here.
Love it.
I'll make you something later.
So tell me, tell me, what's...
It's great to see you.
You look good.
Thank you.
Have you done something different
with the armed entourage behind you?
The armed escort?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
I hear you're in a little bit of trouble.
I mean, look, you try to expose some corruption
and then you leave town for three weeks,
and it turns out not the best course of action to do.
No, you probably want to be here so you can plead your case.
Yep, yep.
Yeah, I'm really sorry about that.
But you know what?
I'll know for next time.
It's totally cool.
Well, I guess without job, like, you've got the...
Are they letting you leave?
Like, are you going back to Kingstown
or do you have to, like, go to trial?
Great question.
I asked the hotel manager and he said, like,
I'm already prepaid for a little bit,
so I can at least stay.
Yeah, I don't know if I'm, like, super welcome
back in Kingstown or what,
so I'm just going to have to see, like, what it is,
what's going on, what's happening.
Don't know.
Love it.
Okay, well, I'm going to go whip up something
in the back here.
You guys want anything?
See, both of them just shake their head.
Says, uh, well, okay, I'll be right back.
A question before you go, though.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um, have you been watching the stars lately?
Uh, like, like, just in the,
like, the stars in the sky
or, like, stars, like, famous people?
No, not, like, on, like, the network sitcoms,
but, like.
Oh, yeah, no.
Uh, well, I mean, I've seen them.
Uh, is there some, is there,
is this, like, a, like, a buddy,
a buddy-buddy romantic moment
where you were looking at the stars
and was I looking at the stars
and we were thinking of each other
as we were looking at the stars,
but not together?
I mean, maybe.
I was just curious if,
if they'd seemed different to you at all lately.
Like, maybe they were, like, going a little quicker
than they had been in the past.
No, I hadn't noticed. I hadn't noticed.
That's, uh, I'll keep an eye out, though.
No worries, no worries.
Are they going faster?
Is that, is that a, is,
is the, is the world spinning
at a much quicker rate
now that there's other worlds?
I mean, I don't know.
I spent the last few days in a hospital, so.
Right. Right, right, right.
Benchworks nights in his defense.
Vinter Smith, notoriously a cloudy town,
which we haven't established until right now.
That's why there's vampires everywhere.
It's, like, forks washing through.
Yeah, that's right.
No, no, not really.
Let me, let me go get you something.
I'll think on, I'll think on this riddle
while I'm in the back there.
Alright, cool. It's great to see you, Bench.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Great to see you too, Cav.
We cut over to the school.
And, Bon, when you're
all ready for the day,
getting, going to pick up Alydin.
Hey, June, how did the night go?
Well.
Easier, once you'd been to Brewed Awakening?
Yep, a little, a little bit.
Just, it was a long night.
There was lots of, um,
lots of night screaming.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, good news.
Um, this morning
I asked Thane to go talk to my parents
and the, and everybody else, like, in their
retirement community and see if they can maybe
come and help with the kids
and take shifts and do cooking, you know, like
they, so.
That would be amazing.
I'm sure my parents will come and I'm sure a bunch
of other folks will come too because
yeah. So
helps on the way.
Helps on the way. Feel lighter already. Yeah.
Yeah, yeah. I'm just gonna, I gotta go
talk to Alydin. She,
she was really having some scary dreams
last night. I'm sure lots of them were.
She's been unusually quiet.
Oh, that is
unusual. Well, thanks for everything
you're doing and yeah,
we're circling the wagon, so
help should be here soon.
Thank you, Bon. And I'm gonna go
find my girl
Alydin. Make your way through
as few kids that give you high fives
and fist bumps on the way by and
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I'm a real rock star
in here. Of course. Yeah, you told some
killer stories last night. Yeah.
Um, and. That are all true
they now believe. Of course. Yeah.
Uh, and you
make your way to find Alydin. Where
does Bon win find Alydin this morning?
Uh, I think
like unusually for
like Alydin would be up at the
crack of dawn, probably bossing
some kids around, getting stuff
sorted. But she is
still in bed.
Not sleeping.
Just
just like teening?
Kinda, yeah. Yeah. Like
real pensive. Just
a look of she has never had
this many thoughts in her head at once.
Yeah, which is saying a
lot. She's been going through
it her whole life. Hey, Alydin.
Did you get back to sleep last night?
Yeah.
But it was the same stuff.
Oh, really?
It's like I didn't leave.
Can a dream wait
for you? Well,
you know what? A month ago I would have said
no, but now
maybe?
I found a very cryptic note
from my great great great
grandmother about the Forge
thing, so... Can I read it?
Of course.
So I sent Thane to get my parents. I thought
we should
let's both go talk to Bazaar
since he is the smartest magic guy
we know.
Find out about dreams, find out about
cryptic notes and feeding sorrow
to a Forge and just really cross
our fingers he has some idea
what's going on.
Couldn't your great
great great
grandmother
have maybe been a little
more specific? Because it's like your
whole job. Yeah, I
flipped the note over hoping there was
like... It's like your whole family's thing, right?
Yeah, like what I mean
by this is.
But no, nothing. It's just
mystery upon mystery. Do you have to cry
on it? I don't know.
Maybe.
It's powered by tears.
Seems counterintuitive though, more wet.
But I don't know.
But I kind of got to figure it out
or Everbane's is done and it has
been in the family for like
six generations. Oh, man.
Yeah, so
I don't know, I thought maybe
I'd buy you a cinnamon bun and we could go to
the magic closet and just like
Yeah. Yeah.
Talk to Bazaar. See how he's
doing. Maybe swing by the hospital
and visit Cav, you know. Yeah,
is he OK?
Yeah, I think so. Well,
I don't know. I
I don't want to lay more on you, but I did hear
that
remember how the guards all like carried him away?
Yeah. And that was so kind.
Uh huh.
Yeah, I guess they arrested him actually.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Not surprise.
Not ideal.
No, and they kind of have that look on
their face too because like they weren't
like, you know when you've
stolen a few things, maybe
too many things and then it's just
a look of disappointment and like you're making
them do their job?
Yeah, it was like that.
Right.
So Cinnamon Bun?
Yeah, let's do Cinnamon Bun and Magic
Closet, hey? Oh, I heard
that that is not the name anymore.
Are you kidding? How?
Cut to Bazaar and Mums
Marvels. The two of you are standing
out front looking at
this beautiful sign.
It's so colorful.
I like it. I like the
bird. Yeah.
I wonder how Bazaar likes
it. Why is it wearing a hat?
I don't know.
Is that bird a pirate?
Kind of looks like
that bird might be a pirate.
Huh.
That's weird. Yeah.
Well, let's go see what the new
shop's all about.
Have I met Bazaar's mom
yet? No.
I don't think we've had an interaction.
Okay. Alydin's a little nervous.
None of us have, right?
Or I guess obviously
Cav has.
There was a very awkward
first interaction.
But they were on the boat together.
They go way back. But yeah, Alydin
and I haven't met her.
The door chimes and
you enter and
you are greeted
with a plethora
of pirate and nautical themed
items.
Alydin, you see entirely new
merchandise everywhere. You see
Bazaar's magical items. They've
expanded since I previously
described what Bazaar saw.
But they're still kind of relegated to
one wall at this moment.
Wow. It's
different. It's different in here.
Hey?
Real piratey. Yeah.
Why? There's a tide
chart. We live on a river.
This is not
Huh.
This book about not
tie-in could be
for anybody.
That's a lot of call for that here.
We are a port city.
Just ask Bazaar.
Oh, thank
God. Bazaar, since you've
been back and have kind of
taken a look at many
of the wands that children are just firing
off and a lot
of these new items,
you've actually come- A lot of quality control.
Absolutely. But you've actually
come to find that some of the nautical
items that you've found
may contain curses.
You're uncertain if
you've pulled all of them off the shelves.
So that's where we've kind
of caught you is like containment
in the back. Come on.
Come on back. I'm taking care of some things and
Fuck. Yeah.
Please come back.
I've never been in the back room here
before. Well, it's nothing fancy
but gets the job done.
What is all this stuff? So
all of this is
the product
my mom, Clara, brought in
which I think she
stepped out to meet with
oh, God, I can't remember his names.
I've been thinking about so many other things.
I can't even remember the name of my own shop now.
Well, it has changed recently.
New sign. Looks great.
It looks really good. People probably love it.
Very. Jake, Jake the pirate
Oh, God. Is he
is he a pirate?
Is it Captain
Jacob? I have no clue. His name
is Jake and like there's
nautical things around so I'm kind of like
pulling threads together.
I'm more concerned about the cursed items that we have here.
I mean,
Alydin and I did meet a
pirate named
Jacob.
Who may or may not be
a cannibal. Excuse what?
He does want to take over the city.
We're leaning towards not a cannibal.
Definitely a pirate.
Definitely wants to take over the city.
With that, there's a
chime and you hear several
heavier footsteps
come into the store.
Cav, you enter in
followed by your two
entourage
and you hear voices coming from the back room.
Hello?
Is that Cav?
It sounds like Cav.
We're back here. Cav, come on. Come on to the back.
Buddy, how you doing?
Doing great. Got a couple of
stragglers with me. Don't mind them though.
They're just on the clock.
Okay. Oh, you were
arrested. Oh,
hey. Big time. That is
Steve. Could you give us a minute?
He's not going to run away. We can't go very
far, Bonwyn. Just maybe out into the
shop. Just our friend almost died.
Keep the door open though.
That would be appreciated.
You know where I live.
It's not really you we're concerned about,
Bonwyn. I mean, I'm taking
responsibility for this very injured
man to not run away.
Can you even run? Debatable.
I couldn't really before.
Cav, how you doing, buddy?
And I give him a big hug and I'm like up to
his waist, I guess?
Might still be tender. Be careful.
No. And I did say.
That's face to belly button. I did say
I gave really good strong hugs.
So, sorry. Do you want me to roll damage?
It's a well known fact. I know. It's okay.
It's the most damage you've rolled.
It's a little ouchy, but it's.
Okay.
Oh, record. Okay.
I figured it was business.
Yeah.
Business. Business.
Welcome to the middle.
Welcome to the middle. Here we are.
Hi.
Here we are. See what I did there?
I wanted it to happen, so I made it happen.
Amy really took charge and I
liked it. You know what I like to
focus on right now? Kyle's
shirt. Oh, yeah. It's so good.
The shirt's came in.
Kyle's got some of our new merch he's
sporting. It looks fantastic.
Do a little
turn on the catwalk and then.
Catwalk.
Oh, there we go. Oh, he's getting tangled.
Nice.
Yeah, it's so nice. We have new
styles, new storefront.
It's pretty dope.
How's the fabric, Kyle?
Voluptuous.
You heard it here first. I'm excited to get mine.
I know. We'll get it sometime.
We'll get it sometime. Eventually.
Postal strikes.
Good things come to those who wait.
Exactly. But that new store
is dumbdragons.dashary.com.
Link will be
in the description when you
listen to this.
Go check it out because
we switched to this new store.
Just so you know, because
a lot of print-on-demand stuff, the margins
aren't great.
We have been getting, you know.
We get a little bit from it.
But this way, almost
50% of what you pay for
the item comes back to us as
the creators, which is huge.
We get to use that for upgraded equipment,
for getting actually physically
together for
shenanigans,
because that's our best stuff.
And maybe going to different
conventions and maybe some live shows.
Like the possibilities are endless.
Thank you.
Thank you. But also,
if you do buy some
merch, send it to
Jess over in the Discord.
Not the merch.
Send a picture.
Is that not what I said?
You could just send Jess
some stuff.
If you buy something for yourself, buy something for Jess.
One for you, one for her.
She works real hard.
Yeah, send a picture.
And we'd love to see
you sporting it out in the wild
because, you know, more questions about
the show is always better. And then you can
talk about all of the great things that happen
in the show.
That wasn't really
a great segue.
And today's patron.
That wasn't really a great segue.
That segue didn't work.
I was going to say, one thing that
you can't send to Jess is the dedication
that we give to each patron every
episode. You get to keep that
one for yourself. And Russ,
do you know who that dedication goes to?
That dedication
goes to Amber
W.
I've never known an Amber
that I didn't like.
So much better than Amber Single You.
Yeah, yeah.
It's a big W.
Wow, Tom.
And Nicole.
Tom has said 10 words tonight.
Fucking nailed it.
Tom'd the shit
out of that thing.
We've missed you, Tom.
Damn.
But that's the end of the middle.
Thanks for hanging out with us, and we'll talk to you very, very soon.
Get back to the episode. Love you, bye.
Bye.
Sorry, I just, it's so good to see
you. I'm sorry you got arrested
and like...
What'd they get you for?
You know, not super clear yet.
Allegedly, they think I'm
some sort of mastermind who was cooking
the books for the city.
But they don't. No, they think so.
That's what I said. That's what I told them.
Betty and Steve, you guys got the wrong man.
Do you know...
Bazaar starts laughing, one of the wands goes off,
and a fucking fireball bounces around the room.
Jesus!
Can I borrow that?
No, it's defective.
No, I need fire.
Oh god, Bazaar, guys...
It's only, how long's it been since we've seen each other?
No time at all. I have a thousand things
I need to talk to you all about.
Okay, hit us with it.
Then so does Alydin, who is, maybe gets priority.
Much less pressing, because
you know, it's not my livelihood
that's on the line here, and the honor
of my family.
Okay.
That sounds very serious.
Put that away. What's going on?
Damn.
When you put it like that, Alydin.
So I can't light the forge at Everbane's
and I found a weird mysterious note
for my great great great great grandmother
who maybe I have to feed its sorrow?
What does that mean?
I said she should cry on it.
I found a mysterious note.
Oh god, what did yours say? Was it also about fire?
No, mine was about the stars.
Okay. Like celebrities?
Nope.
Oh. Like the stars.
The stars in the sky.
Okay, what about them? Do you need to feed them sorrow?
Whatever that means?
No, I don't.
I'll read you mine. It's pretty short.
It says they're rewriting the truth, friend.
Vintersmouth might forget,
but I won't.
Watch the stars, they're moving too fast.
I mean the beginning sounds like
they're just talking about them doing the double
reverse whammy thing on you with the books.
Absolutely, that's 100% what that part's
referring to and then it's like
And then something about the stars.
It kind of goes off the rails for me.
Okay, cool.
Alydin, let's talk about your thing.
Well, you know,
you got a message.
Cav got a message.
I didn't get
like a note kind of
message. But I had this
really weird dream last night.
More than once. Dream message.
Right? More like you just kept going back
to it. It just every time I would
wake up and fall back asleep, I was in the
exact same spot. So there was a tree, right?
And then there was like
all sorts of like clocks and stuff
hanging from it. And then there was like
a tiny little town of
Vintersmouth with tiny little people
inside and the
hands were ticking. And then there was this
woman who looked like she was like maybe
part of the tree. I don't know. And then she
was like you're gonna change
you're gonna change the world and something
about screws and maybe springs.
And then, but am I
gonna be able to
do it and something about time?
Okay, there's like a ton going on there.
Sounds like how I would remember
a dream. Yeah, that was perfect.
Thank you for putting that there though
so that Amy knows. So crystal clear
when you first wake up and then the minute
later it's gone. I was losing
it as soon as I was explaining it
to Bonwyn. Amy
was losing it. So all that's
happening and we still don't know where
Dace is. And there's like a thousand
kids here now. So
how do the four of us
solve all of these problems? Wait,
wait, wait, Alydin, you said you were visited
by somebody in a dream. What did they
look like? So
she was, it was a woman
and her
eyes were like
so shiny. Like
like
like glass. And then
she had like
like plant
solder and stuff but like she was like
she wasn't like part of the tree but she
was kind of part of the tree because her skin
kind of looked like
like tree skin, right? Cool.
And
she was smiling at me but I didn't
feel like unsafe
but at the same time
you know when someone smiles at you like they
know something.
It was kind of like that.
And then she
said something about like
I'm gonna change the world and something about
screws and oh and fire
and fire. And she said something
changing the world
with screws and fire.
Huh.
Bizarre like stops
for a moment, moves the box of
like mishaps off the table
and grabs one of the books that he got.
There's a fire away from me.
Yeah, grabs one of the books that he got from
Kingstown.
He pulls out Fadeels and
Hellish Pacts, the
intertwining of two realms.
And I want to look
through that book for a description of the lady
that she just told me about.
You know what I love about this guys is that it's like
you know in Buffy where like mostly a big thing
that they did was just like
go to the library and like research
things.
Russ, do I see if Portals, Portals,
Portals is amongst the books
that Bizarre
picked up onto the shelf?
I would pull out the whole stack and just set it there.
So yes, sorry, you are looking in
the book that you just said and you're trying
to find any sort of description
or
piece about this woman.
Yeah, it says the book also
includes accounts of powerful entities,
both fae lords and arch devils,
using mortals as pawns in their plans
to open gateways between their domains
and the material plane, hence
the event that we just went through.
As you were
kind of transcribing and taking all these
things down, like it
jogs a memory, so roll investigation
with advantage please.
Beautiful.
Rolls.
You're doing it. That is going to be a
21 on investigation.
Yeah, baby. You find a
passage on
this woman
who fits, there's
a lot there, so you know, take
your time for a moment and then
You know what, I can just read the passage
that I found right here in this book
on page 217. This seems
just of the impossible.
Seems like based off of what I've seen,
Alydin, you might have spoken to
Ysera Thindleweft.
She did not tell me her name.
Do you know her? Did you go to school
with her or something? Me? No.
I didn't go to school. No, I know
sweetheart, I know.
I didn't have a very good sleep last night.
Yeah, that's fair. I meant Bazaar.
I thought maybe Bazaar knows all kinds
of cool people. No, no.
So,
this person comes
from a book about arch
fey and demon lords
and similar to probably
who the banjo man made an accord
with. No pun intended.
But
yeah, so this is potentially
one of those beings.
So,
she used to be a mortal
named Ysera Emberlace
and then
vanished from this Artificer's
Guild nearly 400 years ago.
So,
kind of applicable and odd that she
made this making sense.
So, she became a whispered caution,
an Artificer who pursues
an Artificer whose pursuit
of beauty and precision crossed into the domain
of the unknowable.
Okay.
So, this is
someone who's confused.
So, she's
so she's like
the banjo
man's
witch?
It's
maybe similar.
Let's see. It goes on to say that
Histagree agrees on very
little except for the fact that
she believed Artificer
was not merely, Artificing
was not merely a craft but a
spell-like song that invention
could tap into the same threads that
wove dreams and fey bargains
and memory itself.
Um, last seen walking into
a rift that shimmered like starlight through
silk. A portal. Speaking of a loom
that spins not cloth but
consequence, not one followed, not one
no one dared.
Can people just say things normal anymore?
Does no one can say things normal anymore?
Artificer? Are you an
Artificer? What is an Artificer?
Wow, I mean that's what I went to go get the
books to help me with. I mean I do have
these and I pull those three books
that I'd actually gotten
to the side and say
these were going to be what we
studied to get you
prepared. So yes, your track
was to be an Artificer.
Okay.
They build stuff.
Yes.
That's why I was saying in there that you know
maybe your hands are made to create and
not destroy.
Why don't they just say a builder?
Because that denotes
a more mundane meaning
than what you'll be doing.
Seems unnecessarily
confusing.
Can I rename myself whenever I become
something? You can give yourself whatever title
you want. Oh yeah.
This is all Alydin is thinking
about now.
As long as you feel like you've actually earned it.
Conversation entirely.
What's my new
cool name and title going to be?
Were there moths
around her?
Hm? Moths?
Yeah, moths.
I don't think so. I can't really
remember.
It's one thing not tracking. Do you think that it made it like
I'm going to dream about that again?
Oh, I asked Bonwyn.
What is real and what is magic?
Oh, I'd like to also ask that question.
Like how do we know what is
like in my dream, was I
dreaming? Was I really some place
else with this strange
person and clock trees?
Because previously I would just say
crazy dream. You know, everyone has
crazy dreams.
But like everything
that just happened to us seemed
that was like dreams.
I think for
those touched
either by
the ethereal weave
or by
divine right have
some connection to
a higher plane
when unconscious.
It's maybe when we get visited
by be it a god
or an
epiphany on a spell or
maybe what you experienced. So
it's hard to say.
But knowing your skills
I would bet that it's not just
a dream. She's searching
through shelves and stuff
and finds an empty notebook.
And waves and goes,
if I go into the same
dream, I'm when I wake up, I'm
going to write it down. She puts it in her bucket.
That's a good idea. Dream Journal.
Keep track of
them. That's already a thing.
I really thought I just.
No, you just invented.
I mean, I kind of just, you know,
you grabbed a journal and you said you're going to dream your
you're going to write down your dreams.
I've never heard of that before.
I think you invented that.
She opens a book and
and writes Alydin
Dreamweaver.
Our defensive dreamweaver is
a really cool title. That is
a cool title. I'm like
don't look at it. Oh, sorry.
She goes off into the corner.
Dear diary. Well,
that kind of points us in a direction.
But your fire issue going on
at the
at the forge. Yeah.
So I got this note.
I mean, I'd still like to try the wand.
I like a simple
solution, but otherwise
sorrow. I have
to sacrifice something.
I mean, I have to
as Alydin so kindly
pointed out, it is my livelihood
and legacy of my family.
So you lost a memory
in there, correct? Yeah.
Oh, yeah, you did. Yeah.
Remember, he was in ever veins.
In ever veins. Yeah.
But I don't
remember.
What else? You think
you think maybe he took
the memory that you typically offer.
Oh. To light
the forge.
Do you think I've just been doing it unconsciously
this whole time? Maybe.
Huh. I mean,
does it have to be something tangible? I mean, I know
the note reads like a note, but
a voice, a voice you get back.
You know, if you offer up a memory,
you know, maybe it comes back to you.
OK. I mean, I have some bad memories
that I would be happy to give, but
that probably doesn't really work, does it?
It's got to be something you like.
Well, yeah, there's got to be
two sides of the same coin.
I don't know. Honestly, I
think my dad's coming to help with the kids. I'm really just
hoping he can figure it out.
We can hope that. And I'm
happy to go check it out, see if we can
find out what's going on with it and give it
give it my best crack.
You know, no promises, though.
I appreciate it.
This is so beyond my experience.
If you guys use a wand, can I watch?
Yeah.
Yeah, y'all have to stand behind
me, though.
Far behind me.
Because you're fireproof?
No, no,
but
let's hope so.
I do wear
two cloaks so I can take one off.
Alydin then laughs and writes
something in the journal.
Oh, while we're there,
Pawn, when I've been meaning to ask, as
we make our way out the door, I assume,
do giraffes
mean anything to you?
What do you mean?
Oh, I just
happened to, while
we were in there, there was a party and
giraffes and you
were there.
You know, Neven?
You know, like with
the, yeah, well,
she's my best friend and sometimes
we just, I'll explain.
I'll explain on the way.
OK, sounds good.
You walk out of the store and out into the street
and everybody make
and it's worked out so well
in the fae, everybody make
a perception
check.
Oh, well,
better than probably every
roll I had last time we played.
That's a 10. Yeah, also
a 10 for me, so not good, but
19.
I'm busy.
Writing in my
dream journal. Thinking a lot of
deep thoughts.
Not right now.
Cav, you're not moving
as fast as everyone else and Bazaar
and Bonwyn are talking about
giraffes and Alydin
is writing in her journal and you're
unusually attentive
to everything around you right now,
to your surroundings.
You notice that
your friend's
footsteps appear
to be moving backwards.
I mean, I wasn't expecting that, Russ.
I guess a call out for everyone to stop.
Guys, guys, stop,
stop walking. Okay. Why?
This is gonna sound crazy.
I don't know if we have to start conversations
like that anymore. Okay, yeah,
you know what, after the last few weeks, fair.
It really looked
like y'all were walking backwards.
Like your footsteps
were moving in reverse.
I've been trying this dance called the Moonwalk
that I picked up when I was in,
but I'm not good at it, so.
Like our feet were pointing the wrong way?
Yeah.
Oh, gross. Like our top half
was going like facing forward and
and the feet were.
Yeah, I don't know what,
I just, I don't know what's going on.
What do you want for pain
management?
That's a good question.
They weaned me off the good shit
a couple days ago.
Everybody's kind of paying attention that
if anybody does take a step.
Yeah, I was about to test it.
Yeah, you know, bizarre,
you take a few steps forward, everybody's watching
you do so, and then the
footsteps are reversed.
It appears as if you are walking
backwards as you progress down the street.
But he is progressing down the
street. Yeah, yeah, he's walking normally
as the footsteps appear to be going
the other way. Walk forward,
walk backwards, saying the backwards
man, the backwards man, I can walk
backwards fast as you can.
Nightmares about that, why?
That's unnecessarily creepy.
Who's the backwards man? Don't put ideas
into his head.
Earmuffs. Of course.
It wouldn't be me, it'd be, you know,
fucking Tom Green.
Yeah, but he'll make it into something
super creepy. He's Canadian, we could get him,
I'm sure of it. Hell yeah, dude.
Hell yeah. Yeah.
Write down Tom Green.
You told me not to write things down.
Don't write anything down.
We manifest. Except for this.
Tom Green. Yeah.
Yeah, I don't have an answer
for this one. I'm going to
jump in the air and see
what my feet do. As you leave
the jump, the footsteps
appear to be reversed from where you were
standing. And then as you land
and then kind of take
a couple steps as you land, they
still appear to be going in the opposite
direction. So my feet don't go
in the inverse direction that I'm moving in all
directions, because otherwise they would
have gone up into my legs and that would have been
very painful.
Glad it didn't work. Wow.
I'm really glad it didn't work too, but that was the scientific
end that I was expecting.
I don't...
This is magic,
right?
This is real?
Hold on, I pull out my spell book
and I'm just flipping through and I'm like, come on, something,
something, something's weird, we've got something here.
Nope, that's...
But we can still go.
Alydin starts to walk forward
toward everything. Yes, yeah, we can
keep moving out and
I'm just flipping through my book as we
continue on. We're just walking with our heads down looking at our
right like, the fuck
is happening? Alydin's the first one.
Ken's Google search would be, why walk backward?
Why backward walk?
Why feet not forward, backwards walk?
Alydin, you're the first one to
move forward again
and as everybody's looking
at your feet, so you can only really,
if you are all in fact looking at your feet,
you start doing the
Running Man and
with
a...
the air around you begins
to ripple slightly
and
you are
jumped forward 30
feet down the street
and in the space you were and in the space you
appear, the air
around you and those spaces
appears like silk
being pulled through water.
Bazaar? Alydin's the flash.
Uh, um...
Got something for this?
And as you turn around to look at
Bazaar, everybody can see
that one of your
eyes... Which one? The left one or the right one?
Uh, odds is... Oh god.
Don't be the left. Odds is left,
even's right.
Right. So your right
eye appears to
be glowing with
what looks like a white
moon-like color from a distance.
I am going to...
What am I gonna do?
Shit. Cat?
I don't want to move?
Do I see or feel
anything different? You don't notice your eye
situation yet. You just...
it suddenly appeared 30
feet down the street away from your friends.
You describe this as
a, uh, as like
a shimmering like silk?
Yeah. Cool.
Uh, immediately as soon as I see
it, I am going to Misty Step
to Alydin and
and just like, hug.
It is a very similar
effect. Slightly different.
But very similar effect
that happens as Bazaar appears in front
of you. It's like a quick, ah!
Hug! Yep.
Cloaks around and I'm
gonna try to start just backing up away from
this, uh, this loom
looking thing, I assume.
As you're backing away in this
this, uh,
water effect, it begins
to dissipate as you
as you walk away from it.
I think there's something wrong with that part of the road.
Uh, no. No, no, no. This was
this reminded me of something
that I read in the book, uh.
Did you read
something in the book and you made this happen?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm glad I read the book because
this might have
been that, but the last time
that Ysari, a person, was seen
they, uh, were seen
walking into a rift that shimmered like starlight
through silk, speaking
of a loom. She was talking about the
remember that saying I said
that spins not cloth but consequence.
No one followed her in
and no one dared.
We almost should accidentally follow her in?
I think you might almost have been
pulled in.
One day.
I know, I know.
Dumbgeons and Dragons
Season 4, Episode 28
Starring Amy More as
Alydin, Carla
Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, Tom
Laird as Kavlaran Goldwave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard
and Russ More as your dungeon
master. Dialogue editing and sound
design of today's episode is by Russ
Moore. Our community manager is Jessica
Babiak. Music is from Epidemic
Sound and sound effects are from
Epidemic Sound and Boom Library.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt
Garbutt. And we'd like to say a huge
thank you to our supporting producers
including Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babiak, Cat Waterflame,
Jacob Madden, Ongoron Kiersen,
Perry Matey, OldSchoolGamerD,
Craig Zeiss and
L.A. Branton. Have you been enjoying your time
with Dumbgeons and Dragons? Well, thank you
so much for being here. If you're
looking for more of what you love, come over
to Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon
Cast where you're going to get a seven day
free trial. And when you're a patron
for at least three months, we're going to send you some
merch based on the tier you're at.
Come on over. We hope to see you over there.
Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragon
Cast. Have a great week. We'll talk
to you soon. Dumbgeons and Dragons
is a Dumb Dragons production.