Hold tight! Dumbgeons and Dragons will start in just a moment.
You hear a huge rumbling sound, and then up out of the ground you see this claw
and head of this monster as it emerges up from the storage room down below.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast,
and I'm your dungeon master Russ More, he him. Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she her.
So you guys have a plan, right? Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she her.
People are going to die because of you right now.
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave, he him. Hi, um, what is happening?
And Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, he him. Pointy end out.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon-supported podcast,
and you can join us today at Patreon.com slash DumbDragonCast.
There's a seven-day free trial and a whole bunch of episodes for you to listen to.
We hope to see you over there. And now fuck it, let's play!
Bizard, knowing where the stables are, you're going, I assume, the most direct route there, yes?
Yep. Okay, knowing how
Alydin moves to the city, are you going the most direct route there?
I think yes. One, because it's the middle of the night, streets are empty. Well, streets were
empty, and like her main concern is that she's got like a whole bunch of smaller than her
kids and a scary thing in the basement. Like we're fucking getting out into the public eye.
Stranger danger, and we want to be around some grownups.
Okay, great. So we see Alydin in front, Tally playing caboose, ushering these kids out.
Come on, everybody, let's go, let's go, keep it up.
You just gotta, and I, I, Alydin kind of like falls back a little bit and grabs
a couple kids like by the arm and like hauls them up on her back piggyback style,
and I'm like, carry them, Tally, carry them.
You see Tally picking up one of the, a couple of the smaller kids.
Football star.
Yeah, like just trying to like drag them. Tally doesn't have a lot of muscle mass as it is,
like just trying to do what you're doing.
We're underfed children.
You make it down the street, and then you hear from a couple different points in the city,
you hear this howling call that I've been describing so far.
You hear that up in towards the direction you're going,
but more importantly, from where you're coming, you hear it louder and it like echoes out,
like you turn and you look and you see that there are a couple street lamps,
and it's almost like there's this, this wave effect that's happening around the light as you
hear this sound, and then as you turn back and rush forwards, you round a corner knowing that
this is, you know, you're heading down towards the magic closet.
You run square into the chest of Bazaar.
There's, there's a monster.
There's a monster.
I know.
Come on, let's go.
And I turn around and I say, follow me right here.
Come on, all of you.
And I make sure that I am actually behind them.
And Alydin, you know where to go.
Alydin takes off with a kid on her back.
Come on, you guys.
Yeah, we're coming.
Okay, come on.
I'm ready to go.
Let's go.
Okay, let's go.
Do we turn?
Or what do we do?
I can't care anymore.
Use your strong light.
As you make sure that you're behind all these kids, you look back down towards
where the stable is and you hear like this crunching noise coming from that direction.
You can't see a creature yet.
You hear the howls.
You've heard the howls as you've been running this far so far.
But you hear another one coming directly from the stable.
I'm going to be backing up as the kids.
I imagine I can walk as fast backwards as kids can run forward.
So yeah, I'm keeping an eye on our six.
Alydin, you're making a run for the magic closet.
Every tally, holding everybody as much as they can.
Bizarre, you're hanging back a little bit.
You're passing by different side streets and you see military and guards flooding
with torchlight and having their weapons drawn and are rushing around your position.
You round a final corner and you see the magic closet up in the distance.
Bizarre, you see these guards running up from you're kind of down the main street there.
You see them rushing over the bridge and as you turn back to look down the direction
you come you see this shadowy hulking figure coming around the corner on all fours
and these beady red eyes turn and look at you.
And then it turns away as it sees that there are several soldiers coming up behind
and like bolts into an alleyway.
Instinctively Bizarre would just launch off a shard of ice
from his wrist trying to like hit it as it rounds the corner.
Well that's a nat one.
So a three.
Oh my god you freeze its butt.
So it takes eight cold damage and it will have disadvantage on its next weapon attack
before the end of its next turn so I don't think anything's going to come of that but
as he does Bizarre's going to point it out to the to the militia or to the military people
and say off from the stable ran down that way look for the frost trail.
Will do thank you.
And they rush off after there's three of them following down your directions there.
Alydin you've made it to the front door of the magic closet.
I assume you've left it unlocked.
I think in his hurried state yeah he probably wouldn't have thought to
thought a lot he's like the danger of the town isn't going to be stealing my shit.
Like I mean though a town's on fire looters oh yeah right but if you were
if I was running to save some children I likely wouldn't stop to lock up the shop.
That seems logical.
So Alydin like hoping that that's the case runs like full on and wrenches the knob
as she hits the door and hoping it's going to swing open into safety.
And it does so.
Stumble into it and then get inside and the kids pile in behind you followed quickly
by Bazaar who shuts the door locks it and as you look out into the street Bazaar you see
more military pounding on doors as they're walking through and they're blocking off streets.
Cav you're making your way to the bridge and on the side you're on the noble side
you see a squadron of soldiers.
It's relatively quiet otherwise on this side but you do have visibility quite
clearly to the other side where you see another squadron of soldiers
barring people from the artisan district from crossing the bridge.
Just imagine him like power walking making my way downtown
walking face to face I just I look like I have somewhere to be so they don't bother.
Exactly you just look like you're on a mission.
You've got the white cap and your nightgown.
Oh my god are you still in your jammies?
Only time will tell.
Didn't say he changed so there are four guards on one side there are six guards on the other
side they don't appear to be letting people across from the artisan district.
Does Cav still think this is because of the heist because he knows nothing of this monster
I mean he definitely thinks it's still a possibility but he's been seeing people
running in every direction and something's going down somewhere and yeah no one seems
to be really hassling him so he's less inclined to think it's about that but still
in the back of his mind is like there's a possibility.
Basically from your place to here you would have heard similar howls
coming from over the river so nothing as loud as what's been described from people
who are directly surrounding these creatures but you would have heard that echoing across
the river a nature check could attempt to place it if you want to try that.
Sure well it's a four before any bonus so it's probably not.
Definitely hear it definitely get a sense that it's some sort of creature or animal
but don't make the connection that it could be the same creature or creature type that
came from those those tunnels.
I guess I'll just go towards the guards that are guarding the bridge.
Hi um what is happening?
Sir you need to get back into your home.
Oh well okay I don't really I okay long story short I'm hearing like a.
Down to the military barracks then we need to get you safe.
I see you're pointing at me yep no problem.
Um okay which direction that way for the barracks.
He looks dumbfounded that you don't know where the barracks is but it's
yes lights over there go that way.
Okay can do thank you they start to like turn that way and walk away a little bit
until he's like not watching me anymore and then I try to find a place to like get out of sight.
Roll for stealth.
I mean I really don't want to go to these barracks.
Yeah no that's fair so you're trying to get across the river.
This is the only bridge across the river.
However there's a dinghy that's tied up real old there's a dingy one paddle.
Yeah you move away from the guards enough that they believe that you're
going where they've told you to go but then you have a moment to kind of duck down
in the embankment to see if there's another way across and as you get down through this brush
first what's your passive perception?
Passive perception is 14.
Okay that's probably enough so you get down the the embankment and you look over to the
other side of the city and you see just droves of people being moved to ships
being moved to the docks being moved away from a the bridge but also the city on the other
side. There are military on there escorting people down but on the rooftops behind this
group of people you see this shadowy creature like leap from one the top of one building
over a street and crunches down on top of the next building.
You get down to the bottom of this embankment and suddenly some memory comes back because
not only do you see this small fishing boat but you remember being out on it.
It's Bench's small fishing boat. Do you try to use it?
Absolutely.
All right let's hop in and make an athletics roll.
Roll for row row row your boat.
That is a 17.
Cav comes from a long line of seafaring half-elves.
Of course of course you push the dinghy out and hop in and it keeps the water out well
enough and you begin making your way you're moving down obviously with the with the flow
of the river but you seem to have no issue and you're not catching the attention of
any guards on either side at this moment.
We'll be right back. It's the middle.
Welcome to the middle everybody. How are you today?
I'm good thanks.
Yeah that's great.
Yeah yeah but also all the people listening.
All the people listening.
Yeah you guys do it too.
It was an earnest answering of the question as she looked at me like yeah I forgot we were
recording and it's okay.
Just hanging out.
Yeah just having a good time getting these episodes out here.
We're very happy to be back for season four.
Oh god so happy.
Yeah we've got high action high excitement.
Oh man there's some danger.
There's some real danger you know.
Children are in danger.
They are I'm putting children in danger is what I'm doing.
Holy shit what else is new.
We talk about it in the down time which didn't come out after last episode because we split
one big session putting it out for two episodes.
That'd be too many spoilies I think.
Absolutely so in the down time which will come out basically right after this episode
if you want to join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragging cast.
We talk about the plan for next episode which.
That's right we're planning.
We're using our down time productively.
Yeah absolutely 100% productively planning is happening in the down time.
That's the word.
But that's not all.
Yeah that's not all.
Tomfoolery.
We'll let you listen to the rest of this episode and then it will probably all make sense.
So come join us over there.
We'd love for you to be there and we hope you're enjoying the new season
because we certainly are so thank you.
Thank you for being here with us.
We love you guys.
Love you so much and we'll talk to you very soon.
We'll get you back to the episode.
You have a great week.
Okay bye.
We'll cut back to Dace and Bonwyn.
You've been.
Monster hunters.
You've been rushing through the streets.
Make an investigation roll with advantage for Dace being with you doing basically the same thing.
17.
So are we heading.
Towards the bridge.
Oh do they want to eat the rich?
You're kind of changing my mind about the monsters.
They did fuck up all my stuff though.
What's their intention?
Tell me a lot to think about.
Yes so you are chasing after this creature and you're making your way towards the bridge
and you're getting closer and you're weaving through the streets trying to get a view of it.
Every chance you get just like line of sight on it it ducks over another building
and you lose it and have to rush ahead.
You make your way to like the intersection of like the docks and the bridge and immediately
you see that people are being barred from going on to the noble side of the city.
You see that they're being ushered down to the docks.
You see Cav on the other side of the river
making his way slowly down this embankment and then like stumble upon a small little rowboat
and then as you see that see all of this taking all this in this creature that you've
been chasing leaps across the street from where you are and like crunches down on a building to
your left which is making its way down towards the people who are being ushered down to the
docks. I had already started making my way towards the soldiers that were blocking people
from crossing the bridge as as soon as I saw that so I am keeping an eye on whatever little
adventure Cav is having on the riverbank there but I'm already approaching them and I'm pissed.
Like what are you doing? There is a giant creature right there and you're just what?
Stopping us from crossing?
We're getting everybody to safety.
We're gonna move them out into the lake and everything's gonna be okay.
Do you know if this guy can swim?
I'm pointing up where the creature just landed like we don't know what the
fuck this is. What are you doing? Your people are gonna die because of you right now.
He looks down at you and says we're following orders.
Okay but bear in mind you're gonna die too. You're also over here with us
and that and however many more of those there are.
And intimidation roll.
What if I made a persuasion?
Yeah however you want to do persuasion or intimidation you're coming.
I'm not that intimidating but I am pretty persuasive so that's a dirty 20.
Okay perfect looks down to you looks and sees the people moving to the docks and then
kind of all happening concurrently with the monster being actually visible looks to you
looks to the people the monster and then sees Dace running around the corner and he doesn't
drop his weapons but drops his guard and he nudges the guys beside him and they begin to
rush down towards the people at the docks as well.
Yes great idea help people get to safety instead of just blocking them from getting to safety.
Have a fucking conscience.
Dace now on your position says look we'll deal with this later they're they're moving now
we need to stop that whatever whatever the fuck that is.
Amazing I do have this and I pull out this like crazy five pointed star thing and I like go
and all these extra little blades pop out of it and it's like I mean it looks awesome.
It's unnecessary and I'm here for it.
Is it functional?
I mean all the blades are sharp.
Great love it bring it anybody anybody else you can get let's do it the guards are going
to be moving people we can get a few of them but we need to stop whatever that is.
How is Cav's boat adventure going at this point can I look to see.
At this point yes Cav has made it across and now it's the awkward one man stumble
to try and get the the boat on the riverbank so it's like continuing to move you can't
quite paddle it quite there absolutely you're unknown if you're still in your nightgown.
Cav just jump out come on we need your help.
Okay yeah got it yeah sorry it's yeah old times.
Okay Cav is making his way up into the docks this creature's up on the building
so this creature moves on all fours it's got dark gray almost mottled black skin
that looks like it's rolling up all down its body it's got these huge like four claws that
extend over the edge of this building it has these tusks that come out of the back of its
head and down around its chin these giant gnashing teeth and these red like huge red beady
eyes this is not a creature that you've heard of come across or seen in the wild
and it gives you the same spine tingling chill of the creature that you met at a distance
down in in the caves again at this time and as you're all rushing towards this building
trying to figure out how to attack where to attack what to do it lets out this howl in
this echoing 60-foot cone down towards all this group of people who are now trying to be ushered
off ships and out of the docks and back towards the bridge
and they're going to need to make a wisdom saving throw which half of them do half of them
don't what happened to the half that don't thought the soldiers were going to help them
get on the boats and like get more organization yeah there's some have some of that happening
there's some trying to get them you know ones that are closer trying to get back to the
bridge some trying to get onto the ship but there's a large group of them to get hit by
this mind-breaking howl so everybody in this cone who failed which is a considerable number
of them all clutch their ears and drop to their knees and let out the cries of their own
many of them scatter and some of them turn and look at this creature and you see
like the blood rush from their face as they are now panicking trying to get on these ships
that are being like rocked for the number of people that are on them and running away from
back to the magic closet for a moment
we're just chilling we're just chilling in the magic closet found a ouija board
yeah playing light as a feather stiff as a board proximity we're about we're more or
less one street over from where the docks are you kind of if you were to walk the streets
you'd walk out and back down the main down towards the docks but this howl that i've just
described you hear inside of the magic closet and all of the kids cower and they're hiding in a
corner in the back bizarre you know that this is this is close to where you are and perhaps
down at the docks where you hear the sound of people lots of people who have gathered or been
gathered down there my customers um my livelihood um i am going to tell the children
like stay in here actually go upstairs lock that door too Alydin i am giving you the choice
is there somebody that you trust to watch after the rest of them and if so do you want to come
with me tally yeah you're in charge now okay you're the leader i'm the leader what
you say goes what i say goes you're gonna lock the door behind you i'm gonna lock the
door behind me and you're gonna hug the kids who's crying and i'm gonna hug the kids who's
crying which is all of them get in here and everything's gonna be fine everything is gonna
be okay when we're all together we're gonna go upstairs and everything's gonna be okay
everything's gonna be okay right everything's gonna be okay everything's gonna be okay i kneel
down i look at tally and i pull out a dagger and i say pointy and out oh yeah of course pointy
out okay pointy end out she takes another dagger from inside her body like
both pointy ends oh both pointy ends out all right kids don't hug the kids with the
daggers okay put the daggers away okay kids upstairs upstairs upstairs you hear tally
disappear up the stairs and then the door shut behind you you really want me to come with you
if you want if you feel safe i don't want you to put yourself in danger if you can't handle
yourself but i feel like you can and actually like i have faith that you can but it's your
decision well i'm coming let's go head out the door lock the door behind me
and i start making my way towards where the screams are happening i'll cast mage armor along
the way because it seems like i'll need to be ready for that so i guess two potential ways
you could go down the street and out and back kind of come in from behind whatever's
happening or you could cut through between the buildings and make your way down that way
Alydin which way is faster this way but you're like kind of bigger so it might be that's okay
follow me and she like screws off two of you rush as you hear another howl
you also hear as you see lights down from the docks you hear a returning howl coming from
further back in the city cutting back to Bonwyn dace and Kavlarananan Kavlarananan you've made it back
up the hill towards Bonwyn and dace the three of you are together now arrows are flying Bonwyn
you catch out of the corner of your eye you see Alydin pop out on the other side of the dock
but from between two buildings and then shortly followed thereafter by bizarre i call to them it's
up there come here come here i i look to yeah i looked at bizarre make our way over the two of you
weave through the masses of people that are and that are panicking and fleeing in all directions
and the creature lets out another howl but certainly not as loud as that last one that
you heard as bizarre and Alydin are rushing over to your location Bonwyn and Kavlarananan
you turn and you see on the other side of the main street where this one had hopped across
you see the red eyes of another one of these creatures coming around the corner on street
level and then from the far side of the dock you hear another crunch on a rooftop and there
are three of these creatures surrounding your location so you guys have a plan right
Dumbgeons and Dragons season four episode two starring amy more as Alydin carla max dead
as Bonwyn everbane tom layered as Kavlarananan Goldweave kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard
and Russ More as your dungeon master dialogue editing by carla max dead and sound design by
Russ More this episode featured music from epidemic sound and slipstream and sound effects
from epidemic sound boom library and sound ideas our amazing cover art and character designs
are by matt garbutt and a huge thank you to our supporting producers gabriel lynch jessica
cat Waterflame jacob madden christian brown ongoing kiersen perry matey old school gamer d
craig zeiss la brandon and sarah murphy are you enjoying the story so far well we couldn't do it
without you in fact we'd love for you to join us at Patreon.com dumb dragon cast where
when you sign up for a seven day free trial you're going to get access to an entire other
show two of them to be exact we've got the adventures of and cyberpunk red we hope to see
you over there Patreon.com dumb dragon cast and maybe we'll see you in the community
we're over on discord you have a great week we'll talk to you soon
leaving these enormous claw marks along the dirt floor you say claw a lot too do you want to
see deep gouges large nails i love you res well you too kyle
instinctively bizarred would just launch off a uh oh what's the fucking spell all right
magic instinctively yeah instinctively bizarre would
people are gonna die because of you right now yeah russ he looks yeah i know right
i fucking hate being gross Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production