Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
Bonwyn, everybody's kind of dispersed.
Bizard's gone back to his shop to take a look at investigate the book.
It makes people happy to have Reading Rainbow in their head.
Yeah. To take a look in the book and find possible answers to help you.
Don't come at us. Don't come at us, Reading Rainbow.
Yeah. We know how you treat LeVar Burton.
Closer than that.
Yep. They've all dispersed, go about their day, will reconvene later.
And it's just you and your dad, your mom hasn't returned yet.
And he says, you got some time to help out with some of these beds?
Of course, of course.
How are things going over at the school?
I know I've kind of had my own stuff going on.
And are the kids doing good?
Yeah, they seem to be doing OK.
Your mom's saying that they're, you know, most of them are sleeping
through the night again.
We're trying to get trying to outfit the school.
It's not a school anymore.
So, you know, trying to outfit it as
more of like a like a dormitory, a exactly like a more formal orphanage.
I don't know where all these kids keep coming from, but
they're here. Yeah.
So we might as well try and.
Yeah, we got to take care of them as best we can.
And I know, like all the all the folks from from the Lakeside community,
I've heard are just helping so much.
And yeah, we've been spending lots of time up there.
They've been making up some beds and some comfy things.
And we'll we'll get some went from 40 kids to a thousand.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
That was just a hyperbole.
There's not actually a thousand kids.
There's at least a hundred of them in that school now.
So, yeah, yeah.
And I heard now that June's not having to do like the day to day,
she's like teaching some classes and stuff and we're getting them all reading.
And like that's the school's been closed for so long.
It's so makes me so happy that.
Yeah, these kids are like getting fed and housed.
And we're not, you know.
It doesn't matter what's going on on the other side of the river.
Like we're taking care of our own.
That's right. And we just need to keep them out of our business.
You know, just hide, hide the books, I guess.
Yeah, that's what I hear they do anyways.
And he gets he's continuing working on.
I assume we're like sawing and hammering and.
This whole. Forge thing is just like.
I feel like I should know.
Like how how to help you in this, but.
Yeah, I don't know.
Maybe it's been too long and I just it's it's gone.
So I'm sorry. Yeah, it's just a blank.
Like I tried all the normal things and nothing's working and it's frustrating.
But also, Dad, it's kind of scary.
Like what's going on?
I don't know. Are you are you OK?
Yeah, I'm OK. Like we.
Yeah, I've seen some things, but I'm OK.
Well, I mean, I'm not going to push, like you never have.
But if you feel like you need to talk to get some things off your chest,
like I'm here, your mom's here, like.
Thanks, Dad. Sounds sounds like.
That there was some real weird stuff going on.
And yeah, some real weird stuff.
And somebody got left behind and.
Yeah, we got the kids out, but.
It's just been a hard few months, you know,
pirates, monsters.
Disappeared for three weeks to a scary place.
Kind of a weird year.
Pirates.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast,
and I'm your dungeon master, Russ More, he him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she her.
The shiny eye is just as useless as my regular eye.
Carla Maxted is Bonwyn Everbane, she her.
I know what I get from the Forge.
What does the Forge get from me?
Tom Laird is Kavlarananan Goldweave, he him.
Ribeiro, I've heard of you.
And Kyle Claset is Bizard the Wizard, he him.
Yeah, last time you messed with books, you got in trouble.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast,
and we'd love for you to join us over at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragoncast.
Right now, when you sign up, you'll get a seven day free trial
and instant access to so many amazing bonus episodes,
more of what you love.
Come find it today at Patreon.com slash Dumb Dragoncast.
And now, fuck it, let's play.
We zip over to the Brewed Awakening and Kav,
you're just walking in with your two guards in tow.
Bench sees you come up and says, Kav, can I get you anything?
How about your entourage?
Oh, that's not his voice.
It's more back here.
Yeah. Can I get you anything?
Yeah, yeah, there it is.
Nothing for me today, but whatever the gentleman want.
You go ahead and greet him on me.
Well, we are on the job.
Just a couple of waters, please.
Come on, you guys are so lame.
Just have a drink. What's it going to cost you?
It's OK. You go have a seat here.
Maybe get a drink.
No, can't encourage that.
We'll just get some wings.
It's a good choice.
They do great wings here.
Better on wing night, you guys probably never been here for wing night.
He sends the order back and comes up to you, Kav, and says,
so, did you get your job back yet?
They still got the people following you around.
Have they, like, what's happening?
You know, not much happening on that front.
Seems I'm kind of just.
Look, the wheels of justice turn slowly, they told me.
So I guess I have a little bit of time to kill
before that kind of gets rampant up.
But no, no, no job.
Yeah, no, that's that's fair.
Well, OK, let me rephrase. I'm suspended with pay.
I was just going to ask, I was like, well, hold on, this is.
I am a government employee.
So, like, you're not working, but you are still getting paid.
That's how he's able to treat the guards to.
I'm on leave.
Yeah, administrative leave.
OK, well, I was going to say, if you need a need a job,
need some extra money, like, but if you've got you covered,
then that's that's great until they figure out, you know,
which jail they're going to put you in, I guess.
Yeah, I guess I might take up on that job, though.
I've got some free time, so.
Yeah, absolutely.
And you come with bouncers, too.
So it's like three for one.
Well, I think once they see that I'm, like, not a threat to run,
that they'll back off a little bit.
Right, guys? No, we won't.
Eh? No.
They're just shaking their heads in the corner.
You'll run the second you turn your backs.
I'll run you.
How fast do you think he can run?
Oh, I mean, you've seen me run, not very.
That's why we wear the full armor, so we can still catch him.
It's fine.
She's got the bow low.
Oh, yeah, no, they just do nothing but sweat in full armor all day.
I walk around town doing nothing.
He's sitting out on the patio at those buns.
Yeah, hanging out at them buns, though.
I'm at the weird sister potion shop.
Whatever.
Some time passes and, you know, you get some snacks
and you're chatting with Bench and then door opens
and there's a here's some footsteps.
But people have been coming and going.
There's a little tap on your shoulder.
Excuse me. Are you Kavlarananan Goldweed?
Yes, that is I, one and the same.
Pleasure to meet you.
What would your name be?
Alfonso. It's a pleasure to meet you.
Ribeiro? I've heard of you.
I heard you're a really good dancer.
I try and go incognito.
Good dancer.
But no, I've just come to tell you that your court date has been set.
Seems very timely.
I was just telling my friend that I was told it was going to be a little while.
Oh, well, it has been some time as you've been, you know,
charged and then you were gone.
But then you came back and now you're here.
So your date's going to be in two weeks to the day.
OK, sounds good.
Do you have anybody to act as your lawyer?
Geneal, I'm a lawyer.
I mean, yeah, I mean, my good friend here.
Oh, Carla's new character.
Bit of a dream team for a little while here.
So it'll probably be them.
So defending yourself.
I'm sorry.
Are you taking self-defense or would you like an appointed attorney?
I mean, I've taken some self-defense classes,
but in this case, no, I will I will go for the attorney.
Of course.
Yes, we'll make sure to set you up with somebody
who's well versed in your specific situation.
All right.
So, yes, two weeks at the courthouse.
What kind of law do you do?
Like real estate, mostly.
Real estate.
Yeah, OK.
What kind of crime do you do?
Yep, that sounds great.
So not the real estate lawyer.
Perfect.
So, yeah, two weeks to the date at the courthouse.
Bring your attorney will be there ready to meet you.
I don't even get to meet them before our first court date.
Oh, they've been full.
They will be fully, fully briefed on your legal objection.
You may meet them the day before if you wish.
I would very much like that.
I have some things to tell them.
All right.
Well, we'll make sure that that's done.
Once you have your appointment, we'll send you a letter to
are you still staying at the divorced dad's hotel?
Yes, actually.
And it's the suites this time.
Oh, the suites.
That's why I live there, too.
I know.
And never.
I know, I know.
OK, well, we'll make sure that's delivered to you.
Any other questions you have for me?
No, I guess just more of a statement that I'm innocent
and I didn't do it.
But we'll cover that later on.
I have no say in the hearing.
And he gives you the letter that he was reading off of
and he turns and goes to leave.
At least you have a court date now.
I mean, yeah, I don't know if that's good or bad.
That just means that, like, it's maybe a little sooner
than I thought it might be.
But that's fine.
It's fine, right?
It'll be fine.
It's good to get it out of the way.
And, you know, they're going to you're not guilty of anything.
So they're going to find you totally innocent.
And then you just got to go back to,
I don't know, you can work here.
You can work there.
Maybe, you know, maybe you just get a fishing boat
and take people out on boys cruises.
I mean, that's an option.
I am looking forward to them standing up
and saying that I'm totally innocent.
That is exactly the ruling I want.
That's probably not what's going to happen.
Niki innocent people go to jail all the time.
For real estate stuff?
For real estate.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
Oh, I know what I wanted to talk about.
That's right.
Tell us.
We're figuring it out on the fly.
Excellent.
Tom and I are excited.
What I wanted to say was, hey, we're getting into summer
and our release schedule is going to be all over the place.
So just rip that band-aid off.
Yeah, just we're not going to do any false pretenses from,
I mean, you've already seen it from here on out
until September rolls back every couple of weeks,
might be on a Monday, might be on a Wednesday,
might be all the time.
Don't apologize.
And Jess is in the chat just apologizing.
I'm going to tell her not to apologize.
We've already warned you.
We've warned you.
And you love us.
And you want us to have a little bit of time off
in the summer.
That's right.
Yeah.
So we'll get you as many great stories
as we can on the regular Dumbgeons and Dragons feed.
But if you're out of them, if you're like, ah,
all caught up and they're doing weird summer stuff,
like going on road trips and things.
Weird.
You can come over to Patreon, Patreon.com
or Dragoncast, where Tom runs a game.
What?
I play a cat who doesn't follow any of Tom's rules,
which are very few, very few.
So I have to really work hard to not follow the rules.
And I just encourage it.
I just, yes, and that shit till the cows come home.
It's wonderful.
Carla and Amy play the moral and logical reason,
reasoning factor.
And Russ is just chaos embodied
in a furry kitty cat body.
And Kyle's on the most recent season as well.
And it's really changing the dynamic in a fun way.
A wonderful foil to add into the mix.
Yeah, it's very good.
Sometimes when a show's been running for a while,
and we're talking like a regular running sitcom or drama,
and you're like, oh, they found a structure
and they're doing the thing.
And then they insert a new character.
Then Cousin Oliver shows up and the whole bet's off.
That's a very topical Brady Bunch.
Yeah, no kidding.
So I'm on fire with the topical references today.
Before all of us were alive.
All right, I'll fast forward like 30 years.
Poochie.
They introduced Poochie into the mix in Itchy and Scratchy.
Jess is shaking her head,
so I know I hit the mark with that one.
Nailed it.
Everybody gets it.
Everyone gets it.
Nobody has questions.
Except I feel like both of those made things bad
and gnashed salmon treats.
It just makes everything better.
Makes things wonderful.
So introduces a different dynamic in a good way,
not like Poochie, gosh.
And you can, yeah, there's so much audio over there.
You can be sick of us again in no time.
Absolutely.
Don't worry.
But also when you're a patron,
you get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Rose.
Thanks, Rose.
Rose.
That's nice.
So great to have you here, Rose.
I mean, it's a shame you threw that diamond back into the sea.
Oh, my God.
I was thinking the same thing.
We need to update our references, Tom.
Holy shit.
I was like, yeah, Rose, Titanic.
What?
You know, that movie from 30 years ago.
Oh, no.
Time is awful and wonderful at the same time.
So if all of these references landed with you,
if even one of these references landed with you,
come sign up for a seven day free trial.
Or if none of them did,
because the earliest one was from like 1999.
Just come anyway.
Learn some more old people stuff.
It's fun.
You know, old people stuff is great.
We're cool and hip.
We're cool.
That's right.
But that's the end of the middle, friends.
And we'll get you back to the episode
where something fun is happening.
I'm sure of it.
Guaranteed.
Absolutely.
All right.
Love you all.
Bye.
We cut over to Bizard'd and Mum's Marvels.
And Bizard'd, you and Alydin are in the back
and you've been looking this book over
that you found down at the Everbanes.
And you've come across a couple interesting pieces.
Bizard's just kind of scratching his head
and flipping through the pages and stops.
And he says, OK, so it's talking about bellows in this section.
It's not the bellows that awaken such flame,
but memory offered in pain.
An echo made physical.
The fire must know you.
How can a fire know you?
Oh, God, she doesn't have to light herself on fire, does she?
I wouldn't.
I wouldn't imagine.
I mean, that is an offering in, you know, in pain.
You cut off like a finger or something.
I mean, that's the most extreme route.
Yes, I wouldn't recommend or really condone it,
but it's not the bellows that awaken such flame.
So there's a thing in the margins here,
except backlash if the forge has been dark for too long.
Residual memory storms may manifest.
What's a memory storm?
How long is too long?
Those are good questions, Alydin.
I am not sure, but the idea of a residual memory,
like a residue left over on somebody or something.
Like a memory was taken away,
but there's still like little bits of it.
Yeah, or residual memory storms may manifest.
Yeah, I think you might be on to something there.
Let's see, it keeps flipping through the pages.
We've been going through a lot.
I know you're also kind of reading over your books.
Do you have any questions about what we're doing
or everything making sense on your end?
No, nothing's making sense.
Okay, I'm trying to make sense of it,
but there's a page written in an arcane script.
It looks like it's been magically redacted.
Can you read these lines?
They just show up as black lines for me instead of text.
Like something's blocking it out.
Does that look like that to you?
I lift my eyepatch and I read it.
It's as he describes it.
It looks like there's portions of it
that have been removed, redacted, covered in some way.
No, it's all kind of blocked out there.
The shiny eye is just as useless as my regular eye.
I appreciate the double eye.
I appreciate the second pair of eyes.
You still gave it your all.
So let's see.
Is there a spell you can do on it to like take off a spell?
Like an anti-spell spell?
Yeah, there is dispel magic, but I'd have to double check.
I don't believe I have that in my repertoire.
They used to call it at the college.
It's a spell book.
Well, the margin here on this page says,
too dangerous, too volatile, but if the line fails,
the fire must live on, even if it is not ours.
If the line fails, maybe Malon wrote this.
Like the bloodline?
Like her family?
You're so clever.
You are so clever.
It is going to be so fun helping you learn magic.
Oh, but yes, say the name out loud.
Declare what the forge has meant or what she hopes to earn.
Offer her something she does not want to part with.
But didn't she try that though?
She put her old dagger in there and your little fire buddies.
But that was just one part of this section here.
Perhaps it's a straight up instruction.
Whose name does she have to say?
Her own.
If this was written in the hand of G-G-G-G-Grandma,
then she would have written it from her perspective.
So speak her name out loud.
Declare what the forge has meant to her.
This has got to be direct to her handwriting.
And I'm going to try to recall in my memory.
Does this handwriting look like the handwriting on the note
that Bonwyn found?
Yes, so the side notes in the margin.
So the expect backlash if the forge that line.
And then the too dangerous too volatile.
Both of those lines look familiar
based on the writing you saw in the journal entry.
Okay, I believe these let this this here.
This is the ritual that Bonwyn will need to do.
I wonder in what Thane was saying that it went out
not long before we got back.
So hopefully that's not too long and it's been
it's time still weird for you.
Like I know days and nights are going
but like it just doesn't feel right.
I feel like we never left
but also like it's been a really long time
because like lots happening.
Like did you see the school recently?
That place almost looks like a school.
It's really coming together.
I'm glad to see the community you know
grouping together and getting everyone taken care of.
But yeah, I just haven't I don't know.
Sleep has felt weird.
Everything's felt off.
But this could be dangerous to do.
That's all we know.
Does Bonwyn need to do the ritual?
I would think so.
But also does she do can she do the can she do magic?
Like could anyone pick up a magic book and do magic?
In this situation I think it being passed down in the way it is.
It is a inherited sort of magic
that has worked itself in.
That's the only explanation I can think of
because this is not this is not a spell.
This is not learned magic.
This is a ritual.
And I mean even ritual spells that I have
they are based off of a you know an arcane digitalized spell.
So this is not that but it doesn't mean it can't have magical effects.
Rituals hold power.
With ritual there's faith.
Faith is compelling to people.
Well we should probably get this to her.
Yeah and let's go have some faith in our friend.
I believe they can do it.
You both get up and start heading out
and your your mom's there and she kind of.
Bye again mom.
She she waves and as you go to close the back.
As you go to close the door to the back room.
Bizarre a shimmering bit of light kind of catches your eye
as like the door is shutting
and then causes you to pause for a second and take a look back inside.
And you look back into the room where you just were
and as if from nowhere a spool of shimmering thread
is hanging in midair in the back room.
The light around it wavers like kind of like rainbow and ripples.
I'm gonna go grab it.
You take a few steps forward and it's like as you reach your hand out
it's almost drawn to your hand and you grab it and there's a warmth to it.
You look it over and it is exactly that.
It's a a spool of thread.
Pretty standard size looks like maybe you know about 60 feet probably all wrapped up.
Okay.
As you hold it you hear in your mind a soft hum in a language that you don't understand.
Hey are we going or what?
Oh um yeah yeah we are sorry sorry uh
uh I pocket the I pocket the thread close the door um and uh
I'll pull out one of my brain boogers to remember whatever that whatever that
unintelligible language was just
Bizard and Alydin you're walking through the streets heading back towards
Bonwyn's parents house swinging by Everbane's first to see if she'd come back but then down
to Bonwyn's parents house and then you see Cav with his two guards just walking up and down
the street just getting him sweaty I know it's around here somewhere.
Cav hey oh hey I I think Alydin and I found uh the solution to uh Bonwyn's problem.
Oh very cool was it in a book?
Yeah yeah yeah I should really read more books they have a lot of answers in those things.
Yeah last time you messed with books you got in trouble.
Oh good point ha ha it's not really funny but you know no no but I mean it's what happened
so true true okay uh well we're headed over to uh Everbane's right now.
You good to go?
Yeah absolutely let's go share the good word.
That's right.
No wait the good news yeah the good news.
The good news of these good words.
We've got to head to Bonwyn's parents house you catch her up on everything that's been going on
and that's where we find you.
Okay um thank you for reading the book finding the information I have to be honest
I still don't think I understand what do I have to do I'll just do the ritual and then.
I I mean based off of it says speak her name aloud declare yourself before the forge perhaps
you know it is a it is a bond of your family between each other and
so recognize it basically you're saying hi right that's what it sounds like.
So yeah kind of yeah just sort of uh you know it's like a long lost cousin of a cousin of a
cousin and I'm just saying hey I'm Malin's great-great-great-granddaughter and like
hello it sounds like a good start okay maybe tell tell it what you want it to do oh
Mm-hmm oh also uh part of this maybe you need to you know uh show appreciation
so well look you know here's here's what you mean to me okay I mean it's a good question
what does it mean to you that's a good question I mean I've been thinking about it a lot and
it means a lot to me and my family and the community and so
okay I can do that I think yeah and uh then it talks about what you're
hoping to earn so you know of course it's a give and take with most relationships right
right right yeah so um yeah what do I okay what do I because I know what I get from the
forge what does the forge get from me just like my love is that our trade appreciation of course if
in these moments then um your grief your grief and kind of grief kind of the next part we landed
on but with you know something that's emotionally significant right so I think the dagger um what
did your dad call it poke poke poke poke poke poke hammer hammer hammer hammer
so you know I think we were on with that and the only thing I don't know about is the last
way it says feed the ember right there's no ember there is no ember so it's like a symbolic
ember yeah yeah I was thinking physical because it's got to combust but yeah with everything
else that's going on here I think that tracks a lot more than what I was thinking for some reason
okay I mean do you guys you guys want to stay for dinner you want should I go talk have a
heart to heart with the forge right now I mean I could eat okay well you guys stay for dinner
and maybe help you'll see we're getting pretty we've got quite a lot of beds going
uh maybe help with some desks how how are you with carpentry light carpentry uh I mean if
someone shows me I can I can follow steps pretty pretty easily yeah it's pretty they're this is
it's pretty basic I think I think you'll be all right got it yep we'll get you sorted out
you're tall he looks like he can swing a hammer you can do it I have a swing a hammer before
all right come on over here dinner's being made by your mother everybody's kind of working on
a little bits and pieces and Bonwyn you're passing in to go check on your mom and you
pass by a mirror now to the corner of your eye something catches your eye which causes you to
stop as you walk past this mirror your reflection stops moving
you come back and look at it and it looks at you
you your reflection goes dark the eyes begin to glow like a deep red
and just with a blink
your reflection disappears before you what the fuck is this now okay what's that time
nothing mom just coming in to help
Dumbgeons and Dragons season four episode 30 starring amy more as Alydin carla max dead
as Bonwyn everbane tom laird as Kavlaranan in gold wave kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard
and russ more as your dungeon master dialogue editing and sound design of today's episode is
by russ more our community manager is jessica Babyok music is from epidemic sound and sound
effects are from epidemic sound and boom library our amazing cover art is by matt garbutt and
we'd like to say a huge thank you to our supporting producers gabriel lynch jessica Babyok
cat water flame augur on kierzen perry matey jacob madden old school gamer d craig zeiss
la branton and chibs one oh one two have you been enjoying your time with
dragons well thank you so much for being here if you're looking for more of what you love come
over to Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where you're gonna get a seven day free trial
and when you're a patron for at least three months we're gonna send you some
merch based on the tier you're at come on over we hope to see you over there
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast have a great week we'll talk to you soon
we cut over i'm sorry russ you don't have any house
yeah right i just wanted to derail that whole scene for no reason i love it well because
i'm literally at the bar and there's gonna be an obnoxious drunk person always a drunk
as a bar even if it is noon it's sad i don't think it might be more likely then
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production