Thanks so much for being here, friend.
Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
Alydin, you were expelled from the chamber that we were in, the library.
I thought you were just going to say school.
I got like what I do.
This is the real question.
This is the mystery.
What did Alydin do?
It's a real, it's a memento style game.
Alydin is also covered in tattoos.
Okay.
You're expelled from the chamber and then June came by and like grabs you by the arm
and said you haven't been in school enough.
You need to, you need to get over here.
Got to get my learning on.
You yelled back not to do anything cool while you were gone.
So everybody just sat on the curb.
Like they just waited for three whole episodes.
Excellent.
This is good audio.
As they should.
But we find you at school and this is, this is about a day later.
So you're reconnecting.
Bizard has joined you.
This isn't informal class right now.
I mean, it could very well be formal class, but Bizard has joined you.
You're expecting Cav in a little while and you are asking some questions about
one of the books that you pulled off of his shelves.
The book is Artificers.
Are they just in it for the clocks?
They have to read the book.
Yeah, we'll find out.
I'm sure.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon
master Russ More, he, him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she, her.
You haven't read the book.
Tom Laird is Kavlaranan Goldweave, he, him.
The school of hard knockers.
And Kyle Claset is Bizard the Wizard, he, him.
The potent magic of the fae is so strong to make one forget that they need to use the restroom.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported show.
So every twist, every triumph, every truly questionable decision is possible because
of listeners like you.
Join us today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and now fuck it.
Let's play.
Alydin, how far did you did you get in into our reading?
How far was I supposed to go again?
I mean, it's kind of like at your own pace.
This is, you're supposed to be motivated by wanting to learn because it's your own
craft and it's a really no no setting your own terms is is ideal because I want to
encourage you and not push you.
Well, I read nine chapters.
Nine chapters.
Okay.
Excellent.
So if I could read those, would you be willing to give me a presentation over
chapters one through three next week?
Sure.
But I mean, it was just kind of like, okay.
I tell you what made her a 14 year old about this book.
That's actually boring school stuff.
That's boring school stuff.
I I want you to put what you've learned into practice.
I want you to go through figure out answer for yourself.
Are you just in it for the clocks?
Because what does that you need to tell me what that means?
Well, it gives a whole new meaning to time as a construct for sure.
But I am not just in it for the clocks.
I don't know why I'm in it because I can be and I think that is pretty cool
and I want to know what I can do.
Okay.
You've told me just enough to make me realize what the point of the book is.
And I'm sure if I skimmed a little bit, it sounds like the point of the book
is not you haven't read the book.
No, I'm not an artificer.
It was recommended to me to give to you.
But if I were to make a guesstimation based on that and what you've just
told me are they in it just for the clocks?
Technically.
Yes, because it sounds like you want to know what makes things tick.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I see what they did there.
Clever writing, clever writing indeed.
So if you could because everything's got to intermingle with gears
and moving parts based off of what you've been telling me and I want
you to try to think of something that you want to make using this
knowledge and I want it to be practical beneficial for your everyday life.
This needs to serve you in making your life easier.
Can I just add to my little duck guy and I bring out my little
absolutely there's nothing wrong with improving upon something
you've already started developing.
It's actually giving you a leg up and being able to give you
a chance to go in and review work you've done with this new keen eye.
You may actually see some missteps that you took originally and
so you may not only be able to modify and add to it,
but overall improve it.
So I that's actually a great first place to start.
So any ideas like I'm curious, you know, just with like the
springboard what you want to do with your duck kind of walks
in circles at the moment.
So he's not super mobile, but if I could get him to be more
mobile, I could maybe send him like on errands and stuff retrieval.
Okay, so retrieval that's that's useful especially because they
can probably looking at the size difference your duck can probably
get places that you might not be able to so that could be helpful.
You're pondering this here bizarre.
You're the only two in this classroom right now and as you
two are discussing a a bell in the room begins to ring which
causes you both to turn and this is like a larger size bell
with a rope on it with the intent to like ring it to start
the class but like it's ringing by itself.
That's unusual for you.
Alydin you look at it and the school's been doing some weird
things since it's opened up and this is just one of the many
things that's been happening.
Oh my God that thing again.
Did they change something with the like is it actually time
for class like how that's new.
We can't go by the bell system anymore because they
go off so randomly.
Hmm.
I'm thinking ghosts.
Yeah, that's a possibility.
I guess I don't know what's not a possibility now after
everything we've kind of gone through but hear footsteps
now at distant footsteps coming down the hallway.
They sound familiar.
You could even place them to Kavlaranan then we cut out
in the hall and we see Kavlaranan looking into classrooms
trying to find Bizard and Alydin you get further down
the hallway of the school and like compared to the one
of the last times you were in Kavlaranan like everything
is looking very good in the school.
There's fresh coats of paint over a lot of the school.
There's fresh banners everywhere.
There's a mix of like new desks and some very old
furniture as you're peeking your head in and out of
in and out of the classrooms and then you catch Bizard's
voice as he's explaining whatever lesson he and Alydin
are a couple doors ahead.
I'll make my way in there.
You go to open the door and you turn the knob and then
are like hit by the door as it appears to be locked
even though the handle spun for you and a figurine of
like this lion's head which is in the form of a
knocker begins to speak to you and it says please
state your name and your purpose Kavlaranan Goldweave.
I want to see my friends it pauses and you see it
like raise an eyebrow at a school.
Yes.
One of them is younger and one of them is there
like mentor teacher wizard type the figurine disappears
for a moment and then reappears on the inside of
the class and you both hear announced one Kavlaranan
Goldweave with questionable purpose for arrival.
Shall I let him in?
Yes.
Yeah.
Is this normal?
Figuring disappears again and goes back into the
hallway and he says you shall pass and the handle
releases itself and the door slowly swings open new
security measures so no more kids get snatched.
I mean would you say you're
purpose was just I was coming to see you guys.
Okay, so not a very good security system if that's
what it is.
I that's you just say my buddies in there.
Well, I mean like I could hear you guys but I
didn't give any names though.
So I'm actually kind of surprised it let me
in to be fair that it did say that, you know,
it wasn't necessarily saying it's saying it's
saying questionable purpose, but I guess we
could be like go ask questions, but we knew
the name.
So I want to go over and I want to investigate
this knocker.
Russ side question.
Did I hear how it introduced me to them?
Yes, it would have been muffled.
But yes, you would have you would have heard
it conversing with bizarre and I mean look
it's not the first time cabs been introduced
that way.
So it's fine.
You want to go investigate the knocker?
Yeah.
Okay, you go up to it and roll investigation,
please.
Is there anything what I guess what hold on
before you roll a hard knockers?
Thank you.
What do you what are you doing?
What are you looking for?
I'm just going to go see if I can talk to
it because it seemed to have a full-on
conversation with calf.
So sure.
What do you say to it?
Sup, bro.
It remains motionless in front of you.
Sure.
Can I turn around?
Maybe it only talks to adults only talks
to middle-aged white men.
I don't know.
All right.
Later.
Okay.
So the bell rings itself.
There's a security thing.
That's new tally runs through the door.
Alydin.
Are you done learning yet?
We're playing in the playground and we
want to see you do the thing to get that
maybe doesn't end up in the top of the
flagpole again this time.
Gotta know.
I look over a bizarre.
What are you learning?
What are you talking about?
What are you doing tally?
We have some things to figure out.
I appreciate you wanting to preserve
Alydin's childhood.
I'll make sure that Alydin makes up time
later to hang out with y'all.
Okay.
I overheard you talking about the weird
things.
Did you tell him about the hall pass that
like rewrites itself?
Okay, come and sit down and you start
talking.
Oh, okay.
She comes in sits down and she sits in
one of the one of the desks which are
very school desks with the chair attached
to them.
She sits in and it creaks like unusually
loud and she slaps it that stops it.
So yeah, there was this hall pass and
I had to a teacher wrote on it that
I was going to the washroom and then
I got down the hallway and I looked
at it and it said I was going to
the library.
So I went to the library and I got
some books instead.
You didn't pee in there, did you?
No, I didn't pee in the library.
Do you pee in the library?
No, but you were supposed to go to
the bathroom.
Did you just hold it from that point on?
Yeah, I still am.
Tally, it's recess.
How long ago was that?
A while.
Listen to your body girl.
Okay, that's not great little dude.
Yeah, no, fair.
Thanks for saying so.
I should probably go to the washroom.
But yeah, strange things are happening
and she stands up and now that
she's paying attention to it,
she's got like her legs crossed
and she's walking out the door
and then the chair begins to
groan again and she slaps it
every time.
Yeah, sorry, yes.
Tally, quick question.
Did you get distracted or did
you straight up forget that you
needed to use the bathroom?
That's a great question.
Yes.
I think I did forget about using
the bathroom.
Thank you.
Go take care of yourself, please.
Oh, yes.
Okay, I'll be back.
Zips out the door.
I forgot to use the bathroom.
They're an odd one.
I kind of like them.
It's not the first time.
Right, but like I piecing
the things together you can you
can see the individual parts,
right?
Oh, yeah.
Okay.
The school's got fae all over it.
Absolutely.
I mean, that's a memory changing
effect right there.
Are we sure she didn't just get
distracted?
I really don't think it was a
distraction because the I feel
like your body would still remember
it and maybe the potent magic of
the fae is so strong to make one
forget that they need to use the
restroom.
Why would they do that?
They it's it's chaos.
Like think about the chaos.
Like imagine if all of a
sudden Tally realized it and
then was way way nowhere near
a bathroom.
So people just be pee in
their pants all up in this
joint and pooping everywhere.
I have to say it like that
because we're in a school.
I mean, I hear you're not cool
if you don't pee your pants.
That's true.
I've heard that as well.
Okay, I have not heard that
but I will keep that in mind.
What what what do we do?
What do we what should we is
there anything to do about it?
Anyone new at the school?
Well, there's there's Mr.
McBiddle is new and candle is
new and Mrs.
Felt-Dashian is new.
Okay.
June's still around, correct?
Oh, yes.
Nothing would happen without June.
Then I think we need to talk to
June about where these people
came from.
Yeah, like what are their
credentials?
What are their credentials?
That's a very good question.
Let's go find her.
Why would they want to teach
in this school?
What is their motivation behind
getting employed here?
What and that's just as
just trailing off.
Oh chat.
Wait, don't call it that.
Oh God.
We're back with oh chat.
We're talking Oreos.
Yeah, baby.
Yeah, because what's in the middle?
The white stuff and us because
that's where we are right now.
Well done, Kyle.
Just what I think Kyle's going
to just going to like veer off
and bring it back.
No, we're just going to go harder
into it.
You got to go with the weird
owl references.
It always gets you 100%
every time.
Well, thanks for being here.
No chat.
We're glad to have you.
I hate it.
I know Kyle brought it back to
the middle Russ.
You didn't need to bring it back
back to oh chat.
He's just doing what I didn't.
Yeah.
Now, if you could bring it back
to oh town, that would be
appreciated.
All right.
I'll drop in exactly a
one and a half second clip.
Listen for it.
That's oh town.
Haven't heard them.
There they are.
Get them.
What are we talking about?
Hey, when you join us on
Patreon, you get
not an Oreo,
but you do get some
merch after three months,
which is a very fun thing
that we thought you would
like fun.
It is fun.
Every once in a while
because we get a little
notification saying like,
hey, one of your patrons
is going to get some
merch and I get excited
about it and I have nothing
to do with me.
Yeah, we don't get to be
there when you open the
mail, which is always the
most exciting part of
everybody's week when they
get mail to open.
That's what I found with
Amy being away.
Is there a significantly
less Amazon boxes that
come to me?
Busted.
Nobody's knocked on my
door for a week.
It's been great.
The dogs are bored then.
Undisturbed work.
No distractions.
Well, Russ,
I got to ask because
I'm very curious.
Do the people get to
choose what swag they
get or?
That's a great question.
So when you join us
at the $5 tier,
you get a sticker
It's a nice big glow.
I think it's way too big
for most things.
It's good for a
refrigerator, right?
What I'm looking at
is because you can choose
the size and I'm always
like baker's spanner
always.
So you go for the
largest sticker.
So it takes up like
the back of an iPad,
I would assume.
I guess it's one of
those big ones.
And then our supporting
producers tier,
you get a lovely mug
that has like the
the field scene
that we have where
calves like bent over
like climbing up a mountain.
There's a
the slime off in the
corner that Amy says
looks like a dick.
So there's that too.
You also get an episode
dedicated to you.
Did you know that?
I did know that.
Brand new.
Oh, you knew.
Okay, I knew.
I thought it was new
news.
This is the first
episode you've ever
listened to.
It could be new news.
And hey, welcome.
And if you're starting
right now.
Dip right in at a
totally random number.
I love that for you.
Carla picked up exactly
what I was thinking.
But today's patron is
Lonnie Vogler.
Thanks, Lonnie Vogler.
Thank you so much.
Are you a cartoon?
Not a cartoon character.
Like a
comics character
from 1977.
Because that's a
cool name.
Absolutely.
Lonnie Vogler,
private eye.
Lonnie Vogler from
the Daily Bugle here.
Yeah, right.
Catch the news.
It's me, Lonnie Vogler.
With my hands.
That's how you catch news,
right?
Yes, yes, yes.
Give it to me.
Yes.
Thanks, Lonnie.
Well, thanks, Lonnie.
Join us today at Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast
and we hope to see you
over there.
And now we'll get you
back to the episode.
Okay, love you.
Bye.
Love you.
Cut to the front office
where you would expect
to find,
at the very least, June
or any of the other teachers.
And you walk in
in the front reception area
who there would be another
person there.
Ezzie Mae.
She sees you as you
walk in.
Oh, Alydin.
It's a pleasure to see you.
Well, we brought some
friends.
Nice to see you.
Bizarre.
And I'm sorry.
I don't know
your name.
Oh, hi.
I'm I'm Cav
or Cav Lauren,
whatever you prefer.
Nice to meet you, Cav.
We're here for some info
about credenzas.
Maybe you know something.
Credentials.
Oh, sorry.
Yeah, I was going to say
I know of a great credenza place,
but perhaps we can talk
about that later.
Credentials.
Who's credentials
and what inquiry
do you have about them?
Well, we've got
Faldashian.
This is Faldashian.
Yes.
She's a candle.
Candle.
Yes, candle's
a very keen historian.
Okay.
All right.
And then I just
I made a note.
It's just old bitty.
Is that right?
Oh, Mr.
McBiddle is probably
who you're referring to there.
Perfect.
Yes.
There are three new instructors.
They came highly recommended.
Recommended by who?
Well, Mr.
McBiddle.
The new acting mayor,
Nina Madonna,
came recommended from her.
We go way back.
Oh, good.
Well, I really enjoy her.
She comes in every now
and again to check up on the students
and see how things are going.
If the funding is adequate.
So Mr.
McBiddle and Mrs.
Faldashian came from Kingstown.
They were educators there
whom
Ms.
Madonna knew very well.
Candle came from
not Kingstown.
another small town
not too far from here,
Roysville.
She was also
looking for a move.
She was an instructor
there in a small school
looking to move up
to a bit of a larger
state.
Came in an interview.
Did very well.
Knows a lot about the
different areas.
Unfortunately,
though,
she's not feeling
well today,
as you probably noticed
in your history class
earlier,
Alydin.
I noticed.
Yes.
So Mr.
McBiddle had to fill in.
He struggles with certain
subjects sometimes,
but
that said,
he's a great administrator,
steps in on math
like nobody's business,
and can read an
okay,
an okay substitute
plan.
He kind of just wings it,
though.
Like,
why do they even do that
work some of the time
when he's filling in?
So in history,
he has a
little bit of trouble.
That's good.
A little bit of trouble.
I'm going to write that one down.
And she does.
Title of episode.
A little bit of trouble.
Oh, you,
Kavlaran,
you know,
I'm sorry you didn't
necessarily say where you work,
but knowing
Madonna,
do you happen to work
over there,
or at least
go there frequently?
Look,
it's like a little bit of a gray
area at the moment.
I'm not exactly sure.
I think so,
but like last the other day,
I was just like guarding
stuff.
So I don't know.
Yes.
You haven't been fired.
Not to my knowledge.
Oh,
okay.
Well,
we have some paperwork
that I need to get to City Hall.
I just need to get it to City Hall.
I don't need anything done with it.
Okay,
we can probably handle that.
Yes,
it's down in the basement.
There's a basement?
Oh,
yes,
there is a basement.
I mean,
everything's pretty calm up here.
I could just give a hauler out
to June and make sure
she knows that I'm stepping away,
but we could go take a peek
downstairs,
grab that,
and then if you wouldn't mind,
being that you're so connected over there,
if you could take that back to City Hall for me.
I can certainly drop it off for you.
Thank you.
I'm just going to zip out front here.
I let June know that we're headed down
to the basement just in case anybody else shows up.
One moment and she
heads out the front door for disappears
for a second.
Funny that we're actually getting to the bottom
of things here some somehow.
I kind of thought like
she said we a lot.
So I kind of thought she like wanted us
to go with her,
but then not.
Okay, I don't know.
Well, I think we're going to go with her.
I think she's just telling June.
Oh, okay.
Gotcha.
I can't wait to see the basement.
I wonder what's down there.
Wonder if there are old school records.
I would assume all sorts of fuckery.
You can't say that in school.
She comes back in.
Sorry,
that's a dollar in the swear jar,
but we can head out
head out right away.
Russ, can I roll an insight check?
Sure.
You don't want to pay that fucking dollar.
Is there?
Well, no, I'm fine with paying the dollar.
Look, we just discussed.
I'm maybe on a dollar.
If you can't pay the fine,
don't do the crime.
But no,
I just want to know that like
there's no like underlying like,
ooh,
got to get them to the basement
for something.
Oh, sure.
Yeah.
Roll an insight.
All right.
I mean,
it was a four on the die.
So I'm just going to go ahead
and not even look at what the bonus was.
So,
okay.
We'll say that
being that you
you as the player have suspicions
have
had those suspicions,
but nothing that she's given off
since perhaps obscure paperwork
has come into play
has has really triggered anything.
She seems to know the names of all the people
she needs seems to
you know,
be able to connect a few dots
that make enough sense for you that
everything she's saying seems up and up.
We'll lead the way.
I can't wait to see.
As we're walking,
I'm going to
ask Ezzy.
Ezzy,
where's Royceville?
I'm
not familiar with
where that is.
Royceville is just beyond
the Mee Mountains.
If you go
more down into the south there,
you have to go through some of the forested area.
There is a bit of a
the cowbird swamp.
You have to go through that.
It's a bit of a trek,
but then you make it to this
lovely fielded area
where there's lots of
rare bird species.
It's a lovely region.
A lot of people travel there
just for that reason alone,
but there is a small town there
with a few families
and a very small school.
You're probably not going to find it
on one of like the
the older maps in the school.
It's really just a stopping point
and
well, I mean since a lot of people
have been into birding,
it's
it's really starting to flourish,
but not quite as fast as
as perhaps Candle would have liked
to gain more experience.
I think their goal is to make it to Kingstown
one day.
Good to know.
Thank you.
She leads you down the hall
and out the back
of the school
where there is
a small staircase that goes down
and then there is a
like a double wide cellar door
thinking of like Twister movies
where they pull them open
and she goes in.
I mean every horror movie that has
an exit to the basement ever.
Yeah.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I said Twister movies.
I said tornado natural disaster movies.
Yeah, those were horror movies.
Yeah, I mean that's a horror in their own right.
For those of us scared of nature.
Yeah, fair.
She goes and she pulls one up.
One of you fine gentlemen
wouldn't mind helping me here
just with the other door.
Oh, sure.
Yeah, absolutely.
Little creaky.
Yeah, that's all you can.
I got this.
I feel overlooked.
She she pulls one up.
Slams down.
You pull up the other side
and
she she looks down
and there's a little
shelf with several candles
on it.
She grabs a few and lights them.
Says there's some there's some windows
down there.
But you know, this just helps us
see, you know, all the fine
paperwork that we're looking for.
She lights them for you
and says follow me.
She heads down.
There's a
few steps down into this
into what ends up being
a pretty decently built
more cellar area.
There's a lot of filing cabinets
all down the side
and she starts
pulling.
You know, I stacked it up here on the top.
Just one second here.
She start
filtering through some of the pages.
Don't mind me talk amongst yourselves.
I'll just be just a moment here.
Looking, she's filtering.
This isn't it.
Putting it down.
Maybe June brought it back up and she
off to the side there.
Alydin, what do you think of the basement?
I mean,
it's okay.
It's kind of
I don't know.
I expected it to be maybe a little spookier.
Sure.
Yep.
Well on the mundane side.
You hear her filtering through some pages
and then she's like,
oh, I think I think this is it.
I'm just going to hold the candle here just a little close
and she's walking back over.
Not as you can see her.
She's not really paying attention to where she's walking
and she trips.
The pages fly up into the air.
I'm going to cast control flame to put the candle out.
Good thinking.
Her candle,
I assume it's just her candle you're targeting in that moment.
Her candle snuffs out.
She trips and stumbles.
The pages scatter across the floor.
Oh, no, I'm so sorry.
And she goes to
pick them all up.
Filtering them.
This is this is exactly what just get a moment.
I got a we can organize them perhaps up in the office.
Everybody roll a perception check while we're down here.
Nat 20.
That made up for that one.
12.
It did.
If only that was an attack roll.
That is going to be a 21.
Kyle, you can just let me have it.
No, I got a natural 19.
I didn't get a natural 20.
I mean your natural 20 still I think is better than that.
Yeah, it's totally better than mine.
What's your perception?
Perception zero.
Okay.
Well, I still think it's better.
Nat 20 is always better.
I perceive.
Yeah.
Some things.
Tell me what I perceive.
As he's picking up the pages bizarre and cab, perhaps
you're helping a little bit.
Alydin you are just filtering through looking at some of
the some of the files that are in there pulling a few
open seeing some names and tossing them back closed.
You get down to one of the far cabinets and you feel
a draft coming through bizarre.
You are clocking Alydin as she's walking back as
you've seemed a little hesitant to be down here,
but you see her like stand like dead still as this
draft hits you and I say hit it doesn't like no.
No, I yeah, no, no, but like it's it's a draft where
there probably shouldn't be a draft.
Well, I get excited because I've been underground
before.
I don't know if you guys know this.
It's a bit of a thing around a couple times.
Yes, and I know that where there's a draft there's
oftentimes a new entry or exit point from the
chamber where you're at right now.
So I want to like follow that draft.
I'm holding out my candle.
I'm seeing the flame flicker flame flickering
back and forth and it goes between two cabinets
that are too tight even for you to fit between
not too tight for you and I bring out Cogsworth
Quackington and I want to get him to waddle on
him be between these two cabinets and kind of
like light it up back there to see what's sure
what's back there.
Okay.
Yeah, you place them down on the ground and
little feet are moving back and illuminates
on the other side.
It's tight enough that the little curve to his
walk that he's got right now isn't like he
walks in a circle, but it's a large circle.
It's a slight limp, right?
You walk in with a limp.
You're going to circle around.
It's kind of like that.
But since there's the two cabinets, it just it
keeps him on the straight narrow there.
So so you just walk forward pink pink pink.
Yeah, a little bit go go.
You can see he gets beyond the cabinets
and like the light beyond illuminates like
a larger space than you'd expect and the
draft stops.
Wait, stop stop.
Come back and it starts backing up.
And then it it no longer has the the guard
rails of the cabinet.
So it like backs up into one of the cabinets
just enough that it like throws it off
kilter and tips over.
Bazaar, do you see how it in like now down
like looking at my arm?
Yeah, man, you really need something to fetch
that for you now, don't you?
I got you.
I'm gonna cast mage hand and I'll get the
duck.
No, I can do it.
Oh, okay.
I cast mage hand and it's about to go
through.
I wave at it.
It slaps back a little bit and does like
thumb or gestures and then dissipates.
I give it the middle finger.
That's fair.
It can be a dick sometimes as you didn't
see though, did she?
Dumbgeons and Dragons season 4 episode 55
starring Amy More as Alydin, Carla
Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, Tom Laird
as Kavlaranan Goldweave, Kyle Claset as
Bazaar the Wizard and Russ More as
your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing and sound design of
today's episode is by Russ More.
Our community manager is Jessica Babyok.
Music is from Epidemic Sound and
sound effects are from Epidemic Sound
Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art is by Matt
Garba.
A huge thank you to our supporting
producers, Gabriel Lynch, Jessica
Babyok, Angaron Kierzen, Perry
Mady, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Old School Gamer D, Craig Zeiss,
LA Branton, Chibs1012 and Kudzu828.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon
supported show and because of our
Patreon supporters, we get to keep
telling bigger, weirder, more
heartfelt stories in this world we
love and honestly, that's something
we will never take for granted.
Join us today at Patreon.com
slash dumb dragon cast and help us
tell the stories that you want to
hear. We hope to see you over
there. Have a great week and
we'll talk to you soon.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a
Dumb Dragons production.