Hey, welcome back, friend.
Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in a moment.
The goblins have tossed another log on the fire.
And Alydin and Tally, you're you're you've scooched as close as you can.
It's very cold down here and you're trying to keep warm by the fire.
Do you think anybody up there told Bonwyn, was it, that we haven't come back yet?
How many days do you think we've been down here?
Well, how many times have you peed in that corner?
Well, a lot to start.
Not as many.
It was a lot.
Well, I like to be very hydrated.
As much as I can.
But they've given us a lot of, and she looks down, a lot of moldy bread.
And there was that one fish that was quite nice.
I know you didn't have much of it.
Too bony.
Too picky.
I got a kid.
It was bony.
I didn't want it.
So like 14?
14?
Is that not normal?
No, Tally, we're going to take you to a healer.
Anyway, and it smells.
I just, I needed to say it.
I'm so sorry.
But yes, of course they went and they told somebody because that's what I told them to do.
Well, okay.
Well, I hope they show up soon.
They will.
Because after that fish, I'm going to need to do more than pee.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast, and I'm your dungeon master, Russ More, He-Him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, She-Her.
At this point, you guys have been talking about it for so long.
Tally's taking two shits.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, She-Her.
There's no schools anymore.
History's mystery.
Tom Laird as Kavlaranan Goldweave, He-Him.
We could like maybe hold an axe or two.
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, He-Him.
Is Alydin capable of some stabbing?
With special guest Joe Fisher from Midnight Burger as Rinkip Selador, He-Him.
I think maybe rats or some sort of rodentia carries messages.
I don't know.
It's a whole thing.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast.
Come see what we have for you over at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
It's more of us and it's exciting.
Okay, fuck it.
Let's play.
And we cut to the tunnels.
The group of you are following the map that Bizarre you traced off the map on the floor
that you had seen and it's led you, everybody has the vague idea or even probably a pretty
good idea because you're all adults that know the city very well.
This tunnel system in particular, the one that the kids upstairs told you where
Alydin was supposed to be heading, leads out of the city.
But Rinkip and Bonwyn, this is a direction into an old settlement, which has been
long since abandoned, the settlement of Lingersville.
So it's leading in that direction.
If both of you could roll a history for me, a history check.
I got a 13, I got a 14 history.
Perfect.
These tunnel systems, you have heard stories that there was a large explosion some years
ago that destroyed a lot of these tunnel systems.
And as part of that explosion, there used to be a goblin settlement and it was thought
to have been destroyed by this explosion.
You are walking through these tunnels, all of you crouched.
They are pretty tight, pretty narrow.
And you, after a couple hours following down, there is clear path.
You are following footprints of two small children.
So you're not just wandering aimlessly for hours.
You are following bits of breadcrumbs, so to speak.
You come to a small alcove, which looks like there's a hole on one side of the wall,
which leads out and you can feel a bit of a draft coming into.
Looks like there's a lot of movement back through it based on what you're seeing
from the footprints in the dirt.
A lot of footprints, like how many footprints are we talking about?
Looks like you have been following two sets of footprints, presumably the two kids
you're looking for, but then suddenly there are lots of footprints.
Right.
Like they came out of nowhere.
Like from all the goblins that surrounded them.
Came and got the kids.
But you see now there's like a swarm of footprints.
And the hole.
Yeah.
No blood, no anything like that.
Doesn't look like there was any sort of fight or scuffle.
There was a little bit of pee though, but that was just tally.
There's a scent of urine in the air, obviously.
But yes, it looks like perhaps an ambush of some sort may have happened here.
Okay.
Well now I'm sort of more worried because they were clearly happily just walking
along and then there's all these quite, I mean, these ones seem small, right?
These footprints?
What do they look like?
I don't know if I've seen footprints like this before, but they seem familiar.
But lots of whatever it is.
So that's not ideal.
Well, I mean, what do we know about, what do we know about where we are right now?
We know that, you know, once upon a time, there was something here and by
something, I mean goblins, right?
Okay.
I'm learning something new about the city.
That's great.
This is news to me.
You guys don't know about the goblins?
No, I had no idea.
I mean, this is, this is some good.
Ex-Sheriff knowledge you've got Rin Kit, because I like growing up here, I know
about Lingersville and it was abandoned, explosion.
Nobody really knows why it was so long ago.
There's no schools anymore.
History's mystery.
But now you're saying, yeah, goblins.
So were they, I mean, can you just tell me what you know about the goblins?
Well, they're used to, okay.
So here's what happened.
Were they the, okay, perfect.
Thank you.
What happened was, is that a while back, there was a place here.
There was a, there was a settlement here.
Okay.
Yeah.
Lingersville is what it was called.
And, you know, I don't, nobody really knows what happened.
A lot of people make assumptions.
They don't really know.
Something exploded.
There was an explosion and, and, and, and there goes Lingersville, not around anymore.
There was also here, you know, an encampment of goblins.
Now, if you, now we, we know, you know, we know goblins.
Sure.
Goblins.
Fine.
And, and, and if there's anything that destroys goblins, it's explosions because
explosions pretty much kill all of the things.
Yeah.
Almost everyone's weak to explosion.
Everyone's got a little sensitivity to things exploding.
And so what happened was there was this explosion and I think we all just kind
of assumed, you know, they're bye-bye goblins.
Yeah, okay.
Okay.
Goblins dead.
Not a ridiculous assumption to make.
I don't think when in a big explosion happens, you usually just assume
everybody's dead.
That's why we don't look for the bodies anymore.
However, we've got some, that's right.
However, however, there's some, however, I know I need to apologize for that.
I mean, the thing is we're seeing some strange footprints on the ground.
Are we not?
We are.
Yeah, all right.
So I mean, now that you say goblin.
I mean, it could be saying, I look, I don't want to, I'm not the type to spread
rumors around or anything like that.
I want to, I don't want to get in front of my skis about it, but I'm just
saying used to be goblins here, strange footprints on the ground.
Goblins are a little crafty.
Also kind of hard to like kill all of them because they are, there's always
that one, you know what I'm saying?
So it's just like, and if there's one, I mean, you know, and so I'm just
saying, you know, add some time.
There's more goblins now because they just, they just duplicate.
If there's one, you know, that's what I've heard about goblins.
I don't know what you guys have heard about goblins, but it's like one goblin.
You leave it there for a while.
I thought if a goblin gets wet, it'll, it'll reproduce that way.
That's why you don't know.
That's a gremlin.
Shit, right.
And I think it applies to all.
I mean, you know, I just assume that about all monster
creatures is that they just multiply.
Is that wrong?
I'm well, I assume everything fucks.
Well, I'm not saying they don't do that.
I'm just saying, listen, if there's one goblin, there's going to be more goblins
eventually. That's what I think either by becoming more goblins or by just
getting the word out, like, Hey, I'm a goblin.
I'm here alone.
Come here.
Right.
Yeah.
So goblin osmosis or goblin personals are the two.
Okay.
They have a very compLex communication system that can span miles sometimes.
Miles and miles, you know, it's not pigeons.
It's not carrier pigeons.
We know that now, because as it turns out, pigeons do not do well underground,
but I think maybe rats or some sort of rodentia carries messages.
I don't know.
It's a whole thing where nobody's really sure.
Scholars still argue about it.
But regardless, if there's one goblin here and the humans are gone
because of the explosion, then there could eventually be more goblins.
I'm saying that, okay, here's what I'm, let me wrap it up.
All right.
I'm saying that the goblin population could have rebounded faster, I think,
than the human population would.
And now we've got all these footprints on the ground.
We're underground.
They love it there.
I'm saying we could be, we could have a goblin situation right now.
Goblin coded situation.
Close that circle right back up again.
Just like you always do.
Here we are.
I mean, I'm convinced.
Russ, can we like smell smoke or anything through that?
Because they have a fire inside there, don't they?
Yeah.
Have we noticed anything as we're just having a little meeting out here?
Are you going to spread in fish?
Because you would a hundred percent smell if someone's cooking fish in there.
I am so sad I didn't bring an NPC along because we would be talking about
goblins for the next 25 minutes.
I know we would.
Let's go.
Let's do it.
That's right.
This is what the downtime is for.
I killed a weekend talking about goblins.
Are you kidding me?
I can do this all day.
I wish you would join me in the middle, my friend.
You could join us on Patreon and get an episode dedication.
Hey friends, welcome to the middle.
It's, it's me here hanging out with you.
So it's the biggest party that we have right now.
I don't have a lot to tell you today, but what I do have is a very important thing.
It's the episode dedication, which sometimes when I record by myself, I forget to do.
But if you join us at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast, not only do you get
access to a whole bunch of exclusive bonus content, I swear the cyberpunk
red session zero is coming out very soon, if not by the end of this week.
So look out for that.
Uh, but you also get an episode dedicated to you.
That's what I said.
And today's patron who gets the episode dedicated to them is nine LK nine LK.
Thank you very much.
Uh, nine elk, nine LK.
I feel 90, 90, nine LK, nine LK.
Uh, you know, it's like one of those vanity license plates that you're
trying to figure out as you're walking by.
Like it's probably literally just nine LK, but maybe there's
other deeper meaning to it.
So if there is, let us, let us know.
But, but this is, this is the great stuff you get, uh, when
Russ is hanging out by himself.
Uh, what are some other things that are going on?
Um, well, Joe has been playing with us now for a couple episodes.
He's in one more next week.
Really excited about that.
And we've been busy recording a whole bunch of other great
stuff with some other shows, uh, Dungeons and Drimbus.
We're going to be appearing, uh, in a cyber Monday feature
coming up on cyber Monday.
So a little bit of time to wait, but Carla and I went over there.
Um, we had some friends who, uh, from a show we've mentioned earlier
this season, uh, the looters podcast, uh, two of them.
Right after these Joe episodes are going to be coming to join us.
And then shortly after we start releasing those, we're going to be
appearing over on their show as well.
Uh, so make sure you're listening to all the different shows that we
guessed on, cause that'll keep you busy, busy forever and for always.
Right.
Uh, we'll have more details about all of that as they come up.
And, uh, we'll let you know we're working on more always and forever.
But I think that's the end of the middle.
Uh, let's get you back to the episode.
It's a fun one and I hope you're enjoying it.
Have a great week.
We'll talk to you soon.
Bye.
Uh, let's, uh, let's, I mean, there's no, there's no danger in the hole.
Let's take a peek around.
Uh, so the footprints you've been following stop here.
Like they don't, nothing goes further really like there, there's some
commotion coming from kind of all directions, uh, but most of them do
appear to be that they're moving back through this, this newfound land.
Uh, and, uh, we're going to have a lot of, uh, we're going to have a
lot of people that are going to be that they're moving back through this,
this newfound hole in the side of this tunnel.
Um, who would like to be the one who looks through?
Because it's not big enough for everybody to kind of crowd around
and like three Stooges style look.
Uh, and you know, I, well, I mean, who's the, who's the quietest one?
You know what I mean?
Does anybody have any of that weird, you know what I mean?
Sweet, the sneaky stuff.
Anybody have any sneaky skills?
I'm not very, I have four axis.
I'm not sneaking anywhere.
There's a lot of clanking.
There's a lot of clank.
I clank everywhere I go, you know, they've heard, they've heard you at this point.
I mean, we all, we know they know, they know why I'm here.
They're all just sitting around, actually listening to the history
that they've never been taught generations before they were alive.
Yeah.
It was so long ago.
That's so true.
Uh, anyway, who, who can, who's, who's crafty, who's sneaky?
Anybody I'm pretty sneaky.
Can I try and, I mean, listen, first of all, I want to say,
I'll do it.
I'll go through.
Okay.
I'm not going to send anybody else out of there.
I'm just saying I'm probably a bad choice, but I'll do it.
No, we appreciate your honesty.
I just, if you can give me a minute to take my axis off.
Here's to something.
If I take off all my axis, maybe I'm not so, maybe I'm not so loud anymore.
I think it'd be better if you kept the axes on on the off chance.
Like you need to be ready with those axes.
I should keep the axes on.
Keep the axes on.
Absolutely.
Axe on through hole.
You're saying.
Yes.
Okay.
Great.
I'm going to get out.
Listen, I, because it's a cave, I'm not going to get out the great acts.
I'm just going to get out the battle acts.
And I'm just like, this is more of a cave acts.
I feel then the great access, right?
Cause I don't want to get it like lodged comically in the ceiling.
We all know that.
Or do you not going to do that.
So embarrassing.
Yeah.
And the hard to fix.
Let me tell you, blacksmith.
Yeah.
Hard to fix.
So, uh, okay.
So here's what I'm going to, I'm going to get, I'm going to.
Just take a just real quick look around the corner.
Listen, that decision took too long and I'm sorry, but it's good that we get it
all out in the open and we talk about it.
I feel, uh, I agree.
Came to a consensus.
Yeah.
Uh, okay.
I am looking around the corner.
Did we make you a human?
Oh my God.
Yeah.
That's why I haven't volunteered for it.
Cause I'm a human too.
That's it.
You'd be human.
You look, uh, so, uh, we're going to say that you had a, that had some
sort of a torture candle system, but as you go to look through the hole,
which is, uh, you know, blocks all light from behind you, uh, you look
through and it is a dark cavern that you cannot see anything.
Okay.
All right.
I pull my head back through and I say, okay, so good news, I'm alive.
My head is still on my body.
Bad news.
I can't see a fucking thing in there.
It's completely dark.
So we're going to have to figure out something else.
We're going to have to, we're going to need a light source.
Which may alert.
I can just see in the dark.
So if we, could I just quickly, if I could just scooch around you, I could
just, and then if it is just empty, no worries.
I feel like seeing in the dark should be like some upfront information
that we should have had before we went into the cave situation.
Right.
Okay.
I mean, I told you about my axis.
You're right.
We didn't all explain what we were bringing to the table, but that is
something that I can, would you mind having a look-see through this
mysterious love to take just a little, little looky-loo through the hole.
Kyle is bizarre, like human human.
Yeah.
Wait, what do you mean by human human?
Like, for the most part, we're all half elves.
No, I am.
I am Hooman.
You're just straight up Hooman.
Okay.
Yeah.
All right.
I'm a dwarf, Amy.
Just kidding.
I know that.
Yeah.
Okay.
What am I rolling?
Well, you're just putting your head through a hole right now.
So don't worry about rolling yet.
So you, you scooch aside Rinkep and Bon, when you put your
head through the hole and your eyes adjust for a moment and you
see the same dim luminescence that I described an episode ago
to our good for now.
And so you see down below you, what comes into view is a, a
city of sorts.
It is built with crudely constructed wooden structures.
You do pick up a light bioluminescence coming off of
different parts of those structures and up on the walls.
Not enough that it would provide a huge amount of light for someone.
And now you can roll investigation to see if you see anything beyond that.
That's an 18.
You are taking a good surveillance of this.
You do pick up a dim glowing orange light, like very dim, often to
the far right of this city.
Um, and you see, um, focusing for a moment, you see quick movements down
in the city, same bioluminescence.
You don't pick up what figure or thing is moving, but you see quick
movements in and out of the buildings.
Um, and after a short moment, you hear what sounds like, um, pebbles
starting to roll down some of the hills off into the sides.
To clarify, you're saying city, but I'm picturing like, like
settlement more, maybe like an Ewok village, but underground and goblins.
I don't know.
Your even sounds too fancy for me.
Shantytown.
Something Shantytown is probably better.
Okay.
That's what I'm picturing.
Goblin Shantytown.
It's a great username by the way.
Goblin.
Hi, I'm Goblin Shantytown.
It's very good.
Oh, band name, write it down.
Um, there is, there's, I'm going to say it probably is goblins.
Cause there's like a lot of structures in there.
Clearly a bunch of creatures living in there, but sure.
So that's not great news.
I mean, it's not great news.
There's a lot.
There could be better news coming out of the hole.
Let's just say goblins.
Yeah.
Um, there's a lot of them, I think.
Thank you for the air quotes on goblins, by the way.
I appreciate it.
Cause I don't want to commit in case it's not, you know,
can you give me a rough estimate on how many goblins we're
dealing with at this particular time?
Cause like 10 minutes from now could be more.
Cause we know how goblins are.
We've discussed this.
Right.
Great.
You're right.
They're probably, it's going to be half again.
It's many.
We stay here long enough.
The longer we wait, the more goblins there are.
Absolutely.
Uh, Russ, I probably like, could make a guesstimate, right?
Yeah, based on the size, based on the building.
Do a guesstimate roll.
Sure.
Yeah, do a guesstimate roll.
Uh, we'll call it a three.
I was going to say, whatever you roll, multiply it by a hundred.
That's too many.
Yeah, I rolled a three.
So you tell me what that means.
You could probably guess this shanty size, presuming, uh, a
hierarchical structure of a two to four goblins per structure.
There could be anywhere from 25 to 50 goblins in this town.
That's a lot of goblins.
Yeah.
Okay.
I share that information.
I mean, I feel comfortable assuming that they are the prisoners of goblins.
I, I feel like, based on the information we have, that's,
that's gotta be the case.
Um, so can anyone, I'm sorry, I can't speak goblin.
Anybody?
I don't speak goblin.
No.
Okay.
Um, so, uh, diplomatic relations, probably not maybe the best way to go about it.
Hard to parlay and you can't speak.
Are they known for their diplomatic relations, the goblins?
I mean, I barely knew goblins were even in this, like, you're the one.
I feel like you're the expert in the room.
What I know of goblins, I'm going to say not really up for a parlay.
I'm going to say they're going to be more, you know, I mean, if you live
underground and hide from things, maybe not social.
And so, yeah, so that's problematic because you would hope that just a
nice conversation would get us out of this.
If we could just explain that they're children and if we could just not,
yeah, that'd be, that'd be just mono a mono talk it out.
But I, I, I feel like that's not an option.
Okay.
So what do we think?
Just like get a hose down here and flood them out or.
Do we have a hose?
Is that a,
Oh my God.
Does anyone have a hose?
No, I'm sorry.
Oh, that was a joke.
Just drown them all.
I mean, I thought, I mean, that sounds like a great idea, frankly, but.
Carla, that is borderline tie them up and throw them in the
river right there.
I know.
I want it to get back to our roots.
Does anyone have any ideas?
Perhaps it's just a misunderstanding and they said, Oh, these goblins
escaped, they're bad goblins.
Let's, let's take them back and, you know, maybe just go in and.
I, I don't know.
Uh, 25 to 50 is either for us and.
Well, Bonwyn, you would know it.
Is Alydin capable of some stabbing?
I know Alydin's a little bit older than the other kids.
Can we farm out some of this battle to the children?
I'm just curious if we, if, if we.
Delegation is the key to leadership.
I mean, you have a sling and a screwdriver.
I could be a murderous Dennis the menace.
You don't know.
That's true.
I will say this.
I don't know about the, about the murder, but she is very
smart and very sneaky.
So, okay.
You know, if we could, if she sees a chance to escape, she will take it.
I know that for sure.
I hope they didn't do something ridiculous, like pick up the cage
and try and walk.
Can you imagine?
Oh my goodness.
Because that would be embarrassing for them.
I'm looking at the situation here and it looks like they came from potentially
above to drop in on our friends.
So maybe if someone were to stay behind, make a scene, they would leave,
come down, rain down on that one person.
And that would free up the rest of our party to go down there and, and save.
All right.
So we need a, we need a distraction is what we need.
We need to distract the goblins so that the rest of the party can
move in and save the children.
So bait.
Yes.
Bait.
Just one person to be bait.
That's bait.
Yeah.
Okay.
I'll do that.
No, I.
Ren Kipp, on the off chance that some do stay back, I feel like
your martial prowess would be better served there.
I will stay back and I have means to be able to at least slow them
down as I make some kind of retreat if necessary.
Okay.
So I will stay back here.
I will get my torch out and y'all move forward as quiet as you can.
Of course.
Ren Kipp, all the axes, but, you know, walking wind chime.
I do need to wrap them in some sort of cloth.
I think that would be helpful in the future.
Note to self, you know, for next tunnel excursion, next tunnel
excursion of some sort of sheath.
They're hard to sheath is the problem.
Bon, when we could collaborate, figure out some kind of magical
adaptation to make an ax silent when it clangs against something else.
Yeah.
At this point, you guys have been talking about it for so long.
Tally's taken two shits.
We cut back down.
The trolls are going to hate that though.
It's repellent.
So it'll keep them.
Oh my God, there are trolls down here.
Yeah.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Goblins.
Now there are trolls.
See what you do.
Don't give Russ any ideas.
I'll just throw a troll in there now.
So if y'all want to move forward, I'll wait until you're out of
sight and start making a ruckus.
All right.
Okay.
Sure.
Thanks, Bazaar.
That's all right.
So, so are we all going through the hole and then we're splitting up?
Is that what's happening?
And now we whisper because now we're, now we're talking about going
through the hole, plan mode strategy strategy time.
Okay.
So we're all going to go through the hole and we're going to split up.
Is that the deal?
Yeah, I saw definitely there was a fire in a distance, not a lot of
movement around so we can all try and sneak.
Yes.
I feel like the fire.
How are you going to sneak?
Cause you cannot.
I think we got it.
I think we got to wait for the distraction part.
And then when they are distracted by the distraction, they're not
really going to be listening for four axes in that case.
I say we stay together because I can see and then you can write and
then we can also, we could like maybe hold an ax or two.
Oh, so there's not just four clanging together at
all times.
If you would like to do that.
Unless that's uncalled for.
I don't, I don't want to assume.
I don't want to, no, no, no, we're all friends here.
I have no problem with anyone doing any ax holding if it doesn't
encumber you in any, in an unnecessary way.
No, um, Kav, great idea.
Then we, we all have axes.
Great.
Okay.
So, uh, I'll take the, I'll take the great ax then, since I'm the
ax guy and it's a little, okay, battle ax from one of you.
And then a couple of, a couple of throwing axes.
Okay.
We're all ax now.
This is fun.
This is great.
I guess all like dual fist, the throwing axis.
Um, sure.
I mean, that's, I mean, that's what I do, but, uh, you know,
the more impressive, I mean, I saw it and I was impressed by it.
So their own ax path, you know, let's let's, okay, let's go.
Let's do it.
I think we're ready.
All right.
So, so that I have it three of you, Rin Kip, Bonwyn.
And Kavalarin going through this hole as previously described as barely
able to fit one of you through.
It's fine.
We're doing it.
You've committed to the bit.
Like we're doing it.
Uh, and, uh, bizarre, you're staying back.
Is that what I understood?
Yeah.
I'm going to position myself like towards the, where we came in, like
behind the hole, where it looks like all of them dropped down from.
Great.
Cool.
Awesome.
Uh, who's going first?
Uh, Kav, can you see in the dark as well?
You have dark vision too.
Okay.
So we should, um, I'll go first maybe.
And then, um, Rin Kip can go in the middle.
So he has, uh, two people who can see to help guide.
I appreciate that.
Thank you.
Yes.
Perfect.
Absolutely.
So I'm going to roll for tight squeeze.
Tight squeeze.
There is like a path that they could take not going through this hole.
Yeah, there was, but yeah.
No, I'm just making sure I previously described when we entered.
Yeah.
That's what I thought too.
So long ago, there was so much goblin chat.
They're not going to expect this though.
Right.
Losing my shit over here.
They'll never go through that way.
Is what the goblins are saying.
And boy, would they be wrong.
So I was just standing there like, I didn't prepare the grease spell.
So that's, that's out.
That's on you.
Okay.
We're, we're doing it.
We're committing to the bit.
Yeah.
Dumbgeons and Dragons season three, episode 16, starring Amy More as
Alydin, Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, Tom Laird as Kavlaranan Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard with special guest, Joe Fisher from
Midnight Burger as Rin Kip Celador and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing by Carla Maxted and sound design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and Slipstream and
sound effects from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garbutt and a
huge thank you to our supporting producers, Gabriel Lynch, Jessica
Babyok, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Christian Brown, Angaron
Kierzen, Perry Matey, Craig Zeiss, Old School Gamer D, L.A.
Branton, Nathaniel Teeter and Aaron.
If you enjoy the adventure that you're listening to, we'd love for
you to join us over on Patreon.
Why?
Well, because you get to spend more time with us and we get to
spend time with you.
It's what we love most about doing this whole, this whole thing
that we call Dumbgeons and Dragons.
And when I, when I say you get more of us, like there's a
whole other show, The Adventures of, where we're running a different
campaign, DM'd by Tom, Kyle is starting to run us through a
cyberpunk red campaign.
There's the downtime episodes.
There's hangouts.
There's so much happening.
You can take part in some, take part in all.
We suggest most of it, but you do you.
Patreon.com slash dump drag guest.
We'll see you over there.
All right, everybody have a great week and we'll talk to you soon.
Bye.
This is all stuff I'm supposed to know, right?
I'm not doing this wrong.
This is correct.
Make it up.
What was the settlement called?
It was called, it was called Lingersville.
Yeah.
How big is that hole?
Not big.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.