Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin right after these messages.
Maybe there'll be no messages.
Maybe there'll be a couple.
Stick around and find out.
We find ourselves in the hot block.
The hot block is a busy portion of the artisan district of Vintersmouth, where
Bonwyn's blacksmith, Everbane's, is the central piece.
We hear hammering from inside there.
We have to the left and right, we have the tailors, we have the ferriers, we
have the woodworkers and glass blowers.
Like this is where a lot of the materials that are sold both in and
out of town are getting made.
So they clump them all together.
And as we kind of come down this street, we see those two boat crewmen
who are pulling along this very small crate.
They appear to be quite out of breath and sweating buckets, regardless of the
size. Bonwyn, you turn and look at them and they look like they're about
ready to pass out, which based on the size of anybody else looking at it,
would say that this is, there's something wrong with these two.
Are we almost there?
We're almost there.
And I can get you some, I'll get you some water.
Oh, thank you.
I really, I really appreciate it.
I obviously couldn't have carried this back here by myself.
I didn't think it was going to be this heavy.
Yeah, it looked a lot smaller when we, it's, it's deceptive.
It's this special metal and you just need a touch of it and you add it in.
And it, it's, um, yeah.
Oh, okay.
Ready?
No, one, two, three.
I pulled something.
Okay.
Yep.
Is it there?
Okay.
I don't, no, just here.
Let me just.
It hurt so bad.
Oh my God, Taylor, get it together.
There's some pressure on it.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons, a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast.
I'm your dungeon master Russ More.
He, him and Dumbgeons and Dragons stars Amy More as Alydin.
She, her.
She looks around and goes, Tom Laird is Kavlaran Goldweave.
He, him.
We're good, right?
We can do like a cone of silence.
And Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane.
She, her.
Let's maybe, uh, fewer gold statues and more.
This is going to sound crazy.
I don't know.
Schools.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production supported by our patrons.
Join us today at patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And now we've got a lot to get to.
So fuck it.
Let's play.
We arrive in a very derelict abandoned building on the outskirts of what is.
Known as the Kinsman's district.
Vintersmouth is split into three distinct parts.
There is the artisan district, which we spent some time in last time where
there's the docs, uh, where there's the hot block, where there's a lot of
restaurants, um, a lot of the hubbub of the city and the action of the
city happens in the artisan district.
Uh, there's the noble district, which is where we found the mayor's office.
We haven't really seen a lot of that.
Um, but now we're exploring the Kinsman's district, an area that is
particularly known for its criminal activities.
Um, in this abandoned building, we hear the soft footsteps of Alydin
who's returned home after having an altercation with Sergeant Dase.
Um, and you enter as you usually do and it's silent.
Um, what do you do when you enter this building and give a brief
description of like what you see.
As you enter, it looks just like a regular, you know, abandoned building.
There are crates in the corners.
It's dusty.
There are tarps and things that have been left around, um, pieces of wood
and nothing, nothing really to see there.
You would peek your head in and be like, oh yeah, that's an empty, abandoned
building, uh, but as Alydin walks through the door and shuts it behind
her, uh, she looks around and obviously had checked to see if anyone
was following her and goes out of the shadows and beneath different
crates, um, several other children appear.
One of them, a, a very slender, uh, three and a half foot tall
girl runs over to you.
She's got very tousled brunette hair, appears to be a half elf.
And she says, you, you made it back and you, and you brought
a, and you brought a baguette.
Everybody, everybody come on quick, come quick.
Shh, Tally.
Sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry.
Okay.
I did.
I got a big baguette.
I had to, well, I had to outsmart constable.
What's his face?
Constable days.
And she, she, she got smarter constable days.
Sergeant, Sergeant days again.
Of course you did.
Nobody's surprised.
He's such a big dummy.
He is such a big dummy.
All right.
Here, split this up Tally.
Okay.
You get a piece.
Don't take the biggest piece again.
That's not how this works.
No, of course not.
You get the last piece.
Everybody gets equal pieces.
Okay.
Here, Yanny, you can have some growl.
This is, this is for you here.
Okay.
Yep.
No, I'll spread this around.
This is so great.
This is, this one's bigger than the last one.
That's amazing.
They were just going to throw it out anyway.
So I think we're doing this town a service by making it less thrown away.
There's stuff for no reason.
That would be so stupid.
Why would they throw this away?
It's so good.
Do not talk with your mouth full.
I'm sorry.
Wow.
Here, here's your, here's your piece.
Here's your piece.
Thanks Tally.
So what have you guys been up to while I was gone?
Uh, oh, well we, uh, we, we, we did the perimeter.
Uh, like you, like you said, uh, make sure we didn't see anybody coming
through, you know, the kinsmen, they were walking by not too long ago.
Uh, we, we kept real quiet so that they didn't, so they didn't see us.
Uh, we didn't want any, any busy.
We didn't really want to do anything else beyond that.
I mean, we ventured out a little bit to this, to the back stables, you know,
cause there were some birds out there.
Um, and do you guys practice at all?
So we, well, I mean, no, no, we didn't practice.
I'm sorry.
You guys are going to be out there before you know it.
I can't be doing everything for you all the time.
I'm not going to be here forever.
I got plans.
Okay.
So if you're not practicing, pickpocketing with each other, right.
How are you supposed to pickpocket when you're out there?
Well, that's a good question.
Okay.
Uh, after, after we, maybe we can do some practice.
You can show us again how I would do it.
Uh, yeah, I can do that.
Yeah.
But after I'm tired.
Okay.
Yeah.
No, it won't bother you.
We'll go over to the worst.
Go sit over here and hum our little song that we, that we hum together.
That's the only song.
Anyone knows curls up in the corner, um, on some burlap blankets and, um, just sits
quietly and thoughtfully eats her baguette.
We fade out and we hear a soft hum of an empty room and there's the
sound of flipping of papers, one slowly at a time, scrawling of notes.
And we see Kavlaran seated at a desk, flipping through the papers that he's
allotted for the day with Oak standing ridiculously close, looking over his shoulder.
So, uh, I went and talked to Nina and Nina said that, uh, they, they have
the paperwork for, uh, for the monument and everything looks good.
And I trust Nina so that, uh, you know, so, uh, that's all ship shape.
Um, they did mention that taxes did go up.
Um, and, uh, you know, this was, uh, this was the third strike, um, for
Brewed Awakening, um, uh, for not paying those new taxes and they
had to revoke the business license.
It was all above board and the paperwork was all filled out and
everything, uh, totally, totally on the up and up.
Uh, okay, great.
Um, oh, can you show me the first two written warnings?
You obviously kept copies of those, right?
That you took to Brewed Awakening?
Yeah.
Oh, of course.
No, we're going to have to, uh, either let me see.
Uh, I've got one and he pulls out a piece of paper, uh, from a, from
a pouch that he has, puts it down in front of you, smooths it out.
And he says, here's the first one.
Uh, this one was from, uh, a few months back, uh, when we had that,
uh, had that, that tax increase.
Um, and then, uh, where was that second one?
Um,
see, okay.
Well, the, the only problem I have with the first one is it doesn't
really give any details.
It just says taxes are going up.
Yeah.
And that's the end of the note.
Well, yeah.
And then it, uh, see down here at the bottom, it says Brewed Awakening missed.
There was a couple other businesses, uh, they got, they got
torn off as they paid.
Uh, so Brewed Awakening missed, uh, and, and, and, and, you know, a delayed,
delayed missed, uh, you know, even by a day really just sets everything back
in motion.
So that's really just, um, it's the, it's the, it's what we got to do to
make sure everything's in line and in order in this town here.
Okay.
Uh, yeah.
Have, have you guys considered maybe a more streamlined system for these
collections?
Like if one miss sets everything back, that doesn't seem like a great system.
I mean, a lot of our city's systems run solely off of these tax dollars.
So we really, in order for the people to know what they're getting and
know, and need to benefit from the resources that the city provides, uh,
taxes are very important introduction into, uh, everybody's daily workflow.
Uh, yeah, that, uh, that makes a lot of sense when you put it that way.
Well, I mean, that's what Nina said.
So I, I mean, I never really argue with Nina.
Uh, Nina just tells me that that's what the mayor has sent down and
that's what we're doing.
Uh, so the city guard goes around and collects the taxes and then brings
it on back and then keeps a note if anybody's missed.
And then on the third strike, well, that's a revoke, uh, yes,
revoking the business license.
Okay.
Uh, yeah.
Uh, we're like, we're good, right?
We can do like a cone of silence.
What do you mean?
You know, some trust going on here.
I could ask you a pointed question and, uh, of course.
Yeah.
You can just, you can tell me, does Nina run in this show?
Is Nina running this show?
Cause it seems like Nina's running the show.
Nina doesn't run this show.
The mayor runs this show.
Oh, Cav.
All right.
Just, I was just curious.
Nina knows a lot of things.
Like it's important to have somebody in the, in the organization who, uh,
really just, uh, keeps everything together.
But is Nina running this?
No, Nina, Nina takes orders.
Okay.
Cool.
Um, I'd love like a one-on-one with Nina at some point.
You haven't had a one-on-one with Nina.
Nina's great.
You're going to love Nina.
I'm going to get that on the books for you, you know, probably within
the next two to three weeks, cause Nina's very busy.
Well, yeah, I mean, it sounds like it.
Uh, so in, in order to square away Bench's tax issues, I just get him to pay
what he owes and all good.
He can keep going on his usual business.
Yes.
As long as everything's paid up, but then has to go through a reapplication
process, uh, because we've had to revoke it.
Um, it's logistical nightmare.
It's best just to pay the taxes when everybody comes knocking,
if you know what I mean.
I'm, I'm getting that impression.
That's for sure.
Uh, okay.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um, well, I think, I don't know, it seems like a pretty hard day's work we put in.
Maybe we, maybe we duck off a little early.
I'll go talk to Bench and we'll get the sorter for tomorrow.
Oh, uh, cut out, cut out early.
We haven't been through all of the allotted paperwork for today though.
No, you're right.
We haven't been.
Oh, it's very true.
Okay.
Well, we finished up this paperwork and then second it's done, we can go, uh,
you know, hit the town to two great gents out on the town.
Having a great time.
All right.
Okay.
Yeah, I like the sound of that.
I love it.
Uh, back to the paperwork and he's immediately over your shoulder.
Five o'clock sharp.
As soon as our workday is done, we're just going to burn rubber out of here.
Just got like four and a half more hours to go.
Does it work though, when you're having so much fun?
I would, I would say not.
Yep.
And they closed the good, uh, gastropub.
So like, where are they even going to go?
Where do I have to be?
We'll be right back.
It's the middle.
Everyone.
Welcome to the middle.
Oh, we hope you're enjoying the episodes.
I mean, you're still here.
So obviously you're enjoying it a little bit, right?
We enjoyed making it.
Yeah, it's a lot of fun.
We did enjoy making it and we're happy you're here.
And like fun, new vibes to start the season.
I think so.
Yeah.
There's a lot of different little aspects, I mean, a lot the same, but a
lot of different little fun aspects that are just brightening the entire thing.
Not that I'm saying the darkest timeline was dark.
It was called the darkest timeline for a reason.
Let's call it a spade, a spade.
So huge tone shift, huge tone shift.
More levity, a little more relaxed.
I haven't put anything up my butt yet.
If you're new here, welcome.
That is a reference from season two.
And we hope that you like us enough to go over there.
And that was a teaser.
That sounds wrong.
Is that a teaser or a spoiler?
Absolutely.
Is it a spoiler?
Yeah, I mean, it happens pretty early on.
It's none of them and all of them.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So it's just information.
It's just...
It's factual.
Yeah, let's just sit in that for a moment.
No, we didn't.
And then tell you to join us over on Patreon, patreon.com slash dumb dragon
cast, not a perfect segue to the previous statement.
It's really hard to segue from that.
Well, I mean, depending on your profession.
But we have other things over on Patreon.
Like we have another amazing show that we have a lot of fun doing.
Run by Tom.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah, that one once a month.
It's called The Adventures of and it exists in the world of the previous two
seasons. If you're again, new here, that's where it lives.
But characters who live on their own and it's amazing and it's fun.
And there's baking contests and there's murders and there's
shitting in a well, shitting in a well, lots of cheese, shitting in a well.
So, you know, that's what you got to look forward to.
But when you do sign up at patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast at any tier,
you get a seven day free trial to come give it a little taste, a little see,
a little look see, and we hope that you do because there are a lot of episodes
in seven days. You can absolutely, you know,
it's a difficult economy out there.
If that's what you need to do to get to have some fun with us more.
It's all good.
But you know what, there's incentives to stay a little bit longer.
Yes, there is.
Because starting in February 1st, we're bringing March back, baby.
Merch, not March.
We're bringing, yeah, in February, we'll come back.
After February, March will also come.
Merch is coming back to Patreon.
So when you sign up and stay at a tier for three months,
you'll get a piece of merch sent to you.
So if you're at the five dollar tier,
likely going to be a sticker at a twenty five dollar tier is going to be
a mug and then the game time tier.
I'm pretty sure it's going to be a t-shirt.
I haven't settled yet, but I think that's what it's going to be.
So if you're not signed up on Patreon,
do so because there's lots of great things, including the community and some
incentives like Merch and like a lot of live shows, which will be coming back.
We're putting them on the schedule very soon.
So those will be coming back.
Book club, book club, something we do through Patreon.
Book club, oh my gosh, guys, there's so many things.
Look, but at the bottom line is it just it warms our hearts that you want to
support us by listening, by hanging out with us, by coming to the Discord.
Hashtag, you can avoid spoilers if you come to the Discord and you're not
quite caught up on any part of the story.
Absolutely. There's a special spoiler channel.
Sometimes comments sneak through,
but pretty everybody's very good about keeping spoilers out of the main Discord.
So come join the Discord regardless of if you're caught up or not,
which is weird to say because you're probably caught up on this episode.
And regardless if you're a patron or not, we want you over there too.
Absolutely. For sure.
So no matter where you're supporting us, we appreciate you and want to bring
you more adventures and fun and hang out with you.
So please do that.
Please do that. Thanks, friends.
Thank you. Couple of ads for you and then we'll get back to the show.
Thanks. Bye.
Love you. Bye.
Bye.
Do you love anime and D&D?
Well, hey, then you can check out Warlock.
Warlock is an exciting D&D audio drama
with an anime twist following the adventures of Nova Ravenwood.
Love that name.
Nova's lifelong dream is to become a
powerful sorcerer, just like her father and brother before her.
But there's a hitch.
She can't cast a single spell.
That all changes, though, when she
strikes a life altering bargain with a mysterious woman for power.
Sounds like a tale as old as time is what it does.
But what cost does it bring?
Her new powers aren't all fun and games, either, as she draws
the attention of the shadowy organization Foundation.
Look, it's a thrilling tale that asks the question, who was the first Warlock?
This is a question that I need answered.
But check it out wherever you find your
podcasts or visit warlockpod.com for more information.
There's a rumble coming from inside Everbane's from the burning forge
as the two crewmen who have taken their water and have headed back
towards the docks as you are uncrating your new shipment of Estrum.
Thane, you have to come look at this if you have a second.
Yeah, just a sec. I'm just going to put this away here.
Thane walks over.
Thane is a half elf who is approximately five and a half feet,
also currently dressed in like black slacks,
white blouse, black leather apron, shoulder length, fiery red hair
and deep dark blue gray eye and very sharp facial features, warm but sharp.
And they walk over to you and they're wiping their hands and say,
is that the shipment of Estrum?
Yeah, just got here.
Oh, my gosh.
Have you even seen it before?
Only just sketches of it.
I never. OK, let's crack it open.
And I'll warn you, it's not.
It's not a lot to look at, you know, in the crate, but
it's going to it's going to blow your mind what I can do with this metal.
OK, and I take a like a little crowbar and kind of
crack open the crate and like lift the lid off and as big as I thought
the crate was going to be, no, it's it's you just add the tiniest
amount to the steel and it makes it super strong.
I know it seems really heavy because those two and it is really heavy,
but this is enough for, I mean, a ton of weapons.
So
when it's diluted, it makes the weapons light and strong and sharp.
You can hone it really easily.
It holds its edge.
It's amazing. It's incredible.
I mean, it costs a pretty penny.
But it's it's amazing.
So you got it.
You got a job for this one.
Who are you making it for?
What are you making?
Well, you know, I'm making that light, delicate blade for Ignatius.
Oh, right. Right. Yeah.
I think I here I showed you the hilt, I think.
And it's it's it's going to be pretty ornate on the handle.
But the blade itself is not messing around.
It is going to be.
Well, I saw the sketches. Yeah, that's going to be amazing.
Yeah, it's this is a this is a killing blade.
This isn't just Ignatius in the in the in the business of killing.
What's Ignatius's job here?
No, Ignatius is sort of a
malord, fancy sort of.
Oh, so it's more of a look at what I have.
Yes, but
he wants the real deal and very well, you know, he's got the cash to pay for it.
So let's get him what he wants.
And it gets us this.
And you can you can have some of this, too,
to play around with if you want to, you know, work on something a little bit
more delicate. Oh, I love that.
Speaking of which, Phil down at the dock, they had pirate problems.
Oh, no. Their mast got busted.
And I said that you could probably help, you know, just with like a
coupling for the mast, just something iron simple.
But is that oh, yeah, I've got some scraps here.
No problem. I can whip something up.
I'll go, you know, I'll go down and measure it up.
It'll be thank you. It'll be great.
Take care of that. Awesome.
You're the best.
Do you need help hoisting it up there?
I saw those two. They were really struggling.
I know.
You know what? Honestly, it'll probably break the table.
So I'm just going to kind of work off what I need.
Got it. And yeah.
Oh, and I mean, of course, I know you wouldn't.
But maybe just don't totally mention it to everybody that I have this
because it is obviously pretty valuable.
Oh, of course. Yeah. No, mum's the word.
Don't worry about it. Awesome.
All right. I'll be back.
I'm going to go measure that up,
be back in a flash and we'll whip that up for them.
You're the best.
As Thane grabs a few things and heads out down towards the docks,
give us a description of Everbane's,
the general layout size,
maybe some personal items or things that you have hanging on the wall, if anything.
Yeah, so it's it's big.
It had started out pretty small,
like my grandfather started the forge and it was just pretty small,
but kind of grew and expanded.
And then my father took over the business and it grew and expanded.
So it's quite large.
So Thane
kind of rents over half of the space
in the shop doing sort of like, you know, horseshoes and sort of less finesse work.
And then I have sort of a smaller workshop that's sectioned off.
Everything else is quite open, of course, because we're flames and anvils.
And, you know, it's hot and loud.
But I do have sort of a small office
in the back where I do my sketches and I tinker with things and try
and figure out how to make these specialized weapons that I make.
There isn't like a storefront or anything
so much because everything is is custom.
I love that. We we pull back out of Everbane's here and a couple of people
walk by and give a holler in, hey, Bonwyn, how you doing?
Hey, I'm good. How are you?
Trying to scrape up some more work.
They just bumped up the taxes.
Oh, I know.
It's unbelievable.
Like at some point, you just can't get more blood from a stone.
Right. And I heard they shut down three more shops in the district.
Yeah. Let's maybe a fewer gold statues and more.
This is going to sound crazy.
I don't know. Schools.
Yeah, schools.
Clean up the sidewalks, get some people enough food to eat.
It's it's, you know, I know that, you know.
All right. Well, you have a good one.
I'm going to go try and
make something
with nobody having any money.
It's hard to do that.
And it just kind of fades off into the noise of the block.
Cut back to Alydin
and you are laying in your your makeshift bunk
and you hear a rattle of cans,
which is one of my yes, my trip, your perimeter alarms, security system.
Everybody in the space, all the kids
in the space and tally all shh, everybody quiet
and everybody kind of moves back to the shadows.
What do you do?
I think that
upon hearing the cans, there is like a routine.
There's a planned reaction for that.
So I think what
Alydin and Tally would do would be whispering to the others,
get in your position, which is just to hide for the rest of them.
And
Alydin
puts her back to the wall with the door to her left and just waits.
Hand on her bucket.
That's right.
It's also a weapon over my dead bucket.
I mean, body, you hear some heavy footsteps coming into the stable,
the back of the stable, you hear them kick over some some wood
crates that just crumple to the ground.
Sounds like they're whoever's back there.
There's low grumbling conversation.
You can't quite make out what they're saying,
but sounds like they're rooting around and looking for something.
You position yourself if you would like, you can move closer to try and hear.
Oh, yeah.
If there's one thing that Alydin likes to do, it's eavesdrop.
So she for sure sneaks up all sneaky, sneaky and
wants to hear if there's anything juicy to listen to and make a stealth role.
I mean, information is its own form
of currency, so if you can get something to help you out, absolutely.
Ten, I had a plus three and everything.
Ten's not bad.
Well, ten's fine.
Ten's fine, we're low level.
That was episode one, OK?
I know that was that's in the past, Amy.
One time deal.
OK, yeah, you move forward.
You are reasonably silent.
You're not drawing attention to yourself.
And as you move closer, the grumble conversation becomes clear.
And you hear a gruff male and female talking back and forth.
Kenny sent us out here and said there's an easy access point to get into the underground.
This place hasn't been used in years.
I see the kids walking around here every now and again.
You see anything over there?
It's just crates. There's nothing here.
Yeah, no, like it's a stable.
Why would they put an underground department in a state?
Yeah, I think the intel's bad because, yeah, it just doesn't make sense.
Hey, you hear that?
Hmm, probably just a rat.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's just a rat.
You, PAlydin, hear one of their footsteps begin moving closer
to an entryway where you're very near to.
You hear their breath on the other side, and as they're peering in,
you see just the shadow of them emanating through and into the space.
You're
curled up and tucked away.
Yeah, I'm flat against the wall.
Crouched down.
Just holding my breath.
And looking around to see
if all the kids are well hidden.
Check that corner over there once more, and then we'll be gone.
Anything over there?
No, just some old sacks.
I don't know. Let's go back.
There's no underground caverns out here.
That's all back in the main district.
Nothing connects this far out.
All right, back to the shop.
The footsteps carry back off.
Alydin
waits until she's sure that they're gone and just follows them a little bit
down the street to make sure that they're not doing a whole double back
thing, because she's stupid.
And when she's sure that they have gone and decided to give up on this
pursuit, goes back in and
gives her a little like, I need to figure out the fucking whistle,
because I'm just like,
make it just a Hunger Games thing if you want.
But yes, something like that.
I'll figure it out, you guys.
We'll listen to bird calls is what we'll do.
Here you go. There we go.
Yeah, simple bird calls.
Simple bird calls, you know.
Just a warbler or whatever.
Probably a blue-footed booby, because, you know, it's us.
So, guys, guys.
Yeah, come out, come out. It's safe.
OK, are they gone?
Those are two of Kinney's
dumber bruisers over there.
And they were looking for some underground tunnels.
Underground tunnels?
Do you think they're going to come back?
I don't think so.
There's no tunnels out here.
You guys did a really great job of hiding.
So I don't think they're going to come back.
Thanks. Yeah.
Thanks. It was really scary.
I used that spot you showed me yesterday.
Well, good. And thank you for making sure there wasn't someone in there first.
It was weird last time.
Too many people, one space.
One barrel can only hold one person.
Remember, one barrel, one person, one barrel, one person.
So I think we should look around
for this, because they didn't actually try real hard.
And we haven't been in this spot for a super long time.
Have you guys been exploring anywhere in here?
A little bit, but you find anything?
Not. Yeah, but we haven't checked everywhere.
Like there could be.
That'd be pretty cool.
I wasn't looking for underground tunnels.
New priority.
OK, we need to find if there is a hidden trap door somewhere,
because if there is a tunnel system that can connect us to the main town.
Oh, our life just got a whole lot easier.
OK, underground tunnels.
Let's go. Let's go, everybody.
Let's find some underground tunnels.
This is going to be really cool.
Tally, get the candles.
OK, I'll go get the candles.
Tally runs off.
Everybody scatters as they begin to look
underneath bales of straw.
There's barrels everywhere,
there's sacks of grain that have fallen over that are moldy.
Probably a wheelbarrow of some sort of some sort.
We hear the door open of the Brewed Awakening, which is entirely empty.
There's a big sign up on it says out of business,
which has been just crudely painted
onto this sign slapped up over the front glass.
And inside, on top of the bar, is Bench Ripley doing a set of push ups.
842, 843, 844, 845, 845.
I mean, Bench, wow, that's that's a really high number.
Oh, yeah, well, there's not much to do with the business clothes.
So I just sit here pumping the iron and pumping my muscles up.
Just waiting either any any news on the opening the Brewed Awakening?
Oh, yeah. OK, a couple of updates on that front.
They said they gave you three warnings.
Oh, yeah, they gave me the warnings, but the warnings.
Yeah, the warnings came the same day that the taxes were due.
How was I supposed to get it together?
OK, yeah, like it was like memo, taxes, memo.
You missed them. Come on, man.
Yeah, it seems
I don't know how they're running things here.
It's definitely not what I'm used to.
That's for sure. But a couple of solutions for you.
One is you pay the taxes.
We owe them.
They'll look at reinstating you.
Sounds like it's a bit of a permitting process because you let it lapse.
It's a whole paperwork thing.
Second option, I go get Oak.
I bring him here.
You ply him with some drinks while you're closed.
Yes, no paying customers tonight.
And maybe we get some sort of expedited
paperwork thing through the system ASAP tomorrow.
Well, if you think that would work,
I mean, I'm more than happy to do that, to play the game.
I mean, I don't know, but worth a shot, right?
Yeah, no, that's absolutely.
I mean, I have the taxes.
They just don't take them.
So they just shut down the business so we can have Oak here.
You bring him here.
We have the drinks.
We have the fun.
We say, hey, maybe a business.
I mean, that's the plan.
But yeah, we'll see.
I think I think he'll be a lot more agreeable
once I get him away from from the mayor's place there.
OK, this sounds like a great plan.
You go get Oak and I will get the drinks ready.
And we will maybe plan some whodunit questions.
Perfect.
What do games do to play?
OK, I will figure that later.
That bench goes back into the kitchen
as Cav heads out to get Oak and we prepare for guys night.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season three, episode two.
This episode starred Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue Editing by Carla Maxted and Sound Design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and sound effects from Epidemic
Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garba.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babiak, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Christian
Brown, Craig Zeiss, Barry Mady, Ongarong Kiersing, Old School Gamer D,
L.A. Brent, Nathaniel Teeter, Luna and Aaron.
Want to have your say in the world?
Join us at Patreon dot com slash gum dragging cast.
You'll be able to submit MPC names, store names, street names,
major landmarks, anything you want to help us build out this new world.
For season three, we're looking for it and we could use your help over at
Patreon and you can also join us in our Discord.
Very easy to avoid spoilers in our Discord.
Come on over. We'd love to have you.
Please do do it now.
There's a link in the in the bio
in the link tree. That's where you find it.
We've got a lot of great things coming up in February and we'll tell you more
about them, but head over to Patreon dot com slash dumb dragon cast sign up
and you'll be the first to know about them.
It's a great time and follow us on Instagram.
We happen to post them over there, too.
We're at dumb dragon cast anyway.
That's all I have for now.
Thank you so much for listening to this one.
Have a great week and we'll talk again soon.
So in that sense, Nina's the glue that keeps the motor running.
Motors don't exist in this world.
Nina's the glue that makes sense.
We said the glue keeps the motor running.
Yeah, that's the part of it.
It doesn't make sense.
Wait a minute.
Motors don't exist here.
Otherwise, perfect.
I don't know why my mind is breaking down.
I'm giving you a little bit of an idea.
I'm giving it its monthly glue.
We don't let rust work on the cars.
Everybody scatters as they begin to look
underneath bales of straw and
other things that are found in an abandoned.
Fuck, I'm terrible at this game.
You just gotta shake the rust off.
I can describe things.
You can.
I believe in you.
I've been in barns and they kind of are.
They really are.
Yep, it's just kind of catch-all, right?
There's like some wire.
There's like, yeah, there's barrels
everywhere, sacks of grain that have
fallen over that are moldy.
Probably a wheelbarrow of some sort.
Love it.
They're looking under all of that stuff.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.