Hey, it's me Bench, ah, Dumbgeons and Dragons is coming up right after this.
You all start milling into and find yourselves in the training grounds of Vintersmouth, which are located just beside the military barracks, out in the large open field on the noble side of the river.
As you walk in, you see that there's a large obstacle course and among the obstacles that you see, there's a series of ropes going up one huge wall and down the other side.
There's bAlydince beams. There's like a bear crawl style obstacle.
There are a series of interesting mechanisms and devices that you see from a distance.
You can't quite place what they are and a large ring.
A bear crawl station?
Yes.
You know, like, like where your legs stay straight and your arms are on the ground and your ass is in the air?
Or you think an army crawl?
I was thinking army crawl.
Okay, bear crawl.
I don't know if you guys have taught elementary physical education lately.
I most decidedly have not.
I have not. So I didn't even know that was a thing.
I just like went with the thing where you're on the ground under the water.
I'm going to put a picture in Discord so everyone has the same visual.
That's now what we have to do.
Oh, I like that.
Ours is up, people.
So it's a bear crawl station where you have to keep your arms and legs completely straight to get moving.
Anyways, up near the bleachers in this area, you see Ignatius and several other entourage members.
And you all mill about and make your way over there.
And among this crowd, we have Cav, we have Bonwyn.
Alydin, you're kind of sneaking in at the back.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but I don't anticipate you immediately milling with the main group.
Oh, no. There's going to be a lot of observation first.
Right, right, right, right.
Bench is there.
Oak is covering for you, Cav, today, as this is a work day and you are out exploring extracurricular activities,
which is well within the rights of your position.
And two others from the town, Anapa, who is a human woman from the town.
Short, brown, curly hair, olive skin.
She's wearing her fruit stand uniform, which is really just an apron,
a nice green apron with white threading that runs through it.
100% I just thought she was wearing a fruit stand and I was like, yeah, all right.
I know, me too. I was like, OK, I guess it's just like one of those kind of portable ones.
Yeah, but like it had fruit on it, which will make the obstacle course more challenging.
How are you going to bear crawl in that thing?
Not well.
You know what? Not everyone's going to be accepted. This is tryouts.
That's why there's these obstacles.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons, a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast.
I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More, he, him, and Dumbgeons and Dragons stars Amy More as Alydin.
She, her.
If I do get paid and I come back, oh, oh, we're going to buy a house.
Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave, he, him.
I really feel like I can do this now that they're cheering for me.
And Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane. She, her.
We also should maybe find out what you're going to get paid because he has not mentioned that at all.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D production and supported by our patrons.
You can find that at patreon.com slash D&Dcast.
Hey, sign up for a seven day free trial. And now, fuck it, let's play.
Hey!
You all make your way over to Ignatius who looks like he's kind of in conversation with some people from his entourage as they're waiting for the time at which to start.
We'll give you a moment to talk amongst yourselves as they are preparing whatever they're working on.
Well, I feel like I'm here just to like sweet talk Ignatius into choosing Kav as opposed to wanting to be an adventurer.
But I feel like because I know Ignatius and I have been paying his doorman who are maybe there as part of his bodyguard retinue.
I know these guys, so I'm probably just going to say hi, even if they're already talking.
Sure. Ignatius catches you out of the corner of his eye and sees you walking up.
This is Bonwyn. Are you going to be an adventurer as well?
Oh, no, I don't think so. I wanted you to meet my new friend Kav. Kav Lauren.
Oh, hello, Kav Lauren.
This is Ignatius who is the proud, I hope, owner of one of the finest weapons I've ever made.
Yes, very proud. And it's what's inspired me to put this little party together so that we can go perhaps find some goods and treasure and life beyond just the boring and mundane, am I right?
Yes, yes, exactly. Kav Lauren, I believe, has some good adventuring experience, right Kav?
I mean, I dabbled a little bit in the past, absolutely.
So Kav, you are hanging out at City Hall. I've seen you around there before, I feel.
Well, I mean, like hanging out might not be the right terminology. I do work there.
Interesting.
But I'm not just like hanging out at City Hall. I mean, temporarily. I don't work there full time. Just on loan from Kingstown.
Well, it's lovely to have you here. Do you have any experience?
Yeah, I dabbled a little bit in my in my younger years.
I haven't really picked up the old Warhammer lately, but if this seems like a good idea, I think I'd pick it up again right away.
It's going to be a great idea. And then in the background, all we see is a person falling from one of the ladders.
Totally great idea.
Okay.
Was that June?
That old lady?
Was that June? June, what are you doing?
I'm all right. I'm all right.
Nothing's going to break this hip.
She goes back up.
Ain't nobody going to slow you down.
Of course she goes back up. June's a straight badass, absolutely.
We cut ahead. The crowd has grown a little bit.
There's a few other people who have milled in, but Ignatius calls you all around into the center of the training area and says,
ladies and gentlemen and friends beyond the binary, let us first welcome you all to this beautiful day.
This day of which we are going to perhaps change the course of your life and mine.
No, he's going to try to sell us something.
Yeah, he brought us here for an MLM presentation, it seems like.
Today is the first day of the rest of your life.
What's that? What's an MLM?
Multi-level murder.
Let me tell you why you're here today.
You are here to come with me on a journey through the Mi Mountains and find a stronghold of treasure buried somewhere deep within
that is said to be one of the largest fortunes ever collected.
Who said that?
Legend and lore, my friend. Legend and lore and a little dash of hope and wonder.
That's all we have to go on here, but we also have a map.
But like there's no eyewitnesses?
Well, there were eyewitnesses, the river pirates of old.
They left the treasure there long ago and buried it deep.
But river pirates, the turnover is quite high and they forgot exactly where they left it.
And one day this map, and he pulls it out, washed ashore.
And I've had it with me for six years now.
I was going to ask if they had a map, why did they need to remember where it was?
But now the map's washed ashore.
Well, OK, yeah, I'm with you.
Washed ashore. Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Thank you for all of these deep in-depth questions.
But what we need today is we need a group of three, maybe four people to come along with me.
A lot of you. Looks like I've seen your faces around some some rather young adventurers in the crowd.
And he's you can see that he's pointing at you, Alydin.
Alydin, where are you standing in this group?
Are you you're off a bit?
I'm I'm at the back.
Well, then, as he points to you, like the crowd parts, you are standing.
Come forward. Come forward, my dear.
This is Alydin's like nightmare come to life.
Like she might as well not be wearing any pants.
This is how much she does not want this type of attention.
Oh, no, thanks. No, that's I'm just listening.
Well, you're doing such a great job.
What are you doing here?
Well, I am curious about going and pursuing a life as an adventure.
Yeah, I think so.
Are you ready for danger?
Oh, yes.
Excitement.
Possible mortal injury.
You see a couple of people as he's listing these start to leave the group.
Sir, I live.
I live on the streets out here like mortal dangers is my second middle name.
And what's your first middle name?
Karis.
All right, Karis.
Know my name.
OK.
She knows she does better.
She does better than to correct, like a noble.
She's like, all right, you can call me Karis.
All right, Karis, tell me what you bring to the party before we do all of this.
This show the show pony behavior that they've set up here today.
Tell me what you bring to the party.
I bring my sense of adventure.
My stealthy ways of moving around.
And I'm pretty handy with this boomerang.
Take it out of my bucket.
I was a boomerang in that bucket.
Did anybody guess that there could be a boomerang in there?
And I'm full of surprises.
I think so.
So that is why I should be a part of this team.
Love it.
I will say, Ignatius, sorry to interrupt.
I can vouch for Alydin's stealthy ways.
Who's Alydin?
I'm sorry.
I can vouch for young Karis's stealthy ways.
Perfect.
Glad we're talking about the same person.
She's very resourceful.
Yes.
And sneaky.
And clever.
Well, that's what you need on the party.
She kind of like straightens up.
Like she doesn't get compliments from adults.
Usually it's like, hey, get out of here.
Like, you know, so she's like kind of stands a little taller.
Like, like, yeah, I am resourceful.
Bonwyn is very upset to see her here.
Like, so like, what is she doing?
She's just a child.
Well, I was hoping not to be seen, but apparently the crowds part when someone...
Turns out your stealthy ways may not be that stealthy.
It was information gathering and then...
Not in a big field.
No.
When you're the only child.
All right, Karis, you have been vouched for by one of my most dearest compatriots in this entire city, Bonwyn here.
Karis, if you could come stand on this side, please.
And he ushers you off to his left.
Okay.
Thank you.
We have our first member of the party.
Karis here has everything it takes to be an adventurer.
No need to prove it.
You don't say it unless you mean it.
Right, Karis?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
I think so.
Great.
Everyone else here you shall have to take on.
And he turns and there's big drums that go...
The gauntlet.
One, two, three, four.
We are in the middle now.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
Hopefully you're having a great day because we are.
You're here.
Heck yeah.
Oh, yeah.
We're stoked.
We're coming in with big energy.
Oh, yeah.
We'll see if we can maintain it.
Okay.
So this came off of our monthly gook hang, which is like one of the best times that
we get to have.
Oh, my God.
It is super fun.
It's so fun.
Let's explain what a gook hang is because those are just words that haven't made
sense for literal years because that program hasn't even existed.
It made sense when Google Hangouts was a thing.
When we did like a Google Hangout with patrons.
Yeah.
And it just caught on and now we've gone through like three different softwares,
but it's still the gook hang and we hang out and we just kind of bullshit and
Happens every month on the first Tuesday of the month.
Everyone who's a patron can come, hang out, ask questions or just shoot the
shit with us.
Whatever.
It's all good.
We just love to have you there.
This last one, two people.
It was their first one.
And we have like seen and known these people for a while.
So, so exciting.
It was so fun.
And when you are a patron, you get an episode dedicated to you like today's
patron, Kit LeBlanc.
Thanks, Kit.
Thank you, Kit.
Thanks so much.
I love the name Kit.
Me too.
Just want to throw that out there.
Old timey detective.
That's right.
That's for us.
You know, who is that?
That's Veritas over in Discord.
Oh, secret identity revealed right here in the middle.
I love it.
Sorry, Kit.
Don't dox Kit.
Yeah, no.
And your address is?
No, we won't do it.
Leave this part out.
Private information.
Yeah.
We won't be like Kyle Claset who there is.
Okay.
There's a lot of conversation about Kyle and where Kyle lives because he
revealed his address in Bombarded and like people live very close to him
from our audience.
Oh my God.
All right then.
Oh, Kyle.
From our audience?
From our audience, yeah.
Our people are great though.
They're great.
They're not going to go knocking.
So that's no problem.
Just go hang out around the convenience store around his place.
Maybe create some sort of pamphlet, advertising Bahamut and just like
leave it in his mailbox.
That's right.
And next week, big special guest, completely unrelated to the person we
just mentioned.
This is going to be out of left field.
Out of left field.
Zero way to know who they are, who they're playing or what they're doing
here.
So keep listening.
You know, if you were going to stop today, don't.
Don't stop today.
Next week, there's our cliffhanger for you.
That's what we keep bringing you back.
That's right.
Good times.
Well, thanks for being here with us.
I hope you enjoy the rest of the episode.
It's a great little gauntlet that we get to run specifically Tom's
character through in this next little part.
It's about damn time.
So good luck to Cav.
Thank you.
Good luck, Cav.
There's some highs and lows.
Yeah, absolutely.
All right, friends, have a great week.
We'll talk to you soon.
Bye.
Love you.
We cut over to the start of the gauntlet lined up at the front.
Our three people bond when you are still not participating in the immediate
activities.
Just observing.
That's OK.
Just observing for now.
But now I got to reconsider everything because it's fucking kids going.
That's me.
And I'm still thinking.
I want to see, like, Cav can, you know.
Yep.
So right at the front, we've got Cav, we've got Bench, and we have
Anapa.
Ignatius is standing in front of you, and he says, there are three
ways to get through these courses.
There is an easy way, and he points to one track.
There is a middle ground, and he points to the middle one, and there
is a hard track.
Where you go earns you some extra points, but it's all time-based.
So if you finish on the easy track much quicker than those on the
hard track, you could have a stronger stance.
Which course would you like to take?
And he looks to you, Cav.
Well, I mean, I have to ask, if the goal is time-based, why
would anyone do anything but the easy route?
If you succeed with a greater ability on the middle or harder
track, it earns you additional points.
However...
Oh, so now there's a point system.
Oh, yes, there's points, there's time.
Ignatius is making this up as he goes.
He's making it up as he goes.
Regardless, you pick your destiny.
Are you an easy pushover, just going to take the low road while
everybody else earns their keep?
Well, I've never really been one to not pull my weight.
I'll try the middle.
Perfect.
Love it.
And he lines you up.
Bench, you can take the hard one.
I was going to take the middle road, too.
All right.
And Anapa, take the easy one.
Everyone to the starting area.
You take one step forward because you're already there.
The crowd just takes one step backwards.
Here you go.
I kind of lean closer to Anapa.
He hasn't actually said what we're doing, though, has he?
No, I assume that we're going to maybe run forward and do
whatever comes in our way.
It looks like there's a bAlydince beam right ahead of us, so I
think we'll take it one step at a time.
Okay.
Yep.
Hey, good luck.
Thank you.
You, too.
Ignatius holds in his hand a large symbol.
There's a huge crash, right?
Behind you of this symbol.
End your off.
So first up is a bAlydince beam.
You can decide how you go over that bAlydince beam.
I mean, it's probably we're going to do a little bit of a
skills challenge here.
I love it.
How is the easy bAlydince beam different from the medium and
difficult bAlydince beam?
Thicker, smaller, smaller.
Oh, the width of the beam itself.
Yeah, so that visually, that's how it is.
Length of the beam, too, maybe.
Like long and skinny.
Maybe there's even like an up and down component to it.
Lots of things that could happen.
In game, there is a higher DC for the middle and hard
tiers, and if you fail in the hard one, you may also
take damage.
Spike trap.
Got it.
Yeah.
The other two, no damage.
Well, I've once died during an obstacle course, so.
All right.
Cav isn't the most athletic or acrobatic these days,
but he will go for acrobatics to try to get over
this thing.
All right.
So the symbol goes.
You charge off right ahead of bench.
So he's also taking the middle road.
So he's going to be following behind you.
And Anapa also takes off.
Can somebody roll me?
I want to roll because I'm not going to get to
participate in this.
You can always jump in.
You have first round draft pick who already made
the team.
It's unexpected.
Initially picked last for sports, guys.
That's a nine for Cav.
It's a one for Anapa.
A one for Anapa.
No, a five.
Spike trap.
Did I say one?
You did say one.
Oh, man.
It's a five.
You absolutely said one.
She is carrying the fruit stand, right?
So she is at disadvantage.
It's pretty challenging.
She takes off.
Her hands are slapping.
You know, it is a minus four because she's
wearing this big sandwich board.
She really should have taken that off.
Anapa tries to jump up and like hits right
into sternum.
Yeah, it's unfortunate.
She squishes a nanner right in there.
Cav, you got a nine.
So you take off and not as abruptly as Anapa
was taken out, but you get a couple steps in
and swiftly lose your bAlydince and trip off
as Bench runs up behind you and surpasses
you on this bAlydince beam.
You climb up.
You can get one more chance to see if you
can compete this.
And then you move on and you take a time
penalty.
All right.
Oh, it's an 11 that time.
Yes.
Right.
You make it.
You're following a little bit behind Bench,
but Bench has launched off into the next
obstacle, which is the bear crawl,
which everybody knows is when you walk with
your arms and legs straight and try and
get underneath a low rope.
OK, you made it to the bear crawl.
It's you and Bench.
Love it.
You do see another couple of people
tending to Anapa or, Bon, when you see
this, you see a couple of people helping
to back off the obstacle course.
And a few more people are lining up
at the start.
Alydin definitely like leans down
because Anapa kind of biffed it
and fruit rolled.
There are a couple of plums.
Alydin totally just kind of sneakily
just, whoop, like picked them up,
put them in her bucket.
Perfect.
You know, recommended, obviously,
athletics for bear crawl.
How would you like to approach this
bear crawl?
I mean, would animal handling pay off?
I was going to say with Robax Platinum,
not a sponsor.
Right?
Yeah, Robax is set covering this one.
No, I'll probably, I'll go with
athletics probably, yeah.
Oh, that is a 16.
Love it.
So you are able to, you actually
gain a little time on this one,
making it back.
That's good.
Is Anapa out completely?
Anapa's out completely, yeah.
Oh yeah, like crushed sternum,
I would assume.
They're taking away on a stretcher,
but not a stretcher,
on her just fruit board.
She does give like a little thumbs up
to the crowd though,
and everyone's very, very happy to see that.
Yeah, they're like,
we're glad you're not dead.
Bench maintaining his lead on you,
you make up a little time,
and you're working up behind him
as you are doing this fantastic bear crawl.
Looks just pristine and picture perfect.
And as you reach the end,
you hear a, well,
as you're about to reach the end,
you hear a splash from up ahead,
and you kind of tilt your head up.
You see Bench has gone underwater
at this next obstacle.
You get out of this bear crawl,
out from under the ropes,
and you see that there is a tunnel
filled with water.
As you wait a moment,
you see Bench surface on the other side.
Is it majestic?
It is majestic.
He goes under and whips his hair back.
I'm so glad he did.
Very mermaid-esque.
So you have an underwater swim
that you need to do.
Looks like it's probably 100 yards.
This one's going to be a double check.
We've got a con to see
if you can hold your breath that long,
and a strength to see
how fast you can get through it.
But before we find out
how good a swimmer you are,
let's go check in with Bonwyn
and Alydin.
So what are you doing here?
Well, I was just checking it out.
It's like really dangerous.
I know that you're a survivor,
obviously,
but there's pirates and bandits
and wild animals.
Oh my!
And Ignatius is...
Yeah.
And Ignatius,
and I sort of pull you away
a little bit from Ignatius,
Ignatius is maybe not, like,
super experienced as a leader
of a group of adventurers, so...
You're all doing so good!
He...
Okay.
Yeah, I can see that.
He's not going to be alone, though.
He's not the one who does the stuff.
The guys around him do the stuff.
Okay.
We also should maybe find out
what you're going to get paid,
because he has not mentioned that at all.
That's okay.
Okay.
I do not want to die in Wintersmith.
But you also need to eat food.
I assume we're going to be fed on this trip.
Okay.
I just back away.
All right.
There's no talking sense to this kid.
She's going to get free meals.
She's not interested in money.
Who is this kid?
She's going to get free meals.
She's going to get to see stuff
outside of the city.
She's going to have a roof or a tent
or whatever over her head.
This is like when kids on the street
get sent to juvie
because they get three square meals
and a safe place.
And now no responsibility.
No responsibility now for all those other kids.
But also a little bit of guilt with that.
But at the same time,
if I do get paid and I come back,
oh, oh, we're going to buy a house.
A good one.
We cut back to Cav.
As you are preparing to dive headlong into this pool,
if that's the mode you want to take,
you could also just kind of crawl in there.
Cannonball.
Yeah, no, I'm going to dive right in there
and do my best to catch up to Bench.
All right.
Give me a con roll to see how well you hold your breath.
Okay.
That's a 17.
Oh, you have the lungs of a whale.
You're doing such a great job.
Strength.
Strength is a six.
Six.
Okay.
You dive in holding your breath really great
and you are starting to feel fatigue set in.
You're not sure quite how far you've made it,
but you're not there yet and you're not moving very fast.
And your amazing breath holding is being held back
by how long you've been under the water.
What do you do?
I guess like think back to when Cav was doing this
on like a regular basis.
When he was younger and like, he knows he can do this.
He's just a little out of practice.
You're thinking back to times when you were a little more,
you're digging deep.
I'm digging deep.
I'm drawing on my reserves.
Give me a little inspiration roll,
a little advantage roll on your strength
to see if that'll pull you through.
All right.
Yes, that is it.
Well, I don't know if it's for sure,
but that's a 15.
It's much better.
15 is much better.
I was like, yes, I passed the check.
Thank you.
That seems to be what Russ is saying yes to.
Up above, you saw Bench come up.
You saw Cav go under.
On some of the other tracks,
you see people kind of catching up to Cav
and Cav still hasn't come up yet for a good moment
as compared to the other people around him.
Does anybody do anything?
I mean, I'm certainly going to at least cheer him on.
Like, come on, Cav, you can do it.
Great work.
You're really showing off that breath holding.
That's really good skill, right, Ignatius?
Oh, yes.
See how long he's been holding his breath?
He's been down there for ages.
I hear that's key in adventuring
is being able to hold your breath.
It's so important.
So when things sneak up on you,
you can hold your breath and be perfectly silent.
Absolutely, it's really important.
I love this.
What if you need someone to go down a well?
What if you need someone?
There could be a well on this adventure.
Charis, did you hear that?
Look, he's still holding his breath.
I can fit down a well.
Oh, my gosh.
How do you hold your breath, though?
And as you pull that breath in,
you see Cav emerge from the water there,
not as gracefully.
Where we picked up a little strength,
we lost a little grace.
You went in very smooth, came out perhaps a little panicked.
Cav, are you okay?
You slowed down a little bit there.
Yeah, it's just a little harder than I remembered.
But I got there.
Don't you worry about old Cav.
And as you climb up and out,
you turn and you face the ladder wall.
It goes up 100 feet in the air,
has a rope attached to it.
100 feet.
100 feet is so many feet.
That's really high up.
It's really high.
It's ridiculous.
I said it.
When he gets up there,
is there a salmon ladder, too?
Because that would be...
I love that thing.
I fucking love that thing.
Well, is the final one for you?
Are you going to do it?
Can we see where Bench is?
Has Bench already done it?
Yeah, we flashback some time,
and Bench has gone up and down,
and he's waiting on the side.
He'd be so good at it.
Yeah, his strength is his game.
There are several people who seem to be stuck partway up,
just hanging on.
They've got too far up,
and they've got the shaky legs,
and they're starting to climb back down the side they came up.
The spot could be yours if you can finish it, Cav.
Oh, sure.
Yeah, you know, I'm...
It's a lot, but I can...
Yeah, let's do this.
I can do this.
You can do this.
Everybody, cheer him along.
I really feel like I can do this
now that they're cheering for me.
All right, you go to tackle the ladder.
How do you tackle it?
How do you want to tackle it?
It's pretty straightforward,
but one wrong at a time.
Now, this is one of those net rope ladders
where it's just like you have to go...
Or is it like a rope,
and you walk up as you go up the rope?
Yeah, it's got slats.
You've got the rope,
although I described somebody holding onto it.
The hard one is the rope version.
The middle and easy ones,
it's got the planks and the knotted rope
that you can pull yourself up with.
All right, yeah.
I'm just gonna kind of go full bore on this thing.
Strength, athletics, acrobatics.
We'll go strength.
Oh, net 20.
Snap.
Really dig, dig deep.
Catching your breath after you're swimming,
and everybody's cheering you on from the sidelines.
Even Anapa, who's just laying down
with the brace on her own sandwich board.
And net 20, you describe to me
the flood of emotion and feeling
that runs through Cav.
Cav totally has done this before
in his previous training as an adventurer.
This is something that he's like,
he has done this climb before.
So he just like, he kind of starts slow,
he gets all set up,
but then once he starts going,
he just doesn't break his rhythm
the entire way up,
and he's up there in like no time.
I'm imagining the Mulan song,
he'll make a man out of it.
Let's get down to business.
We see you quickly making it up,
and it might be going in a little slower motion
in your own brain,
but everybody else sees you nimbly.
Compared to you climbing the city hall stairs,
you are swiftly moving up this ladder
and back down the other side,
and you get back down,
and it's like you almost blacked out for a moment.
And now you find yourself,
and everybody's cheering from the other side,
and you look around,
and Bench comes up behind you
and slaps you on the back,
and he says,
it looks like we're going adventuring, buddy!
Us and the kid!
I'm not a kid, I'm 14.
Dumbgeons AND DRAGONS
SEASON 3 EPISODE 9
This episode starred Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane,
Tom Laird as Kavlaran Goldweave,
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing by Carla Maxted
and sound design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library, and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs
are by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babiak,
Kat Waterflame,
Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown,
Craig Zeiss,
Perry Matey,
Ongorong Kiersen,
Old School Gamer D,
L.A. Branton,
Nathaniel Teeter,
Luna,
and Aaron.
And a special thank you to Twiglets
for the name Anapa.
I'm sure we're going to hear more
about how Anapa's doing after their recovery
from the Obstacle Course Challenge.
Hey, you can join us at Patreon.com
slash DumbDragonCast
where your name can be part of those
crazy kids right there.
It's all the cool kids.
We want you to be over there.
It's a great time.
Community and all that sort of stuff
that we need in today's day and age.
That was intense.
I'm sorry.
You can check it out though.
We'd love you for it.
And so you can stay in the know
with everything we have coming up,
sign up for our newsletter.
There's a link to it down in the description
which will take you directly
to our newsletter sign up
so you don't miss out there.
That's all I have for you right now.
We hope you have a most wonderful week
and we can't wait for the next one.
It's coming very soon.
Bye now.
This is All Right.
On your...
On your off.
Fuck.
End your off.
On your off.
Mark said.
Next.
Stop.
Very jarring way to start an obstacle course.
You see Bench has gone underwater
at this next...
Why do I have such a hard time with obstacle?
Obstacle.
Hourglass.
Yeah.
We found Russ's hourglass.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.