You're listening to Dumbgeons and Dragons and we'll start in just a moment.
Kavlarananan, you are sitting ever so patiently in a chair outside of Nina's office and you've been
waiting here for quite some time for Nina to come back. Her receptionist is busy filling out
paperwork at her desk and she looks over to you and says, I swear she told me she was going to be
back in a moment, but that was several hours ago. Did you need a snack? Are you going to just?
A snack would be pretty good. I do have to come clean about something though.
I can't remember your name. I know I've been here all day and it's gotten past the point
of where it's like too awkward to ask, but I just, I need, I need to own up. I need to tell
you that. No, that's fine. I just, I've lost the plot on this one and I don't love the fact that
that's what happened, but that's what happened. I just, I just thank you for your time. Defense
rests. Well, thank you for admitting that and not just calling me. Hey, you like everybody
else does. I'm Gwenn de la Veer. Gwenn de la Veer. You know what? I should have remembered
that. That's my sister's name. Well, it is a very common, it was a very common name for about a year.
Everybody was named Gwenn de la Veer. It just rolls off the tongue. It just has this sweetness
to it. Ah, yes. But thank you for asking. I'm going to go get you a snack. I can go see what
they have down in the kitchen there. Maybe there's some nice pastries. Somebody, I heard
somebody maybe brought in some donuts. I'm going to go see about that. I mean, I do love a
pastry. That would be delightful. And she rounds the corner and you hear like a little, oh,
and then some whispers. She's got goose in the hall. She's going straight to HR. No donuts for
you. Sorry. And then two pairs of quick footsteps going back down the hallway
towards the kitchen. Nevermind no HR. This is like an office romance. Yeah. And Kav does
hear this, but he's still getting over the fact that he actually like owned up to not knowing
Gwenda la Veer's name and is like super proud of himself for like being an adult. So he doesn't
really pay that much attention to it. Like he hears it, but doesn't click for him as to like
what is it, what it is, say a moment of recognition. And then you go back to just
staring at the wall on the other side of the room. I go back and I'm like, it's
Gwenda la Veer, Gwenda la Veer. Got to remember Gwenda la Veer.
Gwenda la Veer comes back into the room with a donut for you. And she says, I didn't know what
your favorite was. So I brought a couple. This one's like, oh, you want both of them.
Okay. Well, I mean, I don't have to have both of them, but like I don't really have a favorite.
They're all kind of my favorite. I got a Crueller and I got just this Long John
and it's got like this cream inside. I think they called it like an Eclair, something like
that. Thought you take your pick or you have them both. I can go get some more and no
problem. I saw Nina and she said she'd be here any moment now.
You saw Nina? Yeah. She was passing by the kitchen,
said she got swept away with a big meeting upstairs. And she'd be right down to see you.
I'm going to go back to the kitchen, get myself a donut because I should have brought
three. Foolish me. And she exits the room. Cav puts like one of the donuts on the desk
and like completely just inhales the other one. And then like not even a full minute
goes by and he like reaches back over for the second donut. After another few moments,
Oak walks into the room. There you are. You've been gone all day. What are you doing?
Well, I've been waiting for Nina, but apparently she had gone into her office earlier,
but then never came out. But then Gwenda LaVere ran into her in the hallway. Is there like a
second entrance to Nina's office that I don't know about? No. So then she probably wasn't
here at all then. She probably wasn't here at all. She probably just gave you the slip.
Gotcha. Gotcha. Yeah. Would you say that's like a characteristic of her personality,
like deceitful? Well, I mean, avoiding people happens a lot. The deceit factor, I mean,
I can't prove or deny if she has told me the truth when she is around in her office or not.
I just assume she's telling me the truth. All right. I mean, yeah, like, you know,
make someone prove you wrong, right? Yeah. Wait, what are you going to ask her? Like,
why are you waiting for five hours? I mean, really, I just wanted to follow up on like the
finances. But I think that's why she's avoiding me. So maybe just go back and look at the
books. Is that a better follow the money, follow the paper trail? Sure. Yeah, we can
follow the books. I mean, we've checked the books time and time again, and they look fine.
I told you the books are perfect. I did them. I heard like a whisper of like a second set of
books. A second set of books. One that perhaps that would be fraud. Kavlarananan. That would be
fraud. Yeah. And like probably a pretty good one. Wait, is that what you're here
investigating? I mean, I'm investigating a lot of things, but absolutely that's part of it.
You didn't tell me you were investigating fraud. Well, I mean, somebody walks by the
office and looks in with just raises an eyebrow and keeps going. You're gonna have
to keep it down a little bit. Sorry. Sorry. It's okay. It's okay. Yeah, there's there was like
a few different things I was supposed to check out while I was here. That was just one of them.
Okay, so if Nina is being deceitful to you, what makes you think she's even gonna tell you?
Are you trying to catch her in a lie? Are you trying to? What's your game plan here?
Well, I had a cousin that was really good at like reading people, you know, like those cold
reads that like the charlatans do on innocent people. I had a cousin who like showed me how
to do that a little bit and I thought I could get something from her just by being in the same
rooms or asking her some questions, seeing the way she reacts, that sort of thing. Just take
some mental notes of like, what's up with Nina? What's up with Nina? Well,
I don't think she's gonna come back. No, it doesn't seem to be that way. Yeah, so
we could continue to wait here. He has sat down beside you at this point, not on a chair,
because there isn't another chair, but on like a little side table. He was just sitting up there
across his legs. He's not just doing a weird wall squat beside him. No, he has to kind of
hover because it's not going to be able to support his weight. So he's holding it, but
just barely. So we could go and we can come back. We could get you. I mean, clearly
you've got a little you've got a little cream on just like in your mustache there.
Yeah. Clearly you had some donuts. I mean, some is a little presumptuous. Yeah, I had to.
Yeah. If only there was something we could do to figure out this solution for you. I guess
I'll just go back to my office and not do anything nefarious. I mean, do you need company?
He gets up and he starts to leave. Well, I guess if you want to come, like, I don't know.
I mean, sitting here has been you're the one doing the investigating waste of time.
Is there any like storage rooms or anything where like old files are kept? Oh, yeah. Yeah,
of course there is. I haven't shown you the storage closet downstairs. Yeah, come on with me.
Yeah. So Kava totally has just like forgotten about the cabinet. And as he starts to follow
Oak down the hallway, he sees like an identical looking cabinet behind Gwenda Levere's desk.
And it like stops him dead in his tracks. Oh, what I just forgot Gwenda Levere said that Nina
was coming back. So maybe I should just stay a little longer because like if she does come back,
I'd hate to miss her. Oh, yeah, sure. Yeah. Do you want somebody to just join somebody to
wait with you? Like I've finished all of our paperwork for the next three days. So I could
just go home or I could stay and hang out. I mean, Mom's probably going to be expecting
me soon. It's getting close to clock out time and she expects me five minutes later.
So sure. Yeah, sure. Yeah. Well, OK. Yeah. You know what? Well, we'll catch up tomorrow
since like all that since all that paperwork's already done.
And I'll just wait here a little longer and then I'll probably call it a day as well.
All right. Well, it's good seeing you. I guess I'll just I'll go lock up the office.
I'll make sure all your stuff's ready to go in there. I'll put your lunch back in your bag.
And yeah, I guess that's it for me. Have a good night.
All right. Yeah, you too. I'll just. Yeah, I'll talk to you tomorrow.
OK, bye now goes back to the one chair and like sits down and just
waits a minute till everything's like calm and quiet and then goes and tries that door handle.
The door handle is unlocked. It's a little it's got a little stick to it, but the door opens
and then it bumps into the desk. Obviously. Yeah. Slip in and close
the door behind me as best I can here without making too much of a racket.
And beeline straight for that cabinet. Sure. And by beeline, you mean awkwardly
move around the large desk inside this very time. I was thinking actually more of a direct
like as the crow flies situation. So step onto a chair, onto the desk, off the desk.
Yeah. Yeah. Love it. OK, great. Are there any windows in this office?
I can't remember. No, there are not.
There is a poster of a nice tropical beach set up on one of the walls, but no, no windows.
Oh, I really hope there's an escape tunnel behind that poster.
And a new frame. Yeah.
Nina's been taking out one bit of drywall at a time.
Yeah, you go and you you're examining the cabinet and the two lower drawers are locked.
The top three, you're able to open them and file through them if you would like,
but the bottom two are locked and secured. Quick look through the top three.
Anything interesting in there at all? Mostly seems like personnel files and documents,
incident reports, that sort of thing. Nothing, nothing out of the ordinary,
just at a quick glance through them. Can I flip through Oak's personnel
file real quick? Sure, absolutely.
Just like I want to see like the one pager.
It just says Oak, stellar employee, five stars, not likely to get a raise ever,
overachiever and never pushes back, quite reliant on his mother.
Also, mother barred from City Hall. I need to know what happened with that.
I'll have to ask him next time we're out for boys night.
Yeah, makes a little mental note to ask Oak about mother being barred from City Hall.
And looks around. I would love to find like a key for these bottom drawers.
Any role investigation, any likely hiding spots that you might leave a key?
Let's see here. That is a 17, but my investigation is not great.
So it's a 15 overall. OK, you move through all of the
upper cabinets on this drawer. You move through all of the drawers
in the desk, lift the papers. It does not appear that you can find a key
that would fit this drawer. There are no keys in sight.
So leading you to believe perhaps that if there were a key, it would be on Nina's person.
Sure. I mean, do I just bust it open?
I don't feel like that's a great approach, but like desperate times.
No, it's not that desperate. I'm going to get out of the
office before anybody comes back to find me there.
OK, you climb back over and open the door and as you pull it shut behind you,
you hear footsteps coming back down the hall and Gwenda LaVere comes around the corner just as the
door latches. What do you do to act nonchAlydint as she comes around the corner?
Actually, Cav just puts his hand up to his ear in the door and he's like,
I thought I heard someone in there, but.
Ah, you're still here. Hey.
Hey, Gwenda LaVere. I was just, I thought I heard someone in there, but
you said there was no any. Yeah, no, I don't know.
No. OK, well, I guess I haven't seen Nina come down.
She might have just forgot and just went home for the day.
That sometimes happens.
That does seem like something that might happen with her.
Yeah, very, you know, out of sight, out of mind.
Looking at the hook across the wall there, it seems she took her jacket.
So I guess she had no intentions of coming back.
That's unfortunate. I'm sorry that you've wasted your entire day here.
Oh, that's totally fine.
It's totally fine. Not the not the first day I've wasted here at City Hall.
Well, you have a great night.
Well, you too.
She goes and sits at her desk and is just organizing the papers for the night.
And as you round the corner and head back down to get your stuff that Oak
has very neatly placed for you outside the door waiting for you.
I grab my stuff and on my way to the Brewed Awakening.
We'll be right back.
It's the middle of the city.
You know, I'm just getting a lot of welcome to the middle.
I'm not looking up Safety City.
No, we're we're doing the middle.
We're talking about tiny cars on tiny streets driven by children.
And what an awesome thing it is.
Alydin would have just a kickass time.
Alydin would be a nightmare.
A hundred percent like just going nuts.
So Safety City.
Get your kids to check it out.
Not a sponsor.
Unless Safety City, you want to sponsor this Dumbgeons and Dragons podcast.
Is that a brand?
Are they branded tiny towns?
I think so.
I actually don't know.
All right.
If you want to give us a public service announcement that we can do for free,
we will do it for you.
We kind of just did.
That's right.
But what we do have going on is this is the second to last episode of this season,
which just to make sure you're aware, we're continuing with these characters.
It's like we're in campaign two, season one.
Whereas before it's like campaign one, season one and two,
and then season three is campaign two.
Like we should have not said this was season three.
Yeah, no, we definitely hindsight.
Maybe I'll tweak how it's presented in the whole thing.
But you know, we'll deal with that later.
But we're very excited because as we record this interlude,
we're starting recording the next season too later.
Well, look how far ahead we are, everybody.
We're not just scrambling to get things going like we usually do.
Killing it.
Loving it.
So summer's going to be a little bit of a break from regular episodes.
We are going to have some mini-sodes that we're getting ready to record as well
that we're going to just explore the city and the people in a...
Not going to say anything else because...
Don't put us in a box.
These can be whatever we want them to be.
Carla has a question.
Yep.
I don't.
My light turned off, so I was turning it on.
It was on a motion activator and I was...
Teacher Amy just went into teacher mode and that's that.
Hand up, have to call on it.
I see a hand up.
Oh, that's adorable.
Thank you for not shouting out, Carla.
Where you can get full episodes throughout the summer is over on Patreon.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
So we've got the little mini-sodes in the main feed,
but we have the Adventures of which we just started
or will be just starting a new season over there,
which includes Opal, Elia, and Night Hunter,
and Kyle's new character.
Kyle, do you want to introduce your character for the Adventures of?
Yeah, yeah.
My character's name is Nash Salmon Treats.
He is a Leonin barbarian rogue and I'm very, very excited
to have played him and to continue to play him.
I love that there's another barbarian on the team now.
Absolutely.
I hate that there's another cat on the team now.
I'm expecting it to be a source of conflict.
I don't think Night Hunter doesn't love it so much,
but Amy loves it.
It's not necessarily that he's a barbarian that Night Hunter doesn't like.
It's just the interactions haven't gone well so far.
Oh, it's fun, guys.
You're going to like it.
Some people get along and some people don't.
Yeah, that's how it works.
Figure it out.
Yeah, we will.
It's going to be a blast and we hope to see you over there.
And when you are a patron, you get an episode dedicated to you.
Which Russ definitely didn't forget and definitely already has the name ready.
Oh no, technical difficulties.
We should probably add it in, right?
It's just so cool he hasn't been able to say it yet
because we keep talking.
It's a real power.
We keep talking over him and he keeps going to put his hand up
and Amy will call on him.
I get on edgewise with these people.
That's how I run our marriage.
When he wants to talk, he raises his hand.
It's true.
Like today's patron, Stuttering GM.
Oh, Stuttering GM.
I love it.
Thanks so much.
I think in any, like in our context, we think Game Master.
But I feel like in many contexts, people would be like,
so like the engine doesn't work that great in the automobile.
It's a very versatile name.
And I was thinking like General Manager.
General Motors, General Manager, could be any of them.
General Mills.
Maybe they make cereal.
We don't know.
Oh my gosh.
Could be Gary McPhee.
We don't know.
Could be.
Gary McPhee is a very specific name.
All right.
Join us like Stuttering GM on Patreon.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
And we hope to see you over there.
And now we'll get you back to the episode.
Okay.
Thanks.
Bye.
Cav, you make your way out of City Hall,
waving goodbye to the security guards for the night.
As you're making your way down to the Brewed Awakening,
it's rather busy there tonight.
And as you take a peek through the window,
walking towards the front door,
you see all of your friends,
Bizard and Bonwyn and even Alydin
inside the Brewed Awakening.
Now is it like wing night
or what's going on in the Brewed Awakening
that everyone's there?
Kyle, why is Bizard there?
Because this is his favorite night.
Oh, I like the idea of wing night.
Sounds fucking good right now.
Yeah, I'd crush some wings right now.
Yeah, for reals.
I know.
Oh, wait.
So is there like maybe something fun
that goes along with that?
So like usually people watch sports on wing night,
like it's a game night or something.
Is it slam poetry time?
I was like, yes.
I had the image of like a cockfight,
but not a cockfight because that's brutal.
But people bring in their favorite chicken
and chickens don't like fly per se,
but they can flap quite a distance
and perhaps it's wing night
and they're seeing how far their chickens can fly.
It's a chicken tossing contest.
And the losers get eaten.
Yes, I love it.
Oh no, this took a turn.
You're thinking of your chickens in the Bible, aren't you?
Although that's really kind of,
it doesn't make sense because you'd want to eat
the stronger wings, like, you know, bigger muscles.
It's like a lottery situation.
The winner is the one who dies.
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
There we go.
You don't want to do well.
You want to bring your least impressive chicken.
They need to build more muscles on those weaker ones.
Your least impressive chicken.
Has everyone brought their worst in the flock?
Let's see them flapping.
Give them chickens a toss.
We see you exiting City Hall
and then transition to The Brewed Awakening
where outside as you are about to open the door,
you hear screams and hollers coming from inside.
And as you open the door, feathers are flying,
like just a plume of feathers flies out
as you see chickens flying across The Brewed Awakening.
Everybody's cheering for these chickens as you enter
and you see, I mean, it's packed,
but you see your friends Bonwyn and Bizard
and Alydin is hanging out with them at the table
and they catch your eye and give you a call over.
Oh, hey guys, did I miss it already?
Just the first heat.
There'll be more.
Don't worry, don't worry.
Nice, nice.
Kavlarananan, good to see you.
He puts down your usual drink, which is?
Some sort of oatmeal stout.
Solid.
Yeah, yes, it's very filling.
It's good for you.
I'll get you something to eat.
Oak told me you only had two doughnuts
while waiting for Nina at her office today.
Then he runs off.
I mean, who's talking about the dough?
All right, well, thanks, Bench.
All right, what did I miss?
How many doughnuts did you have?
Two.
For one person?
I mean, it was like two in two minutes.
Yeah, but you're like.
I mean, for doughnuts, that's a good round number.
That's kind of what I thought.
And plus, like,
Alydin looks you up and is like,
two for a big person, I think is fine.
I mean, sure.
I just, next time I'll grab you one, Alydin.
Thanks.
Oh, I could buy my own doughnut now.
And she looks over to Bizard.
Like, uh-huh.
It's true.
You can.
I'm a paid employee.
Wow, that's very good.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
To be honest with you, Kavlarananan,
it's under the table, so.
Oh, well.
Bizard's going to buy me my first beer.
Eventually, yes.
Yeah, maybe not tonight.
Probably not tonight, but at some point.
So what do you, what's your job entail?
Well, I take things out of boxes and then I put them
in the right places, not in the wrong places.
Because if you put it in the wrong places,
people get confused because I don't know if you know this
or if you've like been in a store a whole lot,
but people aren't very smart.
And like they need you to not only have it
where it is all the time,
but you need to also have like the name on it.
And then they still will come to you and ask you where it is.
So like, I mean, I make, you know,
the place couldn't even run without me.
I mean, yeah, I believe that because anytime I'm in a store,
if something's moved from the last time I was there,
I'm lost.
So you're doing a great service.
God, I hope I don't grow up like a regular adult.
I don't think you have to worry about that, Alevin.
Probably no chance of that.
Yeah, I wouldn't worry.
Yeah.
So about that beer.
Bench comes back and puts down this huge plate of stew
in front of you and then brings the table,
the wings that you had previously ordered
and a pound of all of the flavours
that are being served tonight.
And there's a little flag on top that just says,
Henrietta, fourth place.
Yeah, here you go.
You eat up all day just to do not enough
to keep that big boy strong.
Okay, I'm going to go check out all these customers over here.
I mean, if anyone would know, it's that guy, right?
He starts digging into the chicken,
but takes a half sec and after he grabs a wing,
kind of looks over to Bonwyn and says,
do you still have those thieves' tools by chance?
Unofficially, yes.
This is like Bonwyn and her friend,
Cav Lauren talking now, right?
Yeah.
Oh yeah, then I definitely do.
Okay, cool.
If like hypothetically,
I wanted to get into like a locked drawer,
maybe you could show me how to do that?
Well, I don't know if I could show you,
but I could probably do it.
Oh, I mean, that would also work.
What is in the locked drawer?
Great question.
Don't know.
That's what I want to find out.
What are you hoping is in the locked drawer?
All right.
Well, first off, there's two locked drawers.
Okay, great.
Probably some doors between us and the drawers.
There's some doors between the drawers.
Absolutely.
Okay, perfect.
I'm hoping there's a like second set of books,
like the real books.
Right, the real books,
like Rin Kipp was talking about,
like the actual books.
Yeah.
Okay, so I'm assuming-
The uncooked variety.
Yeah, yeah, the raw books.
The raw books.
So if we're looking for the books,
this is going to be some municipal crime,
like in a municipal office.
That's probably where we're heading.
Some sort of hall in the city.
Okay, yes.
When are you hoping this is going to happen?
I mean, sooner rather than later tonight,
maybe if possible,
but like also it is wing night
and I don't want to like take away from the festivities.
Well, we'll get all our sustenance in maybe
and then we can go check it out.
Chicken flies across the table.
While this is happening,
I pull on Bazaar's cloak
and I like gesture them to lean down a little bit
and as they're having their conversation.
Do they know that they can just get books
from like stores and stuff
and that they probably shouldn't cook them
because it's paper?
That will be another lesson that we will cover.
In fact, you may learn about it tonight
depending on how things go,
but I don't even know where to begin with this one,
but you are correct in what you are saying.
That sounds logical to me,
but there's a lot of things
that you got to read between the lines in those books.
Shit, I think I'm just confusing it.
I didn't go to school, Bazaar.
Well, school is fun,
but sometimes it's expensive to learn things
and when you can just learn them from people
that you happen to be around
and that's what we're doing here.
You don't know what they're talking about.
Kavlarananne is going to teach me how to cook books?
I don't think it's going to be a teaching thing
as much as it is going to be
just a learning opportunity
through observation and experience.
I'm going to observe Bonwyn stealing raw books.
That's to be seen,
but that's the goal, it sounds like.
Oh, can I come?
Well, I mean, if we're invited,
I mean, if it is at a hall in the city
as I kind of look over at them with a glare,
like pretty obvious, but you know.
Really sneaky, really sneaky language
between me and Kav over here.
But, you know, if there's, you know,
I know Kavlarananne's been doing some work up there,
but if there's more credence needed
to be given to a visit,
then who better than a mayor's advisor?
Do you have an office, Kavlarananne?
Can I see it?
I've never been inside of town hall before.
Like, maybe could I have a tour?
I could probably arrange for a tour.
I share an office, so it's not my office,
but you remember.
Like bunk beds.
Yeah, you remember.
Once I stacked a crate on top of another crate
and then Tally slept under that first crate inside
and then I slept on the top.
You know what?
That's very creative.
Thank you.
So can I see your office bunk beds?
Well, there's no beds,
but in fact there's only just the one desk.
But we make it work.
You know, he's really good at the...
Anyway, doesn't matter.
Yes, we'll go and we'll get a tour.
I wonder if Nina's good friend,
Bizard, couldn't maybe wrangle her
as a high-ranking sort of official
into giving a personalized tour
to his promising new apprentice, student,
however you want to spin that and just...
Protégé.
I think that's what, right?
Protégé, absolutely.
That's a very big word for somebody
who didn't go to school.
Did I say that word?
I don't know how to spell it.
Did I say that?
Maybe I did.
As far as asking Nina goes,
I certainly could ask Nina.
I mean, I wouldn't say that we're like friends.
I mean, we work together
and that's about as far as that relationship goes.
I feel like it might not even be that close.
Does she have the rob-ups?
You're getting closer.
You're getting really close.
Maybe you don't want her there
if you're going to take her things.
I never take ever,
but if I were going to,
it wouldn't be when that person was there,
which I wouldn't.
Yeah, hypothetically,
it would not make any sense
to take something from someone when they're there.
But would it be the perfect opportunity?
Well, what if that person was there
without being there
and it just looked like them?
Okay, say more.
I'm going to need to hear more about this.
Bizarre pulls out his tome
and he starts flipping through it
and he's like,
this page right here.
I could make myself look like Nina.
What?
I've seen Nina.
She's half your size.
She's...
You know, there's some adjustment
that's allowed within the confines of the spell,
but I think it could potentially work.
And, you know,
it would give us a lot of ammo against the mayor
and against, you know,
most of the rest of the group
that's involved with their ne'er-do-willing
against the city.
It's a gamble, though.
Caviar, the expert.
Would it be helpful to have someone...
You're blowing my mind, Bizarre.
But they could look like someone
where we were trying to find the books.
That seems like that would be amazing, right?
Yeah, I mean, it really could be.
Now, when you say look like,
does that also include sound like?
Reading over the text real quick,
because it's not something I've really thought about using,
but it's one I could certainly be prepared to use.
What does she sound like?
Does she sound different?
Would he just have to talk a little higher?
Well, I mean, not as comical, I guess, as that,
but, you know, just...
Could you sound like her if the need arose?
Or could you convincingly pretend
you had a really sore throat and just couldn't talk?
Now, that I think I could do.
Yeah, that I think I could do.
As far as I can see,
the, you know, clothing, armor, weapons, those kind of things.
Yeah, I can make myself at least a foot shorter or taller, so...
I mean, definitely shorter in this case.
I would have to fake a voice.
And if anybody were to...
I don't know, I can't touch anybody that doesn't know,
because otherwise then it's like,
ha ha, obviously you're not that short.
So there's a lot of potential holes in it,
not to mention it is a...
Yeah, it's not the most taxing illusion,
but, you know, still have to expend the life essence for it.
Sure, gotta pay the tax, yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
Very, very appropriate, Kavlaranan.
We got a lot of wings to eat still,
so let's just keep discussing.
I'm sure we can hammer something out.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
Snarf, snarf, snarf.
You're gonna have boobs.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, Season 3, Episode 24,
starring Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everpain,
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard,
and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue Editing by Carla Maxted
and Sound Design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound
and Slipstream,
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library, and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs
are by Matt Garbutt,
and a huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok,
Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown,
Angaron Kierzen,
Perry Matey,
Craig Zeiss,
Old School Gamer D,
L.A. Branton,
Nathaniel Teeter,
and Sarah Murphy.
Join us at Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast,
where you'll get a seven-day free trial
and episode dedication and a whole lot more.
We're getting close to our summer break
where we're still going to be releasing
some mini episodes for the main feed
that you're listening to this in.
But we also have entire shows over on Patreon
that we would love for you to come listen to
while we get season four ready.
And again, that's still this is a campaign two,
second season of that campaign.
We're continuing where we leave off, okay?
That's what's happening.
Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
See you over there.
Okay, bye.
Okay, cool.
A G-name.
Interesting.
What a strange, what a strange new ground to be breaking.
You know what?
Sometimes you just have to take the path least taken.
Is it Tom or is it Kavlarananin
that doesn't remember the locked cabinet
in Nina's office?
Oh, I did not remember it at all.
Now that you mentioned it, I remember it,
but it was not coming to me.
Yeah, fair enough.
No, absolutely.
I remember spying it and everything.
How do I get Tom to break into this office
without saying Tom break into this office?
This season seems like it's just going to end in crime.
All around crime.
Yeah, it's ending in crime 100%.
Everyone's going to do a crime.
Except Alydin, who's been doing crime to survive.
The fact that I'm not doing crime right now,
I'm on the up and up getting paid and then crying shit.
Amy not doing crime is almost a crime in and of itself.
Agreed.
I know, right?
When am I the good one?
Dumbgeons & Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.