Dumbgeons and Dragons will begin in just a moment.
The Road to Vintersmouth from Kingstown is a several day journey by walk, a two or three
day journey by horse or carriage, and being that you're out on your own for the first
time, Bizard, what is your preferred or chosen mode of transport here?
Would you walk the entire way to give you time to think, give you time to plan, or would
you hitch a ride on a caravan?
I would have hitched a ride with a caravan, having had to take dealings and like learning
how to make items and objects for the school and part of my training.
I got to know some of the merchants here and there, and I got set up with a merchant
that I, you know, we're good, we're well acquainted.
Steve's a good guy, deals in like metals and barrels and stuff like that, very, very
mundane kind of stuff, but so I took some of the, some of the money that I was able
to acquire leaving my father's house to get a ride down to Vintersmouth, able
to have a little bit of a conversation with Steve along the way to learn what he knows
about Vintersmouth and get an insight into some of the city and maybe where I should
go and took notes on those things.
And then the rest of it kind of just, yeah, plotted, plotted my course of action for
the next few months.
What I, what I wanted to aspire to set up my, my 30, 60, 90, let's call it
that. So yeah, that's a good plan to have when you're setting up a new business.
That's right. Riding up next to Steve, you round a bend and the forest before you
opens into the town of Vintersmouth, often to the left of the river that you've
been riding beside up to this point, there is the noble district and notably
missing from how we've described this city is the, in the time so far,
because we're a little bit earlier, there's no major military barracks at this point.
There is a clear distinction between the two sides of the city.
So we go from the noble district, often to the north of the river and the
artisan district, which borders the river itself, which feeds off of all the
trades that comes in and off of there.
And then further back, which is much more obscured and you can't quite see
into the forest, into the verboten forest, is more of a criminal syndicate
area, which Steve, in his time spent in Vintersmouth, has warned you to avoid,
if at least not for the first little while, while you get your feet
underneath you. Steve pulls into the shipping lanes, basically, and he's got
merchandise to offload and to sell you.
You hop down off of the carriage and Steve gives you a firm handshake and
says, well, I wish the best for you.
If you need anything, I'm here once a week.
Thanks, Steve. I hope to see you again soon and hope that your, you know,
merchanting goes well.
And maybe I'll ask you for some business advice.
Hopefully, hopefully I'll be merchanting myself soon enough.
So may our paths cross again.
Yeah, you got a good head on your shoulders, kid.
I hope so. Thanks, Steve.
He gets a call from the other side of the docks and pats you on the back.
As you start to walk away and you make your way into the crowded
streets of the artisan districts and the storefronts and the different
displays are all overflowing into the streets.
And the town is, well, it's not quite as busy as you're used to in
Kingstown, but it is considerably busier than you would expect for the
size of the city as it was described to you in many of your comings and
goings of people who have been further than you have.
You're walking through when you see smiles on everybody's faces.
There's kids running around with streamers and sparklers and one of them
bumps into you and says, oh, sorry, mister.
It's OK. Where did you get this?
Where did you get this sparkler?
Oh, there's a general store around the corner.
They sell some of these cool knickknacks.
Our friends really, really like them.
Do you mind if I see it real quick?
Oh, sure.
And he hands it up to you and it's fizzing down to the end.
I take it and I wrap my hand around it and whisper some soft words.
And I whisper Ignatius.
And it kind of flares back up, creating like these little
butterflies of fire that like float off of it.
And I hand it back to him as they just kind of whisper round.
Wow. Oh, come look at this.
And a few more kids run over and they say, he just he just did.
He turned it into butterflies.
Thanks, mister.
And they all run off and you see the butterflies
floating away as they run off into the distance.
I continue my way down the streets and kind of rub my temple slightly.
And my eye winces as I walk away.
You're at a fork in the road and off to one side,
you hear the cacophony of blacksmith and farriers and the carpenters
and the metal workers and you hear coming from a district
known as the hot block, hot block.
But as you're starting to walk down there to see what you can see,
you turn and you look down Charles Street
and down at the end, your eye is caught by this very small storefront,
which doesn't even look like it's been occupied for quite some time.
You make your way down there
and it's sandwiched between two very busy shops, one a hair salon,
the snip and twirl, and another looks like a tailor
with many people coming out who are now in freshly adorned clothes.
It's called the threads of fate.
And as much as there is happening on either side of them,
this unoccupied little plot of land is calling to you.
Kind of look it over.
Notice the awning out front of it is a little like off kilter.
Maybe the wood is rotted away slightly.
The metal joist that is holding it together has rusted and rotted away as well.
The shingles are half missing.
There's a broken window.
And I look at it and I say,
I must have her.
She will be mine.
This is my place.
No other will be it.
Who do I talk to?
One of the business owners.
Certainly, this place wouldn't cost too much.
And I look at my clothes covered in road dirt
and then catch my reflection in the in the remaining glass of the window,
seeing my very messy tangle of hair.
And I say, I don't feel comfortable walking into either of those places.
But if we are going to sell, the first thing we must sell is ourself.
We're worth it.
Mom believes in us.
We should believe in us.
And I flip a coin
and I turn to the snip and twirl and walk in.
And as you walk in, the scene of this small shop fades
and it fades into a storefront that is equally bustling
as the snip and twirl and the threads of fate.
And a sign hangs above the storefront door
as children and their parents are rushing in and out of the door.
What does the sign look like and say?
The sign says the magic closet
and the imagery on it is literally a child's room.
That's actually my room.
And inside, you can see next to the bed,
there is an open door leading into a closet with not clothes,
but a sparkler with flaming butterflies coming off of it,
dancing around.
And as it blows in the wind, hangs there, kind of moves,
it almost gives the essence of the butterflies dancing around.
And a child sitting in this closet below them, eyes in wonder.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons,
a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast.
I'm your dungeon master, Russ More, he, him,
and Dumbgeons and Dragons stars today,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard.
I don't like to say anything is impossible, so we'll see.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production
and we make a whole bunch of different shows.
You should check out Facing Fate, where we play a bunch of different games.
It's all improvised still and is a lot of fun.
Go check that out.
But then join us over on Patreon, where you can help us
build the world we're creating here, as well as listen
to a whole slew of other bonus content.
It's a whole other show over there.
All right. Fuck it. Let's play.
The Magic Closet's been open for a good year,
and it's been a prosperous year.
Your skills and your joy for life and fun and happiness
has spread throughout the city.
And you are a frequent stop by not only many of the children in town,
but just about everybody has been there at least once.
But many come on regular occasions for the latest
knickknacks and small magical toys and artifacts
that can bring their party and their day to life
and just bring a smile to them.
Yes, yes. The Arcane Accoutrement.
It is an incredibly busy day for you.
Things have been cleared off the shelves.
You're down to the last few little pieces.
And it's just about closing time as you see the final customers out the door.
And as you go to shut and lock it, there's a hand that comes
and pushes on the door as if trying to enter and says,
excuse me, pardon me.
Oh, sorry, I did not mean to catch your hand in the door.
Please, please come on in.
I have I have a few more minutes.
And of course, I'm not going to be going anywhere else after this.
I was just going to be heading up for a nice cup of tea.
So please, please come into the magic closet.
How can I help you today?
Entering is the sheriff of Vintersmouth.
He's dressed in the finest garb.
He has gold plated armor and he's followed by two burly guardsmen.
He has a giant handlebar mustache
and a small soul patch that extends down his chin.
And his hair is completely slicked back.
And he is holding underneath his arm a well
sculpted helmet.
He says, you're relatively new in town.
Well, the new mayor, Nigel Knobs,
he's putting in some new taxation forms.
Not sure if you've heard of them.
They were released at the latest Business Association meeting, but
wanted to make sure that you had those ready, as today is due day.
He kind of rolls up his sleeves as if as he and the other two men
are pushing their way a little further into your store.
Oh, well, I actually I business has been rather good.
And yes, I've only been here a little over a year now at this point.
But Vintersmouth has been very kind, very welcoming.
Feels very much like a second home already.
So I certainly wouldn't want to take away from the prosperity of the city.
And unfortunately, due to my business, I was not able to make the business meeting.
But that is well within your right
as a as a governmental entity to impose taxes
upon the businesses that do businesses within them.
I only ask, well, two things first.
That is a dapper cut you have and quite a
I wish I could grow a nice
mustache and beard like you have there.
Did you happen to stop at the snip and twirl earlier to get a touch up?
Because it absolutely looks fantastic.
Very suiting, very, very kind of you to say.
And Sheriff Celador.
Oh, Sheriff Celador.
Of course, heard the name.
I think it's probably a good thing.
I have not had the pleasure to meet you.
I feel like most would probably be on the wrong side of meeting you. Yes.
Yes, yes.
Now, most of the people who meet me end up on the blocks, unfortunately.
And we don't want that to happen to you now, do we?
Oh, most certainly not. Most certainly not.
But I would ask a second thing,
and that would be an opportunity to have an audience with the mayor.
I would love to be able to discuss an arrangement
because I understand that not many do what I do in this city.
And in fact, when I say not many, I mean no one.
No one can.
Yeah, there's a certain niche that you've managed to fill and fill quite well.
Perhaps an agreement between me and Mayor Knapps could be reached to where
I provide certain services in lieu of being taxed.
This would be his decision.
I don't expect you to speak for him.
It would be very preposterous to expect you to be able to give me
an answer right now.
So if you would if you would grant me
that window of time to meet with the mayor,
I will arrive to the meeting, taxation in hand.
And I only hope that I'm able to leave with it in hand
and an accord struck between the two parties.
Would this be something you could grant or would you have to return
to the mayor to get approval?
Oh, we can make an arrangement.
I don't know about leaving with it in hand,
but if you think you can sweet talk the mayor,
unlike anybody else before you, absolutely, absolutely.
He's, well, he's taking advantage of his first term here.
He's trying to make a good impression on the city.
And part of that is not bending to too many people.
If you know what I mean.
Oh, absolutely.
My my father was a businessman in Kingstown
and paying taxes was a normal part of business,
something that I helped him out with regularly.
So I understand the necessity for a leader to be unbending, as you put it.
Now, one thing I do know is
I've seen about every face in this town,
whether they be on the good side of the law or the bad side of the law.
I've met and talked with a lot of people
in the little bit of time I've been here.
So a point of communication that reaches far and wide is
certainly beneficial for somebody in power to learn things from.
And that doesn't even account for
the magical abilities that I can provide.
You see, my magic comes at a price.
It is not just done on a whim.
And if their quest is made and I owe a favor to the mayor,
then I suffer the cost.
Of course, these wrinkles here, you think they're laugh lines.
No, they are payment.
No, they make me look dapper, yes.
But they're not supposed to be there quite yet.
This is the price I pay.
You bring the tax payments and we'll see about what arrangement you have for the mayor.
I really appreciate the the Wiggle Room, Sheriff Celador, and
it was a fantastic first meeting.
I'm sure we will have plenty of future meetings.
If I have my way and they will all be.
I think we'll make better friends than you think we will.
And if you are ever having a party, please, please, please come see me.
I have some things that would absolutely dazzle your guests.
I would love to show them to you.
But as you can see, these shelves are quite bare from today's work.
That being said, if you'd like to purchase,
I have some little poppers you throw them on the ground.
They pop, make a loud thing.
You know, if if you're looking for something for do you have kids?
I do. Two of them.
Well, if you want something to entertain your children.
Wait, what are the names?
I may have met them before.
Jason Testa. Jason Testa.
OK, well, I know that they have not gotten these yet.
So you bring these home and I reach down and I grab a little box
and I put them in his hand and say, you bring these home.
They will be marveled.
You will. You will be the cool dad.
He looks down at them and shrugs and says,
if you say so, slips them into his pocket and says, tomorrow
three o'clock tomorrow, three o'clock.
I'll make sure doors are closed and the coffers are packed
in case things don't go the way I hope they do.
Because, again, no need for me to be on the wrong side of the law here.
I've enjoyed my time in Vintersmouth.
You all have created a fantastic town.
All right, guys, next house.
And they open the door and without turning back, he calls tomorrow.
Don't be late.
Wouldn't dream of it. Have a great day. Ta ta.
It's the middle.
Welcome to the middle, everybody.
How are you doing?
Thanks for being here.
Hopefully you're having just the most wonderful time.
We we that's that's what I'm putting out into the universe.
How about having the most wonderful time?
Yeah, absolutely.
I'm hanging out with all my friends here.
Oh, hey, class, it's how's it going?
It's a great time to be here.
I'm never going anywhere else.
Never going anywhere else.
I mean, I want him back as long as you never get off the call.
I'm just always here.
And you all just happen to join on.
Just keeps the room alive.
Yeah, we change rooms every single time, too.
But he's got to have like lots open, always go.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
Really loving getting to know
Bizard the Wizard more, which Tom, you when you came onto the call,
you gave an interesting interpretation of that name.
Yes, I went with a bizarre, bizarre, bizarre.
I mean, but weren't you part of the original conversation?
Yes. Oh, absolutely.
OK, but I rolled in and I was like, I like the sound of that today.
Is also the one who refuses to pronounce Flamikins.
Truth? No, you know what you're referring to us.
Tom will just make a small decision.
Just roll with it forever. Forever.
Amy's not here right now, but maybe she'll roll in later like the last one.
Who knows? We'll see how that goes.
But what we want to tell you is next month
helmed by our regular cast member, Kyle Claset, is we will begin
our cyberpunk red sessions with our session zero,
where we come up with characters and life paths and all that sort of cool stuff.
And it's very exciting.
Heck, yes, it was so fun.
I'm so excited for everyone to hear it.
And I'm so excited to start playing. Oh, my God.
Yeah, I'm so stoked after doing the life path and you like go through.
And it's so comprehensive. It's so great.
They're like really molding who we are before anything happens.
And I'm really excited.
There's like some animation I need to watch.
There's some books I need to read.
The end of the the Netflix series,
Edgerunners, Edgerunners, the first episode, watched it.
It's such a scary world.
I didn't like I knew, but I didn't know.
Yes, it can be very, very dark, very bleak.
But that's OK.
We can bring some levity to it and still have a lot of fun.
And that's exactly what we're going to do.
So when you sign up on Patreon, Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
you get a seven day free trial, which is great.
Come in, dip your toes, test the waters.
And then you'll be like, you know, of course, I'm staying like like Kyle does.
And also, when you're a patron for three months, we ship you merch.
So it's either a sticker at the five dollar tier.
Oh, shit, I forgot a mug.
Yeah, a mug at the sporting producers tier and a sweet,
pristine white hoodie at the game time tier,
which I've gotten a little bit of flack for.
Everybody's just saying that they're trash goblets and it looks great.
It does. Right.
I personally will never wear a white shirt, because if I do,
it's like, why am I eating curry today?
Yeah, why was today the day I went over that turmeric curry?
Of course, 100 percent.
It's like, I haven't worn the shirt in months.
Why did I do this? Yeah.
Yeah. I got to say the combo of getting a mug,
which you usually hold coffee or tea and then a white hoodie.
It's also dangerous. Great point.
Damn straight. You're just up in the game.
So Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
We hope to see you over there.
We're going to have a lot of fun with cyberpunk.
We'll drop some teasers and stuff in the main feed
just to wet your palate and stuff and make you feel like you're missing out.
Because that's what we like to do sometimes.
Unless you're not missing out because you are a patron.
And if you are a patron, you get an episode dedicated to you.
Oh, shit.
What a call out to Russ to say,
you don't have a name.
Stalled for time, but that that that that that that.
Oh, I can't. Oh, no.
Come on, Russ.
Look, I got to go into like select menus
to make sure that I'm pulling from.
I mean, I'm not sorry. I'm glad I remembered.
You did. Oh, I'm sorry. You did.
I'm pretty glad, though, because it's not often we get to like.
Getcha on Russ. Yeah.
100 percent. Yeah, like today's patron,
Isaiah Yarbrough.
Oh, thanks, Isaiah.
Thanks, Isaiah.
Do you think that's like a rock star person?
So you think that sounds like a British rocker?
Oh, I was going to say like British naval officer.
Oh, that's got to be a slash rocker.
Cool secret identity. Either or. Yeah.
Yeah. Rocking the seven seas.
That's right. Thanks, Isaiah.
Join us today.
Patreon dot com slash dumb dragon cast, just like Isaiah.
And you'll get a mug that you can drink hot coffee in a white
white sweater in.
That's the sell.
All right. Thanks, everybody.
Back to the episode. Bye now. Bye. Bye.
We flash forward some 12 years
and the streets of Venturesmith are empty as we move through the Artisan
District and over the bridge towards the noble side of town,
where everyone has gathered to hear the latest and greatest
buzzworthy speech from Mayor Knapp's.
Taxation has gone up yet again, and the mayor has just finished his speech,
which ended in the press grilling him on questions of
what is to come of all of these tax increases.
Where do they go?
When everyone looks around and can clearly see that the
noble region of Venturesmith is quite prosperous,
with its practically gold laden streets and giant monumental statues
of the mayor throughout the noble town square leading up to City Hall
with its glorious fountains.
And as these bombardments of boos and heckles come from the crowd,
Mayor Knapp's is rushed away by his closest few.
A short and slender woman with a well-groomed, black-haired bob cut.
She whisks him away and he is quickly wrapped up by some guard.
And we look and part of this group, along with a few administrators, is Bizard.
Nina, the woman is quickly rushing past you, Bizard,
and you hear her quickly saying, no, no, dear, no, no, it went very well.
They heckled because they love you, dear.
It will be totally fine.
Come on, Bizard, if we have to lighten his spirits, it'll be fine.
Everybody, everybody, come quick back to City Hall.
Absolutely. You only receive criticism because you are taking bold strokes.
People just can't see the vision that you have for the city.
They don't understand that these these taxes will trickle down
to their parts of the city.
It's just a matter of time for these things to happen.
And, you know, people aren't patient like they used to be.
Oh, no, they aren't patient like they used to be, are they?
No, all they want is more, more, more.
But they don't know how hard it is to run a city.
They don't. And you have to forgive them that.
That's not something that they have the wherewithal to understand.
You know, you having the experience you have me being from a large city
and understanding the ins and outs that it takes to run a business
in a in a city like Kingstown.
But, you know, this is one one of the reasons why you come to me
for this kind of advice, this kind of insight.
You know, you can trust me to be 100 percent honest with you.
If I thought you were doing something wrong by the people,
then I would say something.
Oh, well, yes, you've been 100 percent honest with me
since the first day we met.
You came in.
You told me how you were going to turn that artisan district around.
And oh, my golly, you sure have done that.
That's true. I haven't really haven't really convinced them.
That that everything is for the good, though.
Listen, we convince people through their mood
when people come through the artisan sector of town.
They stop by my shop.
I show them a good time.
I get them set up with wonderful magical trinkets
that bring a smile to their face.
The people they're smiling, they're happy.
That's that's one plus one. Mayor Knapp's.
Well, it would be nice to see more smiling faces in the crowd.
Think about it next time.
Maybe we need some of those sparkly bangers
that go off right as I'm coming out.
You know, big flames, big flames.
I think flames coming out would be good.
Agreed. Really establish power.
I mean, a good time, not power, not dominance.
Nina tells me that those are not those are the words I need to use.
Yes, no, I, you know, I understand what you were saying,
and I would love to arrange that for you.
If you could provide me a a small stipend
to be able to gather the resources together.
My my trusted traveling merchant, Steve,
would be able to procure some items from Kingstown
to bring to me from the college I attended there.
And how much would you be willing to provide?
I think I think a hundred gold.
I know it sounds like a lot.
A hundred gold could a hundred.
What could you do with a hundred gold?
Yes, darling, what could you do with a hundred gold?
That's a lot of money for one speech.
Well, see, the idea is that we the hundred gold would lay the bedrock.
We would be able to reuse some of the materials
in the grandiose nature of your presentation and speeches.
It would essentially pave the way for future ones.
We could reuse some of the vessels
that I would store the magic materials and components inside
for them to pop out of.
So the only expendable part, I'd probably say moving forward
after this stipend, we would merely need maybe
10, 10 gold per per speech.
Yes, 10 gold is better.
But yeah, OK, if you say that this will establish the bedrock.
That's what you said.
Establish the bedrock for moving foundations,
future moving foundations.
Yes, yes, yes.
Nina, see that he gets the money.
And as you are walking up the grandiose staircase
towards City Hall itself, he says, see that
see that he gets the money and no questions,
no questions from anybody else in the press.
And he storms inside City Hall.
Nina says, yes, yes, yes.
Come with me, Bizarre.
We will get you your money.
And she leads you back to her office
through the winding hallways and says, I am on to you
without looking at you as she slowly closes the door behind you
as you enter her office.
I'm not sure what you're talking about, Nina.
Well, Bizarre, you have been pulling the wool over the mayor's eyes
for quite some time.
There's something more to you and your offices, I think.
You're free to think that.
And if that's what you think initially,
I'm not even going to try to dissuade you of that line of thought
because that would put me on the defense.
And I have nothing to defend.
So play your game.
I'll continue living my life and serving Mayor Knapps
as I think is best, which I know you're going to do, too.
We're both here for Mayor Knapps.
You want to see what's best for him.
And you don't think I have his best interest at heart, but
you don't know my heart.
You don't know I'm here.
Not truly.
No, no, I don't know why you are here.
I know why lots of people are here, darling.
I'll figure you out.
I welcome the challenge.
I welcome you to try to figure me out.
The graduates from Bernhardt Swan School of Magic, Fighting and Dance
are not so easily classifiable.
Did you hear the three different sectors of education that they offer there?
It's really quite a plethora.
I could go into the history of it if you'd like me to.
Yes, yes, yes, darling.
No, don't worry about it.
I've heard about the Bernhardt Swan School of Magic, Fighting and Dance.
Don't worry.
Here's your big bag of money.
She throws down a large coin purse
that just echoes throughout her office and says, go get your goods.
There's another speech in two weeks.
I expect that to be much better than this far.
Night and day difference.
Night and day difference, Nina.
I promise you will even be impressed,
which I know is hard to do.
Well, she stares you down.
I don't like to say anything is impossible, so we'll see.
Have a good day, Nina.
And we'll be seeing each other soon, I'm sure.
Goodbye, Bizard.
Ta ta, Nina.
You quietly close the door behind you
and you head back down the staircase and over the bridge
towards the artisan district.
It's not how you remember, though.
Everybody is dispersed.
Everybody has gone home.
But there's not as much joy as the days that you first came here.
People are tired.
They're worn down.
Their businesses, even even you have noticed,
like you still manage to maintain a pretty steady business through,
you know, adventurers passing through and just the local kids
spending whatever coin they may have left on sparklers and fake vomit.
But it's a different place.
And as you come back to the magic closet and unlock the door,
you turn and you look out to the streets and nobody's rushing up right now.
Oh, this.
Mom, I feel what I do is wrong.
But I'm doing it for the right reasons.
I. I wish she would send me a letter back.
It's been longer than I care to admit.
Maybe Steve will check on her for me.
I begin to gather some of the coin as I enter in
and kind of separate it out into smaller,
smaller, you know, purses and whatnot.
Five, ten here.
And I begin to make my way around to the other businesses
and walk in very chummy.
Of course, go into the snip and twirl first and
go up to the cashier and say,
I need to speak with your proprietor.
Elanger, will you go get Syndra for me, please?
Oh, yeah, yeah, of course, Bizard.
And she goes and runs quick.
And after a moment, Syndra comes out and this overwhelming
smell of lilacs perfume that Syndra is well known for in the town
just burst through the back door and says, Bizard, Bizard,
what can I do for you?
Syndra, it's finally come back around.
I've managed to take care of some things that we had talked about before.
I know, I know what's happened
to the businesses here,
and I understand the appearance of my involvement in it.
And I want you to know.
It's not as it seems.
You're not in the back pocket of the mayor.
Oh, I know. I mean, I am absolutely 100 percent,
but it is not for the reasons you may think.
And I want to show that to you,
who showed me kindness upon arriving to town, who got me set up,
took my tussled mop of hair and managed to do something
that was sellable amongst the people here.
And same with Elvira over at the threads of fate,
getting me set up with new clothes that definitely had more of an appeal
than the mud strewn olive green
and burlap brown that I was wearing when I arrived that day too.
I don't like to look back on those times.
My clothes were absolute trash.
That being said, I've kept a book and I want you to reach out to.
I know it's hard doing deals with Kenny.
I know we don't necessarily like it.
It's seedy. But I feel like Kenny would at least understand
keeping morale in the city and keeping money in the hands of people
that could use it towards his benefit more than the mayor.
Right. I feel like money flowing in his direction is better used and better
better received by the town.
So I've kept this book.
I want you to work with me to return some of the taxes
that have been taking from businesses so that they can improve their situation.
This isn't going to solve the problem.
I know it's not.
No, no. But hopefully it's a step in the right direction.
After you close today, come by my shop.
We'll get things figured out, lay out the details
and make sure that we can remain as subtle about this as possible.
Make a persuasion roll.
Ooh.
With advantage because of the rousing history between you two.
OK, 15.
OK, Bizard, I'll come.
Only if you're comfortable.
I don't want you to feel like you're putting yourself in danger.
I don't ask that of you. No, no.
And as far as I'm concerned, I haven't talked to you today.
Talk to who? Hmm.
I'll come after.
We'll talk about your plans and we'll see what we can do.
Getting Kinney involved is a even for the right reasons.
It's risky. It's a dangerous thing.
You know that. Right.
But Kinney is the one person that Knops won't won't mess with.
We know this. You're right.
And OK. Yeah.
Do we want the witch or the devil?
That is the question.
Let's hope we answer it correctly.
She looks down and Landra, who was previously in the back,
comes back up front and says, Well, you look like a mess.
Why don't you come back?
I'll give you a snip.
Close up for the day and we can have that conversation.
That's too kind of you, too kind of you.
Yeah, just a little off the top and give it a nice quaff.
And I think I'll be right as rain to deal my wares another day.
She takes you by the hand and leads you into the back room
to get your haircut as we fade out on this scene.
Dumbgeons and Dragons Season 3 Episode 11.
This episode starred Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Also, Amy, Tom and Carla were hanging out in the middle there.
Dialogue editing by Carla Maxted and sound design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and sound effects
from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garbutt.
A huge thank you to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Cat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown, Craig Zeiss, Barry Mady,
Ongarong Kiersen, Old School Gamer D, L.A.
Branton, Nathaniel Teeter, Luna and Aaron.
And a huge thank you from Twiglets for the name
Rinkip Celador or Sheriff Celador.
We may be hearing from more in the future,
but the sheriff of past Vintersmouth as well as Cat Waterflame,
who gave us the name Syndra, smells of lilacs for no discernible reason.
It's just something that goes along with her.
Come on now, keep up.
I think that was all we covered a lot in these two episodes with Kyle.
And we look forward to covering even more.
If you want to help us build the world, you can join us at
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast where there's just there's a form
right there at the top.
You give us your thoughts.
And it's a great time because then we put we put your names
and your your shops and all that sort of stuff into the world.
The Vintersmouth that we're building.
Ah, I can't wait for the next episode.
We might get to meet all four characters in one place.
It's going to be a great time.
What can you do while you're waiting for the next episode?
Well, aside from joining Patreon is you can join our newsletter.
There's a link down in the description to a to a link tree
and it'll take you right there.
Well, I'll take you to a link that'll take you right there.
The world is built in links.
OK, you know how the Internet works or you can go to dumbdragons.com
and on the contact page, we've got to sign up for it there.
That's it, though.
Hopefully you're having a great week.
I know we are because you're here listening to us.
So you continue to have a wonderful week
and we'll talk to you very, very soon. Bye for now.
I'll get you your meeting with the mayor.
You bring tax, you bring tax, you bring tax, you bring tax.
Me sheriff. You're me sheriff.
You bring tax.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production.