Welcome, Dumbgeons and Dragons, we'll start in just a second.
Bonwyn and Thane are quickly followed by Dace into Everbane's.
How big were the scratches again?
Oh, we'll show you.
Big.
Like, big.
Okay, show me, show me what you got.
Okay first of all, don't freak out.
There's an intricate series of tunnels under the city.
You're not freaking out.
Do you know about this already?
Well, no.
Well, we had it.
We had thoughts.
Rumors.
Yeah.
No, it's not.
It's just like you're throwing like there's scratches on a door that is in your place,
but it's an under the ground place.
That's also tunnels under the city and like just underneath all over.
And I'm just trying to deal with it one second of time.
So yeah, just processing more than anything.
Makes sense.
If you want to help Thane and I and you see that not only is there the table and
the anvil, there's like a few other things piled on top.
So we're going to need to move all of this.
Okay, Thane will begin moving things off the desk and there you go, right?
So did you see anything down there?
Should I?
He pulls out his sword.
He starts to unsheathe it.
Like should I just?
Maybe.
Okay.
Cool.
I mean, I'd rather you did and we didn't need it than we all like get eaten by
a mutant bear or whatever.
Bear.
Well, I don't know.
They're big.
They're big scratches.
You'll see.
You only live once is what the kids have been saying on the street.
So let's let's do it.
Here we go.
And I lift up the trap door and like with a quick swing, the sword comes down into the
hole and there's nothing there.
Well, but if there had been, you would have got it.
I would have got it.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast and I'm your dungeon
master Russ More, he him.
Also with me today is Amy More as Alydin, she her.
Her brow is furrowed and her face is red and nothing happens.
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane, she her.
I don't think it could have gotten here subterraneanly by a tunnel.
And Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard, he him.
You are, you know, controlling the weave in a way, but really you are dancing
with it.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast where you can get a seven day
free trial if you sign up today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Now fuck it, let's play.
So the three of you are standing over the door, Dace is processing what he's looking
at on the underside and so holding up his his gloved hands to the size of the scratches
and I mean, I see, I see.
Yeah.
Um, I have some other information as you're talking, he's closing the door slowly down
to the ground.
Yeah.
And we're all working together to move everything back to push the thing doesn't have to
talk about it.
You're just that's the next step.
OK, so a little while ago went on an adventure with Ignatius.
Right?
Yes.
Yeah.
Heard it went well.
Oh, well, I mean, you definitely heard.
Yeah.
I've seen Charis.
I know Charis is OK.
He puts quotation marks.
Yes.
Yeah.
So while we were on that adventure, there actually was a little bit of danger.
OK.
Ignatius didn't experience any of it.
So it didn't like make the rounds via, you know, town crier posters being hammered
up or anything.
But we found an old mine.
Went down an old mine shaft.
Great.
Sounds good.
Definitely had a close escape with some kind of creature that was trying to get
us.
Mm hmm.
That had big claws.
So OK.
So you went.
I mean, we couldn't be.
And you woke up something.
Well, we don't know that it was sleeping days.
It could have just.
It could have just been awake and like blissfully ignorant to our position.
I'm not blaming you.
I'm.
I mean, if you blame anyone, blame Ignatius.
He is the one that took us there.
Don't worry.
Next time Ignatius puts up flyers, I'm taking them all down and nobody will show
up and Ignatius will wander off and maybe just not come back, not come back.
Well, come on.
Come on, Daisy.
You don't want him to leave.
No.
Then the quivering hills will close.
Yeah.
You know, you're right.
You're right.
OK.
So.
So I'm just saying that could be what the creature is.
Just an idea.
It was sort of some sort of subterranean clawed creature.
You went into the Mii Mountains, though, right?
So that's.
Yeah.
Others.
It's quite far.
Other side of the river.
Yeah.
I don't know these tunnels very well, so I don't know if they do go under
the river because the city started on this side and then was expanded once royalty started
to get in.
I mean, I don't think it could have gotten here subterraneanly by a tunnel.
Not that way, anyways.
Interesting.
Yeah.
So it was just a thought.
Yeah, I know.
I appreciate it.
Just, you know, throwing ideas out there.
I've had bear.
It's an underground bear.
Of course.
Wild bear.
Yeah, that makes sense.
And then there's this thing and this creature that chases you out of an old mine shaft
that was that was sealed, that was closed, that was that was abandoned.
Yeah.
OK.
So if you just want to take that back to take it, you know, you're going to
process it.
It's more activity today than I usually see in a month.
Yeah.
I'm going to ask around some of the people, see if there's been lots of people hearing
things.
See if there's any similarities.
Because people have been hearing things, right?
That's what things are.
Yeah.
I see if they have these doors.
Maybe that's what it is.
Trying to find a way.
Because they probably don't know, right?
Like, I didn't know.
Not many people do.
There's only a few people left around who even knew that they could exist.
OK.
Anything else you need to report?
Just the...
Nothing else to report.
But I wonder if you could just come into my office for a second, because I just want
to show you something.
OK.
Unrelated to a creature.
Sure.
It's not a scary thing.
I just feel like I should preface it, because I've given you a lot of information
and none of it has been good so far.
That's all good.
OK.
You show me something in your office.
Follows you?
Yes.
There's a door behind me, because I just want some privacy from Thane.
And then I go to my desk and pull out a little leather sack.
You know the ones.
There's money in it.
It's like the...
The coin bag.
The fantasy equivalent of a big bag with a dollar sign on it.
So you know Charis?
Yeah, of course.
Alydin.
Yes.
Yeah.
So what if you didn't?
What if you just didn't know who that was?
Didn't know who her friends were?
Just maybe left them alone.
Like just totally left them alone.
He looks at you and he has a very puzzled look on his face.
Those kids have enough problems, Dees.
Like we've got real issues here.
Like real issues.
Not even talking about whatever this murder creature is.
We've got corruption.
We've got criminals.
We have a lot of problems that aren't just kids trying to live.
Yeah.
No.
You're a good person.
I know you are.
So free Charis is what I'm saying, I guess.
Great.
Spread the word.
I could do that.
Great.
Cool.
Oh, also check out this thing I made.
And you look over and I pull a switch or like a little lever and wings basically
open up.
They're on a stand and are like...
And it's all knives.
What are you...
Special order?
I mean, what are they even...
They can't even walk wearing it.
What are they going to do with it?
But it looks amazing, right?
It does look pretty cool.
And they're sharp.
So don't touch it.
You see as he reaches his hand out and pulls it back.
Okay.
Someone's going to hurt themselves, but they're going to look stunning.
Great.
Yeah.
That's amazing.
You're making some cool stuff here.
I really like it.
We do like our next round of like armor upgrades.
Put in a good word.
Yeah.
I could definitely get you an improvement on that bad boy.
And I pointed his sword that he had pulled out earlier that was like, you know, it's
fine.
It's serviceable.
But...
He looks down at it and nods knowingly and says, well, I'm going to go, like
I said, ask around, do a little canvassing on the sounds and see if there's a pattern.
If you need help.
Of course, of course.
Maybe not with the canvassing, because I have to work on my, you know, murder cape.
But...
Thank you.
I'm going to go get some more information to see if anybody's heard anything continually.
If there's any stories, rumors of something that might fit the story that you told
about your adventure with Ignatius.
I'll come back and let you know what I've what I found out and see if there's anywhere
that you can help.
I go and I kind of open the door and we're like making our way out.
OK.
If anybody says goblins, this definitely wasn't goblins.
OK, bye!
As he's out and you like close the door behind him, he's again like a dumbstruck
face.
At least you didn't say pirates.
And then walks down the street and I don't know how hard you forced that that coin
on him.
But you look back down in your head and he didn't take it from you.
Well, that's good.
I feel better now knowing that I at least have someone in authority saying like,
I'm not bugging the kids.
Also I tried to give away some of my money, no takers.
So now let's see what kind of trouble I can get into with it.
We'll be right back.
It's the middle.
OK.
Filters.
I feel like what is talking right now because right now I'm trying to run.
He's doing it.
Welcome to the middle.
Oh, hey.
Oh, shit.
It's happening.
OK, here we are.
I panicked.
I didn't.
I forgot how to start.
I think that is how we start a middle.
We just yell.
It's the middle.
Just scream.
Almost at the end, I was going to say of season one, but of season three,
but season one with these characters.
Campaign two of season one.
Chapter.
Yeah, chapter go in there somewhere.
Yeah, only 25 episodes this season.
Big finale coming up.
And some people are just outraged.
The Discord is going off the chain.
Off the...
It's palpable.
Yeah, well, there's riots in the street.
They're all lovely.
No.
But because we are taking a little break, those are big air quotes that I was putting
up there.
I think you could hear them because we're still going to, we're not just like going
to disappear.
No.
Can't do a 25 episode season like normal people and then just be like, we're taking
some time off.
They'll still be like a little something.
I don't know what I'm allowed to say.
So that's all I'm saying.
Say whatever you want.
I think a little something is pretty good.
We haven't actually recorded the little something, so we can say literally whatever we want and
we don't know if it's true.
True.
It's possible the little something could turn into a big something if we're not
careful.
Oh, that's very likely.
We do sometimes tend to get carried away.
What will happen is there will still continue to be mini episodes, little tiny bite
size episodes.
If Kyle's premonition holds true, they could be normal sized episodes by accident.
Probably somewhere in the middle would be my guess.
Normal episodes.
We can't guarantee.
They'll be around the third or the fourth as we are just getting into a stride and
then forget that we have to end it.
But yeah, little short teaser episodes, maybe get to know some of the NPCs around
the city and just build up the world a little bit over the summer and then we'll
be back.
It's not that the season finale, so we're not ending the characters like we have done
in season one and season two where we start with new characters.
This is going to be a continuation some more.
I think as Amy said before, we started recording chapters in this new campaign and we're
very excited about it.
If you would like to continue to get full size episodes where we can guarantee that
they're full size episodes, you can come join us over on Patreon, Patreon.com slash
where we have two, I promise I'm going to release cyberpunk red.
I promise I'm going to do two full exclusive podcasts over there.
The Adventures of and cyberpunk red, which come out monthly.
So those can be there for you.
And when you are a patron, you also get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Yannick Andreas.
Yannick.
Thank you.
Awesome.
Andreas.
I love that.
I have a thing for names.
Well, especially strong, powerful, strong, powerful names.
Yes.
Absolutely.
Commanding.
Just like Yannick.
Yannick's the boss.
We command you.
Or Yannick commands you to go to Patreon.
I don't want to put words in there.
Yannick compels you.
Everybody, everybody asks really nicely in a very Canadian way.
Go to Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast day if you want and maybe you don't have
to.
It's OK.
Let's just continue being here making funnies.
OK.
Have a great week.
We'll talk to you soon.
Bye.
Love you.
We hear their hushed conversation as we weave our way through the magic closet
through a back door and enter this secondary workspace.
Kyle, if you could describe this space of Bizards, which we haven't really seen
yet.
Yeah.
The front of the store is very well tended to, well taken care of.
And as you open the back door, it's just pushing through boxes and then just kind
of like organized chaos is how Bizards sees it.
But it is obviously just a mess of different ideas, different projects.
Like each surface has like obviously a little like semi circle of just junk around like
a single project.
He's got like about like three or four different little work spots that are kind of like that
and then just boxes kind of overflowing, a little stacked up unevenly on different
shelves and everything.
They're labeled at least, whether the items in there are right or not, I mean,
Bizard knows at least.
So that's what's important.
Excellent.
This is where we find Alydin and Bizard and you are seated at one of these
cleared away spaces.
The two of you each have a sandwich that you're unwrapping, having had a long day and
just getting a little energy before you dive into today's more extended lesson.
Thank you for going out and getting these sandwiches, Alydin.
I appreciate it.
They look delicious.
Oh, yeah, no, they are really, really good.
So, so what are you going to teach me?
Oh, well, I kind of wanted to show you something I've been working on.
Of course, most of my items that I sell upfront, they're fun, gags, pranks, little
things like that, that I attribute to being magic.
But I've got this new one that I've been working on.
It looks like a normal quill and I kind of go over to my desk and just kind
of like clear out space a little bit so you can come up and stand next to me.
So you see, I've taken this quill here and I've hollowed out the pin of it.
And right here, I've got a little coil, a very small coil of copper around an iron
rod.
I see it.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to take these two little metal plates
here, very tiny, and I'm going to attach them to those coils and then kind of lacquer
over a little bit so that you can still make contact with them, but they're hard
to see.
And he kind of finishes this up.
It's a little bit of a rush, but it's like, I tell you what, grab that and try to use
it as a quill.
Like to write something?
Yeah, yeah.
Write down a note.
Jot down something.
Here's a piece of paper.
Okay.
Jot down your name.
And she spells out Alydin very, like she doesn't get the opportunity to write
a whole lot, so it's just not a top priority for her at the moment.
So it is all in capital letters and a bit shaky, but that's what she's working on.
He kind of grabs it, he says, well, shit, that's not how it's supposed to be.
And he grabs it and there's a zap.
That's what was supposed to happen.
Well, that's obviously a rush job.
So you were going to electrocute me?
It's just a little zap.
It's just a little playful.
I'm a child.
Oh, it's a little prank.
It's nothing.
Nothing harmful.
But listen, you told me, here's how you set it up.
That was really mean, because you said that out in the front is all jokey stuff.
And then I thought you were going to show me something really cool that you're working
on that no one's ever seen before.
And it's just another prank?
No, you are.
So okay, tell me about the things that you have accidentally magicked.
I've seen the coins the other day, saw that.
What other examples?
You asked me earlier, how do I know if I'm evoking the weave on purpose or not?
What else have you done by accident?
Well, I don't know, like, let's say I'm running from somebody and then I hide.
I know it's not the best hiding.
I know the best hiding spots.
And it wasn't that.
And I should have gotten caught, but they ran right past me.
And I swear, like, it was the worst hiding spot.
Okay, I'm trying to draw a connection for how you may be doing this.
Let's go back to the coins.
You were interacting with the coins.
You had a certain emotion.
How do you know that you are evoking the weave on purpose?
When I first started, I had to focus on, it definitely comes from, this is an obvious
answer, but it comes from a place of purpose and intention put behind it.
But being able to make something sympathetic to the request that you're making, it's
kind of like a surrendering in a way.
Like, yes, you are, you are, you know, controlling the weave in a way, but really you are dancing
with it and you have to, you have to accept it as much as it accepts you.
So I feel like when we were talking earlier about the coins, you said you felt happy
because it gave you a sense of security and safety.
I want you to try that again.
I want you to think about that sense of security.
But I don't want you to use money.
I want you to, fuck, what do I got here, just, I tell you what, here, here's a piece
of tin, just a little tin foil, nothing big, focus on it.
Think about that sense that you get from money and see if, let's see if we can get
something out of here.
A hundred percent thought you were going to just hand me that pin again.
I was going to say no sir.
Okay, so Alydin takes the little tin foil and she's looking at it, squinting her
eyes, focusing really hard and her brow is furrowed and her face is red and nothing happens.
I think this one is broken.
Well maybe I'll have to do more research to figure out a way that we can find out
how you're doing this.
That being said, I haven't gotten the opportunity to pay you for your help.
I know we've said lessons are going to be part of this, but I do want to make sure
that you're taken care of otherwise and your help is keeping me in stock at the store,
so it's allowing me to take care of other things around here and there.
So here, and I hand over a silver.
There's your pay so far.
Well, I thank you.
Go on, take it.
It's yours.
Do with it what you will.
She gingerly takes it from his hand.
They share an awkward stare as she slowly brings her hand over and drops it in the
bucket with a clink.
It's as bizarre as, Alydin takes it, and I think I see where you're going with this.
Nothing happens as you two are awkwardly staring at each other, but as Alydin's
hand moves away and their face softens a little bit, you see the coin light up again
the same way you saw a couple days previous, and as it drops into the bucket there's
an emanating glow that comes up and out and then fades away after a few seconds.
Am I seeing this too?
Just my.
Are you are you focused?
Because I know I'm focused on tossing things.
That's exactly it.
Like I'm like it's I'm not even using my periphery because I'm like,
is it a trap that's like like, OK,
I'm taking it right now.
It's going in the bucket.
So I probably am not yours looking like over my head.
What's your passive perception?
Ten. I'm going to say you're more much more focused on bizarre.
And he's going to play another trick on you or something like that.
Zap your whoopee cushion or something like something's going to happen
that you're not expecting.
And you're just tossing it in as you would anything else that you find.
So, yeah, you don't really even if you do see a little bit of a glow,
you don't pay attention to.
Also, I think I'm kind of like it's been happening forever.
So sometimes there's a little glow somewhere.
I take note of this.
I say, OK, actually, Alydin, I'm so sorry I was mistaken.
I gave you the wrong amount of money.
It's supposed to be too silver.
And I take a silver myself and I put it in the bucket
and I look for the same reaction.
You are placing the money in.
I'm not handing it to her.
OK, yeah, you place it in the bucket.
It clinks in the bottom.
There's no illumination that just happened.
Thank you.
Oh, so the same same sort of feeling, same sort of result
from receiving the first bit of money and then the second bit.
Like I am not sure this is really happening for real.
But I'm very, very grateful for your tutelage.
And so first, are you usually touching something
whenever this magic happens to something?
Are you in contact?
I mean, with some form of item,
like, technically, aren't we always touching something?
But yes, true.
Your logic is not is not unsound.
But yeah, every time that I've noticed it happening, I mean,
Tally has told me a couple of times
because like I don't like sometimes I don't really see it.
But yes, I have. Yes.
OK, that gives me a direction to head.
I think I know how we can help you figure this out.
However, I will have to see if I can have some books
brought in from Kingstown, because otherwise I would be guessing.
But I feel like whenever you come into contact with something
and that's that that is it has to happen like me.
I know that a spell that causes something to light up
like the coins I've seen, it does not necessarily involve touch.
Like people can light things up without touching them.
Well, that sounds not so much the case.
It is. It is a little convenient.
But I am betting
right off the bat that you might have to make contact with those things
if my assumptions are correct.
Well, OK, I'm excited.
Good. Well, speaking of making contact with things,
I'm going to make contact with this sandwich and my mouth
because I am hungry and it's been a long business day so far.
Dumbgeons and Dragons, season three, episode 23,
starring Amy More as Alydin, Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everpain,
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave, Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard
and Russ More as your Dungeon Master.
Dialogue Editing by Carla Maxted and Sound Design by Russ More.
This episode featured music from Epidemic Sound and Slipstream.
And sound effects from Epidemic Sound, Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garbutt.
And a huge thank you to our supporting producers.
Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Kat Waterflame, Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown, Angaron Kierzen, Perry Matey, Craig Zeiss,
Old School Gamer D, L.A.
Branton, Nathaniel Teeter and Sarah Murphy.
Join us today at Patreon.com slash dumb dragging cast.
You'll get a seven day free trial and access to The Adventures Of,
which we're just starting the new season of The Adventures Of,
where Kyle's going to be on that show.
So it's the first time that he'll be in with Opal, Elia and Night Hunter.
If you don't know who Opal and Elia and Night Hunter are,
well, just come join us and take a look.
Join for a week and then realize that holy crowly,
you need to be over there.
Again, that's Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
We hope to see you over there. All right.
You have a great week. We'll talk to you soon. Bye now.
There was nothing there.
Well, but if there had been, you would have got it.
I would have got it first. Yeah.
RIP, Alydin. Yep.
Doctor.
Like Jesus just came to visit.
Shit. Come on, Daisy.
You don't want him to leave now and the quivering hills will close.
Quivering hills will close.
Your mom wouldn't have anywhere to work.
The word that came out of your mouth was direction.
And I 100 percent heard that gave me an erection
and had to just like Carly,
I swear to God, when you listen back to the audience,
like just just listen and just and just picture me.
Absolutely. Just using every ounce of self,
every ounce of self control I have not to like.
Yeah, Bazaar likes magic a lot.
So happy. God.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production.