Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons. We will begin in just a moment.
It's a beautiful bright sunny morning as the doors to City Hall burst open
and Bench, Oak and Kavlaranan come confidently walking out the front door.
Hands on hips, guitars start up in the background.
They all reach up and give a huge high five.
Guess who's back in town today?
Bench, Kav and Oak came to save the day.
Been waiting all week, now it's time to play
with those forms and fires Brood Awakening's on its way.
We've been hustling, bustling through the night
with Bench, Kav and Oak. We'll get it right.
Signatures and stamps were ready to ignite.
Brood Awakening's future's shining bright.
The forms are back in town.
A new chapter to crown.
We said the forms are back in town.
The forms are back in town.
With Bench, Kav and Oak, we're tattoo buddies
and we'll see you tonight at the Brood Awakening's
opening, grand opening, grand opening ceremony.
The forms are back.
Bench?
Sorry guys, got a little carried away there.
Thanks for backing me up though.
See you tonight.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons,
a D&D 5th edition actual play podcast.
I'm your dungeon master Russ More, he, him.
And Dumbgeons and Dragons stars Amy More as Alydin.
She, her.
I've made a big mistake.
Tom Laird as Kavlaranan Goldweave, he, him.
Oh, okay, what's the best?
Oh, fuck, you got me.
And Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane.
She, her.
Bran always said, never believed her.
Thought she was, you know, just telling me bedtime stories.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a D&D production
and supported by our patrons.
You can find that at Patreon.com slash D&Dcast.
They sign up for a seven day free trial
and now fuck it, let's play!
There are the sound of quiet footsteps
moving through a very enclosed tunnel space.
And Tally pipes up and says,
we've tried a couple nights,
I think maybe we'll get through tonight.
So what I heard,
was that there is some sort of like party or something
over at the Brood Awakening.
Oh, so.
Cause like Bench was gonna like
not be able to have the Brood Awakening anymore.
Oh, that would have been really bad
cause Bench is super nice.
Yeah, Bench is super cool.
Yeah, everybody likes Bench.
Why would they close it?
Why would they not have a business?
Well, I don't know if you've been listening,
like I've been teaching you Tally,
but lots of people are really sad
about how much money that they have to give.
Everybody has to give money.
I don't have any money.
We don't have to give money.
Okay, but if we had money,
we would have to give it?
Yes.
So why would we want to have money?
Exactly.
Yeah, the grownups are doing it all wrong.
Fools.
But because of that,
I think everybody's gonna be over at the Brood Awakening.
So tonight is the night.
Okay.
I think so.
Well, okay.
So we're here.
I feel like we've loosened it.
We've gotten some of the dirt away.
Do we just give it?
Can you hear anybody?
Ellen puts her ear up against the wood.
Nope.
Nope, I don't hear anything.
But you're gonna stay down here.
I'm gonna stay down here.
I'll be the lookout.
Yes.
And if anything goes wrong up there,
you gotta run back and you gotta go tell the others.
That something's gone wrong?
Yes.
And then what do you?
Well, then you wait.
And then we wait.
And then you wait.
You don't follow.
Don't follow.
Because that's not safe.
That's not safe.
But something's gone wrong.
Yeah, but I can handle myself, Tally.
Okay.
What if they find out that I came in through a tunnel?
Then other people know about our tunnels.
So are you gonna close the tunnel once you get up there?
So then they're not gonna know?
Yes.
Okay.
But you're gonna keep an ear out.
I will keep an ear out.
And if I scream something like, Tally, run,
they're not gonna know what I'm talking about.
You're talking wild.
Maybe you have an imaginary friend named Tally.
Tally.
I'm 14.
Yeah?
Okay, help me push.
You don't have an imaginary friend?
Help me push.
Okay, yeah.
Grown quieter.
Sorry.
You're groaning too loud.
That's right.
Pipe down on your groaning, Jesus.
You wanna make a strength check?
Oh, athletics check.
I was gonna say, I am so strong.
With advantage, because you have Tally's help.
Yeah, minus one.
Let me see here.
Okay.
So that's a 14.
Oh shit.
14.
I can't do it.
I don't know.
Okay.
And then there's the
sex tape we believe in lime dice okay so that's a 14 oh shit 14 okay it it pushes
more than it has the previous nights you've managed to clear away some of the
dirt around the seams that's looked like it's built up and packed in over
the years you give it a good heave and and some more sand and dirt kind of
falls down on top of you as it lifts up you think you hear something on the
other side and you pause for a moment and then after it quiets down again you
push and feel that the seam releases okay okay okay so here's what we're
gonna do mm-hmm we're gonna open it okay but just enough for me to slide
okay okay okay tally gets positions and puts puts her hands up and holds it
straining underneath it so that you can just shimmy through and I for sure step
on tally's shoulder of course yeah okay yeah you're doing it okay
slowly to a point and then there's a sorry what I see you are up inside
ever pains and you've only really been you know you've walked past it on
your on your route through looking in so you see the forge where there's
red light emanating from a grate that's it's illuminating portion of the room
there's shadows are cast everywhere there's heavy tables off into the side
and you see the faint outline of tools up on the wall and there is a
bit of a glow from a back room you pause and you don't hear anybody you
don't hear anything what do you do oh Alydin is going to very silently
approach the room not dead-on obviously tiptoes to a wall and just
you know scooches herself along the wall to try to peer around the corner
to see what's what is making that light another forge yeah make a stealth
role since you're trying to be super sneaky Carla do you want to make a
perception role for no particular reason sure 12 only an 11 for me
okay this isn't jail now you not as silently as you think you're moving
through the room but fairly silently I'm child silent your child silent
moving through the room making your way towards this back area where there
is a bit of a flickering candle light coming from you peek through a crack
in this doorway and you see inside that Bonwyn is in fact here what's Bonwyn
doing Bonwyn is working on her latest order which is something quite
unusual which she likes something she's never really worked on before her
client Kahlu Kalei has never really likes to cut their fingernails which
is like not the best like it's kind of gross but Bonwyn doesn't judge she
want that gold so what Kahlu Kalei has requested is some sort of like
fingernail weapon so what Bonwyn is making is a set of a full set of ten
and they are basically like like armor and then a claw at the end like
kind of vibe more like it's like armor so it articulates like you can wear it
on your fingers and it will move and it comes to a very sharp sharp sharp point
so so more of a Black Panther than Freddy Krueger yeah yeah they're quite
ornate and beautiful and yeah super light and fLexible because it's using
that estral so they're gonna be really sharp like probably too sharp again this
isn't Bonwyn's problem why does Kahlu Kalei even want these are they
getting in scratching fights who knows but they look gorgeous and that's
actually all that Bonwyn cares about she takes pride in things being
functional and beautiful and that's what these are so she's quite
concentrated because there's very small sort of points of articulation
in each of the finger joints and things like that so she's probably got
like a jeweler's loop or magnifying glasses or on her face with the light
coming down and is just quite concentrated oh my god imagine poor
poor Alydin out there peering in Bonwyn has put it on her hand and is
testing it out and looking at the joints to see if they're moving
totally I'm gonna die tonight yes right so you look through the door you see
Bonwyn working away the door is only open like a crack though like if you
wanted to get a full view of what you what was just described like you
would need to do something in order to open the door you know to make
your way in a little more or at least give you more of a wide view of the
room it is really curious it doesn't want to get caught but really wants
to know what she's doing back there I think what I think the curiosity wins
out in Alydin and she looks around her for something small but heavy she
picks up a chunk of ore and hucks it at the door the front door not her door to
her office but like the front door of her establishment what she's hoping is
that Bonwyn's gonna come out and inspect and then Alydin's gonna slip in the
door Bonwyn has been so concentrating on this project because she needs to
deliver in the next couple days that she hasn't really noticed the time
because she is supposed to be going to benches tonight so she she sort of
sits up suddenly of course and is like Fane Fane can you I think
somebody's here or something and obviously no response and then kind of
actually sits up and looks around and realizes like oh it's dark outside like
she's just been totally concentrated on this it's like oh fine and so yeah had
had it on one of her hands as she was like adjusting things takes it off
puts it down and walks out and say hello is there anybody here and maybe
goes to kind of near the front door to look and see if somebody you know
sometimes people mock after hours or whatever it's not totally unusual heck
Fane could have even come back and been like are you coming because the
party started like two hours ago we're wrapping it up so yeah so Bonwyn
comes out making their way towards the door you've tucked yourself away often to
the side into the shadows as they make their way towards the door you're gonna
try and bolt into the back room or sneak into the back room sneak in yeah
all right no child can run quietly even Alydin knows this make another
stealth role please she's sorty and she's all gangly and weird all right
let's try this one oh fuck off it's a six and that's my plus three bonus
you're in jail too so Bonwyn you making your way to the front to go see if
there's somebody who knocked you you look down and you see this loose piece
of ore that was what was thrown that you kind of stub your toe on and then
you hear a gasp I walk in and I see the claws up you know probably didn't
just lay them down you probably have like some sort of like hand mannequin
yeah like a mold or something yeah just yes a hannigan is what I'm gonna
call it now yeah with these giant claws and Alydin can't help her help
herself she just goes like I've made a big mistake I mean of course Bonwyn
hears this but also hears like the tone of that gasp is that this sounds
like female and young probably so I don't think she's gonna like go back
guns blazing I think she's going yeah I think she is curious also and maybe
stealths her way back across the room to see what's going on and who's in there
like she's armed at all times essentially with like heavy blunt weapons
so she's not too worried not concerned yeah yeah definitely want me to stealth
yeah let's roll a stealth see how much sneaking happens I think oh I do
have good stealth so that is a 16 how long are you standing at the door
watching me looking at this thing yeah I feel like it's a moment where I'm like come over to the
door and and I see that it is this little ragamuffin so yeah I'm kind of
just watching to see cuz I don't know is she gonna try and steal stuff
is she what's she doing a great feeling when you know you have the
upper hand and you're just like I wonder what's gonna happen next what
choices is this person gonna play out so Alydin you're standing there for however long but you
feels like ages after after an amount of time as you are inspecting looking
at inspecting this thing that made you gasp you get the sense that
there's somebody behind I don't think that Alydin goes up to inspect the
item I think she sees super scary fucked up claw hand thing and goes oh no no no
and she knows when to quit and so she's like backing it slowly probably
being like oh okay no this wasn't this wasn't the place this wasn't the
place mm-hmm okay no I'm just gonna go back down I think so and as she's
slowly backing away I think backs straight up and it's like pretty cool
hey yeah super sharp so dangerous I worked really hard on those for about
a month I'm sorry you were telling me some sort of nonsense you're here to
inspect you know what I'm just really sorry that's okay I mean it's not ideal
you really shouldn't be coming in here no I know this was the wrong thing
sneaking yeah sneaking in here wasn't I don't love it and at your door and I
think I dented it too I'm really sorry about that too and now and I
can pay you for that mm-hmm I think so so I can just come back later
during business hours and and and I I can repair that door for you can you
know just looks like it needs a good sand right okay yeah yeah yeah and then
probably like a quick furnish yeah I mean those are those are words related
to doors so that's I I can do that in the morning for you mm-hmm do you
want to see that closer up and I point at the hand oh not realizing that that
probably sounds really scary art are you honest you want to play a game
yeah how it is like oh um you know it looks like real sharp are you gonna
stab me with it oh just let me you know what it gives me a weapon to
like make it a fair fight okay I have this bucket um and she starts
like swing the bucket a little bit no no we don't need to fight I mean if you
want to fight we can't but I didn't mean we were gonna fight no no no I
just thought because you sort of gassed and I thought maybe you thought
it was cool and I think it's cool I've been working so hard on this so
let's like it's like scary cool it's um oh yeah it's really scary it's
super dangerous I'm so too young to like know have something like that you
know what you know what that's a great instinct yeah um but like coming in
here wasn't I realize that now okay so I should like just go back okay um are
you hungry yes oh there's some there's there's more than one of you where's
that voice coming from
hey friends thanks for being here hopefully having a great week I hope so
Russ said he wasn't gonna be here and now he's here so I feel like it's
really thrown off all the plans Russ that Amy and Tom and I made just with
our eyes yeah oh yes we were you said I'm just gonna pop out can you
weed for 10 minutes
okay fair enough well I'm sorry to throwing you off I was gonna let the
dog out but he's sleeping so I thought I could come join my friends but I
guess not I mean you're definitely not supposed to wake sleeping dogs we
know that yeah steer this ship honey go for it so we were gonna talk about
book club we're gonna book club book club we meet quarterly all patrons are
welcome you can go to Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast and this month
ha this quarter we're meeting on March 7th um so you still have time to
read the book yeah if you're kind of keen that's like a week you got time
you got time and this month we are reading a snake fell to earth by
Darcy little badger and I've finished yet but it's a delight so far so read
it come join us it's really fun absolutely and or don't read it come
join us here's talk about this book and other things speaking of other
things that happen for our patrons we dedicate an episode every time to one
of our patrons so thank you Jordan McKenzie Jordan McKenzie doesn't that
sound like a cool kid it's such a cool kid name maybe like he might not have
been the quarterback but he was on the football or the cheerleader it's it
could be like basketball team Jordan McKenzie that's fun okay I was
thinking just like cool kid like not it not a sports kid like a kid I
would think was cool so I guess Jordans are all things yeah so thanks
Jordan if you're a Jordan out there you can be anything you want you can be
anything you want it we just we just plotted out several different futures
for you and that's it for today's middle place featuring like 75% less
for us which you know put in the comments don't hurt my feelings
okay we'll talk to you soon bye oh there's some there's there's more than
one of you where's that voice coming from no that um I am a voice thrower
Wow and you do different voices with the throwing that's really cool yeah
join the circus or something that would be so cool um it's just I made a whole
thing of like crudités and stuff and I'm heading out and I was gonna bring
it with me but there's a lot so like if you wanted like some veggies and
some cookies and it's fine maybe maybe just a couple for the road
they're not poisoned right no no I wasn't actually going to bring a
poison tray of food to my friends no I would these were okay I'm gonna
eat these so yeah no no safe here let me just I'll just are you just right in
the bucket yes please she holds her bucket bond when he put some stuff
together to take two benches because she doesn't love the food there but I
mean it's a lot of fried options and just it's nice to have something to
snack on and it's kind of like a party atmosphere because brute
awakenings back open you can bring something to a party yeah that's what
she has also realized now that she's quite late so like probably she's the
only one even gonna eat this food so yeah I'm Baldwin what's your name oh
I I know um Alydin oh hey Alydin nice to meet you yes you too um you
are very nice right now um considering that I am in here and and I did not get
permission so you didn't get permission I you know what I could be
wrong I'm usually a very good judge of character though I don't think you're
gonna take anything no see I just like to look at stuff okay and what
about your friend you want I'll put it I'll just put a couple extra things in
that yeah that'd be great sometimes my throne voice is also hungry and likes
the the cookies that have the raisins in it I'm tally oh my god tally and
Bonway does move over obviously to where the voice is coming from it was
huh you know my gran always said that there was tunnels that ran totally
under the city but oh yeah that I didn't that I didn't really believe her
but I should have no it's just a myth and if there are any noises coming
and I'm gonna I'm gonna lift it up you know what you don't gotta it's a
Matthew here as the door opens and you see yeah you see tally who's tally even
smaller than Alydin yeah nice nice to meet you why don't you just come on up
yeah of course I'm not gonna hurt you totally fine fancy meeting you here
and I kind of like look down like huh yeah gran always said never believed
her thought she was you know just telling me bedtime stories and I'm
gonna put the thing back down and like push something over top of it there
that's probably a good idea yeah tally hi we're gonna talk about this later
about what about following directions I you didn't yell tally run I didn't but
I also said that if anything happened that you run back I don't know if
that's true well you know it's true you know it's true now tally what I'm sorry
to do this in front of bond one we can't use these tunnels no more well I
mean that's just one door there are many doors yeah I was gonna say I'm
not telling you not to use the tunnels I'm just asking you to please
not use the tunnel into my place of business oh I promise I won't insane
sleeps down here I got my place upstairs it I would feel weird you guys
seem very nice but if like a bunch of like I did not let's just assume that
entrance is like we're the only ones who know about them well we were well
I mean I did not know that you guys also live here cuz like that was super
weird to come into somebody's house that we would never do that oops we
thought we were just gonna see some like cool stuff and and see what you
got going on here no it's um yeah um maybe if you like you could come back
tomorrow or another time in the day to that door um yeah number one you got
to fix that door and then maybe I could just show you around a little
bit if you're curious about like what happens in here I can show you it's
super interesting and cool we make all kinds of awesome stuff as they're
listening to Bonwyn they're absolutely picking out on the food that tell or
that's in Alydin's bucket they're just like mm-hmm mm-hmm why don't you
I've actually got a get over to Brewed Awakening it's a whole thing they
were closed anyway um yeah why don't you come back sometime Alydin Tally so
nice to meet you and we will pay you back for the food and don't worry about
that in fact yeah oh yeah well yeah cuz if you have money you have to give
it away that's that's what they say absolutely ain't that the truth yeah
especially in this town cuz we cuz we heard that Brewed Awakening and that
bench almost it wasn't allowed to open it anymore yeah and we thought
you know what if nothing else you guys should come to the next Business
Association meeting because there's always lots of snacks and we mostly
just get mad about you know the mayor and paying taxes and it's kind of a
fun kind of a fun night but mostly snacks sounds fun okay we are an
independently owned business independent contractors yes we do freelancers yes
yes so we can help too we do work for free no no no what we will we work
off we're gonna cuz cuz you gave us this stuff and that's super that was
super nice of you but but we will like totally pay you back and and and and I
have sandpaper over back home and yeah I will be here first thing in the
morning fixing that door and as she's talking she's they're slowly moving
back to the the front entry not the covered up tunnel like trying to move
like a work and I think as we're like moving towards the door I'm like
picking up the trays that I was gonna take with me and we probably all like
sort of exit through the front door together and I very obviously like pull
a big key out of my pocket and lock the door that's a good idea safety
first yeah yeah well like I said wonderful to meet you both and I hope
I see around and I kind of like throw a couple more things in the in the book
oh thank you oh thanks Bonwyn yeah that's you're really kind um Tally we
should go we're going yeah okay okay good night bye you're dead
we cut over to the brood awakening and the door opens there's a there's a
loud and joyous band playing and everybody's singing in chorus is bond
when you enter with your your trays of crudite and everybody all together now I
get knocked down
June June you gotta keep it down days is just over there
ah he gets it hey everybody sorry I'm late just congratulations bench oh thank
you yeah rousing party having a great time so happy I put on it looks amazing
in here I did that one wall over there didn't quite dry in time but you know
the rest did so don't lean against that wall is your tip yeah yeah it's
not great and you look and you see a guy who was leaning against the wall
and steps away from it and his back is entirely pink a bond when they'll get
you a drink put your platters down we got the we got fried stuff you know
yeah Kavlaranan just help yourself if you like to eat a vegetable up to you
I've been known to dabble every now and then all right well yeah help
yourself June oh everybody just to help yourself thing comes over and
says what took you so long oh man the craziest thing just happened but I
can I'll tell you later okay this is a party yeah no it's fine
Cav was just telling me about is the work he's doing here oh okay is it
really like numbers based because that I mean kind of but that's like the the
the inner workings of it the overall scope is uh there's like a lot of
money that gets spent in this town yeah have you seen that gold fountains
yeah like the statues and change the statues face every other week it's it's
pretty crazy right yeah so anyway yeah I was just I've been looking into like
where this money's been being spent huh yeah I mean if you have any questions
about like history down in the artisan district and and sort of the way the
tax rate has risen from like you know sort of reasonable yeah a reasonable rate
that like sort of kept us in in road repairs and schools and things and then
kept increasing really steadily to about the 80% rate is that ridiculous
whoa it is ridiculous June and the schools are closed and it's well I was
gonna say like the roads look like they're in bad shape so is that not
continued the level of care is not continued with the spending shitty
roads dumb kids yeah that could be our town motto but I'd really rather it was
sorry you probably don't want to talk about work here but we have like a
business association meeting first Tuesday of every month at my place I
at Everbane so if you want to like get a feel for how things are kind of
in that district of the town so I'd love to come by oh my god I didn't
even tell you the best part oh oh you got me yeah oh it's some snacks the best
little sandwiches from tiny sandwich tiny sandoz and more yeah you might need
to fight fame for the snacks cuz they usually get to clean up whatever is
left yeah you don't have to fight me much they're looking pretty strong
but I'll take it into consideration
the evening carries on and everybody has a few drinks more and the band begins
to quiet down and it's just the last few of you who are hanging out as
benches cleaning up a little bit and ushering some folks out the door as
he shuts the door behind a group of drunk individuals there's a what
sounds like a heavy knock at the door and he takes a few steps away and then
hears the knock and then walks back and opens the door and there's nobody
there but there is a piece of paper that's been nailed to the door and he
says oh what the fuck is this and you all turn at that and he pulls it
off and he says oh oh they didn't shut me down it's good I've only been
open less than 24 hours walks over and says adventurers wanted it looks like
Ignatius is calling for a group of adventurers to go up into the
mountains and he puts it down and goes back and picking up a few more
glasses as he goes put that down in front of you yeah yeah I just did a
new weapon for Ignatius so I kind of figured he'd be putting out the call
soon call for what exactly oh um well sometimes the nobles I don't know if it
was like this in Kingstown but they like to play at being like fun
adventurers and they go off and they try and find treasure and like
basically like hire normal people to like escort them out in to do an
adventure I've been okay so that yeah they're essentially cosplaying yes yes
yes they're like just just playing at needing to work for money and that's
fun it's like camping I mean your tone implies otherwise yeah yeah like
camp like camping yeah yeah they usually bring someone to like cook
fancy meals and carry all of their things but of course the adventurers
just like do the work carry their own gear I mean it's not the worst way to
spend a weekend I don't think but he pays okay he does pay okay you have
that one fun one June that's right I shot a rabbit yeah it didn't see it
come like one of those big rabbits yeah not like Kavlaranan you're
probably thinking like yeah who hasn't shot a rabbit but this is like one of those like a
big rabbit yeah okay it had fangs it had fangs it's not just like you know a
little fluffy bunny terrifying rabbit it was pretty terrifying I don't shoot
things unprovoked it started and June just like stone-cold
killer if you're lucky sometime if June ever invites you over for tea you
can see that she has used the fur from the giant rabbit to make this
great cover for a couch and there's like a big tail it's like a cushion it's
incredible mm-hmm and it's antlers are on the wall mm-hmm okay June a lot more
hardcore than I initially thought I love it June is hardcore days ear
muffs Roger your muffs it up June what do you think about the cops fuck
the police yeah June's kind of hardcore love it yeah cav I mean we
know we had fun on boys night but like this is a this would be a great
way to get to know some of the nobles and see how they funnel money I mean you
said you you mentioned yeah we're like off of the mountains at some point too
like you've been around right yeah a hundred percent yeah I didn't even
think about going out there to like see this in action but that makes
total sense there's usually a bit of like a recruitment process you got
to kind of work through but look I mean do the stairs a couple times
before and then you'll be okay well I mean we both know that's not true you're a big strap in person
you're you're you're gonna be fine do you would you like to do it I mean I
know Ignatius so does does the mayor ever go on these hmm okay but like
people who know the mayor close oh yeah yeah all of that class tight with
all of them yeah okay yeah totally like sign me up
yeah that sounds great okay to like spy I mean just to get a general lay of the
land sure and maybe get a couple coppers to fix a fucking hole in your
Dory just put we hear the sound of a quiet conversation that is picking up
as we get closer to Alydin and Tali who are making their way back home
through the streets I'm really I'm really sorry for saying saying that I
was there she sounded very nice through the through the through the wooden the
floor well we we're really lucky that she is nice you didn't see that claw
thing in the back room it was terrifying Tali listen you know I'm the
bravest person so brave I mean you found those times you went in this
time I was beat my pants I thought I was gonna die in the tunnels no with
the big claw hand glove thing yeah no that's that sounds very scary I'm glad I
didn't see that as I've I got in there I probably would have screened well and
you know what though yeah that could have been a bad situation could you
should have just followed directions sounded it sounded fine I know I'm
sorry it's okay you're little you have a lot to learn and don't eat all
these you got to bring some back okay she pulls a bucket away from her as you
round the corner towards the stables you see a couple people putting up
signs on posts and doorways you kind of tuck off to the side as they're
making their way past the stables and they keep going along their way not
noticing you or hearing you you carry down slowly making sure they're gone
and then you go up to one of these signs and it's got a pile of gold in
the center of the piece of paper and above it it says adventures wanted it
has a time and to meet outside the barracks the next day oh oh I think I
know how we can pay bond went back and when I say we I mean me oh yeah
of course tell you what you lost a little bit of trust I'm not gonna lie
I understand I also didn't break it break the door tally I didn't break the
door I dented it with a rock I don't hear the difference breaking something
implies that it's a big break but here's the thing I don't like to be
in debt to no one of course these cookies they mean something these
cookies mean I owe her a favor that door means I owe her a favor I do not
like oh and people stuff so if I go and do this oh are you an adventurer what
I could be absolutely you could be I'm really brave you're really brave I have
skills you have skills I could do this and then I can bring the money
back and I can give what I owe to Bonwyn what we owe well we owe to
Bonwyn collectively and then even probably have some left over to put a
lock on our door a lock on our door you saw that big key that was a pretty big
key that that probably keeps pretty big things out that's right probably keep
those animals out you're gonna do this tomorrow mm-hmm yeah I think so she
rips it down folds it up puts it in her bucket
Dumbgeons and Dragons season 3 episode 8 this episode starred Amy More as
Alydin Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everbane Tom Laird as Kavlaranan Goldweave and
Russ More as your dungeon master dialogue editing by Carla Maxted and
sound design by Russ More this episode featured music from Epidemic Sound
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound boom library and sound ideas our
amazing cover art and character designs are by Matt Garbutt a huge
thank you to our supporting producers Gabriel Lynch, Jessica Babyok, Cat
Waterflame, Jacob Madden, Christian Brown, Craig Zeiss, Perry Mady, Ongarong
Kierzen, Old School Gamer D, LA Branton, Nathaniel Teeter, Luna and Erin
and to thank you to Sharon B for giving us the name Kalu Kalei really
appreciate it Sharon if you want to help us out and build the world
along with us well we need your help you can go to Patreon.com slash dumb
dragon cast and sign up today with a seven day free trial where you can help
us build the world and get access to a whole world of other bonus content
like the adventures of which is in a Patreon exclusive show that only the
coolest kids are listening to right now that's right you too could be a
cool kid don't miss out and so you can stay in the know with
everything we have coming up sign up for our newsletter there's a link
tree down in the description which will take you directly to our
newsletter sign up so you don't miss out there but that's all I've got for
you now be a cool kid come sign up at Patreon have a great week we'll talk to
you soon Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production