Dumbgeons and Dragons starts in just a moment.
It's a beautiful morning as everybody's getting up and going to their respective shops and getting ready for the day.
We see everybody, we see Bizard heading down towards the Magic Closet, keys in hand, ready to open up the shop,
and Bonwyn exiting those buns doe with a coffee and croissant headed up to the hot block.
It has a few of them, probably for Thane and some of the others around.
Kavlarananan, we see you exiting Continental Breakfast in Hand headed towards City Hall.
It's been a bit since you've been there.
You took a few days off with the adventure and then just had the weekend all plugged in, you're ready to go.
And Allaton getting up very early, heading down towards the Artisan District.
And as everybody's bustling about and everybody's waking up for the day, we hear the town criers.
Sounds in the street! Sounds in your homes! Where are they coming from? Who's watching us while you sleep?
They call this repeatedly throughout the day and everybody has been hearing things.
There's been, if you haven't heard them, you've known somebody who's heard them,
but like scratching noises coming from what can only be described as the floors of different businesses and homes within Vintersmouth.
Are there zombies under the ground again?
Yeah.
Oh, fuck.
We jump ahead and we see Allaton weaving through people heading down Charles Street towards the Magic Closet
and it's, the open sign is turned over in the window and you look in through the window
and you see Bizard tending to some shelves, putting some things away for the day
as you are standing outside kind of looking through the window to see if he's there.
I watch him for a minute and I see that he's alone in there.
It's early. There are no patrons in.
So I want to just like really quickly like just like slip in.
I know there's probably a bell or something, but I'm going to try my best not to bang it in a way that just like obnoxiously announces my presence.
So the door opens. There is a small bell, but you slide in just as it's just the slightest jingle.
You get in. Are you trying to, you're trying to not be seen as you enter?
I'm not trying to be not seen.
Allaton wants to be seen and present, but to be recognized in such a way as not a disturbance or a disruption.
So it's not like I'm not Van Damme style kicking the door down being like, teach me bitch.
I want to be like very, very respectful, very unassuming, very like, you know, when you have a minute, very Amy.
I know all the fastest ways to get anywhere in this place.
If you can think of a way we can sexy that up.
Well, we're not like going on a date.
I just want to talk to her about the city's finances and Kyle class it as bizarre.
The wizard, he him a large quantity of those all at once would be quite more destructive.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Patreon supported podcast where you can get a seven day free trial.
If you sign up today at Patreon dot com slash dumb dragon cast.
Now, fuck it. Let's play.
Bizarre, it's been an early morning for you.
You've come, you've restocked the shelves after having a reasonably successful week.
Can you hear a small jingle of the bell, which is a little early for most people to usually come in.
You don't usually kind of come around till the afternoon.
You tell me what you do as you hear the jingle of the bell.
You know, putting away stuff on the shelf and I hear the jingle of the bell and some very light footsteps and say,
Oh, early start to the day.
Who are we helping today?
And I turn a little bit as I continue putting things away and,
Oh, Alydin, right? Is that correct?
Yeah, yes.
How can I help you this morning?
Oh, you know, well, I was just around and like I saw you putting away your stuff.
And I remember that you said that one time that maybe I could come and just like kind of check out your store.
Yeah.
Not in a case your store kind of way, but just in like a checkout your store kind of way.
And yeah, I just thought that maybe that I could do that today.
Yeah.
If you're not busy.
Not yet.
So absolutely.
I tell you what, I've got a got a new package of supplies over there.
Actually, if you'll go ahead and unwrap those careful though, the powder is a little flammable.
So just to make sure that you keep it away.
In fact, let me just move this candle up here real quick.
If you'll go ahead and start unpacking those, they're going to be in little envelopes.
I want you to take them and line them up on the shelf right over there.
Unwrap them.
I'm not going to light them on fire.
I'm going to take the little envelopes and I'm going to put them on the shelf up there.
Yes.
Absolutely.
So.
Okay.
Now.
I'm sure she's scurried over.
She's excited.
Fun thing about those.
You know, some of the some of the fireworks that you may have seen at the the mayor's
announcements and speeches and whatnot.
I've actually been able to take a little bit on the side for those and make a little
little popper things here and there and they make a little small explosion.
So now granted, not to give you any ideas, but a large quantity of those all at once
would be quite more destructive.
So, you know, I only get small batches in here and there, but certainly useful in
some situations.
So just, you know, just again, be careful.
Not too much jostling.
But, yeah, they go.
They come in.
They come into play quite a bit with some of the.
Well, I call it magic, but, you know, not everything.
Magic is in the way that it affects you because, you know, I'm not I'm not sure how much
you know or how much has been explained to you about the magic in our world.
During this, Alydin had like already screwed over, started like unwrapping the package
and it's just like slowed down and is just completely and the minute you said
magic, her face was like, it's happening.
She's like in her monologues, just like, be cool, be cool.
Oh, yeah, no, I've heard of yeah, I've heard of magic sort of before.
Do you know what can what do you what do you know about it?
Well, I went to Bernhard Swan School of Magic fighting and dance.
So I know quite a bit about it, but I, you know, I don't want to give away too much
because. Oh, is it a secret?
Well, I mean, it definitely cost me a lot of money.
Well, it didn't cost me a lot of money, but it cost a lot of money.
So you have to you have to have a lot of money to learn to use magic.
I had to have a lot of money to learn to use magic.
And while not everybody has that, that doesn't mean that there shouldn't be ways to
figure it out, because I mean, I've seen around the town, it seems like schools have gone to the wayside.
And certainly there wouldn't be a school that teaches what Bernhard Swans does.
But it doesn't mean I'm not keen on imparting some kind of knowledge to to those who want to learn.
Granted, I'm not going to impart anything that is going to be detrimental to your health.
But, you know, if you want to learn some things, then.
Yes, I do. Yeah.
OK. Well, then there will have to be a trade that goes on between these.
If you are gaining knowledge from me, then you will help me around my store here and there.
Maybe perhaps do little fetchings for me to go down to the go down to the river
whenever supplies come in and pick up packages that I have brought in from Kingstown or other places.
Does that sound like something you'd be interested in?
Yes, sir. Yep. I could I could do that.
And I'm really fast, too. And I know everywhere.
I know all the fastest ways to get anywhere in this place.
Fantastic. Well, let me let me ask you this.
Why do you want to learn magic?
OK, so here is what I heard is that anyone can do magic.
Anyway, that's that. Anyway, that's what we all like.
One of the older kids told that to me.
And then they went off on a caravan and said that they were going to go and do magic.
And they said that anyone can do it, but that it's really hard.
And you have to be like super strong and stuff.
But that like that everybody has it like in their bodies like blood.
There's truth to what you're saying.
Everybody can learn to do magic now, whether they are able to handle the toll it takes on them is another thing.
You're right. They need to be strong, but not in the sense that like Binch is strong.
You know what I mean? Oh, yeah.
Like up here, she taps her temple. Exactly. Exactly.
Bizarre finally like turns and kind of like kind of like, you know, squats down a little bit to get something from a low shelf.
And he's restocking things. But he looks at Alydin and he says, see my eyes.
See these great fLex here. That is the trade off of doing magic.
You will injure yourself.
You will harm yourself either through slight pains, headaches here and there.
Or, you know, larger magics, more complicated magics that come down the line have the potential to temporarily blind and eventually permanently blind.
If you are not careful with how you use it.
I want you to understand the repercussions upfront so that you can make a decision early as to whether this is actually something you want to follow through with.
So like it will blind everybody?
If they go too far, if they happen to overuse or rely on it too much, magic is magic can be used as a tool, but it can also be used as a crutch.
And if I teach you, I want you to understand it is not a crutch.
You have to rely on yourself first.
And then in dire situations or situations that necessitate it, use magic.
So like if maybe I've maybe did a little bit of magic, like by accident.
Hmm.
Then that magic would likely not be as harmful as magic done with intent.
If you are somehow accessing the weave unknowingly, then you are not...
What's the weave?
There's a jingle of a bell as a man walks in and he's looking at some shelves.
Hello? Welcome in. Welcome to the Magic Closet. How can I help you today?
Alydin, I'm sorry, give me one moment. We have a customer to take care of.
And we cut to a shop that is overflowing with luxurious fabrics.
Satin and whatever it was. What the fuck else is a good fabric?
Silks.
Silks and satins. Brushed velvets.
There's just a wall of tracks and polyester.
And we see Bonwyn carrying a few less treats in hand, a few less breakfast items in hand.
Come in and you hear humming in the background.
That of Nevins who is opening up shop for the day.
Hey, I brought you something.
What did you bring me?
It's your favorite.
And she comes out. Oh, those buns though. They're pretty good.
So good. This one is almond paste stuffed.
Almond paste. Love it. Thank you.
It's incredible.
She takes a bite. Sublime. Thank you so much.
My pleasure.
This is probably going to be the best part of my day.
What are you doing tonight?
Why?
Well, I got invited to another of Ignatius' masquerades.
Okay. Cool.
And I got a plus one.
And wondering if you want to go and just like, you know, see what's happening over there.
Maybe give me an excuse to leave early.
Wow. Well, you know I love you.
So I'm not going to say no immediately.
What is the theme of this particular masquerade?
I know he loves a theme.
He does love a theme.
The last one was of course the color green.
I think that's like every second one probably knowing Ignatius.
This one is animals of the wild.
Oh.
He's veering away from just a color palette, which never goes well for anybody.
But animals of the wild is what he's going.
So I'm assuming lots of masks and furs and stuff.
And she picks up just some huge bolts of fur.
So you're going to, what, be a bear?
What are you putting together there?
I was hoping you could put together some cloth.
No, I'm not going to be a bear.
I was going to be like a fox or something.
So it's sexy animals of the wild.
Well, of course it's sexy.
It is at a brothel, I guess.
It's at the Quivering Hills.
Oh, even if it's just the color green, it is sexy green.
It's how little green can you wear?
That was what the whole theme was.
That's the theme actually.
We can make it interesting.
Will you?
Help me.
I've heard about this animal.
I remember reading about it in school.
Do you remember?
It's kind of yellow with brown spots and has a crazy long neck.
Yellow with brown spots.
Super long neck.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Because I thought.
See if he even knows what a giraffe is.
Yeah, 100%.
You want to be a giraffe?
Well, okay.
It's going to be a stretch to make a long neck sexy giraffe.
Well, I wasn't really worried about the sexy so much.
What I was thinking, though, is that then I would be tall.
I would make a big head, like a big neck comes out.
And Bonwyn's into this now.
Now this is fun now.
Isn't even like, oh, god.
100% because, again, sexy.
This is not what Bonwyn's describing at all.
You know, like a big kind of Papier-Maché tall head.
But my face would be here so I could see.
And it would be bAlydinced on my shoulder.
Sure.
So many things are just so cute about this.
The Papier-Maché.
Paper-Maché, my dear.
No, it's fancy.
It's sexy.
Right.
We're going for it.
It's French.
You know what?
I've probably got some materials we can put this together.
We've got all day.
I don't know how your schedule is looking.
But I can get a start on it if you've got to go get some things wrapped up.
I should at least let Thay know that I'm over here working on a really important project.
Plus I have his breakfast.
Okay.
Well, I'll get started.
I'll pull some materials.
And brainstorm how, if you can think of a way we can sexy that up, I am willing to consider it.
Follow me.
It's the long neck.
So everything you've described up to this point.
But you're you're just wearing next to nothing.
That would be sexy.
But maybe that's too much.
You don't want to draw too much attention to yourself.
Maybe.
Oh, you go.
Maybe we create a two person costume.
One of us.
I'm thinking you because you want to feel tall here.
So you one of us can be the front, the neck, and one of us can be the sexy caboose.
Even you're making fun of me, aren't you?
You're making me.
I'm just building myself up here to be the sexy caboose.
Okay.
Yes.
Yeah.
Two person costume.
Great plan.
It's never.
You're the one that wants me to come with you.
I do want you to come with me.
You be a sexy fox.
I was thrown by the giraffe.
I'll be a giraffe.
Here is my concession to sexiness.
Okay.
The body part could be really tight.
Like a bodysuit.
So it's like very form fitting.
I've got some new stuff in.
Yeah.
It's hugs.
It'll hug and that I can maybe get on board with.
Sure.
Okay.
Yeah.
I'll be back.
Niven's very excited now and she's going through all of the materials that she has
pulling yellows and browns and the most huggy of materials and seeing what she can
string up to make this a two person costume.
And you head back out into the street and head up to Everbane.
Fair.
I honestly believe that she was just teasing me about the two person costume thing,
but I guess I'll find out.
We'll find out when we cut back.
Yeah.
When we cut back to the masquerade ball.
Middle, middle.
Welcome to the middle everybody.
How you doing?
Doing pretty great.
I'm doing fantastic.
Thank you for asking.
Pretty good.
Excellent.
Well, we're happy that you're here having a great time.
As you always do.
And we appreciate you for being here with us.
I feel like somebody just stretched you out, right?
It's true.
We love you.
As if someone was making that hand motion, but no one was.
No.
Russ was in his own mind, maybe.
He really was.
Yeah.
That's happened a lot today.
So we'll just jump right into it.
You should join us on Patreon.
And here's why.
We have a book club over there.
No buttering anyone up.
Just straight to it.
Straight in.
Straight to the goods.
Well, we've got book club.
And you know what?
We have to get straight to it because we're meeting on Monday.
Yep.
Yes.
That's right.
So we're meeting Monday, May 27th.
Somebody quickly look at a calendar for me.
27th.
That sounds like a Monday.
The book is Dirk Gently's Holistic Detective Agency by Douglas.
Adams?
Yeah.
We got this.
Oh, goodness.
I was going to say a different first name, last name.
I got a little messed up there.
Well, now I wonder what you were going to say.
I was just glad you said the title because I continually, I'm like, Girk Gently.
And I'm like, no.
Girk.
It is, if you haven't read it yet, you totally have time.
It's a very short book or listen to the audio book.
I listen to a full cast recording main character played by a hobbit.
It's a delight.
How fun.
Very, very good.
Sweet.
I'm listening to an author.
Not an author.
Just a random author.
Some random author picked it up.
Neil Gaiman raised reading it for some reason.
He has a beautiful voice.
They stop every once in a while and they like promote their own book.
It's kind of odd.
But no, the author himself is reading the book.
So I think that's kind of cool because he's reading it how he imagined it in his head.
I like that.
Yeah.
So exactly.
You definitely have time.
So come join us.
It is really fun.
We just talk about books and stuff and then other stuff also.
What time are we meeting?
Probably 7 p.m. Pacific because my friend Tom lives on the West Coast.
That's me.
He needs to eat dinner before he can come and join us.
You don't want cranky Tom who hasn't eaten dinner to be on that call.
No, we don't want that.
We just is swearing about Dirk Gently and we're like, no, he seems nice.
Calling him Girk the whole time.
Just making myself even madder.
All of this sounds wonderful and great and I hope everybody can join us on Monday.
But if they can't join us on Monday, how often do we hold book clubs?
Book club happens about quarterly.
We take turns picking and we have really run the gamut.
I mean, Dirk Gently is pretty on brand, I think, for the podcast.
But we've had some romance.
We've done just everybody who's in book club gets a turn to pick the book and can pick whatever they want.
So it's super fun.
I love it.
So you can join us at any tier at Patreon.com slash Tom Dragoncast to join us at book club.
But you also get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's patron, Colin Murray.
Thanks, Colin.
Too cool.
You're awesome.
So you should be like Colin.
I don't know if Colin's coming to join the book club, but Colin, you should come join the book club.
Come join the book club, Colin.
We'd love to have you.
And we'll see it segway.
Strong fish.
Know how to get out of the bit is what I was always told.
You just yell, I need out.
Somebody throw me a life.
We just star wipe and we're done.
That's right.
Star white.
The rest of the episode.
I like it.
We love you so much.
Yeah, we love you.
Have a good week.
Indeed.
OK, bye.
Bye.
City Hall is its usual slow self for the morning.
Everybody is yawning and sipping their coffee as they walk around giving nods.
Morning, morning, Jim.
Cav.
Good to see you.
Oh, yeah.
Hey.
Nice to see you too.
Cav can never remember anyone's name.
A lot of buddies and pals.
Hey, there.
Hey, you.
Passport.
Lots of people walking past and you make it back to your office.
Of course, inside your office is Oak, awaiting your arrival.
And he hears the door creak open.
He says, you're here.
It's been so long.
I've missed you so much.
It's what have you been up to?
Where you been?
Who you seen?
You know, we were best friends.
We got tattoos together.
And then you and Bench just haven't called a lot recently.
Oh, well, no.
See, it's actually a funny story.
I kind of got roped into like this adventure thing.
Well, of course.
Yeah.
OK.
So how did that go?
You know, it wasn't the best.
It was.
Well, it was kind of a waste of time.
But I did get to meet.
Oh, what's his name?
Bizard.
And I had some quality time with him.
Yeah.
He seems super cool.
And we were kind of talking about how, like, everything's a little weird in this town.
Like, what do you mean?
Well, just like, you know, I was also chatting with Bonwyn there as well and just like.
You have so many friends.
Yeah.
Well, you know, it's just you got to get out there and like finding things to do
will connect you with other people.
You can't just like hole up at home all the time.
No, of course.
Yeah.
Me and mom have been talking about going out, hitting the town one night.
Well, you know what?
Your mom is super, super nice.
The nicest.
She just might not be like the best going out on the town person for you.
You know, she tried it once.
She hurt her hip.
Really?
I'm not surprised by that one bit.
She makes a great wingman.
She really talked me up to everybody in the bar.
Regardless of whether they wanted to listen.
Have you met my handsome son?
I'm fucking dying.
He works for the government.
Yeah.
But yeah, we're kind of chatting about how like things are weird in town.
Like the money just doesn't seem to be being spent in the right places.
Like we need to go visit a different shop.
Like somebody's not doing well.
We need to go buy some sandwiches.
No, no, more of like the taxes.
Taxes.
The tax money from the town.
Oh, the taxes.
Right.
Not a lot of gold statues and not a lot of like new schools, you know?
Well, what the mayor says about schools is that they rot your brain.
So it was best to get, you know, like the mayor before him,
it just really solidified getting schools out of the situation.
Oh, so it's been multiple, multiple mayors with this platform.
Yeah.
I mean, it started slow.
You know, they started just cutting funding, that sort of thing.
Doing what they could with what they had.
Cutting funding to the school?
This would never stand in Kingstown.
Look, this is just the way it was.
And then, you know, over time, it's just we realized that schools weren't for everybody.
OK.
We still have the one where, you know, on this side of the river,
where some of the kids go.
Sure.
But so it's only the one on this side of the room.
No other ones.
Everything else has been shut down.
Yeah, no, I.
It's a voucher system.
He doesn't see any problem with this.
Yeah, no, there's just the one on this side.
I mean, what's the issue there?
What do they what do they do in Kingstown?
Like schools on every street corner?
No, I mean, that's a little excessive.
But for every like kind of district or even neighborhood,
they have like a school there so that the local kids can go there.
I mean, you could just, you know, learn like I did.
Learn from your ma until she sends you out and gets a job.
And then you learn from that person.
And just like you're learning from me in this role,
because I'm your your superior in this position.
Supervisor, sure.
Super.
Ear.
Visor.
Superior visor is what I am.
You're learning.
You're learning the ropes from me and the way we do things.
I'm your inventors.
That's how we pass information along.
You know, it's OK.
Speaking of superior visors, isn't Nina kick it around at all?
I'd love to finally meet her.
Yeah, Nina.
I thought I saw Nina today.
You did mention that you wanted to meet Nina.
I brought it up at my last meeting with her.
My last one on one there with Nina.
And, you know, she said she was interested.
She would try and make some time.
Well, we're not like going on a date.
I just want to talk to her about the city's finances.
Right. Right.
Well, you know, let's just go see see what Nina's up to right now.
Yeah.
I've got that part.
Sure. Yeah, absolutely.
What do you work?
Yeah.
I mean, we could say.
I can leave this behind.
Don't you worry about that.
Oh, OK.
Yeah.
I know.
I noticed you left a whole bunch of things there.
I told you the adventure I went on.
Yeah, it was the hidden paperwork as he's like walking down the hall.
There was the hidden paperwork floor and it was underneath the desk.
It was tucked away.
I don't know.
You can't hide paperwork.
I don't know what you're talking about.
And I find this attack on my character to be upsetting and out of place from you.
You want to talk to Nina?
You're going to have to do your paperwork.
But after we talk to Nina.
Look, I told you.
I told you that I would get this meeting done.
OK.
I told you that.
And I'm a man of my word.
So let's go talk to Nina.
OK.
Awesome.
Oh, my God.
That's the best pushover ever.
If you want to talk to Nina, you're going to have to get your paperwork done.
But like after.
After you talk to Nina.
Also, canonically, Baldwin and Oak went to school together.
So I don't know what he's talking about.
Not like school.
He's been drinking the Kool-Aid.
Yeah, he's so like, no, no, school's bad now.
Yep.
Towing that party line.
Good for me, but not for thee.
That's right.
He went back home and told mama about it and said, no, Thomas Jefferson's the devil.
We hear those footsteps kind of fade out and the conversations fade out and then
pick back up and there's a small knock at the door and Oak calls in.
Is Nina there?
There's a voice of a receptionist as you open the door and you see, who is it?
And do you have an appointment?
Well, Kavlarananan here.
I wanted to talk to Nina right now.
Well, I mean, I just wanted to.
Yeah, right now, right now.
You see the receptionist kind of nod her head and stand up and go into the next room.
And then after a moment, Oak looks at you and is like, yeah, yeah, we told them.
We're going to get we're going to get you the answers you need for for Kingstown, right?
That's the questions you're asking for.
Yeah. OK, cool, cool, cool, cool, cool. Love it.
And then she comes back out and yeah, come on, come on in.
Come on in.
Two of you walk through the door and it's a smaller office with a large desk inside of it.
Really want to dominate the space.
That's right.
There's two small stools on the one side.
It's confusing how the desk got in the room.
Oh, yeah, no, they actually built the desk in the room.
It was original inside.
There's a large desk, two small stools.
And you see seated behind is the lovely bob cut of Nina, who is taking a sip of her tea.
And she puts it down.
Yes, darling, come on in.
Come in and close the door.
What can I do for you?
Come on. It's been too long.
I mean, I say too long.
It's been I haven't talked to you not one bit.
So please come in and let's catch up.
Let's talk about all the things that you have on your mind.
And then you can send your report back to Kingstown and be on your way.
Let's like we know it's what you want.
I mean, yeah, that sounds really good.
Quick question, though.
How do I get the door closed with everything in the way of it?
Oh, yes, yes, of course.
Just come on in.
Come in.
And she hops up on the desk and kind of elbows you off to the side.
So you just stand right there.
Don't move, darling.
OK, all right.
You're over there.
Everybody just hold your stools, hold your stools in your hands.
OK, you have some good.
Good.
And then she pushes the door shut.
OK, now you put your stools back down.
You sit back down.
Well, lathering repeats once we're done here.
But tell me what are your questions?
Just mainly where's all the money from the taxes going if it's not going to just gold statues in town?
The taxes from the money go back to the cities, the infrastructures, the big meetings, the big, you know, paying all of the very high.
Can we go back to that first one with the infrastructure there?
Yes, yes, yes.
Haven't you seen the lovely gold laden streets here on the sides of the river?
OK, well, there's like the one gold laden street.
Yes.
But every other street's not doing so great.
That is very bad for them.
But there is only so much money to go around.
Oh, sure.
Yeah, no, I understand that part.
Why no schools?
Oak here's saying schools bad.
That's not the attitude that we have up in Kingstown.
Oh, we don't say schools are bad.
We say schools are not necessary.
But why aren't they necessary?
Dear Keflaren, education attains the minds.
Oh.
There's too many things happening in schools that really just bring down the people.
So we prefer that they learn from their elders.
OK, so that comes free.
A story driven narrative type history.
Exactly, exactly.
So they learn from their people and the community,
and then they pick up all the things that they need,
and then they live a happy life without being burdened by
how many years were they putting people through schools?
Are you wasting too much time?
Get out into the workforce, am I right?
And she puts her hand up for a high five.
Sure, it tentatively gives a high five.
Yeah, I know what we're saying.
All right, so there's your report.
I'll see you later.
Oh, OK, can we like maybe,
I'm still going to be around for a few more days.
Can we chat again in the future?
Oh, you got more questions?
Well, I mean, this was just all very sudden,
and I didn't really come with like my A game.
But yeah.
OK, OK, OK.
Let me see.
And she flips open her book.
I could pencil you in.
I mean, you snuck into this appointment today,
so that was right before the mayoral meeting,
which we have in just a few moments.
Can I go to things like that,
or is that only for like the higher ups?
I will ask.
First point on the agenda.
If Kavlarananan can come to the mayoral meetings.
Perfect.
I will promise that I will ask that for you.
And then we can discuss this
and any other questions you have in three weeks.
Oh, that seems OK.
What if I just like swing on by now
that I know where your office is?
Kind of like today.
That would be lovely.
I enjoy that very much.
And I will wait and with anticipation
right here in this seat,
I will be nowhere else in the building forever.
OK, cool.
Waiting for you to swing by.
Alright, so yeah, I'll probably
I'll come back in like a day or two
and we'll chat again.
A day or two and she flips back.
There could be a brief moment
once my tea and perhaps at lunch
that I could sneak in.
So yeah, if you time it right,
the day or two will be perfect.
OK, awesome.
Well, it's been nice to see.
OK, so you got to stand up
and move back to the corner.
Oh, right, OK.
Yeah, OK.
So I just I pick this up
and I move over here.
Yeah, yeah.
You just go back to the corner.
Oh, you over there.
Yeah, sorry.
OK.
Just hold it.
And now you have to climb up
on top of the desk too
because now there's a point
of which you can't get around.
Oh, yeah.
No, there's a whole rigmarole, isn't it?
Sorry.
OK, have a great day.
See you next time.
You want to roll.
How much was Kavalarin
paying attention in that room?
He was paying attention
because he wasn't like there was
no room for the conversation
to go anywhere.
So he was trying to pick up
like any sort of clue he could
while he was in the space.
So if you're looking for
that maybe an investigation role
to see what you may have seen
while you were in there.
All right.
Solid, solid rating on this
investigation skill for me
with my minus two.
That's eleven actually.
And Nina has behind the desk.
There are a couple of
tall filing cabinets
and a small tea set
that was behind her.
It did appear that one
of the cabinets,
two of the lower shelves
that you would have seen
or been able to see
had some fairly sizable
locking hardware on them.
Is there a portrait
of Ronald Reagan?
That's how you know
that she's the bad guy.
There is a portrait of somebody
with a very poorly done toupee.
OK, I make a little mental note
of the locked cabinets.
You and Oak head back
to your office
and Oak says, well, it's time
to do that paperwork then
as you make small talk
back down to work.
Yeah, absolutely.
Should we go for lunch
before that?
Or like, what's the plan there?
Go for lunch.
You just got here.
OK, well, I mean,
just to show you
how much of a supervisor I am.
Let's go for lunch now
and then we'll do the paperwork
when we get back.
OK?
Awesome.
Dumbgeons and Dragons,
season three, episode 20,
starring Amy More as Alydin,
Carla Maxted as Bonwyn Everpain,
Tom Laird as Kavlarananan Goldweave,
Kyle Claset as Bizard the Wizard,
and Russ More as your dungeon master.
Dialogue editing by Carla Maxted
and sound design by Russ More.
This episode featured music
from Epidemic Sound and Slipstream
and sound effects from Epidemic Sound,
Boom Library and Sound Ideas.
Our amazing cover art and character designs
are by Matt Garbutt,
and a huge thank you
to our supporting producers,
Gabriel Lynch,
Jessica Babyok,
Cat Waterflame,
Jacob Madden,
Christian Brown,
Onger Ong Kiersen,
Perry Mady,
Craig Zeiss,
Old School Gamer D,
L.A. Branton,
Nathaniel Teeter,
and Aaron.
Do you feel like you're missing out
on more adventure?
Well, you can join us on Patreon
at Patreon.com slash dumb dragoncast,
where there's so much adventure.
An exclusive podcast called
The Adventures Of that has, well,
five seasons now going into our sixth season.
We've got Cyberpunk Red.
We've got the Session Zero
and Episode One comes out this week.
Tons of one shots, hangouts,
and so much more.
Come join us today
at Patreon.com slash dumb dragoncast.
Seven day free trial.
Get some merch.
It's a great time.
We'll hope to see you over there.
Okay, you have a great week.
Thanks for being here.
We'll talk to you soon.
We hear the town criers
throughout the streets.
Bonjour, bonjour, bonjour, bonjour.
Oh, damn it.
Sorry.
That's exactly what I pictured.
And I was like, wait,
we've literally already done that.
Yeah.
It's happened.
We're only 20 episodes in.
We can't replay that exact scene.
Damn it.
Sorry.
When you say the open.
The open sign.
Is turned around.
To show open or closed.
Open.
The open sign is visible within the window.
Okay.
Displayed.
The open sign is displayed clearly in the window.
Poor Russ.
Poor Russ dealing with two of us.
Cause I assume that's what you were asking too.
We're the worst.
Sorry, Russ.
I was like, I don't know.
I didn't know.
I was like, if it's open,
when I just come in,
I'm going to be like.
You're cautious.
You're a scam.
I am.
You don't just rush in.
You're a scam.
You're right.
I wouldn't just rush in.
But Amy needed to know
what direction the sign was pointing.
Fair.
Dumb Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.