Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
You are restrained by webbing.
Donnie will fly up and try and, like, chomp on one of them Spideys.
The target falls unconscious for one hour.
Nice.
So the eight wolves come in and swarm these two Ettercaps
and just churn out Ettercap meat.
It's just flying everywhere.
The spiders see this and flee into the trees and run away.
That makes me feel very gross.
It's a pretty solid plan on their part.
Well, let's keep going.
My wolves are coming with us.
No, you come to a large clearing where there is a lake at the base
of approximately 100 foot waterfall.
Well, I can't see in the dark, so I'd prefer not to fight at night.
So you turn around and you do see Lascaux come up behind.
Man and dragon take delay.
Wolves no common.
They're intelligent.
I am speaking very good.
I'm a wolf.
He speaks common, but he just isn't really a good talker.
So you guys hunker down and hide away.
Your wolves disappear.
Approximately an hour later, you hear a loud flapping of wings
and a bellowing roar emit from behind the waterfall.
And a large green dragon comes out, bursting from the waterfall,
water spraying everywhere with a dark figure on its back.
And it flies off into the night.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We are a fifth edition Actual Play podcast.
I'm your dungeon master, Russ More.
And with me today is Carla Johnson.
Hey, it's me.
I play Nulara Moonbrook.
And Tom Laird.
Hey, that's me.
I play Flint Firebeard.
And Amy More.
I'm also me and I play Thea Amastasia.
Hey, guys.
This episode is split into two episodes.
Yay!
We love D&D.
We just want to keep playing.
We played so good.
So good.
Fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
You guys are standing at the edge of this lake
that you've come upon at the base of this waterfall.
And this enormous green dragon with a rider on its back
emerged and flew off into the night.
Let's scoot.
Could you not have cast Hunter's Mark on one of them?
Just a question.
I don't care.
Would that have done anything?
It just would mean that it only lasts for an hour.
Never mind.
So probably he won't be back.
That's something you can do.
But I can do it once we see them, for sure.
That would get me a little bit of extra.
But good thinking.
Because I mostly forget I have spells at all.
So good thinking.
All right.
So we run up there.
We run up there.
And as we're running, I say it's about a 15-foot incline
climb to get into the cave.
And then it is a...
Human ladder.
Well, Flint has a ladder ladder.
So we could probably just use that.
I do have a ladder.
I mean, we could human ladder as well.
From what you saw, it is a steep, wet slope
getting into the next area that you saw there.
So you guys...
It's an up, and then it's a quick down, you guys.
Watch yourselves.
So you guys get up.
And if you're just climbing down,
everybody needs to make a dexterity check
or an acrobatics check or an athletics check.
Dexterity, acrobatics, or athletics?
Acrobatics or athletics.
OK.
15, 21.
Thaddeus with a 15 as well.
And a 19 for Flint.
OK.
20 for Flamingans.
And Laska will fuck it up for everybody.
Come on, he's a wolf.
He's got a lower center of gravity.
So you climb and crawl, sliding your way down,
and you descend down into...
You come to a corner, and looking around the corner,
you see it opens up into a large island chamber.
There is a lake of sorts with an island in the middle of it.
And that's all you can really see
from just peeking around the corner.
So you go further.
I whisper to...
Or no, Donnie can show these pictures to Nularaaaa.
Right?
Yeah, sure.
Gee, I'm just so she knows what's going on.
I feel like, is there a little rowboat,
and then there's a cup and something in the middle
that someone has to force someone else to drink,
and it saps their life essence?
No, not that.
No, no rowboats.
OK.
What about any robots?
Is Dumbledore here at all?
No.
What have we been playing this whole game for
if Dumbledore's not here?
I'm not sure.
Russ, how big is this underground lake?
Are you guys going in further,
or are you just looking from around the corner?
How far have you gone before I tell you how big the lake is?
I feel like we go into the chamber.
I mean, there's only one place to go.
You trying to be stealthy?
Yeah.
Everybody roll a stealth.
Thea goes in whistling.
And so does Flameykins.
We're actually singing a duet.
Wow.
That sounds right.
The bold choice.
What are you guys singing?
I've never been in a cave like this before.
Tell it, girls.
Sorry.
So you guys walk in,
and you see the pool in here, the lake in here.
The chamber itself has 40 foot high ceilings
set with all the massive stalactites
and smaller stalagmites set across the ground.
The pool is about the same,
just a little bit smaller than the lake outside,
so about 125 feet across.
And then there is a back wall that it goes to,
which is about another 120 feet.
But you step into the chamber,
and you are approached by a group of elf guards.
And they stand off to the side there
where you couldn't see them, naturally.
And they come up to you and say,
who are you?
What are you doing here?
I'm going to look at Thea, because she's, you know,
elves are real snobs.
I mean, Thea's cool, but come on.
She's got to be the one that talks to them, right?
Racially profiling me.
Oh, my God.
Okay, Thea tries to get over that.
And...
Come on, if we ran into dwarves,
we'd get Flynn to talk to them.
It's happened before.
He's got his belt, though.
He has, like, something special.
I've got nothing but my wits and boobs.
Look, we don't care about his belt.
Who are you? What are you doing here?
Hi, my name's Thea.
My name's Thea.
These are my friends.
I'm trying to be very charismatic and stuff.
And what are you doing here?
Aren't you supposed to be guarding the entrance?
We are guarding the entrance.
We didn't...
We weren't told that more people were coming.
What's the secret password?
Oh, please.
Are you kidding me right now?
Okay.
Bluff check.
That's all I want.
That's all I want to happen.
How many guards is there, Russ?
Nat 20.
Yeah, so, okay, you're right.
There was no secret.
What is this, clubhouse for children?
You do not even look like you're standing at the ready.
We're always ready.
If the boss gets wind of this, you know what he'll do.
What's the boss's name?
Are you fucking kidding me right now?
I slap him.
I step forward and I just backhand him.
Two of the other ones raise their spears,
and they're like, we need to know what...
We need to make sure that you're supposed to be here.
Who, who, who, who does...
Wait, are you an owl, too?
I'm an owl, too.
Tell us, who, who is, who is the boss here?
I feel like we thought I was the boss thing before.
This arc is called Who's the Boss, episode four.
Excellent.
The boss is Naren Vane, idiot.
They look a little taken aback because it appears that you may have got it right.
But they're like, all right, why are you here?
If the boss didn't tell you why we're here, you don't need to know.
Yeah, okay.
The other one, the one who's been the most quiet slaps him in the back of the head,
and he's like, don't get us in trouble.
Okay, fuck, we're just...
Okay, you just go, don't tell him, we just, don't tell him.
Don't tell him what?
Do you keep secrets from the boss?
Oh, God.
We don't, we don't want him to, don't want him to eat us.
Okay, okay.
I don't want to hear another word from any of you.
Yeah, okay.
And we just walk through.
Guys, we didn't have to kill them.
Yeah.
I want all my hit points.
I want all my hit points when I see the dragon.
No kidding.
Two of them get closer to the entrance where you assume they were supposed to be,
two of the other ones you notice go back to,
so you guys are walking into the room like this.
So to the left and further to the back wall, there is an open passageway,
and two of them go in that way.
Is that the only open passageway?
Yeah, what are the directions we can go in here?
So now that you've been allowed access, you see one,
so the open passageway to the left,
and then there is also another open passageway to the right that you can see.
Does Laska pick up any scent of Delaine or anything?
Good question.
Keen smell, keen senses.
Yeah, yeah, sure.
How do you want to ask that?
Well, quietly.
Where is he, boy?
If we need to go left or right, if there's a smell coming from one direction,
maybe we should go that one.
Laska points her nose to the right.
Subtly though.
Subtly.
Like just kind of like starts to walk in that direction and we all...
Yeah.
So you walk down a long narrow corridor,
and you come into a filthy chamber,
and you hear grunting and yelling and sounds like,
oh, quit touching me stuff, you stupid son of a bitch.
And you hear like things being thrown against the wall.
You come around and you see three large ettins.
Pictures.
What's that?
I don't know, but they sound like my grandpa.
It sounds like it was the page after Ettercap.
Yeah, you guys haven't noticed?
Before.
Russ has been taking us through alphabetically.
That's how we fight our monsters.
Okay.
New podcast, Tam Tam, the ABCs of D&D.
And you have to fight all the monsters in alphabetically.
Amy, that's a fun idea.
Thanks.
These guys.
Oh, he's got two heads.
Yeah.
Let me see.
So they each have two heads.
They're big ogre-looking creatures, and there are three of them.
So there are six heads in the room,
and there are six different voices all screaming,
I didn't touch your stuff, and you touched it, and I didn't.
And they hear you come in, and they all just quickly turn and look.
Who are you?
Well, we didn't touch your stuff.
I didn't say you touched my stuff.
You're in our room.
What are you doing in our room?
We're looking for the prisoner.
Oh, they're all prisoners.
What do you want with them?
We need to question one of them.
The biggest of them comes forward to you, and she is quite intimidating.
I didn't walk into the room and go, boys.
I thought about it.
She walks up to you, and she kind of stumbles over to you,
and you notice she's wearing a very nice belt kind of as a sash.
But she says, look, I forget what the question was.
But you got to tell me who you are and what you need with them prisoners,
or else I'm going to call up the boss and get all sorts of crazy up in here.
That's a really nice sash.
You look great.
Yes.
Everyone just kind of turns to look at you, Lara.
And everyone makes some ooh kind of noises.
Absolutely.
What is your object in saying that?
I'm just being nice.
No, I'm not just being nice.
Be on her good side.
A little bit, but also because you made note of it,
I'm wondering if it is like something,
if it is like a mark of rank or if it is like something that has been put on
them that is controlling them somehow.
You know, like if it's like a magical item or something.
Like some fucked up armor that might turn you into a zombie.
She looks down at her sash, her belt sash, and she says,
yeah, that's mine.
You keep your dirty, filthy human hands off of it.
I took it off of one of you pip squeaks.
It all looked the same to me.
I mashed him up and took his sash.
He wasn't wearing it right.
Well, I mean, gross, but you look great.
You look great.
Make a deception check.
No need to.
Hey, maybe she does look great, Russ.
I just showed you the picture.
Are you sure?
Okay, I'll do a deception check.
No need to.
No need to get worried over here.
I rolled an 11.
So she doesn't seem that like picked up on keyed into social cues.
I'm sure she bought it.
She kind of scoffs at you.
She's like, you're making fun of me.
What are you saying?
No, we're not making fun of you.
We need to question one of the filthy human captives that you have here.
Never heard one of you say they were filthy.
You've never heard an elf say that?
I move my hair back and I'm like.
Oh, yeah.
All right.
Go on in there.
Pointy hair motherfucker.
Just let you stroll into the prisoners area.
Sure.
Yeah.
Whatever.
She being sarcastic.
Is that genuine?
I know.
Sounds like you're being sarcastic.
She points her hand to an open doorway to the left.
Naren Vane is an elf, so.
Yeah.
And the guards were too.
So like, it seems like, is it racist or speciesist of it for me to always think
the creatures that seem dumb are like lower caste creatures?
They kind of seem just put to work.
Like we were told to sit here and stare at the danger door.
Like it makes me uncomfortable to think that.
I don't think that, but like, yeah, like there seems like there's a hierarchy in this
world based on intelligence.
It's definitely a thing in D&D that some classes or some races think that they're
higher up.
So playing into that if, yeah, it's like how like high elves are like incredibly
racist.
So if we play into that, then that's like we've got an elf with us.
It's a good thing in this case.
As you guys, I assume, are just walking down the hallway.
Yeah.
Yeah, I say thank you, friend.
I'll make sure to mention this to the boss.
Flamikins Kins kind of waddles up behind.
She looks behind the big one.
She's like, hey, hey, he's stealing your shit over there.
And the big one turns around.
She's like, what the fuck are you doing over there?
And she takes this huge club that she has and just starts wailing on the other one.
Oh, my God.
And then they all start kind of wrestling about and you guys rush out of the room
down the hall.
But they are currently engaged in battle with each other.
OK.
Yeah.
Like in Flamikins Kins.
I know.
It's good.
So you walk down another narrow corridor and come to a door.
It's a rickety wooden door.
Can I receive any traps or any sort of?
It's been kind of piecemealed together from scraps that have been found in the area.
Doesn't mean it can't be booby trapped.
Sure.
Go for it.
Investigate.
I'm going to investigate the shit out of this.
18.
No, it's just a door.
Nice.
I reach forward.
I'm going first now, I guess.
I reach forward and I open the door.
You open the door and inside you see about a dozen elves and one human in varying
states of beatenness.
Some look like they are being more well kept than others.
Others look like they are being used as a dragon chew toy.
Is Delaine the human?
Delaine is the human.
Yes.
Yay.
I made boo.
It's not good.
But yeah.
We found him.
How dare he get captured before we could meet up.
Rude.
Laska goes over and is checking on Delaine who seems to be unconscious at the moment.
But they all seem like they're prisoners, yes?
To make a fair guess, you would say they're all prisoners.
You see similar clothing and insignias or markings to some of the elves that you
saw around Altund and others bear clothing that you haven't seen yet.
So the elves, all of them are elves except for Delaine and they all stand up and kind
of hold their weapons.
They were allowed to keep weapons?
Yep.
They have weapons and they hold them and say, what are you doing here?
Friends, put down your weapons.
We're here to help.
I make sure the door is shut behind me.
Not that they could probably hear over there.
It's all muffled.
What do you mean help?
Well, do you want to be here?
No, but we don't necessarily want to leave because the dragon will come and find us and
kill us.
Okay, die now.
Die later.
It's up to you.
And I start walking forward toward Delaine.
And they half step forward to you and half step away from you.
Like, should we stop her?
Like, that's the kind of feeling you're getting from them.
Are you guys guards?
Are you guys secret guards?
Are you?
I mean, we were brought...
You guys work for this monster.
What is happening in here?
We were brought here.
Who are you?
My name is Thea.
We're here to save the fucking day, motherfuckers.
And she beats her chest.
I love her.
Are you from Altend?
Yes, some of us are, yes.
Others from other settlements that have been attacked.
We were just there.
Yep, we sure were.
We saw Galen.
We saw Gallenden.
We ate some beefy stew.
Of course, beefy stew.
How was the stew?
Did it suffer in quality since we've been attacked?
No.
Do I still have any of the breakfast stew to go that I had that Gallen didn't want?
Do you?
I don't know.
It's been a couple days.
Probably not.
It's probably not very good if you do, but...
Yeah, fair enough.
Yep.
Well, that Galen, he's a piece of work, isn't he?
How do you mean?
Oh, well, I mean, sure, he's the only reason why your settlement is still standing,
but he is giving secret information about the protection of other places in the forest
and essentially throwing them under the bus.
Great kind of guy.
Not sure you want to go back there specifically,
but hopefully the judicial system will get him.
Can we go to our friend and see if he's all right?
Yeah, they've let you by.
Oh, okay, good.
Okay, I keep walking to Delaine.
I had a feeling like half of them were still like...
No, they're still uncertain about you, but they're like,
yeah, I mean, we know that he's the one who made the deal,
but it was to save our people.
At the expense of others.
Whatever, that's not what we're here for.
I'm not judging.
I've done, you know, sketches.
We've all tied people up and thrown them in rivers.
It's fine.
Water under the bridge, am I right?
I love it.
Okay, let's go see Delaine because I feel like he knows stuff
and I want him to be better before we get into any fights.
How hurt does Delaine seem?
He seems pretty beat up.
I'm going to give him my rare healing potion.
What if I just hit him with a Cure Wounds there, Amy?
Yeah, do that one.
As Thaddeus.
Yeah, Thaddeus can do that kind of thing.
Yeah, Thaddeus is going to cast Cure Wounds.
Okay.
Yeah, do that.
As a second level spell slot, so he'll get an extra DA.
Six and seven is 13 plus spell cast modifier of two, so 15.
So some of the some of the wounds heal up and he comes back to
comes back to consciousness there and he looks around.
Fuck, it was his voice.
Everybody's a gruff old man in this.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons where Russ plays many gruff old men.
We'll change his voice.
What do you people do?
No, no, no.
Thea cannot be attracted to a man with a voice more ephemeral than hers.
I was attacked by a dragon and now I sound like this.
I like the voice though, but I definitely would have remembered if that was Delaine's voice.
No, it was something just like, what are you guys doing here?
No, he doesn't say, what are you guys doing here?
Oh, it's good to see you guys here.
Fuck.
Shit.
I'm from the woods.
Delaine.
I feel his forehead.
I'm like, are you feverish?
I'm almost eaten by a dragon.
Is he like well buffed up in his health?
Like we're about to fight a dragon, so I just feel like he should probably be at full capacity here.
He reaches into his fanny pack, for lack of a better term.
Fanny pack of holding.
And pulls out a potion and he appears to be ready to go.
Cool.
And he's like, what, how did you, did you kill the dragon already?
How did you guys get this far?
We snuck in here while he took off for his nightly stroll.
Good thinking, good thinking.
I get by on my charms.
I give him a little wink.
Yeah.
Alright.
You have to say that you did that.
You can't just, you can't just do it.
He winks awkwardly.
Was it ever awkward?
With like a grimace and his like, hasn't seen.
But is Thea like, whoo, fans herself?
Yes, please.
It's been a while.
I don't want to speak for you, Thea, but I think you're into it.
So dang hot out today.
Boy howdy.
Yeah, you feeling better?
Cause that dragon's going to be back like pretty quick.
And I think we're probably going to have to like try to fight him.
Do you know anything?
Like it seems like it's Narenvain.
Oh yeah.
I mean, it's probably, yeah, yeah.
It's definitely Narenvain.
Yeah.
I haven't seen much of this layer here.
Maybe one of these.
If you talk to these motherfuckers standing around with their swords out.
See if we get like a.
Some sort of escape hatch.
Some sort of press the button and run type of thing or.
Well, do we really want to run?
We have an opportunity to end this here.
We want to kill the dragon.
He's killing people all.
Like he's just destroying settlements.
We want to stop him.
Okay.
You down?
And I just look around like you guys in?
Fuck.
You want to maybe save your whole civilization or your whole.
All your friends.
Your family.
Okay.
Other guys here.
You like work here and shit.
And they're like, yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, he took us prisoner, but they let us kind of mill about.
Good.
So what the fuck are we working with here?
And they go on to explain that there are the three Etans.
There are among them.
There are the people in the room.
There are six other.
Cult members, specifically cult members who have been seen.
In the lair.
Humans.
Yep.
Okay.
And then Naren Vane and.
They say Cuth, who is the dragon.
So are the other elf guards at the entrance that we saw also kind of like.
Quasi prisoner guards.
Like they've been taken prisoner, but are being forced to work there as well.
Yes.
Yeah.
We have all been taken captive from various settlements and.
Are told to guard.
Cuth's lair.
When he is not here.
And when they are done with us.
They feed us to him.
Of sorts.
Well, that sounds real bad.
Sounds not good.
We should we should probably like kill this dragon.
What do you guys say?
Fuck I'm doing it.
What are you guys waiting for?
Try to kill the dragon or just wait around to get eaten.
Those are your options.
Solid choices.
Doesn't seem like a hard choice to me.
Okay.
Yeah.
We'll we'll be right behind you.
Lot of faith in you.
Got a lot of faith in you guys.
Do you know the like the layout of this cavern?
Where does Cuth sleep?
What's the schedule?
You guys are like running this this at a low level kind of way.
So fill us in.
We we haven't been able to explore the entire.
There are some areas that they don't allow us to be.
Cuth has his main lair underneath the the the pool in the in the main chamber area.
If you go beneath the pool and into another area that is where his chamber is.
Off of that are Narenvane's chambers.
And from the front area the passageway to the left is where the cultists is where the cultists are.
I say we wait in Narenvane's chambers.
Wouldn't it be great to battle him separately from the dragon?
Yes.
Once he gets up on that dragon, it's gonna be a little harder to.
Are we gonna kill him?
Well, I think we seems like a pretty bad dude.
But I definitely he's been missing for a long time and it seems like I mean, he's riding the dragon, so he must have.
Let's do what we always do.
We'll try to take him prisoner, but realistically, we'll probably kill him.
OK, fair enough. Good.
It's just the old usual.
I'll have the usual, please.
How do we get into Narenvane's chamber?
How can we do it without the cultists knowing?
Well, Narenvane's chamber is you have to go through the cultists area to get to his chamber.
Do the cultists ever leave their chambers?
Are they Brian Wilson? They just like hang out in there constantly?
They throughout the night, they're generally in there the whole whole night.
They mostly only leave to go out on raids.
What about the three Eddins? Are they loyal to the dragon or are they just doing their own thing and they're also prisoners?
Oh, Flameykins could probably help with this.
Flameykins, don't you have a spell that could potentially change the way some of us look to help get us past?
Oh, fuck, guys, I got a disguise spell, I think.
Oh, yeah, yeah. She cast a spell on us before.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
Seeming.
Yeah, we got seeming. We can.
I mean, we can make us look like bushes.
Does that work?
Not quite what I was thinking.
To go back to your other question, the Eddins are here to help protect Kuth's horde.
They, as you may have seen from the ruckus still coming from out there, they they hate each other,
but will fight to protect Kuth and what Kuth has here.
What does Kuth have here that's so important?
His horde, his treasure, whatever dragons love to...
General dragon horde, there's not anything like in particular that anyone knows about?
Not that we are aware of, no.
OK, well, it seems like what we'll need to do is cause some kind of distraction
to get the cultists out of their chambers and then like scoot in there and scoot on in.
Or we could all look like cultists.
But can we do that or can we only look like bushes?
No, we can look like anything.
Oh, OK.
Do you guys still have cult clothes?
No, that was like four years ago.
I mean, OK.
Just been carrying around.
Checking, checking.
The spell allows.
Well, I mean, Thea has a pretty awesome bag of holding that holds a lot of stuff,
so it could just have cult clothes in there.
That's true. We could have kept that stuff in there.
It could have.
That seems actually pretty reasonable.
Where we all look like different people.
God.
I think that...
It's up to you.
I could potentially have a bag of holding that has a bunch of extra different clothes in it.
It doesn't say if I do or don't.
Sure would hate for anything to happen to that bag of holding.
I know, right?
Seems like that bag of holding is really just holding everything together.
Ever.
How would you like to help us defeat the dragon the easiest way possible?
Sounds pretty good, right?
Sounds like easy.
Sounds almost too good to be true.
Almost too good to be true.
What would you have us do?
We would like to get into Naren Vane's chamber.
Our group and any of you that are willing to come help fight.
But we need to get the cultists out of their chambers so we can get in there.
So we need you and the other elf guards to create a distraction.
To start a fire or something to raise the alarm so that the cultists will leave their chambers and we can slip in.
Or a big brawl of some kind.
Can you do that?
Oh, or a big...
See, but I think...
Yeah, that's good.
Yep, yep, yep.
You know, like descent among the ranks.
Make a persuasion check, please.
14.
So the elf, main elf you've been talking to says, okay, so we will make a distraction.
But we don't want to fight the dragon.
We don't feel we would be helpful in that instance.
That's understandable.
We will do our best to draw the cultists out so you can get in there.
But I don't, I can't fight with you.
Fair enough.
Yep, sounds good.
So a few of them pick up their weapons and straighten their clothes.
And they open the door and walk out.
And you hear the Etans hollering and still wailing on each other.
And it sounds like it's kind of dying down a little bit.
And you hear mumbling from the elves as they kind of are just like, okay, yeah, we're just going to go swap stations.
And the Etans don't even look at them, really.
And they go out into the main chamber.
Where are you guys waiting?
Are you waiting in that prisoner chamber?
Are you kind of following behind them a little bit?
I think we have to kind of follow them because we need to be like, we need to find a place to like, you know, we need to be right there.
Tuck away so that when they all run out, we can like run in basically, right?
Yeah, so you follow them to the entrance to where the main area is.
And they tell you to wait there.
And they go over to where the other elves were guarding the front door.
And you hear some low murmuring.
And then you hear hollering from them saying, they're over here.
They're trying to break in.
They're over here.
And you hear the footsteps of cultists coming down the hallway.
And they run out towards them.
And they're like, they just ran back out the waterfall.
We need to go stop them.
They stole stuff from Cuth.
And everybody in that group goes up the slope.
And you hear them go out past the waterfall.
Hey there. I'm your Dungeon Master, Russ More.
Thank you for joining us for episode 37 of Dumbgeons and Dragons, titled Knock Knock Anyone Home, Part 2.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
There you can sign up and get in on some amazing perks.
And we are like 70% of the way to our second goal.
And when we hit that, there will be a Patreon exclusive giveaway.
And we've just added a new tier.
So if you've been there already and weren't sure, maybe check it out again, because something might speak to you more this time.
Some rewards for patrons of Dumbgeons and Dragons include the amazingly fun Patreon bonus episodes,
which will be starting a new story in the next couple months using the fake core system.
So there will soon be a bingeable contained story,
DM'd by Tom, plus all the new monthly episodes that will continue to roll out.
And for patrons $5 and up, you can get in on the monthly gook hangs,
where you can hang out with us and chat about the show and the game and anything else that you can think of.
Supporting us on Patreon makes the show better with each episode and allows us to do new, awesome and cool things for you.
Really hope you have a chance to check it out.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
The next episode will be out next week, and we are back on regular schedule for April 25th.
And boy, is it going to be a big one.
Let's go see how sneaky the group can be as they make their way further into Kuth Slayer.
Super sneaky. That's always the answer.
Have a great week and we'll talk to you soon.
Let's let's scoot.
Yeah, sneak in past into the chamber of the.
So you go down that another narrow corridor which goes off to the left and it looks like a kind of a common room.
There are long tables, split logs where it looks like they used to to eat and there's a burnt out cooking fire.
And then to the right, there is it looks like they're they're sleeping quarters.
There's rough bunks and bedrolls and backpacks in this area.
We walk on through.
To the right, there is an open passageway.
You go into the room and off to the right and it oh and it goes back down a long narrow hall,
which there is a right turn and then you can go a little bit further and it ends in a dead end.
But there's a left turn.
So they told you that you had to go off to the right where Naren Vein's chambers are and you go down another long corridor
and you enter into what looks to be created as a lush living space in this rough walled cavern.
There are select art and craft works that look to be elven nature.
Rich carpets and tapestries that cover the floors and the walls.
And there's a large feature, a hewn log bed and a large mirror and trunk in this room.
I look around for any good stuff.
Well, you know, like we've got a little bit of time.
I peek inside the trunk.
You peek inside the trunk?
Yeah, just kind of like, you know, moving around.
Okay.
What if it's a trap, Thea?
No, you did it.
No, it's totally fine.
This is funny.
So, you go to lift.
They can't help herself, she's a snooze.
You lift the, you go to lift the trunk and acid splashes from it.
Oh my god.
Well, she had her shield out, so it's fine.
And you take everybody within 20 feet of it, which is everybody.
Oh my god, I'm so sorry.
Takes 5d8 acid damage.
Oh my god.
Fuck, that's a lot of damage.
I'm so sorry.
That's fine.
So that is 20 acid damage to everybody.
Holy shit.
And as that happens.
Everyone shoots Thea.
Super dirty luck.
A dirty luck.
She shoots Thea.
So everybody is reeling from this damage that you have taken.
And, I mean, inside the trunk.
Okay, sorry, I'm going to be a dick.
I'm going to be a dick.
I'm going to use my, I'm going to use a lucky.
There's no attack against it, it just happens.
Yeah, it's not like you rolled anything, so adding extra dice to it is not going to solve any problem.
We weren't looking for anything, so.
Is there something good in the trunk, at least?
Did we find some rad shit?
Are you kidding me? It's empty?
No, it's not empty.
In the trunk.
Oh, sorry, you all are poisoned.
I'm not.
Yeah, you're not.
But everybody else is.
Yeah, in there, there's, it looks to be, there's a whole, there's more art and more gold.
I mean, looking at it, it looks to be a total worth of about 1,500 gold pieces.
Oh, I take all that gold I put into my bag.
Much of it you recognize as potential property of the elves in the forest.
Put it into my bag of holding.
Okay.
To give back to them when we're done.
Naturally.
But I didn't get 20 damage acid all over my beautiful face.
So you guys are looking around and maybe going to make some investigation checks?
I'd like to open the chest.
Oh, wait, no, you already did.
A cautionary tale.
Can anybody magical detect magic anywhere?
See if there's any like, I don't know, is this a magic mirror?
What do we, what are we working with here?
I can't detect magic.
I can't.
And I can't remember.
Okay, I go outside.
I can remember if you could.
I can detect magic.
I cast detect magic.
Sure.
Yeah.
You, you sense that there may have been some sort of glyph of warding casted on the trunk.
Cast on the trunk.
But otherwise there are no other magical items in this room.
Who the fuck was that idea like 30 seconds ago?
Russ.
I would like to go back outside of the room with Thaddeus and like back to where the
junction is to come to Naren Payne's room.
And a little bit, yeah, a little bit down that path.
I'd like to cast the alarm spell and make it a mental alarm.
So that way if anybody walks through that area, I find out about it.
Yeah, for sure.
Okay.
You do that.
Yeah, everybody make an investigation check while you're looking around this room.
Thea's not sure she wants to look around the room anymore.
Remember when we all wanted to have all our hit points?
Totally.
So sorry.
16.
That's real bad.
14 for Flint.
I rolled a four.
I rolled a four, so I see nothing.
Thea, you're looking around and you find what looks to be behind one of the larger
art pieces in the back of the room, a secret passageway that opens into another candle
lit chamber.
Hey guys, there's a secret passageway back here.
Are we going to get more acid splashed on us?
Only one way to find out.
Flint, after you.
Yeah, we can tiptoe in there if you want.
So you guys go into this other room.
It's smaller than the last one.
It's about 30 feet by about 15 feet.
And inside you see a small shrine to Fenmeril Mesterine, who Thea you know as the elven
god of outcasts, scapegoats, and solitude, which resembles a pair of white eyes peering
out from the dark wall above a small basin.
You look around this room some more and you see a journal present in this room at
a small desk off to the side.
Dear Diary, I ran away from my family today and started my own thing in the forest.
Dear Diary, if you're reading this, acid in your face.
Everybody takes it.
Is anybody picking up the diary or journal?
Thea's not too sure she wants to touch it.
Is she still detector reading magic?
There is no magic coming off of it.
Well, you can probably read Elvish, so...
I pick up the book and I open it.
You skim through the book and make an investigation.
Give me your investigation check to see how fast you're reading through.
So you pick out quite a lot from this book.
And it reveals, in fact, that Nerenvane is, in fact, King Melandric's lost son,
who Nerenvane frequently throughout his writings refers to as my poor father.
The journal also reveals in some of the later writings that the green dragon mask
is already at the Well of Dragons under Severn's protection
and ready to be assembled into the mask of the Dragon Queen.
And as you guys are reading this, you hear from the front screams
echoing down the halls from some of the elves.
They're faint because you guys are further in.
But you hear the loud roar of Kuth entering back into his lair.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin MacLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.