previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We're gonna keep going a little rock
and save B.A. Baracus.
Wait, did you say B.A. Baracus?
Yeah.
They brought with them something evil.
You see footsteps leave the house
and they run straight for the forest.
It's me, Lent, I'm over here.
Can you help, help me?
Of course we can help you.
Hops on and holds onto the saddle
and guacamole takes off
and you hear a little yee-haw-haw,
as he's going up into the air
and then flies away.
To the cave.
There are two people.
We already got little Lent home.
Lent died a while ago.
Oh, this isn't good, guys.
Russ, you made the kid be the bad guy.
Always with this shit, Russ.
The eye instruct guacamole to take us
to where she dropped off Lent.
And drops you at the front door.
We've really messed this one up.
Go upstairs and there is more of the mist
that you saw in the room with Sasha.
And it's coming out of one of the bedrooms
and you can hear inside singing.
There is no time for singing.
Lock the door, blow out the light.
The hungry only, it's the night.
I'm gonna have nightmares now.
That's a lovely ditty, you teacher.
You're like, dudes, this ain't normal.
The little girl stands up and begins to shift shape.
Ah, the fuck, yeah, she does.
Thea just came to a realization.
What's that?
If the mist was the girl, where else did we see mist?
At Baran's place, his sister is another one
of those stupid Onis.
Sasha swings at Baran and she begins
to take form of another Oni.
There was something that we were doing wrong before.
Oh yeah, initiative.
You guys have an initiative modifier.
Did you know that?
News to me.
I don't even know what this is.
I don't even know what you're saying.
Yeah, like when you roll for initiative,
you have like a plus that apparently
you should have been doing for the last two years.
Wow.
And I just opened my character sheet
and it's just right there in the middle, hey?
Like armor class, initiative, speed.
I don't have anything in that initiative.
I know, because we hadn't been using one,
but I was reading through some weird little
small paragraph on initiatives
and it's your dexterity modifier.
And then as that goes up,
your initiative modifier goes up.
Oh, my dexterity is one, my initiative is one.
Yours is one.
So when you roll, you just add one.
Well, that's really easy math for me.
I can also handle that math.
I think it's best if we learn how to play D&D,
one rule every six months.
I think by the time we are all in our late 50s,
we are going to know this game inside and out.
That's right.
I mean, by then they'll be on like 12th edition, but.
Yeah, there's just gonna be new rules every time.
Oh, God.
Well, they change.
No, we'll be old school and we'll be like,
edition five for life, six for life.
Five?
Five for life.
Say for life one more time.
For life.
Let's make sure we know what edition it is
before we get those matching tattoos.
That's right. Good call.
Amy's got edition 12 already.
No, Amy always jumped in the gun.
She's trying to future proof her tattoo.
It's just good thinking.
Hey, don't touch my dice.
I didn't touch your dice.
You touched my.
Wait, Russ, did you touch her dice?
I touched her dice.
Not cool, bro.
Not cool.
All of them, guys.
All of them.
Some sort of curse on my dice.
So, you guys are standing in the middle
of the living room of this house
and Sasha has just transformed into the other Oni
and it has given Baran a slice on the neck
and he's down on the ground.
Cause that's what happens when the man disrespects.
He probably touched her dice.
Roll for initiative.
And I will.
And use your modifier.
Plus one.
Three.
Eight.
Thank God for that.
Initiative modifier.
Holy crap.
That could have been a really bad roll, you guys.
11 for me.
Wow.
Good thing initiative doesn't really matter.
Yeah.
That's my feeling toward it.
It's like, oh, who cares if I go last?
When we're fighting one creature,
I don't think it matters as much.
When there's like 10, it's more important.
But with one, it's fine.
We got a movement.
It's fine, guys.
It's totally fine.
Plus we've already murdered an Oni, so.
So Flint, you are up first, good sir.
So same sort of Oni as last time.
It appears to be the same sort of Oni.
He looks bigger than the other Oni.
Okay.
Cause why not?
Sure.
Bigger they are, harder they fall, et cetera, et cetera.
Looks to be the same sort of Oni race that you can tell.
Okay.
I guess I will rush it with the old greataxe I've got.
So it's 23.
23 versus AC is good.
Excellent.
Six and 11, nice.
17 and four is 21.
And second attack.
That is a 11.
11 is not gonna do it for you.
All right.
New Lara, you're up next.
Looks like the Oni had a bad initiative roll too.
That is 21.
21's good, yep.
So that is 10 damage on that one.
Second is 20.
What'd you hit him with?
Oh, my flaming sword.
Oh, of course.
I should have said it's just the only weapon I use
unless I'm on a boat and I'm not allowed.
No more boats guys, we're walking everywhere.
Definitely no more boats.
So only eight damage on that one.
Donnie wants to get in on this too.
He gets a 13.
13 is not gonna do it.
Okay.
It is the Oni's turn.
So how I'm picturing this in the room is
the room is about 20, 25 feet.
So not a big room,
but you guys are reasonably clumped
trying to attack the Oni I'm picturing.
Correct me if I'm wrong.
Well, I mean, it's a living room, right?
It can't be too, too big.
No, no.
So the room suddenly goes dark.
Darker than anything you have ever seen
or experienced and you can't see anything.
Not even if I have dark vision.
Surprisingly not even that you have dark vision.
Am I blind?
You don't think you're blind.
Oh, okay.
No, it's just an aura of complete blackness
and darkness has encircled the three of you.
Like the cone of silence, but the cone of darkness.
Yes, so soon as this happens,
you can feel the presence
of the Oni moving quickly past you
and you hear glass smash from what you assume
is the front window of the house.
And it sounds like he is running away from you.
And now it's Thea's turn.
Okay, so the Oni essentially like threw a smoke bomb
down and like ran away.
We're like, where did he go?
I produce flame in my hand.
Working for you.
You don't see anything.
I see nothing.
Okay, guys, like if I call anything,
I'm just gonna end up hitting air buddy.
I don't think you should tackle air buddy.
No, I don't want.
Thea summons lightning and just kills everyone.
No!
That's pretty much what I'm thinking.
So I take my turn to run toward where I hear him.
Okay, so you run.
Like carefully, I run, you know, like when you can't see.
Okay, so yeah, you're just,
you're walking carefully towards the window
and you get to where you feel the window is.
Make a dexterity check.
15 plus.
One.
Oh, yeah, one.
You get to the edge of the window
and you feel it before you cut yourself on the glass.
Are you going through the window?
Sure.
You jump through the window
and as you get about five feet from the house,
the darkness disappears.
Oh, good.
Okay.
Do I see the Oni anywhere?
Make.
Puffing it down the street.
Make a dexterity check.
Whoa.
Six and.
Two, eight.
You have a feeling that he ran off to the left
down the street.
See a couple open doors in some other places.
Okay, well, I'm not gonna fight anything
and I'm pretty sure, have I run my 30 feet yet?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, then that's all I got.
I yell to the other guys,
come on, I can see shit out here.
Probably in my Thea voice.
Come on guys, see stuff out here.
Back to Flint.
All right, so I'm also currently kind of blinded.
Yes, sir.
All right.
And I hear Thea yell out,
so I think the sound's coming from one way,
so I try to get into that direction.
Okay, so you start to move.
Make a dexterity check as you approach the window there.
Okay.
That is a 14.
You do the same thing.
You go and you find the window sill.
You manage to get out of the window
without cutting yourself on anything.
So yeah, you get out into the street
and as you get to about the same spot where Thea was,
things are still pitch black for you.
Thea, things, as Flint gets closer to you,
things get darker again and New Lara, you can see.
God damn it.
You and your Trixie puzzle.
I am the source of darkness, everybody.
Yes, Flint.
Or it's when two of us are,
like it's a mass.
Oh, could be.
Like there's two of you.
Could be.
Oh, but Flint has never been able to see,
so not even as, oh no, because he was,
because he was with you or he was with you.
But I guess, is it my turn now?
Unless Flint wants to do anything else, but yes.
Yeah, I guess if I can't see, I'm pretty much done.
Oh, but I can see now.
So I go to where they are
and at what point can't I see, Russ?
So Flint has moved about,
Flint has moved his full move 30 feet.
So he and Thea are in the same kind of zone area.
You go about 15 feet, New Laura,
and things start to go dark again.
So just as you leave the house
is when things start to go dark
as you get closer to Thea and Flint.
Okay, so I say, guys, I could see,
but now I can't see again.
Can you see?
That guy, bitch.
So no, Ben.
I can't see over here.
So we have to do an experiment
to see what it is, right?
Like if it's Flint or if it's us being together
that makes us not be able to see.
Okay, so maybe let's all back up to,
you said 15 feet from each other until,
like let's just back up until we get our vision back.
All right, well, how about I stand still?
Okay, yeah, sure.
Oh yeah, that makes sense.
And then you guys back up.
Yeah, you do that and you find,
New Laura, you can see at about 15 feet
from where you think Flint is.
And Thea, you can see at about 15 feet
from where Flint is, but Flint, you can't see.
Okay, Flint, you stay there
and then me and Thea will get together.
Let's see what happens.
Okay.
You guys get together and you can see just fine.
We high five.
Yeah.
Sorry, buddy.
Was that a high five I heard?
Yeah, sorry about it.
It's like it's you.
It's all right, guys.
You hear from a house down the street,
a ruckus of sorts, some clatter of shelves
and furniture and stuff being knocked over.
Not a ruckus.
Okay, I throw-
Thea's turn.
I throw my rope to,
I'm gonna walk you like a dog.
I throw my rope- Amazing.
To Flint and I say, you know,
hold on to this, buddy.
You can't see anything.
And I would assume that I would run toward the clatter
but I'm bringing Flint with me.
Okay.
So we'll just say that you-
Let's like as a group maybe, can we all just run?
I feel like we're not just gonna leave you behind.
No, yeah, you run to the house where you hear the noise
and you step in and it's laid out very much the same
as the other house.
You don't see anything
in the immediate front entry slash living area.
Okay, so maybe they are upstairs.
That's the place we found the first Oni.
So I pass the rope to Nularaaa.
Can I ask a question?
Yeah.
Can Donnie see?
Like can Donnie fly over to Flint and see if he can see?
Donnie flies to Flint and he loses sight as well.
Okay.
Well, in addition to our rope leash,
if Donnie stays 15 feet away,
he could also help Flint see telepathically.
So he won't like trip and shit.
So we don't need to watch him so close.
Yep.
Right? Good idea.
Yeah.
And the rope is 20 feet long.
So, so long as it stays taut.
Little bit of slack though.
Yeah.
Little bit of slack.
Of course, of course.
It is, we'll say it is Flint's turn.
Yep.
I just do whatever they're doing
because I'm tied up by a rope.
Nularaaa's turn.
Okay.
And we can't hear any more noise
now that we're in the house.
Now that you're in the house, make a perception check.
Okay.
That is a 10.
I can't even remember if I get bonuses to that.
Do I get a bonus to that?
You should.
How do you play D&D again?
I've already forgotten.
With difficulty.
Great difficulty.
Oh, perception.
It's right there.
So 15.
You see some of the furniture.
So when you're in the front of the house,
there's a hallway that goes straight
to the back of the house.
You see the edge of a shelf that has been knocked over
going out towards the back of the house.
Okay.
I guess we go that way.
It seems like that's the way the destruction is going.
You get into the kitchen and you don't see anything there
but that's about as far as you can move.
And as you step into the kitchen,
make a dexterity saving throw.
Okay.
I will.
21.
Yeah.
So dexterous.
You jump out of the way as the Oni's glaive cuts down
in front of you.
So you miss getting hit off of his first swing
but he swings again and gets a 24 against your AC.
Well, that'll do it.
And that will be 10 slashing damage to you.
Okay.
Since all I've done is move on my turn,
do I get to try and stab him now?
Take an action.
Okay.
Oh, well that was a critical fail.
So nope.
Let's just ignore that.
I'll cut that out.
That's fine.
No, I get my second attack now.
Come on.
What's your attack?
Oh, 18.
18 is good.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I was so scared.
I just tripped the first time.
That's right.
That seems reasonable.
Save because it was five is 11.
Damage.
Russ.
I forgot what we were calculating here.
Russ was just saying that like,
yes, okay, 11.
And then I like poked him like,
damn, right down.
You're the only one keeping him honest, Amy.
So thank you.
You're welcome.
Your turn.
Okay.
Well, obviously I hear that ruckus.
I like want to,
I like, I don't want Flint to run away.
Like, I want to tie him to like a chair like-
You can just tell me to stand still.
Okay, Flint, please, please stand still.
Right.
You're not my pet.
So I say, Flint, I'm running left into the kitchen.
There's been an incident.
I don't know.
Maybe, maybe Donnie can like to pass you some images
of what the fuck is happening.
Totally.
Now was it a spaghetti incident?
Okay, good.
Cause we do not want another one of those.
I know.
So I run into the kitchen and I feel like it,
are they, are they jammed at the front entrance
of the kitchen?
Am I able to get a clear shot at the only?
You can, you can get into the kitchen
to be able to attack.
Okay, very cool.
Then I will attack.
I will attack with my flaming sphere.
Okay.
I'm gonna burn this whole mother down.
Ha ha ha ha.
Okay.
Yeah, I throw that thing at his chest.
Five, eight, 11.
Okay.
So because it's such a small spot though,
and now he's giving it to me.
Well, hold on, we can switch it if you want to.
Because it's such a small area
and because new Lara is engaged in combat,
you can do that,
but she will have to make a saving throw
to see if she can get out of the way.
No, I'll change my thing.
I take out my,
I'm just gonna try to,
how much damage was it?
If it wasn't tons of damage,
then I can risk a saving throw.
Eh, it was 11.
But I mean, I could do the same with a dagger
and I would get,
I don't want to hurt you.
Join the club.
Did Flynn get too close to you again?
Ha ha ha.
You're funny.
I'm just gonna, yeah, I'm just gonna run up
and stab, I'm gonna run up and stab with a dagger.
Sure.
A 10 plus five, 15.
That is not good.
Damn, oh wow, at least I didn't hurt new Lara.
Thanks homegirl.
As you go to do this attack though,
he moves out of the way.
Flint, you see the darkness flicker away,
but it comes back.
And Flint, your turn.
All right, so I'm guessing if it flickered a bit,
it's either, well, the Oni is busy
being distracted by them.
He can't quite concentrate as much
or the time in the spell is running out.
So I guess I should probably just stay put
until I can see a little bit.
Okay.
I cheer them on.
I say, you're doing great, guys.
Back to new Lara.
Perfect.
That is a 14.
Probably won't do it.
14's not good.
But a 28 probably will.
28 will be good, yep.
So that is an eight plus three is 11,
plus five is 16 damage.
And Donny's gonna try and bite him too.
I forgot to get Donny to go last time.
That's a 19.
A 19's good.
And he gets five damage.
Oh wait, there was something,
remember I was doing his damage wrong.
He needed an extra D.
Plus three.
Oh, it's just a plus three, not a plus two.
So sorry, Donny got six damage
and the Oni needs to do a saving turn.
15.
Yeah, that'll do it.
He took some damage on that
and Flint, once he takes that damage,
you get your vision back.
It appears whatever spell around you has now disappeared.
Sweet.
We can say that you just,
because you didn't do anything,
you just deferred your turn.
So you can take your turn.
That would be much smarter.
You can take your turn at any point.
So if you want to go now, you can,
or if you want to wait till after it's turn, your call.
I'm going to defer till after it's turn.
It's turn is now,
and it is going to attack with its glaive.
First at New Lara,
and that is a 19 against a C.
That will do it.
18 slashing damage.
Sheesh.
And it swings its second attack at Thea,
and that is a 21, not critical.
Yeah.
Has only eight damage.
So it starts to run and burst out the back door
of this kitchen area.
Flint, if you want your turn now, you can,
or it's Thea's turn.
I will go now.
Is it still within range for me?
It would be just out of range for you, but.
But you can run.
We're just throwing axes back or something.
Always a good choice.
Yeah, okay.
I'll move.
I'll take one movement to get, I guess,
just out of the house.
So I've got like a shot at him with a throwing axe.
Yep. Perfect.
All right.
Let me just find what I need for that.
Excellent.
One D6, perfect.
So that's a 17.
17 is good.
And four damage.
And now it's Thea's turn.
Sorry, you got more than one attack, don't you?
Oh yeah, I totally do.
Well then, how do you play D&D again?
Hey, it's title of the episode.
How do you play D&D?
It's pretty self-explanatory at this rate.
So that's a 16 that time.
16 is good.
Oh, okay.
And four again.
Consistent.
He's bloodied now.
Thea.
Okay, he is, nobody's in my way right now.
He's just like made a beeline for the back door.
Yeah, he's gone out the.
Took an axe or two in the back.
Yes.
Okay. Both of those things.
So I run out and I pull out my oath bow
and I say death to those who have wronged me.
19 plus four, yeah, 23.
That's good.
Of course it's good.
3d6 piercing, 11 damage.
It is back to the top, which is Flint.
Oh, that's me, excellent.
All right, so now it is within range for me
if I want to run over there and attack it?
Yes. Perfect.
It is not running at the moment
and has turned to face his attackers.
To face sweet, sweet incoming death.
Sounds like a plan.
All right, so I'm going to run over there
and attack it.
Sure.
So that's a 16, which I think you said was good.
Yep.
Nope, I totally rolled the wrong time clock.
This is the top one today, guys.
We are all out of it.
All right, rolling the correct dice this time.
Three, awesome.
And a nine.
So 16, when I had four to that.
And I shall attack him again.
Oh, missed a critical by one.
That's too bad.
Four, seven, 11, and four is 15.
He did it.
No.
Well, in that case, I should probably take
my action surge and one more attack.
Sure.
Because why?
Because why not?
If he's still alive, I mean.
Look at you remembering how to D&D.
I looked at the page and it was right there.
So I better get on it.
All right, that one is a 19, so that should be okay.
Oh, 12 damage on the first one, nice.
And seven is 19 and four is 23.
Oh yeah.
He's regretting having turned around,
but it's Thea's turn now.
You said New Lara hasn't had a turn in ages.
New Lara's turn.
It's New Lara's turn now.
I got thrown off on this whole
jumping in in the order thing.
Yeah, Flint got to just jump in there.
My bad, guys.
No, we were all so excited you could see again.
18.
18's good, yeah.
Two plus three is five, six damage.
Second attack is a 25.
10, 14, 19 damage.
Nice.
So you murdered an Oni.
Straight up.
I don't know if murder's the right word.
Gangland assassination.
You killed that Oni.
Yeah.
That was kind of self defense.
It was, it was.
Does he like mist away and Sasha comes back?
There's no mist around you,
but when you go back to the house
where the people are, where you started.
I'm assuming they like went to take care of Farin
as soon as we were all gone.
Well, you guys didn't.
I hope so.
So hopefully somebody did.
All of his villagers.
Yeah, like we were gone, so.
If they didn't, they're real jerks.
Yeah, it's true.
It's not on us.
They are tending to Barin
and Sasha is there also being tended to.
Yay.
Yeah, if you recall,
there was the gaseous mist in the room.
That's how I figured out that Sasha was an Oni.
Exactly, exactly.
I was so clever last episode, you guys.
You really were.
So good.
Not this episode.
We're sick this time.
It's hard, it's much harder.
Yeah, so you have killed both Onis and you get back
and yeah, they're tending to Barin and Sasha.
Sweet, we did it.
Woohoo, you guys okay?
We did one of the 50 things.
Oh, I'm not great.
I'm at like half points.
Can we have a nap?
I'm pretty tuckered out here.
I'm not the best I've been.
I might be remembering this wrong,
but did the Onis scare away the cultists?
As it was described to you when you guys arrived,
the Oni did scare off the cultists
as it came in from the way they were telling you
the tale of the Onis showing up,
it came in with the cultists at some point
and the cultists started disappearing
before the townspeople started disappearing,
but the cultists left.
Okay, so it seems like after I sleep off my half death,
we've like kind of done what we needed to do
in Little Rock, right?
Like we were coming to free them from the cultists,
but the Oni actually took care of that for us
and then we took care of the Oni.
Exactly.
Yeah. Great.
Yay, I have a list of tasks that we need to accomplish
and that's one of them.
Oh, wonderful.
We did one of the things we needed to do.
But in a big old check mark next to that one.
I jumped into the air like it's about to be a freeze frame.
Ah, I love a good freeze frame high five.
I love it.
So you guys are taking a rest then?
Yes. Yes, please.
Yeah, so they offered to put you up
for whatever time period you desire
and this battle is occurring in the middle of the night
and when you guys wake up the next day,
there are not that many people,
there's not that many people left in Little Rock.
Oh, start baby making you guys.
And you are.
Fill this town up.
That's your answer to everything.
This will be a town of babies.
It's like in Angry Birds
when the pigs come and steal all the eggs
and then they're like, we'll just make more eggs.
Everybody get egg making.
Does that happen in that movie?
Absolutely does.
A messed up children's movie.
That children's movie, hey?
Yeah, one of the main characters is just like,
don't worry ladies, we'll help.
We'll just have to make more eggs.
Oh my God.
Sounds like a great movie for kids.
It's perfect.
I guess they wouldn't understand,
so just all the adults got to be uncomfortable.
Yeah. Perfect.
But the following morning,
you were approached by Baran.
He's not looking great,
but he's up and moving around.
The wound was mostly superficial from the looks of it.
But a flesh wound.
And he says, I thank you for coming
and helping my people.
As you can see, there aren't many of us left
and the town is in quite a disarray
being left by the cultists
and the subsequent attacks by these awful,
awful ogre, oni things.
Would you be able to escort us
to the next city over Mirabar
and hopefully get us there safely?
And help us get set up there.
Well, hello.
It's me, your dungeon master Russ More
and this is episode 10 of Dumbgeons and Dragons.
This one titled, A Hunter in Little Rock, part two.
It is a bit on the shorter side.
Everyone was a bit under the weather
and our heads clearly weren't in it,
but hopefully some good goofs came out of it
and it's still entertaining for you.
Let's move on to the comments and feedback section
from other episodes.
Thank you so much for leaving us reviews.
Like I've said before,
if you can leave us those five star ratings and reviews,
it really helps the show out a lot.
Odd Dad Out from the US says,
fun listen, even for a non-D&D guy.
I'm not a D&D person,
but I do enjoy listening in
as this group of friends play.
They have great chemistry as a group
and just have fun,
which is what any game is really about.
Quasar Ken from the US says, great show.
I didn't know that I needed a live D&D podcast in my life
until just right now.
This show is great.
Keep up the good work.
Thank you so much to both of you for writing those.
And if you think of it after this episode,
please consider leaving a rating and review on iTunes.
Or if you subscribe through another format,
you can send us an email of your love and adoration
or straight up rule correction, whichever works,
to dumbdragonpodcast at gmail.com.
Either way, we love to hear from you, honestly.
Also don't freak out.
There will be a promo for another amazing D&D podcast
called Bros and Dragons podcast
that will come up before we get back to playing.
You should cruise on over to iTunes and check them out
because Doc and the team over there run a real tight ship
and put out a great super fun D&D actual play show,
as well as an out of character show
on the same channel where they interview their players
and guest players and talk about the show.
Check them out.
You can also spread the word about Dumbgeons and Dragons
by telling your friends, family, coworkers,
or mailman to visit us at dumbdragons.com.
All of our social media and download links
are listed there.
On Twitter, we are at DumbDragonCast.
You can use the DumbDragonCast hashtag
so we can track you down
and find out who's talking to or about us.
On Facebook, we're at facebook.com slash DumbDragonCast.
Twitter is certainly the place
to get the quickest response
as I am on that account all the time
throughout the day, it seems.
And you can also send us an email
to DumbDragonPodcast at gmail.com.
We do certainly read every review
and mention on Facebook and Twitter
and try to respond to them as quickly as possible.
So please keep sending those in.
That's enough from me.
Episode 11 will be available April 26th
when the Adventurers will continue
along their perilous journey.
You have a super fantastic couple of weeks
and be the amazing person you are.
Now let's see if we can just pull it together
for the end of the episode.
Here's hoping.
Catch you later.
Did anyone else think Ogeroni sounds like Rice-a-Roni?
I liked the amount of time that passed between his questions.
I wrote it down and waited until he finished.
I wrote it down and waited.
Oh God, Russ, when you're editing it,
please leave in the like literal five minutes
between.
Yeah, the timing was really good.
I didn't want to interrupt
because I thought he had some important things to say.
That's all Tom was just thinking like,
oh my God, Ogeroni.
I was literally very singularly focused
on that one thing.
It did not hear the rest of what he was saying.
Does Baran want us to escort everyone in the town?
They're just giving up on their whole town?
There's like seven of them left.
Well, there's more than seven,
but it is a small village
that previously had many, many people.
And now there's like.
It's just a sad place.
30 people, but yes, that's what he's asking.
Plus somewhere in the woods,
there's that creepy cave that the Onis were living in
with like literally just like bodies and bones
of all their dead friends and family.
I'd move away too.
Yeah, that's fair.
Yeah, it's a good call.
It's a good call.
How far away is the town?
Mirabar is a two to three day trek from where you are.
And where is that in relation?
Yes, to Luskin.
Yeah, is that anywhere towards like the Misty Forest
or the Serpent Hills?
Well, we need to go back to Luskin, right?
To talk to Macauks.
Or to Luskin, yeah.
Just to see like what's up
with the Arcane Brotherhood.
If you look at your,
if you're able to look at your map of Faerun,
Luskin on the coast there
more towards the Northern tip.
You are, if you follow the River Marar,
Mirabar is inland from Luskin.
Where are we now?
And you are-
Triangulate.
Approximately halfway between Luskin
Enhance.
And Mirabar.
Enhance, enhance.
Little Rock, not on the map there, but.
Enhance, zoom.
So right by where it says River Marar
is probably where Little Rock is?
Yeah.
What do you guys think?
We could go help them get there
and then it's just hopefully an easy river boat
with the river ride back down to Luskin.
I agree.
Plus it's like, you know,
it's like saving a baby from a burning building
and then leaving it on the sidewalk and walking away.
Yeah, I feel responsible for these people now.
You're safe now, baby.
Safe now, baby.
I'm gonna get some pizza.
Well, technically true.
Isn't the best.
I feel responsible for these people.
Yes, I agree.
So yeah, let's take them to the next town
and then we'll river ride back down to Luskin
and meet with McAuth
after we do this little, little side venture.
Sweet, let's do it.
Sounds good.
Yes, of course we'll help you.
Excellent, excellent.
Thank you so much.
You're welcome.
For character knowledge of Mirabar,
Flint, you probably,
your character probably knows this quite well.
And how would I know this?
Because Mirabar is a dwarven mining city.
Ooh, fancy.
Fancy, really?
Well, we don't go to a lot of dwarf places, all right?
That is largely populated by shield or mountain dwarves.
I'm a mountain dwarf.
I know.
And don't you have a thing
that makes dwarves like extra love you?
It's his belt.
Sure do, it's the old belt of dwarven kind.
Amazing, you're gonna be so popular.
Largely populated by these dwarves.
I'm sorry, Russ, did you want to say something?
No, I just want you guys to keep talking over and talking.
Fuck.
Ogaroni, guys.
Let's have a short game, guys, it's fine.
Wait, is that a new character?
Yeah.
Ogaroni's getting me way better this time.
I don't even remember what I was saying.
It's largely populated by these shield,
mountain dwarves, and humans.
You know from the last session at Waterdeep
that Mirabar was not represented there.
Why they weren't is not something you know,
but you know that the city holds a large,
you know, large, large, large, large, large,
large, large, large, large, large, large, large,
city holds a large army of dwarven and human warriors
that protect the city and the mines.
And also, Flint, you know, Mirabar was the last place
that you know of the Iron Fist of the Dawn
to have been located.
Oh, my old company.
Your old mercenary company.
So you guys pack up, there are a few remaining carriages
left in town to help carry the people,
but a lot of them are walking,
and you guys set off towards Mirabar.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin McCloud
of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
Dumbgeons & Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.