previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
stab thaddeus is what you're telling me and you're not gonna try and get it away from me get it away from me all right all
right all right if he removes me something will happen to one of your friends what it wants will
become clear soon but in the meantime we'll have some fun that sounds fucking ominous if i don't
try and get rid of it it won't make me hurt you again we need to be all together on this to
get ourselves out of this i don't know if we can afford to tie you up and drag you behind us
we have to get out of this fucking tower we have to get iskander you all crowd around in the
teleporter area and you are teleported you see the bodies of three dead cultists on the floor
here you see a trail of blood running from this room down a hallway Nulara can you go first
yeah as you light down the hallway and into this room and a second trail of bloody boot
prints heading up the corridor to the north standing amid the gore are three humanoid figures
two that look like misshapen statues of clay and stone and one appearing as a humanoid made of
flame and i enter the room the earth elementals and the fire elemental begin moving towards you
so should we just disengage and run for it i think it sounds like a good idea you head down
the stairs to a walkway that appears to stretch across infinite space
welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons we're a dnd fifth edition actual play podcast and i'm your
dungeon master Russ More and with me today is carla johnson oh me first for the fake out
when he knows i'm super sleepy so it's kind of mean i play Nulara moonbrook and amy more
yeah i had something really good to say um when we were recording fake core and i have
thusly forgotten what it was i play the amistacia and finally tom laird i rarely have
anything good to say and i play flint Firebeard i mean i see that based on how much waveform
is in the finished episodes there tom yeah gotta work on that's a lot of dead spaces
so tom's here for his his good looks that's right we need this audio medium i'm here for my
good looks looks good in those jeans right yeah anyways i don't know where i was gonna go with
that me neither he russ is saying some weird stuff this evening already let's just keep
talking about tom and his jeans yeah what else can we talk about with my jeans he got some
new ones and they are very nice and they look great so i don't know if he told you
that russ or what what brand are we talking levi's we talking wranglers like what are you
wearing we're talking silver jeans silver jeans silver do you like that they sell them at marx
work warehouse free plug for them because the jeans are really good yeah that's awesome
all right unless they want to pay for the plug in which case we will accept
thank you two and a half weeks to get marx on the horn okay and uh and nail down that uh
50 bucks 50 bucks seem good that's pretty good every time we mention their name
50 bucks marx marx work warehouse marx marx marx marx marx work there you go we're up to six
thousand dollars wow this is adding up real quick guys right we cut out a bunch but this
still counts because it's on the tape and some frito lay while we're at it
hey did you know we're on Patreon what and when you're on Patreon you get a special episode
dedication to you and today's patron is rachel johnson rachel thanks rachel thanks rachel i
love you wonderful i actually love her a little bit more than normal listeners
why is that carl the johnson because she's my relative wait a second darryl was our shout
out last week too huh this podcast brought to you by nepotism the johnson family
yeah if you're a johnson visit our Patreon get on board and johnson and johnson we'd be very
happy if you delighted to have johnson there's a lot of johnsons in the world so like if we
could get some that johnson money would be better than the marx money hey let's just
broaden it if you have a johnson no that's a good one too yeah right because that's like
50 percent of it's true it's true i mean i'm sorry i just used your last name as a
reference to that's okay i was in the area in the era god sorry i'm so tired i was a teenager
in the era when like big johnson shirts were a thing commonly worn by human beings out in
public so like oh i've been there why was that a thing why was it why not i was like 15
like i guess there wasn't dress coats like there is now about back in your day back in
back in my day we could wear spaghetti straps to school we could which is good and should be
allowed now but like the penis thing probably we probably could have toned that down a little
it's too much yeah um so thank you rachel
also thank you for uh the award nomination from uh jason from take 20 dnd not to brag
but we're up for an award this weekend yay yeah we are so crazy and exciting it's for the alberta
role-playing game awards which i means amy and i get it you guys don't get it
fucking amazing bc badass's award you guys are gonna be so sad yeah that's tom yes we need to
make up an award yeah i'm gonna i'm gonna launch the association get the website up there like
right now i'm gonna i'm gonna google this thomas frantically creating a so much coding
so much i'm gonna be up all night it's gonna be like one of those montages where i'm just
eating donuts and chain smoking and getting this shit done wow um it's part of intrigue
con here in edmonton that happens this saturday october i don't know what happens this
weekend um and we're very excited that we are nominated yeah we don't win it's very nice
that we uh we've been nominated by someone within the community and super cool we're just
very happy we're just happy to be here when we show up we're gonna be like hey guys we're just
happy to be here i have no reason to expect to win so you know it's just nice to show up
yeah yeah you could be like one of those people at the oscars when they didn't expect
to win and then they have to go up there and be like oh i didn't think i was gonna win
i want to i didn't write anything out played off the stage because they let me bring up my tome
of scripted things just in case this was so unexpected
yeah because mine's rolled up like in parchment and then it and then it falls down the stage
and rolls down the middle aisle sure yeah and it's not a list of everyone i want to thank
it's just a list of things i hope to get for christmas just your hit list you're all the
motherfuckers that piss me off rolls down the aisle like damn amy's angry such a doink
and then it's crossed off but then like two weeks later it's back on the list like
hashtag married life exactly pretty much hashtag married to your dm
that should be a trending that should be a trending thing on twitter
okay we gotta stop guys he's getting that look on his face like the one that killing look
like now paisley now fuck it let's play dnd
so you guys found yourselves walking down some stairs and the steps descend to a walkway that
appears to stretch across infinite space thousands of stars twinkle in unfamiliar
constellations and meteors streak through the vastness above and below the path just
past the base of the stairs a door framed by nothingness rises from the path and 50
feet beyond that the path meets an intersection with another door straight ahead
so it's heaven
is there anything to stop us from falling off the path no there does not appear to be any
walkways guys don't fucking go near the path oh shit is it like rainbow road
for mario kart because that was the worst one it was the worst one russ how dare you do that
to us i mean it's very similar to oh fuck in the fact that it's a it's a it's a pathway
that looks like it goes through the stars fiaz wolf is clenching a turtle shell oh oh fuck
oh boy so now what kind of turtle shell is it it's only green so who knows all right
all right i was gonna say is it a blue spiky yeah oh if it's a blue spiky we're all done for
whoever's in front is done i kNulara you go first at this rate probably Tiamat's in front
so you might just want to launch that blue shell touché touché you fall you've solved
my mario kart riddle so no guardrails we've established uh yeah no guardrails now so let's
walk towards the things sure i'll go first okay what's marching order here i want to go last
okay because i've got that turtle shell in my ass
uh well i guess i'm in the middle somewhere then does thaddeus want to not be beside like near me
because i would understand hold on a second wouldn't wouldn't donnie be near you because
he's big right he's big now walking beside you i mean yeah he's like a flying walking
dragon type of thing yeah yeah so yeah donnie would be beside you two by two by two two by
two by two yeah okay so yeah flamey kens up with flint there thaddeus keeping a close eye on his
good friend Nulara for it's fair reasons for reasons for valid valid reasons he looks to
you and he gives you like the two fingers to the eye and then two fingers i give him two
because i want him i want i that's what i'm looking for yeah um and you guys begin to
walk out onto the pathway and as you make it about halfway onto the pathway you see
this start like it's all encompassing there's stars you see far off planets
array of different cosmos feels and everybody make a dexterity saving throw
meh 13 okay that's a 15 for flint and a 12 for thaddeus and a 12 for Nulara that's me
as you were walking and taking in all of this beautiful spectacle that you see meteors begin
to zip by across the pathway but all of you are dexterous enough that you don't get knocked
by them you manage to keep your footing as these zip by like within inches of some of you
well that's kind of amazing i mean you couldn't ask for a better experience you look down and
you see that it looks like like there's no bottom to this place so if you work infinite space
is so we're talking like non-stop soda pop at a restaurant just bottomless yep okay endless
breadsticks oh man but that's how they get you they want you in here just so full of those
breadsticks so full of those delicious delicious breadsticks the infinite breadsticks infinite
breadsticks breadsticks breadsticks uh so oh look he's making that face that he makes that
one face that he makes that means he loves us so much yep all my favorite people um
flamingans you're the star expert being a pirate yeah still they call me star mcgee
yep star hunter star king green star lord lord i think that was taken i feel like that
has a different ip i said star come lord uh are these constellations and things we're seeing
the same different ones as we saw when we were in the maze hold on let me let me keep looking
hmm nope nope they don't look quite the same as the ones in that weird place
uh no it looks looks different all new and exciting like we're in a different
different other different space god damn portal jumping zonthal's tower maze business
you know life on a pirate ship is much simpler you guys should join me after this whole
business is down you know what we just we just might do that maybe we will this conversation
aside from stopping to look has taken the time that it takes to get across the pathway
and you reach the t intersection where directly in front of you there is a door to your left
down a 25 foot hallway is another door and to the right is a hallway that curves off to its
left um let's check this one okay i'll open the door since i'm there first do you want to
like check for traps or anything oh uh oh yeah that's probably something unless you just want
to send flamingons first i mean we're going first no it's totally fine i'll uh thought
pirates were brave i'll give it that one uh so i got a two which is uh not great it looks
like a clean as a whistle door can i even understand doors at that point you know it's
a door he presses his whole body against the door and just waits right you weren't looking to see
if it was a door you're looking to see if it was jerry-rigged with anything but i mean i've been
struck dumb and i no longer am able to process any information clearly you're ready to just
throw yourself through this magical door that is your new best friend okay i'm gonna i'm
gonna spring the door open and be ready you open this door and inside you see that this
small seemingly storage closet is lined with shelves holding hundreds of different
containers and jars and vials filled with different liquids and everything is covered in
dust hey hey flint what's that what's in there uh it just seems like a lot of knickknacks
and or patty wax well give this dog a bone and i
yes amy yes it's amazing i i pad forward because i am still a winter wolf and i peek my head in
do i recognize any of these potions because i spent time on that ship with the alchemist
building uh big splody bombs and stuff make an investigation roll 12 as you examine them
um they mostly appear like there are different mundane and exotic reagents and components that
would be used by a wizard or some sort of alchemist in different spells but most of
these supplies look like they have been there for a long time and they've been either
evaporated or congealed or decayed from whatever they once were and they don't look
usable anymore so like nothing in there worth taking no there's no like footprints in the dust
to the one like real dope shit cabinet where they've been going in and out getting things
there is not okay no okay guys there's there's nothing in here mother stuff in here
nothing useful it's yucky stuff what she said okay uh okay where to next left or right well
left leads to a door and right leads to nothingness or or somethingness or or somethingness could be
somethingness you don't know well if we if we check the door first it could just be another
storage closet i'd have to double bat true let's i agree let's like eliminate the door
possibility or maybe find exactly what hopefully guacamole's behind that door um and then we can
come yeah because who knows what if that path goes for like eight miles the other way let's
check the door does it end in a rap battle after eight miles god i hope so because i've
been practicing so hard you guys can you lose yourself in the music the moment i mean you
only get one shot the only redeeming factor is mom's spaghetti but then you barf it up anyway
all right uh yeah so we'll we'll go down to the left there russ uh okay who's why who's
walking down and who's opening i think same order same order yeah i will roll to check for
things yep uh that's better that's a 15 it's a push it looks good it looks good to you
you that's that's a good i pull when it should have been a bush yeah all right i uh i open that
door again it opens with a loud creak and you look in through the door and you see two massive
hourglasses that occupy this irregularly shaped chamber and their glass globes are nearly 15 feet
across with each hourglass rising almost to the ceiling 30 feet overhead each is suspended
by chains and pulleys and gears in such a way that it can be turned over to set its sand running
slumped against the wall at the far side of the chamber is the cultist who called to you from
the balcony of the tower his dark robes are charred and torn and a blue dragon mask is
clutched in his red stained hands shit okay i'm uh i'm gonna hustle over there and uh check
for a pulse make a medicine check 14 okay what's everybody else doing as clint hustles into this
room um i'm i'm looking at these giant hourglasses uh i'm also gonna do a medicine check because i
have like i don't know i'm good at that so i just want to like do something are you
maybe gonna stab him by accident 22 hey that is not by accident as by compulsion i didn't
like trip and stab my good friend thaddeus i did it intentionally it was very much i did a very
good job of it although i regret doing it you did you did a handily clint and Nulara rush
over to check the body of what you can tell uh flint for sure uh is iskander you check for
a pulse and you check over his his wounds um there is no pulse there's no sign of breath
no sign of movement um what does it look like he died from you're not there what does it look
like he died from thanks girl the wounds inflicted the wounds he was hitting ross in case
you couldn't hear that yeah that's what that was oh god please stop okay well that came after
oh you're just gonna edit those together oh magic of radio um the wounds inflicted on his
body look like they were perhaps done by the elementals that you met once you arrived down
in the dungeon the ones we ran away from so bravely yep okay well we weren't gonna win
yeah i know that was a good choice with our lives yeah and we you know what we do not
often choose to run from a battle usually we're like we're gonna have to go sometimes we forget
that that is an option i think yeah like we just don't do that we forget a lot of things
here on dumps and dragons yeah exactly it's a weird choice um i call up so
he's dead then yeah i couldn't find a pulse Nulara could you no i couldn't find a pulse
and it's i mean it seems a little anticlimactic he's just here and he's just dead to be honest
with you after we've been trying so hard to get here we don't even like get to talk to him
that being said here's the mask we're looking for so that's pretty great hey flint you should
probably hold on to that yeah all right i'll keep that safe thea says a little like not
trying to be too pointed about it but like maybe Nulara shouldn't hold on to it just
that's fair that's fair i should not hold on to it yeah i'm gonna grab that there mask there russ
okay sorry is he like speared to the wall or is he just like did he just die right he slumped
he sustained wounds and he it looks like he came into this room and sat down and died okay
what yeah i don't know why i thought he was on his feet i want to um i have that hourglass
that we took from the wizards in the ice storm hall area okay so i'm going to pull that out
see if anything happens it's not much of a plan but like we have like a remote control
yeah like i don't know we've now arrived in a room with some giant um hourglasses
it makes sense so anyway i pull that out and like i guess hold it out in front of me kind of like
pointed at the hourglass wave it around yeah yes exactly exactly exactly do you explain to the
group what you do or you just do this i think i just do it i don't even think it's that
weird i think they would no i don't know you pull it out and you you begin moving it around
and nothing appears to be happening with it or within the room as you're doing this um i
do i know what these are maybe how would you know what these are okay well i was you know
i worked in university and though i wasn't the world's best scribe i have nowhere i'm going
with that i wasn't the world's best scribe and i used to like fuck off and go read stuff
that i thought was interesting to me and being a druid and having all my natural abilities i was
super curious with what wizards um or sorcerers could do and so i think i've probably read
something that might have to do with something like this sure making our cantor roll i will
oh that's a 25 holy shit damn was that a rainbow justified it was amy in your random readings
will say that you don't necessarily know what these hourglasses are but you perhaps came
across something about xanthal himself and you know that he was a master of spatial magic
which is not only the physical space around you but he dabbled in the manipulation of time
hold on you guys i feel silly talking about this as a wolf so i i morph back like from
back legs to standing legs you know is that the sound it makes when you transform from a
winter wolf because you've done that a lot of times and i did not know that was the wet
sound you were making usually i put in something majestic like a big like
and like an eagle sound comes from this noise can i know that's i'm going back
and re-editing every time don't you re-edit shit and putting in um
um
i not so majestically turn back into an elf and i say i've read somewhere that xanthal was
really interested in the manipulation we know of space dealing with all of his stupid portals
that we've been going through here but but also time and i mean i don't want to be too literal
with this but there are two giant hourglasses in front of us i think this might have something
to do with with time travel wait do you think we could use these to how far back do you
think we could go could it be like minutes could we maybe arrive in time to save iskander
or do you think we could go back even further well i was hoping to go back even further
not not to be selfish or anything but i'm hoping to go back far enough to save guacamole
well it's a heavy pregnant silence
are you thinking i i want you to get guacamole back what are you thinking we go back to like
the beginning of the maze we have to go through the baby Tiamat we go back and murder Tiamat
when she's a baby Tiamat is she's not on you know what we can't explain this to you right
now just be quiet the grown-ups are talking no you know what i want to hear more about
flamagan's theory there of Tiamat as a baby if we're traveling back in time there's got to
be a time when Tiamat i put my hand over her back i don't i don't know how i don't know
how it would work i don't know if we would be transported to that moment in time to change it
or if we would be rewinding time and then end up in the exact same moment whether or not we
would keep our memories or not but i just i i know it's selfish but i i just i have to try
i don't even think it's that selfish i mean guacamole saved our butts and
flown us around and i mean she's a part of the team i just
i i just worry about shit's already pretty bad in the world and i worry about
messing it up more we don't know what these things can do maybe maybe we should just try
like a little a little bit maybe we could just go back a couple minutes if if we can make
it work some light time travel yeah yeah just a sprinkle of time travel maybe a few grains of
sand maybe we can i don't know moderate how much how much time travel happens um flint
would you mind helping me i think the left one if i mean if we're looking at it from the
door the left one is the past the right one is the future sure sounds like a good enough
theory to me um i i beckon him over flint uh flint slaps both his biceps and brings his
hands together ew and uh and pulls his sleeves up and walks over how much are the tickets to
the gun show they're free baby how uh how hard do i pull on this thing as hard as you want
what is the pulley like is it a rope or is it like a chain you said chain yeah uh let's pull
together let's just see how much strength it's gonna take to move this thing okay yeah we'll
uh we'll reef on it one of you make a strength check with advantage because the other one is
helping you roll better i'm on it oh net 20 yeah jesus that gun show compliment really
like pumped you up right really landed now yeah i've been flirting with him this whole time he
just doesn't know it so you begin to pull on the chains and it takes it takes quite a lot
of effort for you to do so more so than you think should be needed um and as they begin to
move and the hourglass begins to tilt you hear this hideous ear-grating groan as the chains
break free from the rust that set into them and the gears begin to move after however long
they've been sitting still you get it to the point where the sand begins to run how far are
you going with this i just want like a little bit of the sand like a 45 degree angle like a
just a trickle just a trickle yeah the sand begins to trickle into the empty basin
um but as it does so nothing appears to happen what's Nulara doing during this uh just like
spectating okay i mean you know realistically probably just just watching about stabbing people
thinking about your stabbing regret i feel for stabbing people but yeah i mean probably just
like bracing in case we whip through some time portal at high speeds sure so yeah nothing
nothing appears to occur as the sand slowly begins to trickle into the next do you guys
feel any different does anything feel different no no i mean god i'm kind of hungry were you
hungry before they started pulling the pulley yeah so that hasn't changed then no but she
asked how we were feeling okay that's not what i meant that is a good point that's a good point
uh should we try a little more well maybe maybe we need to do both at once maybe it's
maybe this activates i don't know something well should we i'll try giving it a little more
so don't turn it like all the way up right but a little little a little more it begins
to freely flow into the basin anybody who's watching it make an investigation roll i will
14 that's a 10 so i'm watching intently but apparently seeing nothing i'll roll for that
i was going to say is that is so a solid eight for that is everybody who's who's actively
watching it you you catch glimpses of shimmering diamonds as they roll through
um and as flint and thea turn the hourglass and it begins to flow more freely into the basin
nothing occurs
hey there i'm your dungeon master Russ More thank you for joining us for episode 57 of
Dumbgeons and dragons the hourglass want to start by saying that you are wonderful listeners yes
you with your help we are experiencing some amazing successes and we are always humbled
by your constant ability and want to share this show our show your show with your friends
family and all the strangers that the internet brings to you at the time of recording this we
have an amazing growing Patreon community that show their support by giving us their hard-earned
dollars to enable us to do giveaways make upgrades and just make the show better with each and
every episode we have a super fun facebook group that grows every week with new people
looking to create a fun community to talk about dnd the podcast and find ways to draw inspiration
from each other and be better gamers around the table our twitter account has just passed
3500 followers that's insane and we're still trying on instagram i mean if you have suggestions
about what you want to see on any social feed but especially instagram please fire us a note
dumb dragon podcast at gmail.com the too long don't read of this is thank you for coming
along with us sharing with us and experiencing the adventure of Dumbgeons and Dragons with us
we love you all final big thanks to sirenscape for some of the amazing atmosphere and sound
in today's episode make sure you check them out at sirenscape.com to bring your games to life
links for everything mentioned today can be found in the description below
our next episode will be out wednesday october 17th so let's finish up this
week's though and see if amy can remember the word for hourglass that really is the
question this week have a great one we'll talk soon
uh this maybe i don't know maybe this one is broken uh let's try the other one okay i slowly
like let the chain back and put it to its natural position you mean you don't just
let it go and make it go like i don't i don't just let it go rus are there any of those
handy like oil cans that you can like beep beep on things to like you know that dorothy
yes that's exactly what i thought of the tin can man oh i mean tin can yeah he was a tin can man
uh not not in this room that you see yep so nothing so you let it you let it fall back
to its original position um and do do you two go over do you ask somebody else to go do
that i'm already all warmed up with the gun show i might as well go all right flint you
walk over knowing the full strength of what you need to do to turn this you turn it to
the same position i assume yep um and allow it to flow freely but not all the way up
into the bottom basin and again nothing begins to happen those watching do see uh more
diamonds trickle through mixed in with the sand anything guys no just pretty diamonds
uh jeez um i don't know should we try both at the same time or go all upright with one of them
like there's a couple more combinations we could try so um thaddeus can you help me with this
one yeah yeah i can definitely do that oh god he speaks sorry yeah i just got stabbed and i
almost died i know it's been really rough on you buddy it's fine he's had a rough couple days
so we yeah let's try pulling it at the same time you guys want me to do anything
no girl you're fine get over here yeah raw raw you and me we'll be cheerleaders in the
background okay i like it yeah uh so thaddeus and i start pulling at the same time that flint
starts pulling pull harder you're very strong i make weird straining noises don't poop yourself
okay you're doing good the hourglasses begin to tip up are you going all the way up or you're
going to that 45 degree we'll both go to the 45 and and see like is anything anyone feeling anything
no not feeling anything nothing appears to be occurring as you do this let's let's keep going
i don't know why i feel like i need to talk above sand dripping out of no because it's the
chains are making loud noises well sure it's loud yes right yes the hideous noise is still
going on let's tip them all the way up oil can all right full power i guess coming up
crank it up to 11 both hourglasses are vertical now and the sand is flowing freely into the basin
and everyone in the room observes and feels like a warble in the air movement in the space
around the hourglasses and within the sand but nothing physically appears to change did anyone
feel that yeah i was just gonna ask did anyone feel that i guess i guess you did yeah i mean i
felt something but i don't know that like did anything change i mean iskander is still
super dead still deadsville yeah population is still grinding and stuff
well they're not grinding because it's stationary vertical um let's let's let them down
obviously nothing's happening um so that we slowly put them back to put them back to normal
i walk over to the one that i was nearest to and i put my hands into my little like
obviously a component pouch or something in my little thing and i rub some ruby dust on my
hands and i put my hands onto the glass and i say you magic and i cast detect magic
that's the best spell catching hey you magic you magic hey you you you magic hey sand you magic
you you magic saint
you do this and you detect within the sand itself faint auras of transmutation magic
but it's weak you feel like it has faded over the years and it is not at its full strength
you guys in inside of these there there was a magic um probably allowing for time travel but
it hasn't been used in so long and if magic isn't if it doesn't have a source it
source it it weakens it dies and i can i can barely feel this magic
that this isn't going to do anything for us so clearly this is all from xanthal like the
cultists haven't been using these things probably not which is good news because i'd hate to
find out the cult of the dragon had a big old time travel device so yeah that would that
would be rough for us that would be bad so i guess that's the silver lining i'm sorry that
it didn't work so that we could find guac but damn diamonds though right
what about them they look very big they do look big do you do you want the diamonds
i mean good idea flint how big are the diamonds i mean this is like a 30 foot tall thing
i mean they have some varying sizes but most of them like you know palm sized small apple
sized diamonds those are pretty big diamonds oh flamey can just go for it all right she was
the butt end of her crossbow and she begins like hitting the glass or the did she forget
that it was loaded and the arrow shoots out behind her i'll uh i'll bring my axe over
and help her out with the butt end of my ass all right make an attack roll there sir
don't roll my dice for that is a 21 uh and give me some damage damn damage you magic sand
i rolled full damage so that's 17 damage you join flamey kens and hitting at this hourglass and
she hits it a couple times but then you take one good swing and
shatter the hourglass and the sand begins to pour out at your feet you see diamonds are
mixed in she all like i loosened it for you like a pickle jar she looks like she's like yeah thanks
for the help but i would have got there but that's okay um all right well i'm just gonna
start putting these in my satchel here if nobody else wants them i mean we don't do a
lot of money stuff but like uh throw me one like apple sized diamonds seem like i mean
eventually we're not gonna be saving the world and you're gonna want to buy a kingdom
holy fuck uh fine throw me one okay okay i'd already started walking she throws a diamond
towards thea i catch it handily left-handed thea's left-handed i just decided character
development what cannon and you transport to the other side of the room what the
fuck and in your hand the diamond begins to disappear okay what just happened what'd you
just do what'd you do i threw you a diamond she throws a diamond up in her hand and is
looking across the room and it lands back and she teleports 30 feet across the room and the
diamond begins to disappear in her hand she's like these are motherfucking teleport diamonds
i guess not all the magic is gone flamingans were you like are you guys directing that
like are you thinking about a place and then you get to the place or you i thought i thought
about that place that i'm standing here flint throw me throw me a diamond i toss her a diamond
and as i catch it i close my eyes and i think of just outside the door so i can't see it but i
think of it you teleport to just outside the door to this chamber i walk back in through the
door as the diamond disappears in my hand magic okay so is this the first time she's seen
magic i mean it is not it is definitely just get very excited we were literally just in a
hall of like infinite space and nothingness which was pretty fucking impressive that's amazing
pretty good yeah um i these could definitely i mean it seems helpful so i'm gonna take a few
yeah i think i'm gonna take three they're like apple size yeah yeah well i don't have
a bag of holding anymore so i'm just gonna take three yeah three seconds in my pockets
they're weird bulges happening everybody takes so it's like high school you take some time to
search through the sand and you each take three i was a boy in high school
oh and as you begin to move towards the door you see flaming kens still digging through the
sand and she manages to take a couple more flaming kens come on yeah yeah they're big
okay let's go okay so we have the mask should we just go to like a teleport elevator
a tele-teleportivator i don't know tele-teleportivator tele-teleporter
well what about that other uh hallway we didn't go down i don't know what do you guys think
like what if what if guac is in there i mean she could be then we better bring some chips
oops i turn around and i deck her oh fuck i just it you know if it's just another room or another
storage area i just i i can't leave without knowing we're right here no we might as well
yeah we might as well check off the boxes i mean honestly we could walk in there and see
a teleport evader right we don't have to go back through past the elementals and everything
so thank you guys let's let's go see and everybody cross their fingers and hope for guacamole
same thing i do every time i go to a party me too all right we walk down the right right oh it's
the best when they show up and there's guac that or like seven layer dip oh love seven
right give me a good seven layer day not sour cream i want like the taco seasoning in the
sour cream i'm not an animal yeah yeah yeah and you know what no sour cream at all for me
some lactose intolerant you put some greek yogurt in there oh even better it's like
so rich okay sorry we walked down we walked down that's fine yeah the the hallway of nothingness
i guess i need a snack stay tuned for our new podcast seven layer dip chat oh my god
first episode layer one walk walking order marching order what's who's going where first
just like all my youtube comments
i guess i'm in the middle like me and donnie are in the middle again so basically same marching
order you begin to walk down this hallway that curves to the left as you walk and
you begin to see a light shining out as the corridor opens into a room set with
comfortable looking oversized furnishings flint you're the first one to see this
do i just like do i just want to take a load off do i just want to have a seat
because it looks so comfortable maybe okay in the center of the room a red-skinned creature
wearing armor of flame bronze and volcanic stone sits cross-legged on the floor studying
a chessboard and he looks up as you step foot into the entryway of this chamber
and he lets a big smile across his face and he says hello
so
these are different stars than normal are they the same stars as we saw when they were
different stars than normal in the maze i'm gonna ask flamey kids in game okay do it
this is how i'm gonna set up all rp for now funny
this part gets cut out every time just move to the bloopers sorry is the much needed the
hinges with exhibit signs of much needed oil i'll record that that's bullshit there's a
fucking loud creek is what there is that's what all my sound effects are for okay i'm sorry
the word hourglass is never on the tip of my tongue ever and i always have to mentally search
for the word even if we're repeating this word repeatedly in the episode i just wanted everyone
to know my struggle that's fair that's fair the pulley system is to the left
uh hourglass hourglass fuck
oh that's fine okay uh yeah so i
it begins it begins it begins it begins it begins it runs
that was amazing and they bark at you in response i'm watching a video and it literally
looked like amy started barking it was incredible and she just did that starting i know it's like
okay this is next level with the sound effects now well you know i just really um i was just a
winter wolf so i go up to it i'm just like whatever that guy from police academy's name
is amy's the new him michael winslow michael winslow Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons
production