Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Flint was staring down the horde of zombies having just killed Nergoth Bladelord.
Are they running or shambling?
They're not slow, but they're definitely not running.
I don't know what that means.
Guys, we've got three options.
Zombie horde, don't know, more drakes.
Or do you guys just want to run?
Let's fucking run.
You all begin to book it.
Nularaaa, you make room.
As you carry forward, you see members of the cult of the dragon that you are now charging towards.
Guys, we just need to keep them busy till our horde of zombies is here to help us.
You four pile through them, knocking them to the side.
Nularaaa, you turn to see the eyes of a dragon looking right at you.
As you clear the hallway, lightning comes down the hallway and strikes the remaining cultists.
I think we just want to keep heading deeper towards the center.
Flint, as you and Nularaaa move the last boulder,
you realize that the light source is coming from a monstrous building.
Screams and roars come from over the edges as another blair of the Drakorn sounds.
And you are looking at the Temple of Tiamat.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We're a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast.
And I'm your Dungeon Master, Russ More.
And with me today is Amy More.
I'm Amy More. I play Thea Amastasia.
And the thing that bugs me the most is when I step in a puddle with socks on,
nothing enrages me more.
I feel like that was pointed. Also with me, Carla Johnson.
I am Carla Johnson. I play Nularaaa Moonbrook.
I just try not to let the like petty bothers of day-to-day life like really get me down,
you know, and try to like just stay really positive all the time.
It's pretty cute.
That's what I mean. That's not true.
I get irritated about everything all the time,
but I just want to tease Amy because I love her.
And Tom Laird.
Yeah, that's me.
I play Flip Firebeard and I'm straight up 100% with Amy on this one.
Let's get into it.
Puddles on the floor, socks, fuck, just the worst.
See, Paisley's on.
Paisley agrees.
Which is our new podcast called What Did You Step In?
Each week, we delve into what we stepped in this week.
I stepped in a lot of snow yesterday because I hiked up to Heart Lake.
And let me tell you, there's a lot of snow up there.
Fair enough.
So, that's bad.
Russ was just kidding, but now we're doing it.
No, guys, I didn't really want to.
I stepped onto a baseball field.
I didn't step into it, but I stepped onto it.
So that was fun.
We had an informal softball practice.
You know what?
Sexy pitches back at it.
That's right.
Cut off our stepped in podcast here.
And if you want more of this stepped in podcast,
you got to visit us over on Patreon where we might
talk about what we stepped in in one of the Goo Kangs.
So look forward to that coming up, everybody.
Whenever that is.
But Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
You can come over there and check out what we've got going on
and what we've got going on.
It's a great community that you can be part of for anywhere
from a dollar up a month.
You can get some great bonus rewards and tears.
No, great rewards, bonus content at different tiers.
There it is.
That was a struggle.
You got there, though.
Good for you.
It was tough.
Sorry.
Sorry, everybody.
We also dedicate an episode to a patron.
And today's patron is Devin Michaels.
Hey, thanks, Devin.
Devin, you're the best.
Thank you, Devin.
Two first names again.
First names again.
Yeah.
Because sometimes we had a previous patron who had two first names,
like a first name for his last name.
You know, all those people named Michaels has a first name.
Yeah.
How many people do you know named Michaels?
Almost.
So close.
I mean, there's that.
That's all I have to say.
That's my whole defense.
It's so close.
You two are like Mario there for a second.
I was so close.
It's me.
That's good.
And yet, you were so close.
So Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
So close.
Can this episode be called so close?
I guess it depends what turns out.
It depends.
We die this episode.
Almost made it to TMS.
Almost.
A new host rule.
I think if anyone rolls like a crit fail,
they have to immediately say, so close.
At least today.
Yes, at least today's session.
We'll obviously forget after today.
We can't even remember how to play the game
from week to week.
We certainly can't remember jokes from week to week.
Speaking of which, fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
You four step out of this caved in entryway.
Into the caldera of the well of the dragons.
You look and you see over the rubble ahead of you.
The peak of twisting cornices reaching up
of the five towers of the temple of Tiamat.
You look to the sky and you see
a swirling storm and cyclone that has built
since you went into the volcano.
You see metallic and chromatic dragons
tearing each other apart in the sky.
Roars and calls and screams of battle
surround you, bouncing off the walls of the volcano.
I'm going to change back into my regular as I say.
Holy shit, you guys.
Yeah, that about sums it up.
At least we're heading in the right direction.
We've got to be, right?
Yeah, I mean, if this isn't where we want to be,
then I don't know where we want to be.
Agreed.
I mean, I don't want to be here.
Oh, no, that's not what I meant.
To be clear.
To finish the job, we need to be here.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, guys, let's finish the job.
Do we see, like you basically described,
it's a big tower, but with five towers, I think, right?
Yeah, so you just kind of see the peaks right now
because you're kind of down in a collapsed portion of the volcano.
So you can't really see the full scope of the tower
from where you are.
If you so desired, you could move somewhere to do that.
Actually, I think we live here now.
See, this is what I'm asking.
All right, so you set up a homestay.
That's what I was wondering if, like,
so we've kind of cleared all this rubble,
we've made it through, and like,
are we on the exterior of a building
or do we, like, see paths or, like,
what is in our immediate vicinity
as opposed to just, like, the scale of the battle beyond?
You are in a collapsed pit.
So what you see is just rubble from rock and...
Oh, we're in a hole.
You're in a hole.
Yeah, we're in a hole.
You guys, we have to climb around in this hole.
I'm trying to fancy describe this hole.
No, it was too fancy.
But I should just say you're in a hole.
Don't be too fancy for us.
Russ, you never need to fancy describe a hole.
I didn't get it.
Fair enough.
No, for the love of God, we're like...
What kind of special area are we in?
You're not, you guys.
You dug yourselves into a hole.
Nice job.
Can I carefully clamber to the top
and just peer over in a sneaky way
because we don't know what's up there.
How deep is the hole we're in?
The hole itself is quite large, like,
longest point, like 150 feet,
widest part, almost 100 feet.
Less of a hole more of a crater, then?
Well, yeah.
It's a very large volcano.
What a big old hole.
I tried to fancy describe it
because it was more than a hole,
but you just hear that it was a hole.
You guys are in a little more than a hole.
Ah, yes, I get it.
You're in a collapsed crater within a volcano.
When anybody would like to begin walking up,
it would be considered difficult terrain
for those that that affects.
So a dexterity athletics roll.
So it's obviously a fairly steep sides out.
What if we used a ladder?
Does anyone, does anyone have a ladder?
If only someone had a ladder.
If only someone had a rod of lordly might.
Wait a minute, guys.
I can help us out here with this here ladder.
Flint, it's genius.
I love it.
Well, let's do it.
You know, this ladder is coming real handy
a bunch of times.
This always makes me feel like a fucking hero
to have this thing.
So I press the.
It's so big too.
I press the corresponding rod button
and extend it into ladder form.
Do you say something like go go gadget ladder?
I don't believe I've ever said anything for it,
but make ladder go now.
That new intellect headband is really working out.
It's really good.
It's bringing you all those real good words.
You begin scaling up the ladder
and you it takes a quick minute,
but you get to the top of the hole that you're in
and you are now on the edge
and you look out before you
and the caldera is blanketed beneath bones
of hundreds of dead dragons.
But that is not the most arresting feature.
A mind numbing structure that you saw the peak of
looks like it has pushed up beneath the tangled bones
to tower above the blasted volcano.
Partly volcanic ash fused with dragon bones
and partly stone imbued with the dark magic
of the nine hells itself.
The temple of Tiamat is all chaotic angles
and jutting buttresses.
Within that snarl of cornices and soaring angulation
you make out five asymmetric towers
topped by twisting steeples
and you see landing atop those towers
one of each of the different five colored chromatic dragons.
Do they see us?
Yeah, are these living dragons
or are they like sculptures built in
at the top of the towers?
No, sorry, they are just landing.
They are alive.
You are kind of hidden among different bones and stones
so they have not seen you directly as of this moment.
Well, I guess, yeah, dragon bones, huge.
Yeah, the scale of this place is enormous.
It feels so tiny.
All we know is that this was the way
to where they're doing the ceremony.
Not particularly helpful now that we've arrived here
outside this fucking monstrosity.
What do you want to do?
Should we just try to make our way to the tower?
I mean, if there's a sacrifice going on,
couldn't it be there?
Yep, I mean, certainly that's the direction
we need to go sneakily.
Let's go in that direction.
Everybody make a stealth check.
Do I have to make a stealth check for my owl?
Yep.
Yeah, how's Guacamole getting around
now that you're out in the open?
Just like walking carefully.
Just on her tippy toes, real slow.
I rolled for myself.
Were you so close?
I was so close.
I rolled an eight plus one.
Okay.
So nine, oh god, and Guacamole got a five,
oh plus four, so she got a nine.
There we go.
It would have been better.
Those aren't sneaky rolls, you guys.
I got a 16 with Flint.
Don't walk near me, I'm super loud.
I got a 12 and Donnie got a 13.
You, not so quietly for the most part,
are kind of climbing through these bones
and around large boulders that have broken free.
You are about 200 feet from the tower,
so you are trying very hard to stay hidden
from the Chromatic Dragons
who seem to now be turning towards
one side of the tower
that is away from your direction.
As you continue to get closer,
you hear orders quietly being called
from around the far side of the temple
the closer you get.
And as these orders are being called,
you see the five Chromatic Dragons
leap up into the sky
and begin circling the location.
Double cheeseburger, fries, no ketchup.
Oh, it's the dragon drive-through, of course.
I'm sorry, I'm stressed out right now.
Yep.
There are so many big things.
As they are soaring around,
you hear another blast of the Drakorn
that echoes off the walls
of the inside of the volcano.
Can I use my lucky loo
to see if I can see what they're circling
with a little more clarity?
Or is it blocked out by the tower?
From what you can gauge
by what you can hear
from where the orders are coming from,
it's coming around the far side
of the tower itself.
Okay.
So if you were to see them,
you would have to physically walk around.
Yeah, that doesn't sound great.
We should just get to where we're going then.
Yeah.
You kind of keep an eye on them,
and they are circling,
getting lower and lower
to the one side of the tower.
And you have made it
to the side of the tower.
And is there a conveniently placed door?
Not at your current position.
Too bad.
Any windows?
I mean, I've often heard
that if there isn't a door,
sometimes there's a window that might be open.
Sometimes there's a window.
Yeah.
Very high up in the tower,
there appear to be slats
that could be construed as windows.
Could, are they like
human body size sneak through slats?
It's very high up.
It's hard to tell exactly how wide they are,
but they would probably be very big.
How high up is very high up?
The tower itself is probably
three to 400 feet tall.
And these windows are?
Somewhere kind of mid-range there,
so 100 to 150 feet.
You guys want to hop on Guacamole's back
and fly up to one of those windows?
I'm a little reticent to fly up
with the dragons flying around.
Seems like that would make us more visible.
That's a fair point.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Okay, should we continue
to walk around the side of the tower essentially?
There's got to be a way in somewhere, right?
Or do dragons just fly in the top?
Maybe.
Oh, could be like a helicopter pad.
Yeah, but someone has to do...
The cultists got to get in and out, right?
I don't know a lot about dragon architecture.
Sure.
But what else are we going to do
other than pick left or right and go that way?
Yeah, so they're kind of on the other side
of the tower from us, Russ, correct?
Yes, that is what you are making out.
Okay, so it would be like whichever way we went,
it would be essentially the same distance
or are we shaded to one side more than the other?
Because if we go around the side
that they're like furthest away from us,
that gives us more time to go around
without being discovered in theory.
Yeah, if you were to say go right,
you would probably be closer than if you went left,
like you would reach their location quicker
than if you went left around the building.
Long way around is left.
Well, my legs are tired.
Let's go right ways.
I came to the opposite conclusion.
Me too.
I was thinking let's not go
where the troops seem to be amassing.
Let's go the other way around.
Oh, okay.
Let's go that way.
Where maybe we can stay a little more hidden
for a few more minutes.
Yes, no, that's better.
Thea doesn't strategize.
My dogs are barking, guys.
Let's hit right to it.
The dragons don't kill me.
My feet will.
These boots are murder.
You begin walking and you hear a couple things.
Above the orders, you hear screams forming.
You see the dragons begin to stop circling
and they begin to soar down to the volcano floor.
You also hear a loud cracking boom from off in the distance.
If you look, you see clouds beginning to push and make way.
Before we walk any further, I say,
okay, guys, so something I was just thinking
because you guys are so good at the strategy stuff
and everything, but here's something
we just haven't tried before.
I'm just going to throw it out there.
What if from a place of hiding where I can see people,
before we like get into the thick of it,
I can like hurt them with some of my ranged spells?
I love it.
It's a great idea.
You know, just open up maybe some moon beam
or blight some bitches or something,
but they won't see me or you guys
and we'll have a bit of an advantage.
Yeah.
I mean, like I think that's a real good plan.
I don't know why we've never thought of it before.
I don't know why it took me this long,
but you know what?
I'm here where it counts.
I mean, I think where we are right now,
we're kind of exposed.
So I think unless there's no other solution,
that might be plan B and maybe finding a way
in this tower stealthily might be good.
Oh, no, no, for sure.
We still need to get in here,
but I think like if we get in here
and we see people before they see us
and I forget my plan,
I've told you guys that this is a viable option for us.
Let's go.
So you're continuing along your path.
And we do that real sneaky walk that they do in cartoons.
All right.
So super slow.
Yeah.
All right.
So at that pace, you're going to be walking
for kind of a long time.
Well, we do it a little faster.
I mean, a little bit faster.
Normal pace.
Yes.
Yep.
Got it.
Okay.
So you continue your trek around the building
as you get closer to where you assumed
the dragons landed or were circling.
These screams become more intense.
Are they human screams?
Uh, one could presume.
Yep.
Are they screaming things or just general like, ah?
Just general screams of perhaps pain and or agony.
If you were to roll an insight,
I'd give it to you because it'd be pretty low.
13.
Yep.
Definite pain and or agony and or fear.
I'll give you a fear for that one too.
Can we tell which kind of direction
the screams are coming from
or are they just kind of at the tower
and that's all we can tell.
Because of the tricks,
you can kind of hear them all around you,
but it's also from the direction
that you were walking
close to where the dragons had landed.
Okay.
I mean, those screams sound like they could be maybe.
Sacrifices?
Yeah, yeah, some sacrifices.
Stands to reason.
So maybe we go see what we can see.
And I mean, I do have that looky-loo
if we're still far away.
You continue to walk,
taking a glance around every corner as you go.
And you come to the final tower to walk around
as you have kind of counted them out
as you have been going around.
And you look who looks around the corner
or do you kind of go three heads at a time there?
Three students.
Shotgun lowest head.
Stands to reason.
Middle head?
I'm the tallest?
You are the tallest.
Comedic style.
You poke your heads out
and you look to see people being tossed
into the air into dragons' mouths
and a group of them
surrounded by the five chromatic dragons.
How big of a group are we seeing?
How many people in this group?
And how are they being thrown into,
like the dragons are grabbing them
and throwing them up
and catching them up like popcorn?
Oh, they're playing with them like orcas play with seals.
You and I, Carla, made the same face
as soon as he said that we were both like.
Yeah.
You see, well, at this point
there probably looks to be about 20 people remaining.
But does it seem,
it doesn't sound like it seems ritualistic,
but does it seem ritualistic
or the dragons are just being like hungry
and fucking gross?
I mean, they are surrounded in a specific order.
I mean, in defense of the dragons,
if you put a hungry tom in front of a pizza,
it's going to get gross.
You could probably infer
that these are the sacrifices.
OK.
Well, I mean, feed people
to five different dragons.
I guess I was like in my mind
I was picturing like priests doing ritualism.
Ritualistic murders.
Temple of doom type stuff.
As opposed to carving things on their bodies.
Calima, yeah.
Yeah, what not.
But yeah, I mean, it makes sense.
Five dragons eating people.
Like.
It all tracks.
Do we know anything about this ritual?
Because I worked in a library.
OK, roll a library check.
My dice is going to be in time.
Arcana or history?
No.
It's a 12.
It's a 15.
Do I know that here?
So here's my specific piece of information
I'm looking for.
Do I know that the sacrifices
have to be living before ingested by the dragons?
I'm about to get Machiavellian on this shit.
No, I was thinking the same thing.
Like if we kill the people, are we helping them
or are we stopping them?
Yeah, that's my question.
Like, oh, yay, they're all dead.
Thank you for coming in and doing that.
Or because I did work in a library.
She's got those library powers.
Dragons are my favorite enemy.
Maybe I have like, I mean, you think
we would learn as much as there was to learn.
I have a dragonborn in my head.
Maybe he knows something.
Everybody fucking roll.
I'm going to give you something here.
But I'm just trying to think how to phrase it.
OK.
From your readings and from your inner head
and from your just general knowledge about dragons.
They prefer to eat things alive.
But the ritual itself does not necessarily dictate
alive or dead.
Although sacrifices generally means things
have to be alive first.
But it does not specify if they were to die
by a third party and then if the dragons
were to eat them.
There's not no subtext or...
There's no footnote.
No footnote there.
As they might not have run into that yet.
It will be in version 2.0 next millennia.
So this definitely doesn't seem just kind of
like an as animalistic as I first pictured
in my head.
It's more like calculated.
Yeah, guys, I was really hoping
that there was going to be a way for us
to not have to try and fight five dragons.
Yep.
Anybody coming up with anything?
Um, can we sneak by these dragons somehow
that are busy eating these people?
Sorry people.
But I mean, in order for a ritual to happen
there's got to be some magic,
some magic casters somewhere.
There has to be some sorcerers or wizards
or somebody.
At that moment you hear the same crushing crack
come from the same direction
as where you saw something rolling
amidst the clouds.
And you turn and you see a massive ice fortress.
This is a fucking ice giant's castle?
A flying ice fortress?
Floating down through the clouds.
And it crashes into the lip of the volcano.
And is basically charging across the floor
of the volcano.
The dragons turn to look and see this
and they throw as many people up in the air
as they can and begin flying towards it.
You see a board, you see frost giants
readying weapons and waiting for the iceberg
to slow down.
For the iceberg to slow down.
Well, hello there.
Welcome to the middle part.
It's us.
People you were just listening to previously.
Yeah, just a few seconds ago.
I love that we haven't figured out
like the proper way to get into these yet.
I mean, I had it.
I had it down 70 episodes.
We just showed up and just flipped the table.
And then I was like, hey guys, come on in.
And now it's just not there.
You know what else you might've seen
on our social feeds?
That we got a big old invite to Hollywood.
Hollywood.
And by we all, I mean two of us.
So Amy and I are going.
Sorry, Tom.
Oh, it's all right.
I would have loved to go.
But as it turned out, I already had vacation plans
in that exact same time period.
So I'm not missing out too badly.
Carla's got that wedding she's planning.
We're the only ones who have enough free time.
Not enough on our social platter as it were
to be unavailable for this event.
But what is this event?
This event is D&D Live 2019, The Descent.
So yeah, we're going to Hollywood
and we got invited by Wizards of the Coast
to go play their new module
with a whole bunch of other great podcasters,
including the Broad Swords and Venture Maidens
and Taking Initiative and Drunks and Dragons.
Oh, there's a whole list.
So many people, so awesome.
So much more awesome than us.
I can't wait to surround myself
in all that awesomeness.
You know what?
I was listening to Drunks and Dragons today.
They don't listen to us, so they'll never know.
They were talking about how they're very nervous
about the live shows.
So we're nervous about them too.
So we're just all nervous.
Speak for yourself.
I was on stage like the other day and I'm like, yes,
I need a crowd of people clapping in my life.
Well, Amy, I feel like if you could roll
for some sort of performance check
while you're playing and bring your tap shoes with you,
I feel like that would really seal the deal
for whatever you were trying to do in that game.
Just build it into your character.
They haven't announced how they're doing characters,
but just put a little note.
Also does tap dancing.
Perfect.
Yeah.
You're a bard who tap dances.
That's your instrument.
It's my instrument.
Happy feet, motherfuckers.
You're a penguin bard who tap dances.
Sorry, wizards.
We won't swear.
We promise.
Oh, right.
Yes.
Gonna have to probably keep it clean.
It's a family event or something.
We really shouldn't have sent Amy then.
Right?
Oh, God, sorry.
Anyways, that's in May.
The 17th, 18th, and 19th,
if you're gonna be in the Los Angeles
slash Hollywood area or you live there
or you're near there,
you should come see us and hang out with us
and all that great stuff
because it's gonna be an amazing event
and tickets are on sale soon, if not already.
So check out the website
that's linked in the description.
Now we're gonna talk about something different.
Now for something completely different.
If you're liking what we're doing
and maybe you see us in Los Angeles
and you really like what we've got going on,
maybe you visit us on Patreon,
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
where you can join the sweet community
and get some sweet bonus rewards
for supporting us.
Like a game that Tom runs,
a side-scroller.
So awesome.
Russ plays a kitty cat.
Yeah, he does.
Yeah, I do.
A chatty cat.
That's about it.
There's also other things.
If you don't want to hear Russ be a chatty cat.
Final thanks to Sirenscape
for some of the amazing atmosphere
in today's episode.
Make sure you check them out at sirenscape.com
to bring your games to life.
And the next episode,
it'll be out next Wednesday, April 17th.
So let's get back to it.
We're getting close to that Tiamat.
Getting close, nearing the end.
And close to my birthday.
Oh, fun.
A little teaser for next week.
Have a great week.
We'll talk soon.
All right, so they're all distracted.
It appears to be at the moment, yes.
And some sacrifices have been left in the middle?
Not many,
because there was some talk about things.
Well, yeah, they threw things.
I assume they threw as many as they could
up into the air and then caught and ate them?
Yeah, oh yeah.
Okay.
I just imagine them being like,
whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop.
See you in a few.
Yeah, there appears to be three to five people
still left running now.
Running where?
Away from the tower.
I would say anywhere.
At this point, it's probably better.
Well, no, I know.
But if there is like an entrance or something
from where they were brought into it,
I'm assuming they weren't brought through
a hole that they had to take boulders apart
and then crawl themselves out of a crater
and then around the end.
That's how everyone gets in here, Amy.
I don't think it is.
Then maybe we could,
maybe going in that direction,
we might find some people to kill.
I don't want to fight dragons, you guys,
or I'll fucking die.
Yes.
You continue to see the people
running across the volcano
and from around the tower,
you see blasts of energy following behind them,
striking one of them in the back
as he falls to the ground.
I mean, now is probably a good time
to get on Guacamole and ride up somewhere.
Well, if I follow that blast of energy?
Did we see a muzzle flare?
Like, do we know where it came from?
Didn't appear to be a dragon blast,
more a magical spell cast.
I think I could tell that as a spell cast.
Yeah, no, that's what I'm wondering.
So we didn't see where it came from.
It came out from further around the tower
where you could not see specifically
who or what casted.
Well, I mean, let's go fucking see.
The dragons are as distracted
as they're gonna get, right?
Yeah, I guess so.
You continue to walk around
and two more blasts go out,
hitting two more of the people.
Okay, now we run around.
You run around and you see
a massive lit entrance
to the temple of Tiamat
and standing at the gate,
I'm assuming you're peeking around
rather than just bolting around the corner.
I'm always peeking.
Um, you see three red-robed wizards
standing at the gate.
Guys, guys, I'm gonna use a spell.
I'm doing like mad hand gestures.
One of them casts more spells
than fires them out at the remaining people
and two of them begin to turn
and walk back into the temple.
I'm gonna cast Stone Skin upon myself.
Before they exited,
I was hoping to hit them all
with Eldritch Blast.
You can most certainly give it a go.
Guys, guys, I'm gonna blast them.
And so...
One per each.
Okay, I just feel like
I had already rolled that
and it was an 18
and for some reason
I just decided to roll again.
Well, you gotta roll it three times.
Okay, well, this one's a 15.
This one's a 26.
There we go.
And this one's a 26.
I peeked around the corner
and I've essentially just like
put my fingers out like a
kkkkkk
type of motion.
Thea makes weird cat noises
and throws Eldritch Blast out.
The one red wizard who is looking towards you.
He sees them coming
and he deflects the one
that is going to hit him.
The other two hit the backs
of the other two red wizards
and they take
eight and seven.
They are struck by these.
They let out a cry of pain.
Turn to look
and the other red wizard yells
to them to get back inside.
They run and begin closing the door
as the red wizard turns
and continues to run.
Roll for initiative.
Guys, I think we're heading inside.
I got a 12.
I got a 16.
I got an 11.
The two wizards who were running
for the door
and beginning to close it
is their turn
and they continue to push
the large heavy doors closed.
Now it is Flint's turn.
You are a fair distance
from anybody
in terms of travel distance.
75 to 100 feet
from the door.
All right.
Can I dash on closer
to the door as best I can?
So if you dash
you're going to move double your speed.
Yeah.
So that will get me
roughly 50 feet away from the door.
OK.
And can I see either one
of the red wizards
that are attempting to close the door?
Like, are they visible at all?
No, they would be more behind the doors
pushing them closed.
I know previously, Russ
that you've been
in control of when Bort takes over for me.
Is there a way that I can trigger that
if I needed to?
We've never done that before.
So we're setting new ground right now.
I'm going to say, yes, we can try it.
Your new roll DC
that you've been rolling has been 12.
OK.
If you roll under 12
you become Bort.
If you roll over 12
you remain Flint.
So give me a little narrative
of Flint Bort
in the talk to transition
and see what happens here.
Yeah, as Flint's running towards that door
he knows Bort's got some skills
so he has a little thought bubble above his head.
Bort, are you ready to take over here for a second?
I got an idea.
What do you have in mind?
Well, you got that skill
where you can kind of almost disappear
if I remember correctly.
You take that step into the ethereal.
Yeah.
You think that's going to be helpful right now?
Yeah, I'm thinking we're going to need
a little fun voodoo to take care of these guys.
So I'm going to roll.
OK, I rolled a nat 20
so I guess I stay as Flint.
You are Flint.
Poor time to roll a nat 20.
A super confident version of yourself.
I guess.
No, no, buddy.
You're right.
I got this.
Yes.
OK, I'm going to throw my dwarven thrower
at the red wizard that's still outside the doors.
Sure.
He's running back to you
so you got advantage on this roll.
OK.
Well, first one's an 18
but you never know.
I might get that crit again.
Rolled it under my computer.
No.
So OK.
So the first one is a 28.
Yeah.
You mean that almost 30?
Don't want to assume.
I got to make sure.
That's fair.
We're so fucked if that didn't hit.
Right.
So that's 10 damage.
I'm assuming Flint is like talking out loud.
Oh, yeah.
No, he's just a straight up crazy person.
No, that's good.
That's good.
That's good stuff.
So you two, you see you see Flint like book it.
Like he's running.
Like there's no tomorrow.
And you hear him grumbling as he's running away.
And then he stops and he has a bit of a confused.
That should have worked better.
And then he throws his hammer
and hits the red wizard in the back
and it recoils and comes back to him
as the red wizard is propelled forward closer to the door.
He's now about 25 feet from the door.
Should have tried to take out his feet.
Sorry, guys.
It is the remaining red wizard's turn
and he runs through the doors as they slam shut.
And you hear yelling.
Well, probably mostly Flint because you're closer.
You hear yelling from inside.
What was a fairly bright light
coming through some of the windows, it gets brighter.
And the dragons in the air
and off in the distance, they were incredibly loud.
Some of the music in today's episode
is by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io
and Scott Buckley at scottbuckley.com.au.
Sound effects can be found at boomlibrary.com
and at sirenscape.com.
Stopping the picture recording.
Something else happened with the foot getting put in something.
I know it's amazing.
We like teed it up so well.
Horrible.
That's worse than water.
Yep, that is 100% worse than water.
Worse.
I guess I do both voices, don't I?
All right, I'm just going to talk to myself here for a sec.
Hang on.
Welcome to the club.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.