previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
we're gonna open them out like the Wizards of Thay.
there's a couple guys stationed or they were last stationed at Xanthels Tower.
you're gonna find Naer Gotht Blade Lord, Jorgen Pawl, Iskander.
he's there too.
they don't want Tiamat to come back, they want power for themselves.
you guys got shrunk down.
a whole bunch of tiny frogs are coming out for the sock.
and you fly towards Gransys as he's just ducking in and you see his head kind
of poke back out.
Squish him!
Grants us looks over to us like,
I was right.
These were the grunts that I accidentally shrunk.
I've been talking to their head honcho here
and he seems to think that we can settle the differences.
There's apparently also something else that I,
I'm still not a hundred percent sure what it is.
Shut up, what do we have to fight?
I don't know.
I'd love some sort of weapon
if we're fighting something.
They're gonna give us some weapons.
They lead you to what looks like
an open coliseum or arena
and they push all five of you through this door
and the big gate slammed shut
and stepping out is a giant white sock dragon.
That's my sock!
And it lets out a moaning, dry bellow.
So they're gonna let us go.
I just have to make sure that I get them back
to where they came from.
So you guys have drinks and you rest.
The next day you are called upon by Leosin
and he leads you to where the council
is having their meeting and he opens the door
and you see the entire council chamber
barking and yelling at each other.
It's mayhem and chaos.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We are a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast.
I am your dungeon master, Russ More
and with me today is Tom Laird.
Whoa, surprise order, that's me.
I play FlinkFirebeard.
And Carla Johnson.
Hey, how's it going?
I play new Laura Moonbrook.
And Amy More.
Yes, I am.
I play Thea Amastasia.
Welcome, everybody.
Thanks for having us, Russ.
Thanks for being on the show.
Happy to be here.
Thanks for picking up that Skype call.
I really appreciate it.
Even though it's Tom's birthday,
wish everybody Tom, wish everybody Tom birthday.
I would like to wish all the listeners.
Everybody birthday happy.
Hashtag wish everybody a Tom birthday.
Happy birthday, Tom.
Happy birthday.
Way to celebrate it with our 30th episode.
Yeah.
Tom, you're turning 30, right?
Sure, we'll go with that.
I'm sure there's a three in it.
It does start with a three.
There you go.
Nailed it.
Yeah, well then we're good, solid.
So Patreon, you get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today, our episode dedication is to Gabriel Lynch.
Hey, Gabe.
Thank you, Gabriel.
Thanks, Gabriel.
For supporting the podcast.
We really appreciate you,
as well as all the other amazing people out there.
All right, fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
He's second week in a row.
He is feisty.
That's it now.
That is how we start a game.
I like it.
It's aggressive.
It's final.
We're not fucking around anymore.
No more Chitter-Chatter.
Except now we're gonna get into all the Chitter-Chatter.
Welcome to the council session
where we talk for two hours.
Oh, shit.
I just heard everyone turn off the podcast
simultaneously.
Oh, come on.
This is gonna be much better than episode two.
Yep, they've already swiped left
and that little delete option
is just hovering right there.
Tune in to the very end
when we all compliment each other a whole lot.
I'm gonna listen to it at the very end, though.
None of this skipping through stuff.
Yeah.
There will be a quiz.
You enter the council chamber
and unlike the last time you were here
where there was quiet and order,
the entire room seems to be erupting
in argument and chaos.
You hear much heated discussion
about the death or suicide
of an aide from Neverwinter
who, Leosin mentioned,
had been reported as having hanged himself.
You see and hear an argument
between who you remember as Delaine Winterhound
of the Emerald Enclave
and King Melandrech,
the Elven King of the Misty Forest,
who is waving off concerns from Delaine
about dragon attacks in the Misty Forest
saying the elves have increased their patrols
and fortified their positions.
During all of this,
you see Lady Leral Silverhand
quietly observing the room
from the head of the council table.
And then from behind you,
you hear the heavyset footsteps
of Lord Dagult Neverember
as he strides past you
in followed by a human woman
who is very well dressed in silver robes.
You feel drawn to her presence
even more than the regal Lord Neverember,
but you do not recognize her
from the previous council session.
Lord Neverember sits at Lady Silverhand's right
and the woman following him sits beside him.
You enter the room further
and catch the eye of Lady Silverhand
who calmly says above no more
than a quiet conversation level,
council is in session.
Be seated.
Everyone quiets in the room
and goes to their seat.
There are four open seats
between Delaine Winterhound and Anthar Froome
who sees you hesitating by the door
and calls you over.
Come on now, you're as much a part of this as any of us.
Sit down and let's begin.
Yes, sir.
I stride over and I take a seat beside Anthar.
Yeah, of course, yeah, I just go sit down.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, just go and sit down.
Frances says,
so, okay, yeah, let's go sit down there, okay, yeah.
Oh boy.
I thought we ditched him.
I looked behind me and I was like,
have you been here the whole time?
Frances is still with you.
So tired all of a sudden.
Frances pulls up a chair
and scoots really close to Nulara
and says, oh, what do you think is gonna go on here?
Shh, just be quiet, please.
Everybody kind of, oh, yeah, okay.
It's been a while since I've been one of these.
I just don't remember how it goes.
Everybody kind of looks over in his general direction.
He's like, okay, sorry, yep.
As everybody's seated and settles in,
Lady Silverhand says,
ladies and gentlemen, we have much to discuss
and not much time to discuss it, unfortunately.
Our goal here today is to learn what we can
from our deputized investigators,
what they have learned and gained.
Second is to hear what is occurring in our various regions
and determine the correct course of action moving forward.
Flint, Thea, Nulara and Grancis,
what can you tell the council of your findings?
Oh, wow, Grancis is a part, he's, we are.
He has been assigned to you.
We are.
No one else wanted him.
I'm part of the team.
Oh, nobody's gonna jump in, I'll jump in.
What do you got?
Thea tries to just squash the feeling
of like really being trapped, like shackled to this man.
I'm really torn between just letting him talk
because I kind of want that to happen.
Yeah, me too.
Yeah, I say, I'm sorry, can you repeat the question?
I completely blacked out after the part
that you said that we're all together.
Since the last council meeting,
tell us of your findings.
Tell us of what you have found, your adventures
and where you come today.
It has taken you a little bit longer
than we had anticipated.
So something must have gone on.
Shit, he's making us recap, bitches.
It's the beginning of the year in episode 30.
God damn it.
And there's a song.
Let's start at the end.
We captured Ver'Am the White
and we've brought him here to you.
Oh, we're Quentin Tarantino-ing this bitch, I get it.
Who's Quentin Tarantino?
He works down the street.
He starts at the end of his stories all the time
and works backwards.
Interesting.
Yes, Ver'Am, he has been in interrogation
and he has told us some surprising things
about the cult.
How much do you believe what he says?
What did he say?
We really didn't get a chance to thoroughly talk with him
as we brought him straight to you.
He told us that you had a thorough conversation
about the goings on of the locations
of the Cult of the Dragon
and various people who may be swayed to our cause.
They have the Drakorn.
Remember, that's why we left,
originally was to go searching to see about that.
Yes.
They got it.
They wanna use it.
So no surprise there,
I guess, just confirming what we all suspected.
The wizards of Fae are going to cast a spell
that we'll call Tiamat.
There are people within their organization
who can be swayed.
They are, I have a list of things here.
They are in Xanthal's Tower,
Nargoth, Bladelord, Jorgen Paul, Iskander.
These sound like people
I've definitely heard of before.
And who are these people
in relation to how the cult is run?
These are groups that are helping
the Cult of the Dragon, I believe.
I believe Bladelord fears that Severin
will succeed in his plan
and Tiamat will end up destroying the cult.
And so he definitely doesn't want that.
He could be convinced to work on our side.
He wants to bring back the,
this is what it looks like my notes say,
Draco Bitches, but I bet it says Draco Liches.
Probably liches, not bitches.
Is that Jorgen?
That is Nargoth.
Yes, the Draco Bitches.
I haven't heard of them, but the Draco Liches, yes.
Then I wrote some hippogriffs
and that was the most exciting thing that happened.
So I have no further memories.
Oh, that was the big Harry Potter episode.
I remember that one.
We hear that you have swayed
the Arcane Brotherhood to our cause.
I didn't really think it took much swaying.
Yeah, they're on board for helping.
They are a great asset.
How did you go about bringing them onto our side?
We returned Macoth from her icy prison
and they seemed pretty amiable after that.
Icy prison, where was she being held?
She was the prisoner of the ice dragon,
whose name is?
Aruthator. Aruthator.
There it is. Or agruthator.
Yeah. Or,
all variations of those words.
Yes. Of course, of course.
And what of Aruthator?
As he is known to have dealt with the cult of the dragon.
Yes, he's the one who sold them the Dracorn.
Interesting.
And he is studying magical tomes, right?
To become-
He's wanting, yeah,
he's wanting to procure his own magic and spells.
And so Macoth was there helping,
translating with all the books
from the Arcane Brotherhood.
You see Heads nod around the room
and to your left, Anthar kind of grunts,
and he's like, you know, the Arcane Brotherhood,
I seem to be the only one here
who doesn't think this is a good idea,
but they've been known to harbor some evil,
evil wizard types.
Oh, oh, oh, what's that damn elf wizard bitch's name?
Is that-
Primsbane. Primsbane?
Oh, fucker.
Was he part of the-
You don't know.
Oh, well, I will ask.
Does the name Thelonious Primsbane
mean anything to any of you?
You see a look of not much recollection
among anybody in the room.
Well, he's like a little bit of a loose end.
He kind of, he's kind of after us a little bit.
I just want to go full disclosure here.
I look over to Flynn Newar
just to get like the, like,
Lady Silverhand says,
is it something of urgent concern
that we should look into?
I don't know,
but he seems like the kind of guy
who could just like pop up at any moment, you know?
Hmm, interesting.
It's kind of like a side plot bad guy.
Oh, was he a side plot bad guy?
No one knows exactly when those characters pop up.
Okay, well, we weren't able to defeat him,
which is really a thorn in my paw,
but I can't remember where I was going with this.
I seem to be the only one who doesn't like this,
so I'll just keep quiet over here.
Okay, good, good.
Looks to you, he's like,
I still don't like you.
I pat his thigh.
Inner thigh.
Oh my goodness.
He gives you a wink and a nod.
Oh, what about the thumbs up?
No thumbs up.
Oh, okay, I haven't quite reached thumbs up status yet.
Yeah.
You know, he's a human.
It's a dwarf thing, obviously.
Oh, fair enough.
I'm confused.
I've been flirting with so many different characters.
Sure, yeah.
It's just, it's kind of been.
So, sorry, Ruthatar was killed?
No, we fought him, but he managed to get away.
Wounded severely.
Well, that is something.
It takes dragons quite a while to recuperate.
So, maybe he will be out of the fight
for long enough to help us.
So, the Arcane Brotherhood is working with us.
You mentioned there's a rogue wizard and Varam.
Where did you find Varam and?
Varam had lost his mask, and he was.
His white dragon mask.
And he was trying to find it, and we found him first.
Did you procure ways of obtaining his mask?
No, it's back in possession of the cult.
So, that is why he is helping us, I take it.
Yeah, he's dead if he goes back to them, so.
Oh, hey, here's a fun fact.
This is how I talk in council meetings.
Hey, fun fact.
Time for one of your Lara's patented fun facts.
Yeah, quick sound a little bitchier about it.
Yeah, totally.
The cult has all of the things they've been collecting,
all the treasures in the Well of the Dragon?
Nope, it's an extinct volcano, like real super villains.
That's right, the Well of the Dragons.
Did you get, obviously Varam has given this information,
but for the council, did you get the location of this?
The northern end of the Sunset Mountains.
And that is where they are held up.
Did you get any further information from Varam
as to how close they might be to actually bringing Tiamat?
He thinks they're pretty close.
I am wary to send troops there as of yet.
I feel we have more information to gain
before moving forward.
I myself have been to battle and lost many, many an ally,
and I don't wish that upon anybody as of right now.
Delaine Winterhound speaks up.
So about the dwarf, you brought him here.
He's been known to upset the natural order of things before,
and I feel like holding him here,
we might be asking for more trouble than what it's worth.
Is there anything that we should,
now that we've kind of got the information out of him,
is there, like, do we wanna just offer him up
to get him out of here, or do we wanna?
He could potentially be leverage,
why would we just give him up?
Well, it seems like if they're-
No, no, no.
That was a stupid idea.
No more talking from you.
I see how it is.
Fucking shut down.
Right?
Why don't we take him for a reconnaissance mission?
He'll be able to show us exactly where to go,
potentially help mitigate pitfalls,
and at the very least,
offer him up as bait or distraction.
You don't think he could double cross you
and send you to the wolves, so to speak?
You don't think that I could turn into a wolf
and just tear him from limb to limb?
She raises a good point.
I like you.
You're good.
All right.
So you wanna go on a reconnaissance mission,
is that what you're saying?
Where are you going on a reconnaissance mission?
Well, Silver Lady just kinda made it seem like
things weren't ready and we needed more information.
I was reading between the lines,
I see what she's saying.
Fair enough.
Lady Silverhand says, you have gained much.
Is there anybody else that you swayed to our side
while you were out there?
Well, we saved Mirabar.
We saved Little Rock.
We saved...
Oh, what about the Army of Mirabar?
Axe of Mirabar.
The Axe of Mirabar.
The Axe of Mirabar has been reluctant
to join the council,
but they are an astounding force
that if they are on our side,
then that is another plus in our column.
Well, they're about as half as outstanding
as they were before.
How so?
Well, remember that Primsbane guy we were mentioning?
He kinda did a number on their army.
Oh.
Well.
But they still have a lot of troops,
so that's good.
That is good.
And babies are born every day.
This is true.
Takes a while for dwarves to age,
but that is okay.
The more numbers we have,
the better, is what I say.
We'll suit up every baby.
It'll be an adorable army.
Not effective.
This baby dwarf army sounds pretty awesome.
Very cute.
They'll only be as high as your knees,
but they will be vicious.
Last time we were talking to this council,
we were supposed to find Macoth.
Did it?
You're welcome.
We were supposed to find Varam the White.
Did it?
We freed Little Rock.
I'm looking at my list, you guys,
of things from one year ago
that we were supposed to accomplish.
Very exciting.
And then the other thing is
that the worm-speaker Nereveen
is in a misty forest stronghold.
We ever track that guy down?
Maybe we should do that.
King Melandrich says,
what was that name?
God.
Worm-speaker?
Nerenveen.
It's not possible.
Well, it's on our to-do list.
It's in the other info section.
Flips the page.
It's down in a footnote.
He says,
no, Nerenveen is my son.
And he's been lost for many, many years now.
We find things.
We're the finders.
That's pretty good.
I mean, it's better than what we currently have,
which is nothing.
Delayne speaks up and he says,
you said the misty forest is where this Nerenveen is.
That's where he was last seen, yep.
As I've been trying to tell King Melandrich here,
he says, oh, fuck off.
Anyway, I have
heard and have been getting reports
that there have been many recent dragon attacks
in the misty forest.
This could be connected to what you have found,
might not be,
but if this Nerenveen, son of King Melandrich,
fuck you.
Maybe he's working for the cult now.
That's fucking impossible.
King Melandrich tells me that it has been taken care of.
The elves have increased their patrols
and fortified their positions,
but as I asked him,
he has not heard from his patrols in quite a while.
I'm sorry, can King Melandrich speak for himself?
I don't wish to, my dear.
Oh, this man speaks for you?
This man is a fucking idiot.
Do you want us to find your son or not?
If it is my son, he's...
Do you believe your son is working
for the cult of the dragon?
That's not possible.
Why? That's not possible.
That's not how I raised him.
Oh, doesn't count.
Anyways, with all due respect here,
he hasn't heard from his outposts in quite a while,
which means that these dragon attacks
could have taken out large elven villages.
He himself hasn't been back there in a while.
Oh, Thea doesn't feel good about this.
She's all like, my people.
Delaine says,
But with more emotion.
I'm willing to lead a team there.
I know the area.
I just need support in case his reports aren't true.
I kind of like, like a group huddle.
Come here, come here.
And then we whisper loudly and like,
shh, wha, wha, wha, wha, wha, wha, wha, wha, wha.
And then we say, we'll do it.
I don't know, I'm speaking for everybody.
Of course we'll do it, right?
Oh yeah, we got this.
This is what we do.
We're trying to find the people
running the cult of the dragon.
And if that's our next clue
as to where one is going to be,
we may as well go.
Maybe we can save some lives while we're there.
Maybe we can kill a dragon while we're there.
Ooh, that excites Thea.
Lady Silverhand says,
Well, add it to your quest log.
Because this is, this is happening now.
Delaine Winterhound will lead a team
of you investigators to the Misty Forest,
where hopefully King MAlydindrich is true
in that his cities are fine and everything is good.
If not, you may find the next step we are looking for.
Granthas should stay here, I think.
What the fuck, we got the airship.
He does have the airship.
I can get us there, look at his flip.
Yeah, let's not, let's not spend like,
like three months traveling.
I spoke in haste.
We'll take the airship.
He can stay on the airship.
He probably should.
Perfect.
We're also whispering in front of Granthas.
Definitely.
I can hear you, you know?
I mean, I gotta make, okay, I'll go.
What'll happen is I'll drop you in the Misty Forest.
I gotta go make a swing by some frog places
with an old buddy of mine.
We'll get to that later.
But yeah, it'll be fine.
You guys do what you gotta do
and then I'll come back and swing,
pick you up, lickety split.
We'll be back here, Bob's your uncle.
I put a finger to his lips and I go, shh, shh, shh.
We will go to the Misty Forest.
Lady Silverhand says, wonderful.
Well, it seems we have determined our next step.
Lord Neverember had one more piece
that we needed to discuss before we go.
Lord Neverember stands up and says,
thank you, Lady Silverhand.
I've been approached by
and sent a representative from the Metallic Dragons.
This is Elia.
Elia, please inform the council
of the Metallic Dragons' request.
I look over at Flint and I go,
are they talking robot dragons?
You know the Metallic Dragons are dragons.
They are just metallic in color.
They're the gold, silver type dragons
and they always lean on the good side of the spectrum.
Whereas the Chromatic Dragons
lean on the evil side of the spectrum.
Elia stands up and says, thank you.
Everybody feels very drawn to her,
like I mentioned before.
When the Cult of the Dragon sounded the dracon,
as you know, its tremors were felt across the north.
Many metallic dragons began to investigate what it meant
and gather information on the cult.
One of those dragons, Protanther,
invoked an ancient draconic rite of council
summoning ambassadors from among the Metallic Dragons.
The council has determined what they want
and what the council here wants
have overlapping similarities in,
of course, stopping the rise of Tiamat.
And they wish for a representative to be sent
to their council meeting in the Nether Mountains
to find out how, if at all, you can help each other.
She looks to Lady Silverhand and she speaks.
Having such an alliance would be
immensely powerful in our fight.
Is this something that you, four,
she looks to Thea, three,
if Grancis has somewhere else to be?
He does, I'm sure he does.
He's a busy guy.
Can take on and handle the negotiations
with the Metallic Dragons?
Are we being asked to be in two places at once?
Elia says the council meeting will be held
when you get to it.
If there are matters that need to be taken care of
before that, with the Misty Forest,
they would be understanding in that.
They do not wish to wait much longer, though.
Well, it only takes us about four months
to accomplish a goal.
Totally.
What do we think?
I mean, it just sounds like
having more allies is a good thing.
That you know the Metallic Dragons
to be some of the wisest and smartest creatures
in the land.
I would like to meet those creatures.
I don't know about you, Nularaaaa.
I think it is a good idea for the alliance.
I think we are not diplomats
and this will not play to our strengths.
However, I'm willing to go
if that's what the council wants.
I think as long as we can properly articulate
the side in which that we are both on,
I think it will be fine.
I think we are all on the same team.
What exactly are they looking for?
Are they just looking for an amicable show of faith?
I have only been sent to ask for a representative.
Okay, so they just want to chit chat.
I say we go.
Sure. Of course.
Grant just says,
I can make sure that I've done my thing
before you guys go there and we can,
I've talked to lots of dragons before.
You speak Draconic.
Well, I mean, they speak common too.
Very common.
Look, they were yummy mashed potatoes.
Just don't get me started.
Yes, we will go.
I got distracted of our common talk.
You know, the star of John Wick 2.
Of course, of course.
He's an underrated actor.
Shut up.
Been watching him in Hell on Wheels.
He is amazing.
He's pretty good, pretty good.
Sounds like we got a new list of tasks.
Yes, we are in agreement.
Wonderful.
So you shall head with Delaine Winterhound
to the Misty Forest
and then go to the Nether Mountains
and meet with the Metallic Dragons.
Promptly witch reporting back here
as to findings of both.
Sorry, what do you mean by promptly?
We don't do anything promptly.
As quickly as possible.
As time, of course, is of the essence.
Well, you have much to prepare for.
I will dismiss you from the meeting
unless there's anything else
you require from us before you leave.
Just standard provisions.
Definitely could use some more healing potions.
Yeah, that'd probably be good.
Yes, we can supply you with all the things you need.
As many healing potions as your airship can carry
and it shall be so.
Lady Silverhand dismisses you
and then carries on with the meeting
and you hear as you,
are you staying, are you going?
What's happening?
I think we should go.
Yeah, great.
We're terrible at interacting with things.
Let's on to action.
You hear kind of the general conversation
as you are exiting the room
is just different heads of regions
talking about the different things
that the cult is doing in their countries,
in their realms.
And it sounds like it's not looking very good.
The cults have been sacking cities
and there's not a lot of people anymore
fighting back against them in a lot of these areas
that they are hitting.
They're hitting a lot of smaller towns.
Again, taking treasures
and just general murdering of people.
Well, that's not good.
Well, hello there.
I'm your dungeon master, Russ More.
Thank you for joining us
for episode 30 of Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Can you believe it?
30 episodes titled A Council Meeting in Waterdeep.
Wanna take a moment just to say thank you
for joining us for these 30 episodes
or if this is your first episode, thank you as well.
The show of support from our listeners
and other podcasters that we've received
over the last year has been amazing
and it's with your support
that we keep making each episode better.
The next episode will be out January 31st
and this next episode coming up
will feature our very first guest star, DM Doc
from the Bros and Dragons podcast.
Go check out his podcast
and give him some love over there.
But let's get back to the episode
and set forth on the next adventure.
Have a great couple of weeks
and we'll talk soon.
What you doing?
Gathering supplies, throwing them on the airship,
punching Grancis in the stomach.
Hoi!
How many healing potions
am I actually updating my inventory to include?
Yeah, ditto.
Like, I'll give you,
I'll give you,
how many did you have last night?
You started to say 50, did you say 50?
I was gonna say four.
Four each?
Yeah.
Okay.
It's not as good as 50,
but I'll take four because I had a zero.
They're gonna give you each one rare
and three uncommons.
So the one rare is an eight d four plus eight
and the uncommons are four d four plus four.
Uh oh, this means fights are gonna get real hard, guys.
Yeah, so you gather your health potions
and you head to the airship
and there is a new person there.
First you get word from a representative from the council
that Delaine Winterhound will be heading out on foot.
Oh God, it's gonna take him forever to get there.
I'm pissed about it because I really,
I thought we hit it off.
Why is he going on foot?
He's a man of the ground and of the wild.
And approximately how long will it take him
to get there on foot?
Oh, not long.
How long will it take us to get there by air?
Less than long.
Oh my God, you're so specific.
It's all the units of time you've got to lose.
Don't worry about it.
Story things, we'll just figure it out.
Okay.
So yeah, he will be heading out on foot with his wolf
and he will be meeting you at the rendezvous point,
which she has left for you.
Right, we totally talked about it.
Yeah, which you totally talked about
and it's totally in this scroll
that has been handed to you.
Perfect.
And you get on board the airship
and there is another older man standing there.
Oh joy.
Is it Grandsass?
It's Francis, Francis' twin brother.
It's Francis and Grantsass.
Nope.
Super team.
Tells stupid stories, does stupid shit.
Grantsass comes aboard and he says,
yeah, no, this is my buddy.
He's going to help me take the frogs back.
I mean, after we deal with all your misty,
misty forest dragons and stuff.
You want to know his name, I take it.
Yep, yep.
Yeah, yeah, you want to know his name.
Hey, Thaddeus, this is my friends,
the, my best friend, Laura and Clint,
all of which are great friends.
This is Thaddeus, sicker, crumple.
I've been calling him Crandall this whole time.
And he says,
If anyone got my Simpsons reference, you're welcome.
Yeah, it's true, one person got it.
Somebody did and they were delighted.
And they signed up for Patreon right after.
I'll work more Simpsons references into my games,
that idea.
He looks at you and he's like,
judging by the look on your face,
you've spent a little time with Grantsass.
Yeah.
Just a little bit.
How do you?
Yeah, the only.
Seems like it's been forever.
I was trying to talk to you.
Go for it.
How do you know Grantsass, Thaddeus?
Oh, we go, we go way back.
We were, we were in the magic military a long time ago.
I was his, his guy who made sure he didn't die.
Oh, he only had one of those guys?
Seems like that'd be like a full-time five person job.
Why we don't work together anymore.
Anyways, yeah, we've been on a lot of excursions,
including this frog excursion,
which I'm being roped back into
to help them bring thousands of frogs back down south.
I'm sorry, are these frogs currently on the airship?
Yeah, oh yeah, they're down below.
They're not big, he kept them small.
He's gonna make them bigger.
Yeah, no, we remember.
Oh boy.
All right, okay, I mean, there's just some frogs.
Yeah, we may or may not have been kidnapped
by these frogs before.
Anyway, does this not seem like a bad idea
to anyone else to have thousands of frogs
in the bottom of the airship on the way to a mission?
Oh, don't worry about it, guys.
I got them all locked up there.
They're in, and we talked about it.
You know, ribbit, ribbit, frog, frog.
And we came to a conclusion
that they just wanna be back home.
Okay, but do you swear you're not gonna mess with them?
You're not gonna shrink anything?
Swear on your mashed potatoes.
Swear on your airship you are not going to shrink
or embiggen anything while we are on this ship
and we are with you.
Yes, sorry.
I swear on my airship and my mashed potatoes
and my pancakes that I will not shrink in
or embiggen anything on the airship while we are traveling.
Excellent use of embiggen, guys.
Yeah, I'm loving this.
It's a perfectly Cromulan word.
Thaddeus is, he's an older human male
who is about, just about six feet.
He looks like he's in his late 70s.
Wrinkled, sun-worn skin and long flowing white hair.
Not like the crazy hair of Grancis.
He looks to Grancis and says,
once this is done, we're done, dude.
Like, seriously.
Dude. Yeah, yeah.
He's an old hippie, I like it.
It's an old hippie.
Yeah, I got it.
Okay, let's just, you know, one last,
one last, one last kick at the can.
And he goes and fires up the airship
and you guys start flying off towards the misty forest.
What are you guys doing on the airship?
Playing that dice game?
Oh, yeah.
I roll two sticks, a half a heart,
and a side nostril.
Nobody knows what you're talking about.
You win.
This is like the game of cups.
You have a full cup.
For pretty much a solid day,
just play this dice game.
Grancis had the dice game, that's what he had, yeah.
Here, guys, I learned this when I was on the water ship.
Here, you might be able to play it.
It's pretty intense, though.
A lot of rules.
A lot of confusing, confusing rules.
So you guys are traveling for about a day
and it's a little, it's about a day and a half flight
to get to the misty forest from where you are.
And you are suddenly in what appears
to be a lot of fog.
Grancis yells out, he's like,
just keep an eye out, make sure we don't dip too low
and clip a tree or something, you know.
I'm sorry, who are you talking to?
You guys.
We are to keep an eye out.
Yeah.
Aren't you driving this airship?
Yeah, now I'm a fucking pilot.
God damn it, I look out the window,
I'm like, I don't see anything.
And as you look out the window
and you say you don't see anything,
there is a burst of black flame that strikes the airship.
And a adult black dragon swoops overhead
as you begin plummeting to the ground.
And Grancis yells, I told you to watch out.
Hold on to your butts.
I had to pop in here at the end
because amidst being bickered at,
I forgot to mention that Thaddeus sickercrum-uple
is an NPC name given to us by one of our patrons,
Adam Farber.
Thank you, Adam.
If you have a name that you want to submit to us,
please leave us a comment below.
And if you want to see more of our videos,
please subscribe to our channel.
please leave us a comment below.
And if you want to see more of our videos,
And if you want to submit to us,
just check out the rewards at Patreon.com slash dumb dragon
cast.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin McLeod
of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
Karla.
Yep, I have some stuff.
I sent you guys a page.
Okay.
Uh-oh.
Y-O.
I'm the work.
I'm sorry, I didn't read it.
All sorts of like vocal activities going on.
I know, I like it.
And he's panicking.
Freeing the natural voice over there.
Russ just nodded, very like,
I can't believe you got it that fast.
I'm just looking through my notes and it's like,
well, there are some people we saved.
There are some people we saved.
Surely some of these people will help us
if we need them too.
I'm sorry, what accent is this?
I don't know.
I like it though.
It was very British at the beginning
and now I don't know.
He's just getting angry.
So he just, you know, you know, loses it.
This is Elia Stormborn.
Elia, please inform.
That's not your, that's not your real,
like Elia, yes, but is it Stormborn?
No.
It is?
Okay.
I was like, I was pretty sure.
It's Daenerys Stormborn.
But you gave me a micro heart attack there.
I was like, what is this shit
you're launching on me right now, Russ More?
Oh yeah, this is a fucking surprise crossover.
Bitch, get on board.
I feel really bad for Russ when he talks as Grancis,
because the look I give him is like,
I'm just sitting here just looking at him like,
just stop talking.
Why, why do you exist?
I agree.
I always feel bad when I mean to Grancis
cause like it's Russ being Grancis.
So just so you know, I think you're great, Russ.
Grancis, it's the worst.
I originally designed Grancis to be super useful,
but then he kind of quickly became super un-useful
and you guys just went with it.
So that's what we're going with now.
Hey, the airship comes in real handy.
It does, it does.
He's good for that.
It cuts down on our time.
Yeah.
Yeah, that was the one thing that he had going for him.
Anyways, Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons
production.