Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Who in the Cult of the Dragon can be turned?
The answer to this question has three parts.
The first you will find on your current path and quite near, but you must move quick as
his light grows darker as the seconds pass.
You hear grinding stone coming from the northern wall.
You see six blizzard folk readying their clubs and javelins, holding spiked shields,
charging forward in attack.
You walk down some steep stairs that lead to an uneven stone bridge.
Moisture drips down from the high ceiling, covering the bridge in a slick moss.
Flint and New Laura, you make it across, but you hear from behind you the slip and
the, what sound would Thea make as she slips and falls into a dark pit?
Ah, fuck!
You fall 80 feet.
As I fall, I hug myself like fuck and I cast Cure Wounds upon myself.
You grasp yourself and regain 10 hit points.
As you feel yourself hit the solid stone floor, and you take 36 bludgeoning damage.
Ooh, boy!
Fairly conscious as you look around you and see the beady eyes of many yonty young swarming
around you.
Welcome to Jemjins and Dragons.
We are a fifth edition D&D podcast.
With me today, as always, is our wonderful DM, Russ More.
Thank you for having me.
I enjoy being here.
And playing New Laura is Carla Johnson.
Hey, I like this new intro style.
This is pretty fun.
And last, but certainly not least, Tom Laird, playing Flint Firebeard.
I'm totally leased.
Well, I wasn't going to say it.
Yeah, I really like this new intro, too.
I think this should be liked in every time.
I like it.
Two notes.
You called us Jemjins and Dragons.
I did not.
You did.
Second note, you didn't introduce yourself.
And last, last, but.
I mean, in Amy's defense, I'm pretty sure we're undergoing an aggressive rebrand to Jemjins
and Dragons.
This is how we're telling you, Russ.
We have a new name.
Don't worry.
I'm going to play it back right now.
It's going to be like Jemjins, Jemjins, Jemjins, Jemjins, Jemjins, Jemjins, Jemjins
and Dragons.
I look forward to listening to it.
Okay.
That's good.
Welcome, everybody.
Yeah, you're Amy More.
Amy already said welcome, everybody.
I did.
Get with the times, Russ.
I don't remember saying Jemjins.
I didn't notice.
Honestly, I didn't think you did it.
But as Russ said, I'm sure he's now going to have another loop of you saying it.
So I guess you did.
Yeah.
You should probably just let it go otherwise.
You know what?
I'm going to go ahead and say that Amy said it right and Russ is wrong.
We're going to see who's going to be in cronics.
We're going to have to.
Guys, my character is going to get killed tonight.
I'm sorry.
Are you currently at 10 hit points?
At the bottom of a pit?
I don't know, but I will be in about 30 seconds.
I don't think you will be.
And Flint is pushed.
I believe I believe that maybe you guys are just going to save the day.
We're going to save the hell out of you.
You're going to be fine.
I'm very excited.
It's all good.
Don't worry.
No pressure on anybody dying.
Maybe if you if you're looking for more of Jemjins and dragons, you're not going
to find us under Jemjins and dragons.
But if you go to Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast or Jem dragon cast or Jem dragon cast
I hate you with with a silent D U M B instead of a D J H Z shut up with your spelling.
We are up there.
And if you become a patron and join our community for as little as a dollar a month,
you can get a sweet shout out like our random patron today, the Bros and Dragons podcast.
Hey, we know them.
They're great.
They're super awesome.
They've got Bros and Dragons.
They have.
I lost it.
I'm drinking beer.
Yeah.
Doc and the guys over there put on an excellent show.
You should go check them out.
I'm also on that show.
You are also on that show.
I am.
They've got a big season finale coming up or just happening depending on when this
episode comes out at the end of the month.
So it'll be coming out soon.
It'll be coming out soon, I think.
Listen closely for my big motivating speech that isn't at all causing me major anxiety
issues.
Excellent.
I look forward to it.
You just need to watch a lot of like Braveheart and The Matrix.
Maybe some read over some Sir Winston Churchill speeches.
Just don't watch any Neville Chamberlain speeches because that is totally the wrong
attitude.
Yeah.
History.
So thank you, Bros and Dragons, for contributing and joining our community and posting and
all that great stuff over on our Patreon page.
Yeah.
Thanks, guys.
We really appreciate you.
If you want to get a shout out or any of the other sweet rewards, including the
Dums and Sidescroller episodes, just visit Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
Check it out.
And we'd love to have you over there.
You said check it out.
I said check it out.
There wasn't a chuck.
It was definitely a chuck.
Don't worry.
We'll play that one back, too.
Check, check, check it out.
Good.
And you'll hear shh, shh, shh.
Oh, man.
Now I'm all nervous because any time anybody misspeaks, it's like they're just going
to get it.
No, you guys are fine.
You guys are fine.
Neither one of you is married to me and then has criticized my speaking.
So you're totally good.
You know what?
That is a valid point.
You're totally good.
It's fine.
Basically, the only reason I'm here, I think, is to criticize people speaking.
Okay, I'm done.
None of us just corrected him.
We just let that lie.
You guys are like, Amy's got this.
I'm sure she's given the worst stink eye right now.
And I did.
So everybody remember what happened last time.
I'm laying at the bottom of a pit, just a shell, just a broken woman surrounded
by...
We also discussed the Christmas card photo.
I think that took up a lot of time.
Oh, yeah.
Christmas card photo.
I need a picture of your lovely faces.
It doesn't have to be in any weird pose because I've got an idea in my mind.
That's better than my idea?
Yeah, because your idea is going to take much longer to do.
So I just need a picture of your smiling, lovely faces.
And I'll put it on a card and it will be great.
Sooner rather than later.
Thanks.
Okay.
And this ends this episode of Card Chat.
Our new podcast within a podcast.
Can we start?
Because I have something I want to do because I'm in imminent danger right now.
And I got to like fix shit.
Okay.
We're going to play some D&D now.
Let's fucking play.
Okay.
As you recall, Thea slips on a slimy bridge and falls...
You're going to say banana peel.
Nope.
It's fucking banana peels keep popping up.
They're dangerous.
Thea slips and falls off the slick moss covered bridge falling down 80 feet.
On the way down, Thea tucks in close, casting healing hands and a shimmering light emanates from her body right before she hits the floor with a sickening thud.
Flint and Nularaaia, you hear this thud as well as the sound of hissing and writhing from below.
You can't see quite down that far.
And Thea, you look up having taken 36 damage.
Your healing hand spell keeping you conscious.
Sorry, it's twice now.
It's healing word.
Your healing word spell keeping you conscious.
But only barely as your vision narrows and you see the eyes of many yonti younglings closing in on top of you, ready to feed as you are prone and stunned.
Okay, what does stunned mean?
It means you can't take action right away.
Why?
Because you're stunned.
Because you fell 80 feet on your head.
Whatever, I'm just winded.
Well, fine, then I won't do what I wanted to do and I'll do it once I'm getting eaten.
Let me confirm to you what you can or cannot do.
May I cast?
May I?
It's not even a cast.
It's not even casting.
I'd like to wild shape.
Stunned.
You are incapacitated.
You can't move and can speak only falteringly.
Flavin'.
The creature automatically fails strength and dexterity save throws.
Attacks against creature have advantage.
And incapacitated means you're incapacitated.
Can't take actions or reactions.
Is wild shape really an action?
I mean, it's a thing.
Roll for initiative.
Get this off of my area.
I'm sorry, are we all rolling or is just Amy rolling?
No, everybody.
Well, yeah, no, I'm going to need you guys.
Unless you guys don't want to do anything.
14.
Yeah, we're just going to watch from the bridge.
You got this.
Why was it true if we had to get down there before or what?
I got a five.
Yeah.
Oh, damn.
God, our initiative rolls are bitchin'.
You want to roll guacamole in there?
Yes, I will.
She rolled three.
OK.
My extremities are really heavy.
Goddamn owl.
Hey, she's your ticket down into that messy pit.
OK, Nularaaa, you are up first.
It's a straight moss covered walls all the way down to the bottom of this pit.
Well, it's 80 feet.
Flint, how long is your ladder?
It can extend up to 50 feet.
I'm pretty sure.
OK, because I can't do anything else.
I am going to, I guess, wait for guacamole to land because I think she was flying and then get on her so she can take me down there because I can't do anything from 80 feet away.
You're delaying your action then.
Yeah.
OK, so Thea, your turn.
You are stunned.
So I do nothing?
So I think you do nothing.
I can't even cast a spell on myself.
That's an action.
Well, then I lay there.
Well, let me see if there's a way you can get out of it.
Oh, I want to do that.
Yeah.
Pretty sure.
Seems sketchy.
In the meantime, I shout down, Thea, we're going to come get you.
And I'm just like.
Flint, she's speaking falteringly.
It's not good.
You are.
Yeah, no, you are just stunned for two rounds.
Two rounds?
Two rounds.
Get the fuck down here.
OK, so snakes.
If I was able to just drop a healing potion onto her, would that do it?
Pretty sure you have to drink those.
I'm pretty sure you'd probably hit me in the face and be like, oh, she takes three damage.
She's stunned for another two turns.
Sorry.
Being as it fell from 80 feet, she's now dead.
Yeah, this actually went right through her skull.
It's crazy.
So the yonti younglings are up next and they swarm over top of you.
You feel snakes climbing all over you and around you and they bite you.
No, they don't.
Four.
That's.
They don't do it.
It probably doesn't happen.
Fifteen.
Well, fuck.
Against your AC.
Not damage.
Oh, OK.
I thought I just had to take it.
Then no, that doesn't work.
So there.
Yeah, you must have squished that one a little bit.
Did I fall on it?
OK, so 80 feet away.
Yeah, 80 feet straight down.
OK.
How far am I able to fall without taking massive amounts of damage?
Like 20, 30 feet, 40 feet.
I mean, you could probably.
I think that the limit is like 15 or 20.
Let me just look that up here.
You just want a free fall.
Well, no, I have a plan.
Yeah, 30 feet.
30 feet.
OK.
Before you take damage.
Well, 30 feet you take damage.
So anything under that you would you would, you know, you'd be OK.
OK.
How am I going to work this?
OK, I'm going to use my extendo ladder rod of lordly might thing, which goes up to 50 feet.
And I'm going to like hook it into the side of the bridge that we're currently on.
OK.
And I'm going to extend it all 50 feet, slide down it and then drop the last 30 feet down to these yonti younglings.
Do you have a parachute?
OK.
No, but I can drop 30 feet without taking damage.
You take damage at 30 feet.
Yeah, but it won't be crazy because it's only 30 feet.
That's what I thought.
No, you fell from 80 feet.
I guess jumping is more of a.
Yes, I'm going to get you to make a dex check or an athletics or something.
Athletics or acrobatics.
Do a something check.
I like it.
I'm on board with it.
That is a 17.
You hook in your rod of lordly might and push the right button and your ladder shoots straight down.
And you ride that ladder down, screaming something heroic.
He screamed something heroic.
Look at this heroic thing I'm doing.
And as you get to the bottom, you stop for a second to slow yourself and dive into a tucking roll, taking only six damage as you quite firmly hit the bottom.
But you would still have your you would still have your actions.
Yes, excellent.
He makes an incomprehensible dick joke about the shaft and the sliding.
All right.
OK, so I've got all these younglings around me and I have my attacks available, correct?
Yeah, you landed relatively near to where Thea is.
So there are some some of these younglings near you.
Most of them are on top of Thea though.
I'm pretty good with my axe.
I'm pretty precise.
So maybe I'll try and take a few of these off of her.
Sure.
Don't miss.
I would never miss.
Twenty one.
Twenty one will hit.
Yeah.
Excellent.
And eleven is nineteen and four is twenty three.
A lot of these small youngling yonti snakes scatter in pieces, but still there are about half of their mass swarming on top of Thea.
I'm going to do that again.
That's a 19.
Twenty four.
You swipe down and clear them pretty much completely off of Thea.
There are a few left that kind of scatter towards the walls, but it looks like you have cleared pretty much all of the snakes that are in the direct vicinity that you can see.
Excellent.
What do you want to do next?
I should probably help Thea to her feet or something like that.
Yeah, if we're out of combat, can she just get guacamole to fly down there and get her now?
So yeah, guacamole comes down and picks you up and Flint hops on her back and she flies you back up to the top of the bridge on the same side that you fell off of.
No, she puts you on the other side.
Okay, good.
We have to cross this thing again.
And as she lands in there, the walls and the ceiling are about as tall as she is at this point.
So she has limited movement going into this next tunnel phase.
She will walk.
Okay.
Oh wait, it's as tall as she is?
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
So she drops you off, but there's limited room for her to actually move and continue forward, is what I'm saying.
Well, I can't continue forward.
I apparently am still just laying there like a like a jerk.
Flint and New Laura, what are you doing?
I don't know.
Flint, you got any healing potions?
Is Flint there?
Yup.
He had to look.
He's rifling through his bag.
I did. I had to ruffle through my bag a little bit.
I have a healing kit, but I don't have any healing potions.
Yeah, no, I'm pretty sure I have several healing potions still.
May I have half one?
I'll just double check my notes.
You're coming to a little bit more in your mind at this point.
Oh yeah, I still have like four. Yeah, take two.
What do I have to do for a healing potion?
You just have to drink them.
And?
And I'm hoping Flint wrote that.
It's a 1d4 plus 2.
Thank you.
You're such a dick.
Drink it.
Ooh, I rolled a four.
So that's one potion.
So that's six.
Three plus two and that's five.
That's excellent.
Up to a balmy 21 hit points.
Oh, that's good.
So I assume that that kind of revives me and I'm not stunned and shit anymore?
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
I will cast Cure Wounds on myself.
May I Wild Shape?
Yeah, you can do whatever you want.
I Wild Shape.
So you stand up and dust yourself off and Wild Shape into?
First I call Gwakmuli back and she becomes her Jade self again.
And I Wild Shape into a Winter Wolf.
So yeah, you take these potions and shape into this Winter Wolf.
So the three of you now have just a narrow stairway leading up in front of you.
And you get to the top of that stairway and you are at a T intersection.
So you can go straight down another set of stairs or to your right there is a hallway.
And you look down that hallway and along the right wall you see two open passages,
followed by nearing the very end a closed door and along the left hallway there is one closed door.
And at the very, very end there it looks to be a left turn into another open passage.
So you've got a set of stairs straight ahead of you and a long passage with doors to your right.
Who's feeling lucky?
Wait, the wolf can talk?
Can you talk as a wolf?
Yes, I can.
Yes, the wolf can talk.
Oh, right, you can.
We figured that out when you were just growling for an entire episode.
That never happened.
It did.
Yeah, I don't know.
Down the stairs or down the other hallway?
What do you guys think?
I just have a bad feeling about stairs now.
That passageway and the falling.
I have no good reason not to go there other than like the stairs are giving me the heebie jeebs right now.
Yeah, I look at I look at new Lara and I say stairs are weirding me out.
Let's go this way.
Gesture with my big old wolf head.
Sounds good.
So you have developed a phobia of stairs and you turn down the long hallway as you step about 20 feet down this hallway.
You hear the sound of grinding stone behind you and you quickly turn around and the passage which you came is gone.
Perfect.
Exactly what we wanted.
And you turn back and you kind of double take and blink a few times because you think your mind is playing tricks on you.
But the hallway begins to undulate like the movement of a slithering snake.
Oh, God, we're in a stone snake.
And the passages and doors that you saw before come in and out of view as you stare down this hallway.
Spooky.
This should be our Halloween episode in the for 2018, I guess.
Yeah.
Let's hold on to this episode.
Find out how they got out of the temple when.
Do we want to try one of these doors?
One of these disappearing doors?
Is there a door at the end of the hallway?
There is a yeah, there's a door to the right and a open passageway to the left that you remember seeing at the nearing the end of the hallway.
Can I do like a perception check to see if I can figure out what's going on?
Like if this is actually happening or they're playing, you know, like they have already been inside my brain.
I don't like it very much.
Yeah.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So you're looking for something specific or you're looking for something magical.
What are you looking for?
I am looking for something that will ground me more in reality to see if this is a trick.
Sure.
That is a 24.
It appears to you that the hallway is in fact moving.
At least that's what it seems to you.
When you look down to the end of the hallway, the door and the passageway are the only things that you can see that stay constant in the hallway.
The other doors along the walls, they fade in and out as the hallway moves down the corridor.
But the passageway and the door at the very end remain constant and follow with the movement of the hall.
The wolf is looking at the wall too long and throws up.
Shouldn't have sat in the back of the car.
Oh, that's really funny.
Guys, it looks like the door at the end of the hallway isn't moving.
Like, let's go that way.
Also, wolf puke.
Like, let's get away from that.
I say, like, let's just book it down to the end of the hall.
Yeah.
I'm already kind of starting to walk in that direction.
I follow you, Lara.
Okay.
Why walk?
We can run.
So you push to the front.
Like if we're going to book it down the hall.
It's true.
Yeah, let's get out of here.
Yep.
So we run to the end of the hall.
So you are running down the end of the hall.
And just as you were about to make it to the end of the hall, about 20 feet from
the end, and you hear from behind you as you are running a door open and the sound
of slithering and footsteps come out behind you.
And you turn to see three lizard folk spring out at you and one slithering, yawn-tee,
pure blood.
Roll for initiative.
16.
Also 16.
13.
Do we roll off or does it go by our initiative bonus, Russ?
It'll go by your, yeah, your initiative bonus.
So mine's three.
Carla's up first.
The yawn-tee, pure blood is first through the door and first up to strike.
And what are his snake versus human parts?
Yeah.
Oh, you can't see any snake parts, but there is one.
Oh, God.
Gross.
Is it one of his toes?
Is that what you mean?
Yeah.
No.
He is all snake.
Is it just me?
I feel like it's not because I feel like Amy's here with me that everything in
this game sounds perverted tonight.
It's me and I'm sorry.
The latter, the falling.
No, like I have been thinking it too, but then you keep giggling when I am trying
not to giggle because it's very immature, but I mean to it.
It's my shtick in this.
I am gross.
And I lied.
I looked at the wrong page.
He's all human looking, except for his eyes that have a very.
Except for his dick.
It was actually his dick.
It said so in the book.
If he's clothed, we'll have to assume he has a snake penis.
Yeah, obviously.
Yeah, but yeah.
Sneaky snake penis, a sneeness.
He's up and he jumps at you with a scimitar and strikes.
At what order were you guys in?
Last.
Strikes at Thea.
What?
You were last and you passed the door, so you were first to strike.
Oh fuck.
I mean first.
He strikes you with his scimitar.
First one for a 22, second for an 11.
A 22 will hit.
That's four slashing damage at you.
And then the lizard folk are up.
This is about a 10 foot hallway.
So Thea, you are first line of defense.
Fuck.
You're a badass wolf right now.
It's fine.
I know.
Well, thank God I have more hit points as a wolf than I do.
Thea regularly does.
Thank God you are smart enough to immediately shift into a badass wolf back there.
At least I have that option.
I've been so low on my hit points that I'm like, oh yeah, okay.
I guess I'm going to become someone else.
It's just a good strategy.
Two of them throw javelins, one at New Lara, one at Flint.
The other one strikes at you with his heavy club twice.
So the heavy clubs are 21s, both of them.
Are you sure those aren't javelins because you mentioned the javelins first?
Okay, I'll throw the javelins first.
No, he's first in line.
So he hits you twice with his heavy club.
Damn.
How heavy is it?
It's 8N.
It's real heavy.
That's 12 total bludgeoning damage.
The javelins come flying through the hallway.
That's a 22 at New Lara and an 11 at Flint.
Nope.
I am, obviously.
New Lara, you take 8 piercing damage as this javelin comes, which seemingly,
as it flies through the air, it seemingly straightens out the hallway as it comes
towards you and begins undulating again as it strikes into you.
God, I hate that word.
Undulating.
Engorged.
Moist.
New Lara, you are up next.
Throbbing.
All words I hate.
Gooey duck.
Tom's got some weird ones.
What other words do you hate, Tom?
Those are words I hated.
I was just saying words.
I would say the grossness of a gooey duck is more its appearance than its...
The name is super fun and the appearance is gross.
The word is fun.
The appearance, bit of a snake penis, gotta say.
Minus ninus.
Right.
Okay, well, I obviously pull up my sword and say booey caliente because I'm real mad
that I just got javelined.
Where are we at?
The Olympics?
This is bullshit.
Oh, wait till the shot putters come out.
And who's closest to me?
The yonti?
There is a lizard folk that jumped in front of the yonti.
Okay.
Well, that's who's going to get it then.
Maybe.
That's a 13.
Against the lizard folk.
That does not hit.
Okay.
Well, I'm going to try again then.
That one will be better.
That is a 21.
Yeah.
Oh, geez.
Yeah, 21 will hit.
Sorry, I lost a sneeze.
Okay.
It's always in the last place you look.
That is 20 points of damage, which is maybe the best damage loss I've ever had.
So great.
Yeah, so that lizard folk's dead.
Oh, thank goodness.
She sliced him in half, but it also caught her eyes, so he didn't even bleed.
He's just two pieces.
Yeah, it just smells real lizardy because I don't know what lizard smells like when
it fries.
I was going to say like bacon, but it could smell like bacon.
I don't know.
I ate snake before.
I ate snake.
Yeah, and it just was like chickeny, honestly.
Yeah.
It's just nice.
Donnie's going to come in and not bite that guy because he'd be dead.
I guess the other lizard folk, he'll try and give him a little chompy chomp, but he
won't because that's a nine.
No, that does not work.
Flint, you're up.
I'm going to barrel my way through to this yawn tee and kick the shit out of
it.
Okay, yeah.
It's a 21.
21 will hit.
Are you going for the yawn tee?
Yes.
20.
Okay.
You don't seem sold on these damage rolls, Ross.
I believe it.
He's just not thrilled about it.
Oh, okay.
I got you now.
That's a 22.
22 will still hit.
Yep.
Four and 10 is 14 and four is 18.
Okay, so this yawn tee isn't looking so good.
Your turn there, Wolfie.
It is?
Yep.
Who's left?
There's two.
There's a lizard folk and a yawn tee.
Lizard folk behind the yawn tee, which is, in the yawn tee's opinion, a very
terrible place for them.
I'm just going to give you the inner monologue here as we go.
Oh, okay.
Well, I step forward.
They are fired.
I step forward so that I'm aligned with Flint so he's not in front of me.
I am going to blast my cold breath.
It's a 15-foot cone, so it should hit all three.
Yeah, you'll hit all three.
It's only a 10-foot wide hallway, so.
Each creature must make a dexterity saving throw.
Okay, so we've got another dice.
The yawn tee's snake penis is totally moving like crazy trying to get away.
I like it because it has a mind of its own.
It's like, get me out of here.
Yawn tee rolls a 14.
Yep.
And the lizard folk, they roll a 12 and a four.
So the lizard folk will take the full 48 cold damage.
The yawn tee will take half.
The yawn tee turns sideways and gets just less of it, holds in his breath.
Wow.
He put his penis like right out there too.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's all about, it's all the yawn tee.
This is our new favorite.
This is like our new star.
We need to get out of this temple so we can stop talking about snake penises.
It's too late, Russ.
Every episode now.
27 cold damage.
So you've got.
I'm going to like.
So yeah, even though the yawn tee turned sideways, all of them.
Wait, what were you like, Amy?
Excellent.
Are now frozen solid.
All of them.
Well, because they're cold blooded motherfuckers.
Yeah.
So they're all.
Anyone have a hammer?
I've got smithing tools.
So you're like just going to tinker with them?
I have a ball peen.
It's a hammer.
Get your minds out of the gutter.
I know what a ball peen is.
Literally a hammer.
Yeah.
Like if he takes a good whack at them.
Or like, I mean your axe too.
Will they just shatter?
I would like that.
Because I'm mad, you know, for good reasons.
You hammer them with your wolf paws.
Oh, could I just hop up and like push them over?
You know when the dog gets too excited and jumps up?
Yeah, that's probably a little better.
Okay, I do that.
You just playfully jump up at them.
Look what I did.
Yeah.
Knock them over and they smash into a gazillion pieces.
And the hallway is still undulating.
Yeah!
I said it again.
What you guys doing?
Do we continue on through?
I don't want to be last anymore, you guys.
I want to be in the middle.
Can I be in the middle?
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
So we keep running down to the door?
Yeah, so you're only about 20 feet from the end of the hallway.
And then there's a door to the right, which as you approach, you kind of get the smell,
a foul smell that seems to be coming through the door.
And to the left, you see a hallway that extends down further.
Just an open hallway ahead of you out to the left.
And a door.
A smelly door.
The hallway to your left, though, doesn't appear to be slithering like a snake.
Undulating.
That was the last time you had to get it in one more time.
Can we identify the bad smell, like death, garbage, poop?
Oh, I have keen hearing and smell.
It smells to you of like trash and filth.
That's garbage, you guys.
And garbage room.
Alright, then left?
Left.
Sure.
You run barreling down this, it's about 70 foot hallway, and there's a doorway at
the very end and a right turn immediately at the end of the hallway.
And the right turn opens into a large, dark room that appears, even with your dark
vision, you can't really see very far into this room.
So there's a door directly in front of you and this dark chamber.
I sniff at the door, do I smell anything?
It doesn't smell, it doesn't smell great, like it smells through the door without
actually looking in there.
It smells like, it smells very lived in.
Oh, like dormitories.
But it doesn't smell like trash and filth, if that's what you're looking for.
Guys, this one smells a little less disgusting than the last one.
Like, like kind of sweaty people.
Like people are in there, but like probably not lounging in garbage.
Just personally, I would feel better going through the door.
I can't see shit in that room.
Well, let's go through the door then.
I keep feeling like I got little yonty young crawling all over me.
I can't, I paw at the door.
I'm a dog and I don't have hands.
You open this door and it creaks open and you step in and it looks like it has been
turned into some sort of prison.
There are cells with doors and it doesn't appear on first glance that there is any
other way out of this room.
How many cells?
There appear to be six cells all empty.
How'd you predict my next question?
You did.
You predicted it.
Well, if you're looking for how many cells there are, you're probably looking for
if there's anybody's in there.
Well, yeah, but hold on.
Last time we found someone who we thought was kidnapped and imprisoned.
It was a ghost boy.
It's always a ghost boy with us.
Or a witch.
Don't forget the witches.
Alright, so I guess, sorry, dead end.
I just wasted everyone's time.
Shall we go into the dark room of despair?
Let's go into that creepy ass dark room, I guess.
Sweet.
You step back out into the hallway and try and look closer into this room and you
feel like you're being watched back from this room.
Could anyone give us a little light?
I'm holding a flaming sword.
That's the best I can do.
Don't you, don't you maybe like a ball flame or something fancy like that?
I don't know if I can cast.
Oh, you have your wolf right now.
I don't think you can until a higher level.
I don't have anything helpful here.
I'm also the only one that can't see in the dark.
Although Donnie can see in the dark.
I might be able to cast.
I don't know.
I have good dark vision.
Yeah, he said even with our dark vision, it doesn't mean anything.
Yeah, you can't really see very far in there.
Your flaming sword doesn't appear to emit much light into this room.
Well, friends, do we really want to enter this dark chamber we can't see into
or go back down the hallway and try a different place?
I'm game for whatever.
Well, the only other place was the garbage room, no?
Well, plus all the other hallways we've like come down that had other things in them.
Like other chambers off them and stuff.
It would be backtracking, that's what I'm saying.
Sorry, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Let's backtrack.
Or should we just run in blind?
It's always worked well for us in the past.
No, let's backtrack.
Somebody else make a decision.
Panicking.
Flint, what do you think?
Yeah, I don't know.
I mean, I don't really like the dark room
and the garbage room doesn't seem like a great idea.
So yeah, back to that other hallway.
Yep, okay.
Okay, great.
What order are you going in?
Me middle, middle.
I'll go first.
I just like to ask because it's a narrow hallway.
So it's good to know who's in front and who's behind.
I guess I'm at the back.
Flint and Thea, you begin walking down the hall.
Laura, make a wisdom saving throw.
Oh no, not your mind.
13.
You turn to follow your friends,
and then you hear a noise coming from the dark room.
And you see green flames lighting along the walls.
Are they on braziers?
I'm not telling you.
Crossover.
You don't see them.
You see green flames lighting along the walls
down the length of this chamber.
And they are illuminating serpent statues.
And at the end of this chamber,
you see two beyond tea standing
and one sitting at a throne.
At the foot of this throne,
there is a dwarf in purple robes
who appears to be bound and chained
and looks like he's been beaten up quite a lot.
But you hear in your mind,
as soon as this room lights up,
you hear the voice of a female,
and she says,
One of your friends is a traitor.
It would be best of you to take them out.
And you failed your save,
so you believe that Flint or Thea are a traitor.
Okay.
God damn it.
Why do you always be fucking with New Lara's mind?
I know.
Because she went last, okay?
She can't handle it.
I knew as soon as we turned around,
the person at the back was going to regret it.
It should have been me.
I have advantage on wisdom saving throws and stuff.
I stop and turn around when I notice she's not walking with us.
I'm like, New Lara, come on.
And I brandish my sword and say,
Which one of you is betraying me?
I yell, not again!
And I guess then I approach my friend Thea,
who is next closest to me.
You're in the middle, dude.
I'm going to say roll for initiative.
All right.
Maybe we attack you first, bitch.
Well, okay, hold on.
No, New Lara will get the first strike
because you don't know that she's attacking you.
But we'll roll for initiative after that.
Well, did she not like when she called out
and then approached with her weapon drawn?
That was not a clue.
Yeah, no, that's fair.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's fair.
It's not like she has like a surprise attack anymore.
She's like, guys.
That's right.
Roll for initiative.
Hey, just because she's going to be attacking us
doesn't mean she has to be stealthy or good at it
because deep down, she doesn't want to do that.
Yeah, dudes, I don't want to be good at it.
Why do you think I just did that?
New Lara, what did you get?
Oh, a five.
Really?
I also got a five.
I rolled a two.
Plus what?
Plus nothing.
The wolf gets nothing.
So New Lara goes first then.
So Flint, you're up first.
Oh, dear.
Okay.
Sorry, I have a question.
Sure.
As I am turning to look back at New Lara,
her back is to the chamber.
Do I see the lit break?
That's a turn, so you don't see into the chamber.
So there's a door directly at the end of the hallway,
but there's a turn and a bit of a hallway
and then the chamber off to the right.
So you don't see directly into the chamber
from where you are.
Okay.
Sorry, Flint, go ahead.
Sorry, I still don't know what I want to do.
Probably want to hit her.
Well, I mean, no, but yeah.
Yes and no.
Yeah, I mean, character knowledge,
you don't, you don't,
she's just asked you a question at this point
and is seemingly approaching you to talk about it, maybe.
With her sword drawn?
I don't know.
She mentions one of us betraying her,
draws her sword and comes towards us
and I'm supposed to be like, hey, what's up?
Do what you got to do, bud.
Yeah, can I, ah, man, I don't know.
I don't want to attack her,
but that seems like what I should probably be doing.
But I have a feeling that like Flint
would also be conflicted about this
because he's friends with her
and they go back a long way
and this is like he doesn't want to attack his friend.
Yeah, I mean, you don't have to necessarily attack.
There are other things you can try and do.
Like think about a combat,
like think about combat in a movie.
They're not always trying to like murder each other.
They're sometimes just trying to stop what's happening, right?
True, but I mean, all of my skills are attack-based.
I remember when we attack,
we can just say we're not attacking to kill.
We're just attacking to incapacitate.
Yeah.
Yeah, all right.
Yeah, you know, instead of like an attack on her,
I'm going to try and like tackle her and hold her down
to like see what's going on here.
Sure.
So we'll probably want to make it a strength contest.
Okay.
I know you've got awesome strength as well, Karlo,
but we got to do this.
Yeah, it's okay.
So just a roll plus my strength bonus.
Yeah, you bet.
And then high as three.
Okay, 19.
Well, mine's terrible.
Eight.
Sweet.
Yeah, you rush like, yeah,
you just rush at new Lara and knock her to the ground,
but she still has kind of this anger in her eye
directed directly at you, Flint.
But her sword is knocked to the ground as well,
so she doesn't hold that anymore.
And then the wolf comes over and gives her puppy kisses
and then she forgets all about it.
I was really thinking about that.
Like, I come over and lick her face profusely.
You can't be mad about this.
Flint, are you, you're good?
Yeah.
You got more actions.
Do I like talk to her or something?
You can talk to her.
Yeah.
You guys could have a conversation.
What are you talking about?
Nobody's trying to betray you.
The yonti told me one of you is a traitor.
Well, there's your problem right there.
Why are you listening to them?
We've been with you a long time.
We're your friends.
I believe them.
Okay.
But why do you believe them?
You don't even know them.
New Lara, it's your turn.
Okay.
Am I prone?
Yeah.
You are not prone with Flint holding you down.
So you would have to make a strength contest to try and knock him off and then you could
stand up.
Okay.
Or grab for your weapon or something.
Well, I'll try and get up first because swordplay while prone is very difficult,
especially with a dwarf on you.
So 12.
Yeah, I got 10.
Funny.
I just had my worst strength roll last strength contest and that it was probably yours.
Okay.
So I guess I get up, like I push him off me and get up.
But is that my whole turn now?
Like getting up from prone means that's like my whole thing, isn't it?
It's half your movement.
Okay.
So I will grab my sword.
I guess attack my friend Flint.
And that's a 29.
Oh my God.
So good thing he's a big strong dwarf.
Oh God.
16 damage.
You okie dokie?
That's nothing to Flint.
He's very robust.
Do I get my second attack or not?
Because I was prone and I was using all my time to stand up.
Yeah, we'll say your strength contest was your first action.
So, oh, hey, once again, like last time I was mind-crazed.
Yeah.
Donnie is going to try and give me a little chomp to wake me up.
Go Donnie.
That is a 21.
So that does.
Now I'm just now I'm rolling damage against myself.
So that's a thing that's happening.
It's like four damage.
So I guess I don't on my turn get a chance to try to wake up from this business.
No, no, not this one.
Great.
How about because Donnie and I are telepathically linked,
he would have been able to see what I saw when I looked in the chamber.
So he can now share that information with my friends so that they know there's three Yanti and probably Vram in that chamber.
Yeah, because we're going to have to kill them to make you back to yourself.
Yeah. So Donnie, in your minds, Flint and Thea is like,
Oh, there's some snake guys in there and she's gone all whoopee again.
Maybe you guys want to go in there.
I don't know about her.
I'll try and hold her off and do something crazy like wave my hands in the air.
Like you just don't care?
Yeah, that's going to be a good song someday.
Are you are you poisoned right now?
Just brain poisoned probably.
No, I meant by Donnie's bite. Are you like paralyzed?
Oh, well, he doesn't have to do that.
He's got a bite or a sting.
Oh, I gotcha.
He's a little creature that's like what the fuck and he's trying to wake me up, but he wasn't actually trying to hurt me.
You see, you know, you hear what Donnie tells you and then you see the image of the lit chamber and the Yanti waiting at the end.
And it's your turn.
Okay, I, I see this and I get it immediately because we had just gone through this in the chamber with the basin, the puddle.
Yep.
Stupid puddle.
So I how far is it?
Can I in my turn run into that chamber?
I can't believe we got very far.
What's your speed as a wolf?
As a wolf?
All of the speed.
50 feet.
Oh, Jesus.
See, I told you.
You would make it into the chamber and about two thirds of the way to the Yanti if you were to dash.
I will dash.
You run down the hall leaping past your friends, round the corner and run into what you now see as this lit room.
Along the walls you see the six serpents lit by green flame.
Make a perception roll.
21.
You look side to side at this as you're running into this room and you see eyes of Yanti behind each of the statues.
And you make it two thirds of the way to the throne where the Yanti priestess will call her is sitting.
And the other are standing by and you see Veram as well.
Sorry.
How many feet between me and the Yanti and Veram and blah, blah, blah?
You're about 30 feet from them.
Damn.
Okay.
Can I turn back into myself and have my action?
Your action was your dash.
That is an action.
Oh, I didn't know that.
That you double your speed.
Oh, okay.
So I'm just in there now.
Okay.
Yup.
Fuck.
Okay.
Well, you know, I'm upset and I make poor decisions.
That's fair.
We'll see.
But Amy is going to use a healing surge before the end of her turn, right?
Absolutely, I am.
Uh-huh.
How do I do that?
Are you still a wolf or are you still?
I'm still a wolf.
So you have to do a spell slot.
Shit.
Guys, I'm using all my spells.
Oh, maybe that's a bad idea.
No, I still have decent, I've got 67 hit points.
So it's more than Thea has ever had.
It's way more than I have.
So Flint, you're up.
I'm going to dash my way to, I guess, just outside of that room because I don't
think I can cover quite the distance that Wolfie could.
You can just run.
You don't necessarily have to dash to make it to the entrance to the room.
Do you have anything you can throw from the doorway to, I don't know, try to hit the priestess in the face?
I do have hand axes that I can throw.
Want to throw what?
Sure, I'd love to.
Don't hit me.
Are you directly in my way?
Yeah, but I'm a wolf, so I'm short.
Oh, nice and low.
I'm not going to.
Yeah, no problem.
It's a large chamber that you're entering into.
OK, so how far away are they?
About 75 feet from the doorway.
OK.
Bonus, 17.
Which one are you aiming for?
The one that's on the throne, I would assume.
Is that not the priestess?
Always aim for the one on the throne.
Yeah.
Like, if you come for the throne, you better not miss.
That's all I'm saying.
That is true for battle in these circumstances and also bathrooms.
So the...
Yeah, you strike the priestess, who is all serpent form.
She has two arms, but they are covered in scales.
She has a snake head and a long serpent body.
And yes, you strike her with one of your axes.
Four damage.
I expect so much more from you every time.
It's a throwing axe.
I know.
Like, I'm not surprised because of the weapon.
It's just you.
So it glances...
Oh, wait.
Go for it.
Wondering if I should change what I was thinking of doing
instead of just the throwing axe.
It's all right. It's too late for that.
Throwing axe is fine.
Yeah, you've released.
Yeah, so it kind of hits her in the shoulder
and you see a bit of blood come off of that wound.
Does she say, nobody makes me bleed my own blood?
A little more serpentine.
Nobody makes me bleed my own blood.
Since I was running down the hallway,
is that like all of my actions or do I still have my second attack?
You still have your second attack.
All right.
And I do believe I still have one of those ice grenades.
Yep.
I had two and I only ever used the one.
So let me paint the picture for you, though.
Okay.
Priestess is sitting on the throne.
Oh, crap.
Veram's right there.
Veram is directly in front of her and he looks pretty beat up.
He is like clinging on to life right now.
And there are two other Yon-T standing kind of just behind her.
Okay, let me grab my notes and see what I wrote down about that stupid ice grenade.
One sec.
I got it right here.
20-foot blast radius.
Each creature must take a DC 15 deck saving throw,
taking 5d6 piercing, 2d4 cold, half on a successful save.
You have a range of 60 feet, so you can't even throw it that far.
You would hit the wolf.
Awesome.
I'm going to do that immediately because it will give the wolf superpowers.
Oh, my God.
It probably would.
I can't take cold damage.
I'm a winter wolf.
Yeah, okay.
I guess I'll just whip another axe in at the priestess.
Sure.
15.
15 will hit.
Oh, okay.
I was not expecting that.
4 damage.
Okay.
New Lara, you're up.
I guess I come into the chamber and...
You are directly behind Flint as you walk around this corner.
But she had to like move around Donnie,
so that obviously would have sapped something.
And he was waving his hands.
Hey, guys, she's coming.
She's coming.
He like bitten her pant leg and was like trying to slow her down.
He wrapped around her leg.
She's just calling him down the...
So it's not a surprise then just because...
Because Donnie's yelling.
Donnie's yelling.
She's coming.
She's coming, guys.
Well, and it's not like it would have been a surprise anyway.
Flint is a battle-hardened warrior.
Clearly the other person he was fighting he doesn't just like forget about.
But I guess I am going to try and attack him again.
I'm pretty sure I failed though, so that's 15.
Not enough.
Okay.
Second attack is a 19.
That's enough.
I'm sorry.
16 damage.
At least you're consistent.
Okay.
Donnie's not going to try to attack me because last time all he did was hurt me.
He's a little tired out.
Yeah.
I think he is probably just, yeah, still trying to try that arm waving,
trying to send me like telepathic signals about not killing my friends.
You know, the usual.
Shows you images of all of you kind of cozied up by the fire along the trail.
Exactly.
Remember the good times.
That time Flint baked cheesecake for everyone.
New Laura, at the end of your turn, you hear the same voice in your head say stop.
And you put your arms down and your sword drops to your side.
And you feel like you can't move.
Now it's the auntie priestess's turn.
And she slithers forward.
And she says,
Why are you in our temple directing it towards Flint?
Because she doesn't know that the wolf can talk.
And I will use that to my advantage somehow.
We came to stop you.
You came to stop me.
It has nothing.
Yeah, that's what I said.
It has nothing to do.
No, that's what I said.
With this dwarf.
I just keep cutting her off.
Make a wisdom saving throw.
Oh no, no.
It's all right.
I feel good about it.
Oh, 14.
I think that's what I rolled, dude.
Yeah.
You hear her in your mind and she says,
You only wish you could stop me.
Now I must ask you to hurt your friend.
That's what I said.
Yes.
It's your fault.
You're in.
I don't know.
You don't.
find us at Patreon.com slash DumbDragonCast. All of our socials are listed at DumbDragons.com or you
can find the links to share with your friends and family who may be into us in the description below,
along with every other link mentioned today. As always, if you don't mind leaving a review
on iTunes or Stitcher or anywhere else they allow reviews, I think Facebook allows reviews
now and I've got that figured out, that would mean the world to us. It's something that
really really helps the growth of smaller podcasts like ours. The next episode we're
gearing up for is coming out December 20th and I don't want to reveal too much because that'll
ruin the end of the episode so let's not do that. Let's just say we're really excited
for these next couple episodes. We put a lot into them and we hope that you enjoy them as
well. Let's see if Thea, Flint and New Laura are able to get out of this slippery situation.
We'll chat in a couple weeks. Talk to you later.
But it's Thea's turn. Where is she?
She's like 20 feet in front of you.
Yeah she is. Okay, okay, so here's what I'm gonna do. I'm gonna run at her. I'm gonna
jump over top of her. I'm gonna land behind her. I'm gonna whip around. I'm gonna cold
blaspheme. She's about 15 feet tall and you're about 20 feet behind her. How's the guy hiking
you straight jump? I don't know. I don't think that's a trait. You're also entering her zone
so she can like try and hit you as you go by. Whatever you want to do though. Can I just
walk around her then? Okay, I walk. It's less cool but it gets a jump down again. Yeah sure.
I walk around her. No, it's fine. It's not like we're trying to entertain people with this
or whatever. So I walk around her lazily because she doesn't know that I'm a creature
of intelligence. Maybe I'm gonna go pee on something she didn't know. So I walk behind
her and I turn and I do this so that I don't hit Varam as I cold breath the bitch.
She's obviously watching you do this so she makes her dexterity saving throw
which is an eight. Well she's gonna she's gonna get the full brunt of my cold. Sounds more
like she didn't make it. Welcome to the cold zone. I say that out loud just to shock her like
hey I can speak you dumb bitch. Not like ice to meet you. Oh no that would have been so much better.
What killed the dinosaurs? 21 cold damage. It was the ice age guys the ice age. Yeah yeah yeah.
I was with you because I was like right there for those those amazing bad Batman movie puns.
So the other two yonti it's their turn and they rush youth yeah and they are two
uh human human type yonti with snake heads brandishing scimitars. So first one comes to
attack you wolf. With his scimitar making two attacks. I lift my leg and I pee on him.
So that's a 22 and a 22. Yeah that hits. We're gonna die here guys. Hey where's the
confidence? I'm just frozen in game so I don't really have much. So that's nine slashing damage
from the first guy. That's a 17 and a 15. Um I think both of those hit me yep. That's 12
slashing damage and then as they strike you 10 more yonti step from behind the statues.
I yell it's on and the priestess says we don't want any more to die. I say give us varam
and she slithers quickly to varam and pulls out a dagger that looks like a snake penis dragon
tooth. So close. So close. That looks like a dragon tooth. Which incidentally enough
looks like a snake penis. And holds it to his neck. He has promised us wealth for releasing
him. If you look for him you give us wealth. Well I think he's lying because nobody wants
him. If he lies he dies. Oh good rhyme. He appreciates the rhyming. And she says
attack and flint it's your turn. No I'm the only one on my team.
How far away? They're still like way away from me. You got a good distance but you've been
given a direct order to attack. So you are 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 60, 70. So you're 70 feet so
yeah. Well I walk my 30 feet closer. He's kind of saunter he's like do do do do.
New Lara it's your turn then. Oh I'm am I unfrozen? Yeah you've also been given the
order to attack. Okay I guess I just trundle along 30 feet behind flint.
It's a really slow death I'm looking at here. As you are both walking towards Thea all the
other yonti begin to crowd around as well and she says there is a way out. You must never
come back here. Can we take Varam? She looks down to him and she says Varam is of no use
to us anymore but I do not wish any more of the yonti to die. I can appreciate that.
You know family I get it. What if we- Are we in a Fast and Furious movie?
Yes. Family. So all right so you'll let my friend's brains go.
They're weak it's not their fault. We'll take Varam off your hands for you.
We will never return. Deal? The deal seems fine. It's very generous of you.
You turn around and all of the yonti and flint and New Lara are standing directly behind you
at this point and she says stop and flint and New Lara you get your minds back.
There is a seerage to pee. And she hands you the chains that are around
Varam's neck and says he is yours. I put them in my mouth.
Dog walking its master. Yep.
He is quite incapacitated himself. He's kind of mumbling nonsense it seems right now.
Guys he's going to be super useful.
He's already tied up so it'll be easy to throw him in a river.
Maybe we could give him a healing potion or something before we go so he can at least walk.
That's you flint. I think you're the only prepared one.
Like that I can't cast a spell. I toss him a healing potion.
Can he catch it? No it hits his chest and shatters on the ground.
Flashbacks. I know right?
Traumatic flashbacks. I told you he was incapacitated and
speaking gibberish. Are you sure that it was a healing potion and not a pass without a trace
potion? Don't go fuck yourselves. Jesus okay.
Do you toss it to him or do you like hand it to him and feed it to him?
Well if he's that much of an invalid I guess I baby bird it to him.
We all look on horrified. As flint.
It's a dwarf thing guys. Puts the potion into his mouth
and then just regurgitates it into Veram's open mouth.
Flint we'll say you get a hit point back from that too.
Hey look at that. Worth it.
And Veram regains six hit points from that.
And he kind of comes to a little bit. You can see he's a little more conscious in what's happening
but he doesn't you know say much. What do you guys do?
Come with me if you want to live.
And he screams because there's a wolf talking to him and he's surrounded by snake people.
What's the quickest way out of here your your highness?
Back the way you came.
Indeedy do. I turn and just start walking out.
We'll be off then. Good day to you.
The yonti part and you walk back out of this chamber and as you step through the opening to
this chamber the green lights flames behind you extinguish and the shadows of the yonti
disappear into the darkness and you walk back down the hallway and it as you are walking
it appears to be still undulating but as you walk down it it straightens out as you are
walking the spell seemingly disappearing behind it you walk across the bridge and back up
through to the door where Diderius's tomb is and the stone wall grinds open you walk back
through and down into the lunch room where the bearded devils are and they all jump up
as you turn through and they say what have you done to master?
Oh this guy?
For him yes you know you asked about him you found him what did you do to him?
No we.
Yeah we found him.
We found him we saved him.
You're welcome.
You lost your master you are terrible subjects and horrible things are going to come
to you.
Well danger at door hasn't opened yet so they can't be coming soon um okay and they
kind of step forward and try and grab at Varam to take him.
I growl but more ferocious.
I think that was more intimidating.
If I had hands I would have slapped away one of their hands
we're gonna go get him fixed up you guys have done enough.
Okay uh.
You sit and you watch the danger door sit sit.
They look to Varam.
So ironic.
And from behind I nod Varam's head forward we can get Bernie's style.
And they say okay master says we stay watch danger door you go on your way you bring
him back though.
Oh definitely.
Yeah I don't want to watch the danger door anymore.
Shut up.
And they go back to watch the danger door and you walk back up the stairs and through
the room with the throne and the the large Goliath type guy with the long beard and
toga and he turns to look at you and allows you back through.
So you still have the you continuing on there's the door to the library.
I know god we promised books.
Oh yeah.
We haven't found any books.
Should we just pop in and just let her know we haven't forgotten about her.
I like I feel really bad you know like she died doing her like job and now she still
can't do her job but I mean it's part of a bigger thing that we're working on
or do we just do we just ghost.
No pun intended.
Because she is one.
Thoughts feeling.
I'm torn I like I want to just go but I feel bad.
I also feel bad.
I'm wondering like will she appreciate it or will she be like you didn't fulfill
your promise and then all the doors will lock and roll for initiative.
Like this is this is what I think too but I feel bad.
You know what being nice member she was our friend kind of in theory.
Does Ram have any books in his pockets.
No good question.
We first come.
Search he doesn't appear to have any books in his pockets.
It's probably a literary guys.
Because it's probably like a source of shame for him and we've just exposed that shame.
I think we should just pop in quickly.
I think we should do the honest thing.
I think that that's what our characters would do
because we try to do the right thing.
Yes I agree.
Sure yeah.
So you begin walking through the throne chamber.
Everybody make a perception check.
17.
18.
Wouldn't have minded that I'm a wisdom throw from before.
8.
I'm too busy just holding on to Ram to perceive.
You begin walking through but the door is open the first door is open to where
the skeletons exploded and you initially took a lot of damage.
And you see in the pile of skeletons that seems less large now.
Some of them have seemingly cleared away.
You see a single book sticking up out of the wreckage.
I don't see this but I'm sure someone else.
No no.
New Laura and Flint both look and see this.
Okay go grab it.
And we started humming the reading rainbow theme.
And then you walk into the library and Ilda forms in front of you and says you have brought
you have brought what was that?
No don't worry about him it's cool it's cool.
You came you came back to fifth how was her voice she was an old lady.
Yeah oh yeah no ALex mentioned she's like she was she nearly
gone to a car accident with your old lady voice on the way to work apparently.
Hold on I need her voice.
Uh amazing.
What did you do here something something dark side okay you brought you brought book back
who is he he's it seems bad oh god you you brought me a book back.
She looks to you.
We did and I hand her the book.
She grabs it from you.
It drops through her hands and you have an awkward silent moment as you both realize
how stupid that was she initially does that then then it's like yeah I can hold things
I just do that to make fun of people.
Always joshing around this one and then she picks it up and kind of skims through it and
says this was master's book and she puts it back on the shelf and she says thank thank you
and as she looks to you she begins to
dissipate and there's a bright light and she is seemingly gone from the room.
Oh you guys guys we did something good we we had a problem we solved it.
I'm not crying dogs just a dog eyes just tear it's a thing.
Um you carry on back up through the narrow hallway where the the skeleton boulder
rolled down behind you and you see kind of along the the hallway and feel creeping past you
the bones and the fragments from the boulder moving along the side of the hallway back
up towards the mosaic sun and climbing back into um and you step into the room where you
fought the tiled chimera and you see the tiles moving back into place in this room as you walk
through it you step into the room with the hooded figures where flint was initially caught
and drawn into whatever trance he was in and their heads turn to meet you and you hear the
sound of grinding stone as they follow you out and you step out into the daylight and you look
and you see your horses tied up where you left them and you look to the sky and you see
Grancis yell down from his airship and said oh boy they kicked me out of the city and it's
only been a few days i didn't even last that long you guys done yet
music in today's episode was by Kavin mcleod of incompetent.filmmusic.io
1d8 plus my spellcasting modifier are you shitting me can i re-roll that
i didn't see it i didn't see it
Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production