Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Suddenly, the room was filled with an unexpected ice storm. Seems weird.
As you squint through the haze, you see four figures standing on a tucked-away balcony.
Surprised to see you made it this far. I shall deliver you and the traitorous Iskander to him myself.
Remember that he has a fire breath weapon?
So Donnie lets forth his flame breath and, uh, chars the first one.
He's up in flames, running around.
I see him, like, frantically trying to pat himself out while he's on fire,
and I aim for just what I think should be his head region.
His name was Harold.
Oh, well.
He had a family.
And then you see him vanish and then reappear up on top of the balcony,
and a fireball begins to form in his hands that he releases down towards Donnie Noir and Thea.
But that fireball's like one of those super slow fireballs,
so it takes like three turns to get there.
And then you release your dwarven thrower and it connects square in his sternum,
and he, like, grabs onto it, but the dwarven thrower pulls him back with it.
Oh, that's a mistake, yeah.
Into the room, he bounces off the telescope and falls to the ground.
Oh, like that guy in Titanic.
Lara and Thaddeus, you feel drawn to a dagger.
If you give me to her, we will never be able to be friends again.
Thaddeus, I really, I just, I've never asked you for anything before.
I just want the dagger.
Can't you just give it to me?
I, no, no, it's my dagger.
Thea begins to run towards you, but she's not fast enough.
In the moment that he hands the weapon to you and you drive it into his chest,
and it goes through his armor into his heart.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We're a D&D fifth edition Actual Play podcast,
and I'm your dungeon master Russ More, and with me today is Amy More.
I love sparkles.
I'm Amy More, and I play Thea Amastasia.
Also with us today, Carla Johnson.
I've decided to take a heel turn.
Apparently, I play Lara Moonbrook.
And with us also, Tom Laird.
What?
I am indifferent towards sparkles.
They're fine.
I could take them or leave them.
Oh, and I play Flynn Firebeard.
How's everybody doing?
Whatever.
Yep.
I'll concur with that.
Whatever.
Yep.
One of our own was hurt last episode, and it's still pretty raw.
Apparently, last week left a poor taste in people's mouths.
I don't get it.
Russ, we are stressed out to the max.
There's a missing fucking owl, and now this shit is going on.
I mean, come on.
These are bad people.
Hashtag fine guac.
If you go to Twitter and put in hashtag fine guac,
there's a whole movement going on.
I love it.
People threatening to not listen to the podcast,
but they keep coming back and saying that we haven't found guac yet.
So it's a tough one.
I don't know how well it's like a three strike situation,
like they're going to give you some chances,
but you better fucking follow through on finding guac.
I mean, we'll take us where the story takes us.
Well, maybe when we do find guac,
she could be like, you're the one now, dog.
It wasn't going to be, but now it is.
No, it needs to be a wonderful reunion.
Oh, God, I hope there's a reunion.
Oh, God.
Sean Connery is.
Yeah, I get it.
It's good.
Where you can get more of us,
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
where people will be less angry at me.
Oh, I don't know.
For the most part, true.
I mean, I don't know.
And when you're a patron of ours,
you get an episode dedicated to you.
Like today's dedication is the one and only Daryl Johnson.
Yeah, Daryl.
Thanks, Daryl.
I know that guy.
That's all I'm going to say.
All right.
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
you can ask Daryl for yourself.
He doesn't want to be associated with me right now, probably,
because I don't want to be associated with me right now.
Yeah, yeah.
Another way you can support us is you can rate and review us on iTunes.
We appreciate that.
It helps all podcasts grow and get in front of more people.
It's a fantastic thing.
And if you call Russ a doink in your review,
we will read it in the podcast.
Yeah, we will doink it.
That'd be so great.
Yeah, if you call me a doink in the review,
we will read it in the podcast.
I laughed out loud for that.
When the episode title came up, you doink,
I like fully laughed out loud,
because of course Russ makes those up.
We don't know what they're going to be.
Oh, my God.
What a delight that was, Russ.
It was a delight.
I thought it was so funny.
By far the best thing I've ever said on the podcast.
I mean, it was up there if it wasn't.
It was a wife thing.
It resounded.
Everybody loved it.
Fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
Yeah.
We find New Lara standing with a dagger in the chest of Thaddeus
as he begins coughing and he grabs at New Lara
and he's got this look of why on his face.
What's everybody else doing?
Dying a little on the inside.
New Lara, you hear in your mind of mine a voice and it says,
yes, yes, you will do to return me to my master.
Let's have some fun, shall we?
And you pull the dagger out and quickly sheath it on your belt.
I say, New Lara, what the fuck?
Thaddeus, oh, my God, are you?
Oh, my God.
And I'm like, I guess, going to try and like,
take his armor off to like, get to the wound.
Make a medicine check.
Yeah, that's a skill I have.
It's not.
That's one.
Totally one.
Everybody has some.
Oh, I actually, I'm fucking baller with medicine, you guys.
Been holding, holding out on you this whole time.
25.
Oh, my God.
Yeah, all right.
She fucking performs open heart surgery, saves his life.
Fixes him right up.
You managed to quickly get his armor off.
And you're everybody's kind of watching you do this,
as they just saw you stab him.
And now you're taking his armor off and bandaging him up
and applying pressure to the wound.
Is he still alive?
He's just like, yeah, OK, then I am going to give him
my last rare healing potion that I was going to use on my own dying ass self.
But I'm going to give it to him.
New Lara, what the fuck?
He drinks the potion.
Lara, you see the wound begin to close,
so it's the potion is taking effect and it looks like it's working.
Thaddeus, what happened?
Oh, my God.
How did you even get hurt?
I thought that we beat these guys.
You stabbed me.
I stabbed you.
Are you delirious?
What are you talking about?
As, yeah, Flint's walking over there is like, yeah, dude, you stabbed him.
What are you guys talking about?
Why would I stab him?
It's a great question.
Any thoughts?
Fighting over that fucking knife.
You guys were fighting over that dagger and you took it away from him
and then you fucking stabbed him with it.
What dagger?
What are you even talking about?
The one that's in your belt.
Can I snatch it like from her scabbard daggers going scabbards?
Yes, you can try.
Yeah.
Yeah, I want to try that.
Make a dex.
I'm going to fucking roll.
I'm going to do a dex roll.
It's going to be the best thing ever.
Can I roll two d20s and just add them together to get my lesson 10 number?
Let's say you roll with advantage because she doesn't know what you're doing.
You're just quickly trying to do this without her knowledge.
Okay, well, I just legit roll the one.
Excellent.
Maybe roll your other one.
It's going to go up.
It was a 16 plus two, 18 plus one.
Sorry, 17.
So you are still wolf.
So you're trying to grab it from the handle and pull it out of her belt?
I think I'm trying to rip the leather belt buckle loop shit right off of her.
I don't think I could be very precision.
I don't think I'm lifting it out by the handle.
I think I'm grabbing hold of the whole scabbard and just ripping.
Sure.
So you bite into the scabbard and you see a red glow come from the gems
and it doesn't move and you take four damage.
Do I drop it?
Did I take it off?
Where you grabbed it, it doesn't come out or come off.
I kind of like yelp a bit as I'm assuming burns my mouth.
And I say that take that off.
Take that off, Nularaa.
That thing's evil.
Okay, well, I grab it and try and take it off.
It doesn't remove.
Nularaa, seriously, take it off.
But am I like, you can see me trying to move it and it just won't move?
But maybe you're really good at pantomiming a struggle.
So I'm pulling on it.
Guys, I can't move it.
Well, Nularaa is never getting naked again, you guys, apparently.
Well, I'll always have a belt on.
Weird.
Apparently.
Fine, we can have sex, but I'm leaving my belt on.
And my socks.
Okay, Thaddeus, are you all right?
Do you know anything about, I don't know, evil bewitched daggers?
Nope.
Do I know anything?
Can I roll a history check?
Oh, I know fucking nothing.
Maybe I might know something.
Yeah, everybody who wants to can make a history check.
Well, I rolled a three.
I think history's for twice.
That's a 26.
I rolled a 20.
Nularaa, you're trying to remove the dagger and you're kind of looking at it.
And what you can see is, because the blade won't remove from the scabbard,
you see an ebony crossguard which seamlessly flows into a worn leather wrapped handle.
There are two red garnet stones.
I did say gems last time, but they're red garnet stones.
I don't think you know about this specific dagger, even with a 26.
Guys, help me, like, try to get this thing off of me.
I don't know if it burned Thea's mouth when she tried to bite it.
You're not even going to try?
Cut my belt off me.
Jesus, you guys.
This thing just made me stab Thaddeus, is what you're telling me,
and you're not going to try and get it away from me?
Get it away from me.
I don't have hands, it's all you, Flint.
As Flint is approaching you to try and cut off the belt,
Nularaa, you hear in your head,
if he removes me and we are separated,
something will happen to one of your friends.
And then the voice goes away.
Uh, so I guess I just start to back away from him.
Nularaa, what are you doing?
Hold still.
How's he supposed to get that off you if you keep moving?
Guys, I can hear, this seems crazy, but I can hear the dagger in my head,
and it's saying something bad is going to happen to one of you
if it's separated from me.
I mean, it already used you to stab Thaddeus.
What worse could happen to us?
That seems like a risky fucking thing to ask.
What worse could happen?
We've just been in a death maze for like nine and a half months.
Fair point, fair point.
It's noted.
Nularaa, you hear the voice come back and it says,
yes, yes, he was weak, but he looks fine now.
Guys, this dagger is evil.
It's so evil, it's happy that I stabbed Thaddeus.
Of course it made me stab him.
I didn't think it would regret it now, but.
It really takes it back down.
It's like, oh, you know what?
It should have done that.
It was a step too far.
But Nularaa, if we don't try to separate you from it,
you might just end up stabbing one of us again.
But if we do try to separate you from it, something bad's going to happen.
I guess.
This is like the epitome of rock in a hard place, isn't it?
What does it want?
I don't know.
Dagger, what do you want?
I roll my wolf eyes at her.
I roll my wolfy eyes at her like, you give me this attitude now.
What I want will become clear soon.
We will just have some fun in the meantime.
Is it talking to you?
Yes, it said.
What it wants will become clear soon, but in the meantime, we'll have some fun.
What?
That sounds fucking ominous.
So I think.
Not that we don't trust you, Nularaa.
You shouldn't trust me.
I literally just stabbed Thaddeus.
Fucking help me.
Guys, help me.
Make me not do anything bad again.
I don't want this to happen again.
Can we tie our hands together?
You hear in your head, Nularaa.
If you don't try to get rid of me, I won't make you hurt your friends again.
Don't worry.
It says if I don't try and get rid of it, it won't make me hurt you again.
But I still think you need to stop me.
Like you can't leave it as an option.
That is a like legit abusive relationship you have with that knife.
I don't know.
I think maybe you should walk first and we will constantly have our eyes on you.
I don't know what else we can do.
We need to be all together on this to get ourselves out of this.
I don't know if we can afford to tie you up and drag you behind us.
Thaddeus casts Zone of Truth.
OK.
And asks that dagger some fucking questions.
Thea just blurs out.
I like to take shits in people's shoes when I'm a wolf.
Hold on.
There's a saving throw with Zone of Truth.
So whatever.
She spills all her deepest darkest secrets.
So it's just against his Spell Save DC there.
And Flame Bekins probably has to tell the truth too.
I know everything.
I don't know what's happening.
Spell Save DC 16.
You don't really know.
You got to ask like some leading questions to figure out who saved and who failed and whatever.
Yeah right.
Because we're not like I'm feeling in a truthful mood.
I could still be lying.
It's like a riddle.
Fuck.
I don't know what to ask.
What should I ask?
What do I ask?
Don't just go silent on me guys.
I don't know, Tom.
It's your choice here, man.
What do you want to know?
Well, yeah, as I say, I assume this thing was like its own
being, not just an inanimate object that can talk.
Well, I mean, you don't know.
You don't know.
I don't know.
I think I know from you.
Okay, you know, but who the sweet fattiest Thea Nularaaa don't know.
Flame McKinns doesn't know anything.
Don't ask her.
I won't tell you.
Even if I knew.
I miss her though.
There she is.
I haven't talked in a while.
Yeah, we were all happy about that.
There were some stabby, stabby things happening and I got real freaked out.
Reminds me of a time when I was a pirate.
And she goes off on a diatribe a bow when she was a pirate.
Sounds right.
That does sound like her.
She's really small and I'm really big and I just kind of go over and like
lay down like when a big dog kind of like lays on you
and just kind of like crush her to the ground and just lay there.
What are you doing?
I muffle her with my fur.
Still allowing her to breathe, of course, just no more talking.
Okay, what's Thaddeus and Flint and Nularaaa and Donnie doing?
I mean, I guess just because you cast the spell
doesn't mean you have to now follow up with questions.
You don't.
He just goes zone of truth and then goes.
But he probably doesn't say zone of truth in game, right?
He just cast a spell.
We don't even know.
There's a verbal component to it.
So he would have said something.
Oh, what did you say?
That's what I want to know.
Yeah, me too.
Zonus of truth is the classic, the classic utterance.
We always make the same jokes and I fucking love it.
Did you say lamb?
I love that.
Ah, lamb.
We're awesome.
Fuck, I don't know what to ask.
Tom's having some serious regret here.
Okay, well, it's okay.
Okay, guys, we have to get out of this fucking tower.
We have to get Iskander
and I'm terrified now that I'm going to hurt someone else.
Trust me, we won't hurt anybody.
We won't let that happen.
Okay, I mean, I just, I can't live with myself now.
Just if something happens, just stop me.
However you have to.
Okay, so where do we go?
And this is awkward,
but I really need to take a healing potion
because I'm going to fucking die.
I have like one sixth hit points.
You don't look so good.
I mean, aside from the fact that you're all
weird about your stagger thing here.
And she tosses you a rare healing potion,
which was the 8d4 plus eight.
Well, how is everyone else?
I definitely need to take my uncommon.
What's an uncommon I think?
4d4 plus four is uncommon.
Everybody's drinking their potions.
I'm still not great, guys, but it's okay.
All right, do we have to go to this elevator?
Like, let's like, we have this.
Do we have the time sand thingy?
The white shimmering hourglass?
I guess you're a wolf still.
No, I just keep forgetting the word for hourglass.
I mean, yes, I'm a wolf.
I'm stupid.
What does it do?
Well, is there one of those?
Like, let's go to the teleport thing.
That has the hourglass on it.
Yeah, and press it and see what it does
now that we have it in our possession.
Good idea.
Because last time we just, like,
felt a wave of power, but it didn't do anything.
I get up off of flamekins.
And I say, you can ride on my back if you want to.
That was pretty, that was mean of me.
Yeah, yeah, that's sweet.
My legs are getting tired.
Do you need healing potion?
I hand her a yellow potion.
I already drank one.
I drank it.
Yellow potion, you dink.
No, I drank it.
I'm okay.
I'm good.
You sure?
Yeah.
Okay, well, I got this.
We need it, man.
You just let me down, your buddy.
Thanks, though.
I mean, I had one and I drank it.
Maybe, maybe next time.
Oh, you're so funny.
What a time for a prank.
You're all murderous.
You all crowd around in the teleporter area
and you press the hourglass
and you feel the same wave of energy.
And then the bright light comes
where before it was like a, you know,
it was like it didn't let you go through.
But now that you are holding the hourglass,
the bright light comes
and you are teleported into dark room.
As you enter this room,
lamps on the walls activate
and provide bright light within the room
and you see the bodies of three dead cultists
on the floor here.
Hey there, I'm your Dungeon Master Russ More.
Thanks for joining us for episode 56 of Dumbgeons and Dragons.
What was that?
If you enjoy what we're doing with this show
and you can support us through a monthly monetary pledge,
we invite you to join us on Patreon,
where for $1 per month,
you're definitely absolutely 100% helping
make this show better with every episode.
But also you get access to a whole backlog
of monthly bonus episodes,
plus new ones on the 15th of every month,
where we're playing a thriller, horror,
sci-fi genre in the fake core system.
And if you can swing it,
just $2 a month gets you access
to our monthly gook hangs as well.
And those are an absolute blast.
We answer as many spoiler-free questions
as we can about the future and past
of the story and the show and us
and we just chat and have a great time.
Check out all the details at
Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast.
But another way you can support the show,
because we know that sometimes it's just not possible
to give a pledge that involves money.
I get it.
What you can do is share a link to your favourite episode
or just to the show in general on social media.
Talk about us to your friends and family
or write a review for us on Apple Podcasts,
Stitcher or wherever else you can write reviews.
There's some links down in the description there.
Every little bit helps get us out
in front of more people
who will hopefully love the show as much as you do.
All of our social media links and more about us
and the show can be found at dumbdragons.com.
So go check out the website
and join, follow or like where you can today.
And thanks to Sirenscape for some of the amazing atmosphere.
Make sure you check them out at sirenscape.com
to bring your games to life.
Links for everything mentioned today
can be found in the description.
The next episode will be out Wednesday, October 10th.
So let's get back to it.
Have a great week.
We'll talk soon.
Lamps on the walls activate
and provide bright light within the room.
And you see the bodies of three dead cultists
on the floor here.
One of them has clearly been stabbed
but you see a trail of blood
running from this room down a hallway.
I felt on my nose.
Actually, Nularaaa, can you go first?
Yeah.
It's just easier to keep an eye on you.
You get it.
I do.
I go first.
I assume, hopefully, towards my boy Iskander.
I mean, he's not my boy we've never met, but you know.
Yeah.
I mean, you know, for all intents and purposes, he's our boy.
Okay.
So Nularaaa, as you head down this hallway.
And we are keeping very close tabs on her, correct?
And we like we're walking with her.
But we just want her to be in front
so that she can be seen at all times
and not stab anybody in the back or whatever.
The hallway itself is five feet wide
so it's single file down the hallway.
But Nularaaa, you are first one to the base
and it opens up into another large room.
And you see that as the lamps illuminate
as you light down the hallway and into this room
blood streaks the floor here,
including the smeared trail leading back up
to the chamber where you came
and a second trail of bloody boot prints
heading up the corridor to the north.
Standing amid the gore are three humanoid figures,
two that look like misshapen statues of clay and stone
and one appearing as a humanoid made of flame.
Oh, these are all statues.
I mean, probably not for long, right, guys?
Well, it's magical world we're in.
Who knows?
Uh, Kate, while I do the classic.
Where I hold up my hand with the fist so everyone stops.
Does that mean you're going to stab us?
No, it's when she starts moving her hand back and forth.
It's stab or hand job.
Oh, boy.
It's a dangerous game we play called stab or hand job.
Guys, there's blood everywhere in there
and three statues, I guess.
One is like a flame person
and then the other two are just like big misshapen blob creatures.
I mean, realistically,
they're probably going to turn into real people we're going to fight.
I just wanted to warn you before we went in there.
All right.
Thanks for the heads up.
So I'm going in.
We all OK with that?
There's nowhere else to go.
OK.
And I enter the room.
As you step foot into the room,
the earth elementals and the fire elemental begin to move.
Move and begin moving towards you
in a fashion that looks like they want to take a swing at you.
Roll for initiative.
Thaddeus is up first.
Do it, Thaddeus.
How far away from Newlar are these guys?
15 feet to the closest one, 25 feet to the fire one,
which is farthest away.
And how big is this room?
It is 40 feet by 40 feet.
So it's a big old room.
It's a big old square room.
OK.
Right where the first guys are there,
I'm going to cast Russ's favorite fucking spell,
Cloud of Daggers.
That's fun.
Haven't had that in a while.
I guess because there's been no song kitty in a while.
So this will be right on top of them sort of thing.
Sure.
On the start of their turn,
if they're in the range, which they will be
because it's the start of their turn,
they will take 4d4 slashing damage.
All right.
Then it is Flameykin's turn unless Thaddeus is doing anything else.
Believe he can only utter words of encouragement past that point.
Describe the room as you enter.
There's an immediate hallway that goes like off to the left
as you enter the room and there to your right.
Just to describe that there is a table
and there is a table in one corner
and two longer tables with papers and stuff on them
towards the back of the room as you enter.
Flameykin's slides in and under people
as she was probably nearer to the back there
and she was on me here.
She's just OK.
She's just riding you and she lets forth an acid splash.
No, I do not consent to this.
What?
Actually, you did offer so I did when we got in,
but I'm not going to ride into battle with her.
No, she's on top of you.
You said she's on you.
She's riding on top of you, throwing acid bubbles.
She's like, we got to do this together now, bud.
She singes my fur.
I'm going to be pissed.
Yep.
One target must make a dexterity saving throw,
which it does not make.
And then it's going to take 12 acid damage.
And then it's one of the Earthstone guy's turn.
So he takes how much damage from you?
Let's find out.
Soorty Mcdagger's.
Soorty Mcdagger's himself.
Feels good, doesn't it, Russ?
Feels good.
I like it.
When it comes, when a cloud of daggers comes to fruition.
Right.
All right.
So that is 10 damage.
It just rushes forward and slam attacks.
I'll say new Lara and Flint.
Get a slam attack each.
Those are slamma jamma.
That's a 12 and 11.
So I don't think it really matters who.
I touched your dice.
Oh, god damn it.
This is what you've been doing this whole time.
Get out of here.
Stop ruining my dice.
Keep ruining his dice.
Keep ruining his goddamn dice.
So one of these elementals makes a big swing
and you duck out of the way and it is your turn.
And sorry, just to be clear, we walked in
and immediately to our left is the only exit from the room.
Is an open hallway.
And is the elemental, did it slam in between me and that exit?
No, it's still over top of you, in front of you.
It swung over your head and you ducked out of the way.
Okay.
Well, I mean, it's right there.
So I'm gonna take a swing at it.
But also, guys, we've tried to fight these before
and it doesn't really go great.
So I say, let's just try and get through
and get down that hallway.
What do you think?
This is what I'm saying as I am about to stab
because I'm a good multitasker.
I mean, I'm ready to ride like the cavalry into battle,
but whatever you think.
That's a 25.
25 will hit.
Okay.
I reach up and I just grab her pant leg
and I just really slowly like pull her off my back.
16 damage.
Okay.
Then I'm going to try and get it again as a 22.
That is 14 damage.
All right.
So your two big slices, they cut in
and they don't look like they do quite as much damage
as you think they should.
Sounds right.
Okay.
Then Donnie's gonna try and recharge.
Fails.
What else can he do?
Why not bite a big pile of dirt, Donnie?
Why not?
I mean-
16.
Did just suggest a run, but-
Yeah, but they're like right there.
It's true.
16 does not hit.
Okay.
Donnie takes a bite and it glints off the stone of this elemental.
And then it is the fire elemental's turn.
So it rushes forward to Thea and Flamikins
and moves to, it just moves to touch you.
Ooh, touchy.
That's going to be an 18 for Thea and Flamikins.
And a 17 for Flamikins.
Yeah, that's gonna work.
That's gonna-
Definite touching happening.
Syngy, syngy touching.
It's gonna be hot, you guys.
So hot.
Cause it is.
You're going to take 11 fire damage and you are ignited.
What?
Well, she's covered in fur.
Like your fur is on fire.
I thought you meant like ignited with a fiery passion to murder.
Oh, that would have worked too.
Yeah, that's possible too.
Flamikins is going to take 12 damage and her clothes ignite as well.
And if I'm still on fire my other turn, I continue to take damage.
And then it is Flint's turn.
So it didn't seem like traditional weapons did a whole lot there.
So should we just disengage and run for it?
I think it sounds like a good idea.
I'm on fire, motherfucker.
I mean, she's on fire.
All right, yeah, let's do that.
You're disengaging running down the hall.
Yep.
Okay, Thea's turn.
Can I use my action to stop, drop, and roll?
I mean, you've got a goblin on your back.
Oh, do I?
She'd be down with it too though, probably, cause she's also on fire.
No, I pushed her off by her pant leg.
Until a creature takes an action to douse the fire,
the target takes 1d10 fire damage at the start of each of its turns.
You're going to take the damage anyway, regardless.
So you're going to take 1 fire damage.
Damn it.
But then if you are to douse it...
I roll around on the ground.
All right.
Oh God!
No, I had dragged her off of me by her pant leg.
This is funnier this way.
Okay, I'm going to take out what I did before.
Yeah, well, and I successfully, hopefully, dousing both of our flames.
I just roll all over her with no regard.
She's like holding on, like as this is happening.
Oh God!
You douse the flames.
And can I disengage?
Yeah.
And can I dash?
Yes.
I do those things.
Well, you can make it with a run.
Oh, I'm sure I can.
I'm a very fast wolf and I drag.
Yep.
Thaddeus is up.
Flame Echans is already out.
I assume Thaddeus is doing the same.
Nularaaa and Donnie are still in the room
and one of the earth elementals has a turn prior to your turn.
So it is going to try to slam attack.
One at Donnie, one at Nularaaa.
Can you not sing while I talk?
25 to Nularaaa, 24 to Donnie.
Okay, well that'll hit both of us.
Nularaaa, you are going to take 16 bludgeoning damage
or halfsies for your armor stuff.
And Donnie will take 15 bludgeoning damage.
And then it's your turn.
Then I'm going to try to get out of there.
You know, the old get out of there.
Classic move.
The old get out of there.
So you take that hit and then both of you disengage
and enter the hall.
So as you enter the hall,
there's immediately a staircase that goes directly down
and a door that goes off to the left.
Which way do you run as the first one through that direction?
Which way is the trail of blood going?
Quarter to the north.
So it goes down the stairs.
Okay, let's hustle down those stairs.
All of you head down the stairs and you descend
to a walkway that appears to stretch across infinite space.
The walls disappear.
Thousands of stars twinkle in an unfamiliar constellation
and meteors strike through the vastness above and below the path.
Just past the base of the stairs,
a door framed by nothingness rises from the path.
50 feet beyond that,
the path meets an intersection with another door straight ahead.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
You bite into the scabbard.
And find that her belt is really well made
and you just end up dragging her by her waist.
What kind of damage?
Not cold.
You took four not cold damage.
Not cold damage.
I kind of like,
just having a fight with a giant snake on our bed is epic.
That was horrible hand motions for us to be doing back there.
I can't see our video.
No, our video is completely black.
It'll be interesting.
Yeah, so I use my axe to cut off her belt.
It's the most proper cutting tool.
This is a precision move.
I'm going to stop right there.
Do I have to?
Can't we just put me at the bottom automatically?
No, because I feel good about it this time.
Do you?
I'm going to use your dice.
I had a really bad roll.
So people, I'm not going to be first.
I had 12.
Sorry, six plus one initiative.
Well, that's right.
Looky here.
Guys, I'm broken.
I'm bad luck.
How far away from new are these guys?
I don't know what that sound effect was, but I liked it.
Earth glides.
So it glides along the stone.
No, that doesn't.
Does it say like radical?
And it throws up like some hand symbols as it does it?
Hang ten.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.