previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
In the room you're in now, there is a statue in the center of the room of a god named Loth.
And in the portal, you see the face of an ebony-skinned, white-haired drow.
And he says, you adventurers have had quite the journey, haven't you?
You are the three who I need in order to get the power.
Oh, this fucking guy.
That was a game, right?
And what makes you think we're going to tell you?
Well, you're never going to get out of the dungeon without telling me.
I've heard that one before.
I need to know where to get the train.
You continue walking down this hallway and it takes you through a winding path.
You see a false stone wall.
It pulls out and towards the corner and it reveals an unlocked wooden door.
Good catch.
Too good to be true or too good to pass up.
What do you guys think?
Too good to pass up.
There is a mosaic of legendary monsters and a buzzing noise can be heard.
Flint, you are swiped at by a dragon-esque looking statue.
Bring it.
And as it punches through the wall, the wall crumbles and out pour four 10-foot wide,
hairy, huge spiders.
Four giant wasps about the size of halflings zip quickly past your head.
It's getting a bit crowded in here.
With your leaping jump, crumbles the final gargoyle in the room.
When you hear another buzz and you see a blue orb and out steps Tibby.
You guys ready to blow this pop stand or what?
And then as quick as it began, it ends.
You look around and you quickly realize that you are no longer in Faerun.
We open on a field to the east of Mirabar.
It's on a high hill to the west.
You see the town of Mirabar and to the east, the wide open plains of Faerun.
The static in the air quickly forms animals scatter from the area
and this blue orb appears and you are back in Faerun outside of Mirabar.
Not in the dungeon.
And you look to Mirabar and you see plumes of smoke coming up from the city.
You are a bit stunned having just stepped through the portal
and experiencing what you have just seen and done.
Thea now owns a book of the druids, which brings into question some thoughts she had
on what it means to be a druid and in control of her powers.
Flint, as you step through the portal, you hear the anguished cries of Bort,
a dragonborn hunter-ranger, screaming at you for having torn him from his land and world.
I did not ask for this.
Just a heads up.
But you have it now.
But I mean, if you're going to blame someone,
don't blame the guy that just had it thrust upon him.
Let's just take a minute and you can maybe discuss amongst yourselves
in character some of the things you've seen and done
and how you're feeling about now knowing that there are parallel worlds,
not just planes as you were used to with the guild,
but parallel worlds in other universes.
Thea sits down on the ground and pulls out a joint and just lights up and is like,
Oh, Jesus.
Yeah, guys, this is a lot to take in.
I mean, those guys seem great and all.
But what the hell is going on?
I thought we were dealing with dragons and that was crazy enough for someone
who's just a simple person.
And now I find out, oh, there's whole other dimensions.
There's whole other worlds.
There's whole other groups of people that we don't even know about.
And now one of them is stuck in Flint.
Yep.
And the animals, man, the animals.
Remember that elephant?
Yeah, I don't know.
If I was a religious person, I would be having a crisis of faith.
Since I'm not, I kind of just want to go like hide in the woods.
That's kind of my go-to to feel better.
But we got a lot of shit we have to do.
We have people counting on us.
What's going on over there in Miravar?
The whole town's on fire.
What happened since we left the dungeon?
How long have we even been gone?
Oh, God, that's a good question.
I wonder if time works the same.
Exactly.
I look at Flint's face and I throw him a joint.
And I say, buddy, you look worse than you did after you got out of the Fist of the Iron Dawn.
This is much needed, for sure.
Flint, do you want to make a constitution check?
Yeah, right.
That is a 16.
Bort rolled a 20.
Out of Flint's mouth, which you guys have experienced this before,
Bort begins to scream.
It's like it kind of fades in.
Why did you bring me back here?
Why did you bring me here?
Where am I?
The elix shuffles back on the ground away from Flint.
He said I wanted to come back.
I did not want to come here with you.
I look at you, Lara.
But if the choice was that or die, isn't this a better choice?
I don't know.
What if we can get you out of his body, into a new body somehow?
Do you have that sort of power in this world?
Maybe.
We can certainly search.
Flint, you want to make a con check?
That is a 18.
He rolled a six.
Bort is gone and Flint is back.
Flint, where did you go?
What did that feel like?
What's going on, buddy?
Tell me.
It does not feel good when that happens, I'll tell you that much.
So is Flint aware and can hear everything that's happening?
Or is it like he has a fugue state and blacks out
and finds himself in a completely different location?
Why am I covered in tattoos?
Basically, how I am going to treat it is there are two drivers at the wheel.
When Bort wins the con, he takes control and he can say and do whatever he wants
Flint's body to say and do.
They probably not right now, but probably very soon I'm going to have Flint and Bort
have a conversation about what they want.
But for the rest of the episode, we're going to say Flint is in control.
But Flint, you feel like there's someone always pulling at your mind
to try and get control of your body.
Sweet.
So I have to concentrate all the time?
Yeah.
That sounds uncomfortable.
This is going to go great, guys.
Maybe you don't want to take that joint now.
Maybe you don't want that.
Fuck it, Bort.
You just take over.
Bort, I'm tired.
I need some Flint time.
So you just go right ahead.
Should we go down to Mirabar or should we just go back to Luskin?
That's where we were going to take the box, right?
We need to go get your armor.
Oh, my God.
Yes.
Yeah, right.
I've forgotten all about my armor.
I just get a tingly feeling all up and down.
And possibly a new trucker hat for Donnie.
Guys, we have to go back because Primsbane probably has control
of the entire Mirabar army by now.
We can't just let them run rampant over the whole world.
Thea lays down in the grass.
It's like, can't we?
Thea's having a crisis of druidness.
As you lay down in the grass, you begin to feel a rumble.
In the ground.
Pardon me.
Not that kind of rumble.
You begin to feel a very even-paced cadence.
Guys, someone's marching.
And as you look to the east over the top of another large hill,
you see the remaining soldiers of the Axe of Mirabar marching towards Mirabar.
Oh!
Guys, they haven't made it there yet.
Primsbane probably isn't controlling them yet.
If we can cut them off, maybe we can work together to stop Primsbane,
and then we can try and figure out what to do to get Bort out of Flint
because this is an unmanageable situation.
Oh, it is not working for anybody.
Okay.
Thea, are you okay?
Sure, let's go.
Oh, yeah.
So that joint kicked in.
You're a bit more relaxed.
So Thea does a somersault.
Just like a little, like, woo, in the grass and gets up
and starts walking towards the army.
Everybody else just does laissez-faire about it,
or you guys have a different notice?
I'm ready.
I want to cut them off,
and if we can get an army on our side fighting this dumb bastard,
I'm happy to do it.
Let's get some help.
How far out are they?
They're a fair ways out, maybe just under a kilometer,
but you're about halfway between them and Mirabar.
Do you guys want to hop on?
I know you shouldn't smoke and fly, but...
But Guacamole would be the one flying.
Yeah.
Do you guys want to hop on and get there fast?
Let's do it.
Good. I don't want to run.
And?
What if Guacamole gets a contact high?
My joint is done.
I pulled that back pretty fast.
This will also give us a chance to observe from a distance
or easily retreatable if they're under Prim's Bane's control, hopefully.
Guacamole has really good sight vision, and we can...
Really good sight vision?
Yeah.
Yeah, sight vision.
Shut up, Russ.
I'm not high right now, actually.
Those words just came out of my mouth.
Guacamole has really good vision.
You bastard.
And we can talk to each other telepathically,
so I can ask Guacamole if they look like...
Because they looked weird, right?
They looked undead.
Yes.
Right?
So, okay, I summon Guacamole.
Gwak!
And my wonderful Jade Serpentine Owl.
Comes forth from the...
Is that what you say when Guacamole comes up?
Yeah, I do now.
Perfect.
Hi, Theodos.
Gwak!
So, yeah, we telepathically communicate.
So we hop on, because she's already wearing a saddle,
and we... and off we fly.
You fly up and you're up in the air.
You're able to see Mirabar better.
And it looks like there are buildings on fire.
You can see soldiers of the acts of Mirabar in the city,
and you can see people running from them.
So the soldiers in town are...
Oh, but we knew that.
The soldiers in town were all overtaken.
Yes, and as you fly more towards the army
that's coming towards the city,
they see you and they stop their position,
and you hear them readying their archers
as you fly down and near them.
And they yell up to you.
If you don't want to be shot from the sky,
you should probably come down now.
Do they say that in unison, or does like a dude say that,
or do they say it like a bunch of people say it at different times?
A single dude at the front says that.
Can I see how they look from here?
From what you can see, they look to be normal.
They are all wearing full armor and with their headgear and stuff, but...
Can Guacamole see anything?
You or Guacamole see nothing
that appears out of the ordinary with them.
Okay.
Guacamole lands like a good, you know,
a decent distance away, like away, you know, for safety.
And the guy who yelled at you,
he looks like he's got much finer plate mail.
You could say he's probably the commander or leader of this squad.
Then he yells out to you and says,
you need to start explaining to yourselves what's going on here.
Why is there fire in Mirabar?
And what are you doing flying towards us?
Guys, he seems like he doesn't know anything about what's going on.
This is perfect.
What's going on?
What's your name, sir?
I'm Commander Hammerstryker,
and I am the commander of the acts of Mirabar.
Okay, Hammy, listen up.
You want to make a history check first?
Are we all making history checks?
Yeah, everybody can.
History.
16.
19.
16, only because I rolled a 10.
That could have been real good, though.
You all know that the acts of Mirabar
is commanded by Commander Torgar Hammerstryker,
and he has been the commander of the militia and the army in Mirabar
for close to 300 years now.
So that, to you, checks out.
Hammy, my man, Ham the man, Ham the man.
Who are you?
I'm Thea Amastasia, and these are my compadres.
What's your group name?
None of your fucking business.
That's our group name.
Oh, let's dial it down a notch there.
You see some of the soldiers get a little more agitated.
Sorry, I'm sorry.
Someone else start talking.
Elbow Flint, go talk to him.
You've got your charm belt.
Dwarves love to other dwarves.
It's all the dwarf love.
I put my axe away, and I walk up and I say,
Torgar Hammerstryker, you've come just in time.
There are some serious problems going on in Mirabar.
Well, I see that, but what is happening?
Sorry, who are you?
My apologies.
I'm Flint Firebeard.
I used to be with the Fist of the Iron Dawn.
What do you know?
What's happening?
We arrived in town a few days ago,
and it turns out my old company was here on some unsavory business,
which is part of why I left their ranks.
A bit of a plot has unfolded since then.
There's an elf wizard that seems to have cast a charm
on the rest of the acts of Mirabar.
Here in town, that has corrupted them,
and they're all in his control,
and who knows what they're doing,
because now we see that the city's on fire.
Did it just start getting on fire?
I don't know.
We were transported to...
It's a long story.
I don't know.
We just got back from where we were,
and we saw the town burning.
Okay. Well, that's not good.
We have half of our army here.
There were 500 soldiers left in the city,
and 500 were scheduled to return before we got back.
So that's...
If he has charmed them all,
that's a thousand soldiers that he has under his control.
Do you know anything about the charm?
Yes. Take off all your clothes.
I beg your pardon?
Who is this?
He's asking you, Flint.
This is Thea Amastasia.
She's a druid,
and I've been traveling with her for the last few months.
Great.
He's charmed the armor.
Charmed the armor.
Okay.
Yes, because we met another person from the acts of Mirabar
who was named...
Anyone?
Do you know a dwarf named Ostrich Battlehammer?
He's a close friend, yes.
We met him.
He was uncharmed because he was off duty,
not wearing his armor,
and he appears to be one of the only soldiers
not affected by this charm,
and their minds appear to be gone.
I'm sorry.
I know these are your soldiers,
but they are overtaken by this elf,
and he is controlling their words and their actions.
Do you know if this is a reversible charm?
We tried removing the armor,
and it had no effect.
We don't know if there's a magical cure,
but just removing the armor didn't do anything.
So if we go in under this with our armor on,
we are at risk, as you understand,
to become charmed as well.
Perhaps.
Not so crazy now, am I?
It could have been a one-time cast of a spell that he did,
but we're not exactly sure,
so it could be anything at this point.
He may have set up some sort of mist tent
because it was hot,
and they all walked through it wearing their armor.
Sure.
Yeah, I get it.
Anything's possible.
Yeah.
Okay, you don't know how you got out.
Okay.
Well, this is tough.
There is a sewer entrance into Mirabar.
I don't want to take all of my soldiers beyond this point,
really, in case whatever's happening turns them,
but I could come with you
and try and get in without my armor, obviously,
and see if we can't figure things out
and then hopefully drop whatever charm
or figure out if we can't all come in
to help clear the city.
We released Ostrich.
We were all trapped in the dungeon together,
so it's possible he escaped
and we could find him,
and maybe he has learned more in our absence,
or he could now be possessed or dead,
but you say he is a good friend of yours.
Yes.
If you know where he may be,
that might be a good starting destination for us.
He's the only one we saw that wasn't under this spell.
Well, I know a couple places
we could probably look for him.
Hopefully, the entire place hasn't been completely overrun,
but yeah, we need to get in there somehow,
so let's get your armor.
Or, you know, save the town, but either one.
We do have some armor being made.
Okay, maybe that's a good place to go,
because if I can't get in with my armor,
maybe there is another armor that I can be outfit with,
but yes, let's go do that.
He begins to take off his armor
and give his next-in-command orders
to hold their position until they hear otherwise
or see a signal that is safe to enter the city.
I would like to roll a perception check
to see what Thea's reaction to him taking his armor off is.
What's Thea's reaction to him taking his armor off?
She sings inappropriately,
and he says, all right, guys, let's go in through the sewers.
And he leads you to the south of the city,
where the river is,
and there you find an entrance to some sewer tunnels.
Gross.
I mean, yay.
You enter into these sewer tunnels,
and Flint and Hammerstriker,
they are able to walk through quite well,
but Thea and Nularaaaa, you gotta duck a little bit.
I complain about it.
Well, you're quite tall, aren't you, Thea?
I'm almost six feet tall.
That is quite tall.
And he says to you, he's like,
so where are you getting this armor from?
The guy in the shopping district?
This is the day they realize
they need to ask names and locations.
He has an underground entrance as well.
The entire city of Mirabar has an underground entrance,
but there are two blacksmiths of decent quality,
because this sewer will tie into those tunnels,
and we can probably go check them out.
Well, this blacksmith had a bunch of kids,
if that helps you out.
Oh, Patrick.
Then we'll go see him.
Yeah.
So you travel through the sewers,
and you don't see or hear some ruckus above,
from the streets above,
but you come to a side tunnel
that eventually connects into the underground
Mirabar tunnel network
that you had been in previously
when escaping the dragon.
It takes a little while,
but you get to the same blacksmith entrance
that you were at before.
Hammer Stryker goes up
and kind of peeks through the door.
He kind of gives you the wait a second hand signal,
and he sneaks in.
You hear some shuffling about,
and then he comes back and waves you up,
and you walk into the blacksmith,
and it looks like it's been turned over,
like everything is knocked off the walls.
No.
And...
No!
Thank you for reacting appropriately.
Sorry, everyone else got to do it,
so I wanted to get in on the fly.
Well, he was real nice,
and I just feel bad.
Made it through the dragon attack,
and now this dumb soldier has probably attacked him.
Under the spell of this primsbane bastard.
I start sifting through the remaining things,
trying to find maybe the armor,
because I asked them for it to be fancy.
Are you trying to be quiet when you do this,
or are you just kind of milling stuff about it?
No, I'm trying...
Well, first, I'm just looking around,
but if I do move anything,
I would like to be quiet about it.
Should I make a stealth check?
How about first we say...
Hail, Patrick!
Rather than just walking in
and digging through the piles of rubble.
Thea's high.
Thea don't care.
Oh, you're right, you're right.
Thea goes in and starts just rummaging through things.
Very quietly she starts rummaging through things,
because you got a good stealth check there.
But Nularaaaa, you do yell out,
and you hear from a side room,
you hear kind of a stir,
and like a picking up of a sword and shield,
and you hear...
Who? Who's there?
Patty!
Oh, it's you.
Did you bring the army, too?
You brought the dragon.
Did you bring the army?
And he kind of slowly walks out of this back room.
Looks like he's been in a bit of a battle,
but he looks okay.
Just looks like he's been roughed up a little bit.
Do he and Hammerstriker embrace or anything?
They know each other?
Do they kiss on the mouth?
Hammerstriker...
...was clearing another room,
but he walks in at the same time,
and they don't kiss on the mouth.
They acknowledge each other,
and Hammerstriker asks him if he's okay,
and then Patrick says...
Well, the Axa Mirabar came in here
and just started looting and tearing stuff off the walls,
and I didn't know what was going on.
I fled through the tunnels,
but managed to sneak my way back in after they had left.
What's going on?
But you guys, you three,
there's bad news bears about you.
Every time I see you, something bad's going on.
Well, you're not wrong,
but we don't cause it.
We try our best to help.
And that's not really true.
The second time you saw us,
it was a quiet afternoon when we came to order armor.
Yeah, so what, two out of three times
it's been a total shit show?
It's not so bad.
It's pretty bad.
Speaking of which...
Did anyone steal my armor?
Surprisingly, no,
but the price has gone up.
But it was free,
and then I also paid you for it, so...
Yep, the price has gone up.
All right, Hammy, you know what to do.
Okay.
I fucking love Thea.
It's so great.
You got this, right?
I'm making not clear gestures.
He looks at you like,
what are you talking about?
And he looks at Patrick.
He's like,
Patrick, we need some armor.
I am not wearing my armor
because apparently these folks say
that there's a charm on the acts of Mirabar armor,
which has turned them into something,
something that's not normal.
I mean, you made a deal with her.
You should probably just give her,
even if she's paid.
Patrick says,
Fine, fine.
I'll give you the armor.
Thanks, Patty.
You're the best.
And I should have something in your size there, Torgar.
So he goes into the back
and brings out armor for Torgar and for you.
How pretty is it?
It is very pretty.
It is very shiny.
It is plate armor.
You lift it and it is light as a feather.
I give him 30 gold pieces
just because I'm so happy.
Why do you gotta,
whatever.
He takes the 30 gold.
You are hilarious with the money.
A watching contradiction.
But then I pay him anyway.
Yeah.
This is how I do it.
He hands the armor to Torgar
and you both now have armor.
I put mine on and I go to Nulara
and I go, zip me up.
I zip her up.
Sure, it's a zipper.
Why not?
I was just being funny,
like how girls put on dresses
and then they have to get someone to zip them up.
It's a zipper.
Okay.
The only zipper in Faerun.
You've got it.
That would be amazing.
You know how complicated it is to put on armor?
You need a page to put it on you
and tie it up piece by piece.
It's exhausting.
Zip, zip.
This is amazing.
That was worth the 30 extra gold you just gave him.
Certainly was.
What's my armor class now?
You have a 16 armor class.
Hoping for 18, but okay.
What kind of armor do you think is gonna give you?
I don't even have 18.
I was gonna say I don't have 18.
Damn, badass.
I'm wearing badass scale mail
and I don't even have 18.
Your armor class without armor is 11.
So you have plus five armor.
Damn, that's nice.
Okay, amazing.
I just feel like I get hit a lot.
Well, you do because you put yourself
in the middle of gargoyle.
You do kind of jump right in.
That room was small.
Yeah, we were all in the middle of some stuff
in that dungeon.
That room was tiny.
You are a squishy druid.
Just keep that in mind.
But now you're a little less squishy.
So you guys are all armored up.
Patrick, can you tell us anything about the soldiers?
Did you make their armor?
Did you notice anything different about it?
We're trying to figure out how to fight these guys
or how to stop the charm that Prisbane has on them.
There's me and another blacksmith in town
that have been making the armor
and they do use a rare metal alloy
that we've been developing.
It's not used for any other type of armor.
That's the only real difference.
What's the metal called?
Well, we've been working with Clan Ironstar
to use their dark steel alloy
and combine that with mithril armor.
A dark mithril alloy, if you will.
And no one else in town is allowed to use it.
It's specifically for the acts of Mirabar.
But, you know, seems kind of big now.
But really that's the only difference though.
I bet that has something to do with the spell.
It'd be an easy way to target it, wouldn't it?
Do I know any, like, out of character,
do I know of this spell?
Is there any way that I can...
You know that there are...
Did I ask this already?
Now I feel like it may have asked already.
And you said you know that there are control spells.
In character, you know that there are
spells that can control minds,
usually done by necromantic wizards.
However, you know those spells have limitations.
You know, usually if they're going to do that,
there's a set number of targets
that they are able to control
while maintaining concentration.
But what you've seen is likely
he has control of 1,000 soldiers,
which is far outside the realm
of what you know could be possible
by a spell of that sort.
I imagine him sitting in a room somewhere
with the look of like consternation,
just the constant focus
of trying to keep track of 1,000.
But you know that there likely
could be something else at play
along with some sort of control spell.
Well, I want to hit things, you guys.
I want things to hit me.
I want to test this metal.
Where to?
Should we try to find the other dwarf?
Or should we try like,
do you want to just like go find Primsbane?
I don't really, I feel bad actually.
Maybe you guys can just remind me.
When we fought the dwarves in the dungeon,
like, did they ever come back to themselves?
Like, do we have to kill all of them?
Or can we break the spell?
We tried taking off the armor
because that was the only thing
that we could think to really do.
And we're not like super magical.
So there might be a magic fix,
but taking off the armor didn't help.
No, and their faces were blue
with like black veins and stuff like that.
So I guess like my inclination
would be to go to the source
and see if that,
like if we kill Primsbane,
if they become uncharmed
rather than just like fighting
and killing a bunch of people,
like it's not their fault.
Yeah.
Oh, no, for sure.
We should try to take out Primsbane.
Yes.
Okay.
Hammer Stryker, where do you think Primsbane is?
He's the one we need to find.
We need to kill him
and see if we can save these soldiers.
The most fortified location in the city
is likely where you were
when you were in the brig.
That building has the most fortified position.
It's the hardest to get into.
There's only really two entrances,
the front and there's one getaway exit
out the rear,
which exits into the tunnels.
So we do have a way in
through the underground system.
My guess is if he's in town
and doing this,
that's where he would be.
Back to the dungeon.
I guess we don't know if he's in town,
but it's a good starting spot.
Let's go.
Should we try to find Ostrich?
On the way.
Keep an eye out.
Hammer Stryker, is there a way
you said you thought you might know
where Ostrich was?
We could use more help.
Can we swing by,
pick him up on our way to go kill the Dark Elf?
Well, we can.
There are a couple safe houses
that we could get to
that aren't on site.
So we can go try and swing by there
and see if maybe he's holed up.
Let's do that.
You guys head back down.
Patrick stays behind.
He's not coming with you,
but you four head down into the tunnels
and it takes you a little while.
You don't run into anybody
before you make it to an exit
from the tunnels,
which brings you out into a street,
which Hammer Stryker says,
okay, the safe house is just
across the street here.
He looks out into the road.
There appears to be some guards
down at the end of the way.
So we just have to make it
across the street,
down a couple of doors
and get into the house
without them seeing us.
Nulara, you know what to do.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
I'll pass without a trace
and we'll be real sneaky.
Hello, welcome back.
It's been too long
and I've missed you so much.
It's me, your dungeon master,
Russ More.
Thank you for listening
to episode 15 of Dumptions and Dragons,
this one titled,
A Stutter in Time.
This episode is dealing
with the portal jump
that Flint, Thea and Nulara
made to Enan,
the world of bros and dragons.
If you missed that episode,
it's their episode 32.
So you should head over to iTunes,
check them out,
bros and dragons
and specifically episode 32
to hear some of that crazy stuff
that went down
and what we're dealing with now.
That's all I've got.
The next part in our adventure
will be available June 28th.
I know, so far away.
It'll go quick though, don't worry.
With episode 16.
Let's get back out there
and see if we can't start
cleaning up this quest log though.
Talk to you next time.
Last up to one hour.
Must stay within 30 feet.
Yeah, we've got to stay within 30 feet
and we just get a plus 10
to stealth checks
and we leave no trace also, hence.
Yeah, you leave no footprints and stuff.
Yeah.
You cast pass without a trace
and you feel
and the magical wave wash over you
and it appears to have succeeded.
So make a, as you head out
into the street,
make a stealth check everybody
with a plus 10 bonus.
Oh, it's a good thing it's a plus 10.
Plus your stealth.
24.
Nice.
20.
18.
Hammer striker got 14
but that's still good enough
to make it to the safe house
across the street and you get in
and as you get in
and shut the door,
you are unnoticed.
You go into the safe house
and it looks like it has been
turned over as well.
Hammer striker calls out
and says,
Ostrick, are you here?
And you wait a second
and there's no call back.
Well, shit.
There was several safe houses, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, we're invisible for an hour.
We can traipse all over
this goddamn town if you want.
Sure. Yeah, absolutely.
It says maybe we can look around here
and just see if
see if there's anything left behind.
Oh, for sure.
I go upstairs.
Is there an upstairs?
I don't know.
Okay.
I go into the next room.
It's a rancher.
They don't do well with stairs.
You just want to do
investigation checks.
Yep.
Fuck my rolls.
Five.
16.
12.
Takes about five minutes
and hammer striker calls you
as you're each searching rooms
and says that he found a small stone soldier
that he knows that Osric owns.
And he says he found that tucked behind
one of the cabinets.
So he feels that he has been here
and he might be at one of the other locations.
Okay.
Great.
Let's go.
Sneakily.
As you head back out into the street,
do you guys want to take the tunnels
or do you want to just take the street?
I guess whatever's faster.
Like the spell lasts for a while.
So as far as we know, no one is looking for us.
So I guess the most direct way we can get there.
Hammer striker says, well, we can head through the streets.
That'd probably be the quickest way.
It's a little twisty down underneath
but we're more than likely to pass by a few guard posts.
But yeah, we can head through the streets.
It'd take us about 10 minutes to get there.
They're on the far side of town there.
So you guys head out
and you're walking through the streets
Has anyone else noticed
that Russ is really making mentions
of how much time things take?
Yes, I did also notice that.
It's important to know.
Totally.
I'm so torn.
Like I want it to be other bad guys, not soldiers.
Like this is their commander
and he's going to have to fight them.
There are a lot of moral implications
that I'm not that comfortable with.
Oh, for sure.
Yeah.
So you head out into the street
and you take a turn away from the first guards
that you saw.
You walk out into a main road area
and you're sticking kind of to the side
but you see a group of 10 soldiers marching up.
Make a stealth check.
24.
Still plus 10?
Yeah.
Sweet.
29.
17.
Hammer striker got 16.
So you guys make it by.
Hammer striker trips as he's walking by
and all of the soldiers turn their heads to look
but they just keep walking.
So you make it by them
and you make it to the second safe house
without alerting anybody.
He leads you in there and it looks very similar.
So he calls out and he says,
Osric and nothing.
You don't hear anything back.
You want to make investigation checks?
Nope.
18.
19.
Five.
All right.
Hammer striker got four.
Thea, you are searching rooms
and this safe house is bigger than 30 feet.
So you guys are extending beyond the range of the spell
but you step into one of the rooms
and just kind of pass through
where the range of the spell is
and you hear a startled yell
and as you become visible to Osric
he swings down at you with his axe.
Make a deck saving throw.
16.
He misses you and looks at you and says,
where have you guys been?
Around.
Jesus.
Hey guys, he's in here.
Wait, we were around Jesus?
Well, you know, some of those dragonborn had long hair.
All right, yeah, fair enough.
Okay, we join them.
Then do we all disappear again?
Wait, that's what I'm trying to figure out.
You stay by the front door.
But it's concentration, right?
So I can choose for us to not be invisible
but before I do that, does he look okay?
Is he him?
He looks to be him.
Yeah, he doesn't look like he's taken over.
It looks like he's been in more battle
than when you last saw him
which looks like he had been interrogated with force.
Because I got some questions.
Yeah, for sure.
How long have we been gone?
Uh, you guys have been gone for three weeks.
What?
That was unexpected.
Yeah.
Okay.
And what, I mean, I think we can surmise
but what has happened since we left?
The armies just run rampant, destroying the town?
Well, you guys disappeared.
Yep.
And Leonid and I, we didn't know where you went
or what happened, obviously.
So we tried to escape and were confronted.
I managed to make it out
but Leonin was taken prisoner again
and I haven't seen him since then.
I managed to make it to one of the safe houses
and it was ambushed.
All of them were.
I fought my way out, went into the tunnels
and hid for quite a while
and I've been hopping between them ever since.
Leaving clues, hoping someone would come back
from the other troops unaffected
but after you guys left,
500 more of the soldiers came back
and literally, when they hit the city limits
they turned into the same monster,
zombies, not themselves.
Well, we know that it's the armor now, at least
because this fine gentleman right here
is not wearing the armor that was, you know.
You know.
Hammer Stryker says she's apparently been smoking
and I don't really care for her.
Listen, if you were in an alternate dimension
that you didn't even know existed
and where one day was actually three weeks back home,
good sir, you would need a little something too.
Yeah, he looks at you like you smoked way too much.
And off in the background,
I just make that crazy person
like finger around the head in a circle kind of motion.
Little did you know, Flynn's doing it for himself
because he's got a screaming dragonborn in his headstone.
Oh yeah, it's not great in my head right now.
Hammer Stryker and Osric are discussing
what the situation is
and Osric has come to the conclusion
that he believes that Primsbane is also
in the town hall area where the brig is
but it is overrun with these soldiers.
The only quick way in would be the tunnels
but he feels that that's going to be
fairly heavily guarded as well.
Is there a way that we can get a message
out to the thousand troops
that are outside of Mirabar right now?
I don't know.
We'd have to find a way to give them a signal
what did you want to tell them?
Find different armor, come back, save the city.
I still think we're better sorted
to do like a small mission
where we take out the leader
and see if it fixes everything.
I suppose so.
Yeah, because again,
we don't want the soldiers to have to...
I mean, if that's what it comes to,
that's what it comes to
but they're not going to be real keen
to come and fight their compadres.
Could we at least send a message
saying something like,
it is the armor under no circumstance
should you come near the city
with your armor on?
Because the last thing you need...
They know not to come
unless they're signaled.
So I think if we don't signal them at all,
that would be the better solution.
Okay, I'm just trying to be proactive.
Well, let's go and kill some dark elf.
It sounds like a couple of bad options.
So what do you guys recommend?
This is your town.
You know the lay of the land
way better than we do.
Are the tunnels the better option?
What do you suggest?
Because we have to take this guy out.
Osric says...
The tunnel, as guarded as it may be,
there are 500 soldiers
standing outside their front door.
I think the tunnel is going to be
the easiest way in.
That said, there will still be
some hard fighting to get in there,
though, I think.
Once we are in,
we may be able to bar the bulk
of their soldiers from getting in.
If we are able to get past
some of their defenses.
Tunnels it is.
Let's do it.
As you turn to leave,
Nularaaaa, you hear...
Well, all of you hear,
but the source is coming from Nularaaaa.
You hear a static charge,
like a electric shock, lightning.
Not that you're shocked,
but that kind of sound.
And you hear a voice crackling in.
The sound is coming from your arrow quiver.
And you hear the voice of
what you think is Salazar.
And it's coming in through static,
and he says...
Tibby, Tibby, where are you?
Where did you guys go?
We just, we just got your signal back.
Ah, you stupid mech.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin McLeod
of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
Dumbgeons & Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.