Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Come on in, my friends.
I feel we have much to talk about.
We might actually wanna just talk to him.
I just want to know how you guys
keep getting away from my traps.
This isn't the first time, you know.
I feel like this power I'm looking for
is what's actually helping you.
Now, which one of you has the key to get it?
Have a seat at my table.
We can discuss this.
We can see if we can join forces
for the betterment of everyone.
No, we will not join you, you psychopath.
Necromancer?
Have it your way.
I'll just have all my zombies kill you
and then, well, I'll find it on you somewhere.
I'm going to haul lightning.
He doesn't move.
Oh, he's just choosing not to make the save.
Oh, fuck.
That's fun.
Yeah, totally.
You call this lightning.
It strikes five feet above him
as if there's a dome covering him.
You hear from down the hall
the breaking of what sounds like the front door.
And Torgar yells to Osric,
we have to go slow them down.
Bugbear on the far right of the room.
There are three in this room.
There's one towards the very back standing by a door.
There's one off to the right in the room
and he begins to work his way backwards
towards that door.
And both of them just ready themselves.
He says, I think it's time for me to go.
A portal opens on the floor beside him
and he jumps through.
What's behind that door?
You hear, it sounds like zombies hitting the door
that you entered from previously.
And you open this door,
you see in the center of those spires
is a piece of the Axe of Mirabar armor.
And there are three bubbling jars.
And inside of those jars are brains.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
This is a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast.
I'm your dungeon master, Russ More.
And joining me today, continuing the journey
is Amy More playing Thea Amastasia.
Yes, it is.
It's the same joke you used last time.
Damn it, let me try again.
Hi.
Just take it one more time.
What up?
I like it.
Oh, that's so much better.
Thank you.
Playing me Laura Moonbrook is Carla Johnson.
Hello.
And Tom Laird playing Flint Firebeard.
Drop the chalupa.
I like it.
You're trying to make that happen, hey?
That's right.
Bringing it back.
This month, we are,
well, we have a couple of things going on.
We have a new website, which is up.
Everybody can say how awesome it is
because they've totally seen it by this point.
Oh, it is amazing.
Wait, we have a new website?
Oh, it looks so good.
I haven't seen it.
Once again, Russ has done all of the work
and gets all of the credit
for anything that looks good
and anything that is bad,
we'll take the blame for.
Yeah, that's about fair.
Does that seem fair, you guys?
That's a good division of labor, I think.
Yeah.
Yeah, we have a new website.
You can go to dumbdragons.com to check that out.
It's got lovely pictures of all of your lovely faces.
I didn't give you a picture.
Not yet, but you will,
cause this is in the past, Amy.
This comes out August 2nd.
Pretend you're in the future for a second.
I have a really hard time.
I know, I know.
Also, we have launched our Patreon page.
You can go to Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast
to join the adventure and if you can,
contribute starting from $1 a month
to get some sweet perks
in the Dumb Dragon Realm and Universe.
If you do contribute $1 a month,
you get access to all of our Patreon only content,
which will feature exclusive
Patreon only released episodes and bonus content.
The first episode of our Patreon only content
will be released this month with Tom Laird
DMing his own game here with
Oh boy.
The three of us playing.
We'll give you a little taste of that
and then hopefully that catches you
and you wanna get more of that.
We'll be releasing those.
We'll talk about this later,
but maybe every month, we'll see.
See how that goes.
Tom, how you feel?
How you feel about that, Tom?
Tom?
Are you there?
Oh yeah, I'm feeling great, guys.
Feeling great about it.
It's only one a month.
There are also other reward tiers.
If you donate $5 a month, what do you get?
Nudes.
Tom?
Apparently nudes.
It's not on there.
It's not on the website.
You're not getting nudes.
You can be picked at random
to have an episode dedicated in your name.
That's right.
You get all the Patreon episodes
plus you could be picked at random
to have an episode dedicated in your name.
So right now it could be you, John Smith,
who has this episode dedicated to you.
Kind of like how we dedicated it
to Taco Bell at the beginning.
Exactly.
Precisely.
We'll talk about how we're dropping your Chalupa
instead of Taco Bell's.
Exactly.
And how about that $10 a month or more, Carla?
You get to ask questions on a future Q&A episode
and you get to have an MPC named after you
or a name that you supply.
Within reason, I feel like Russ put that
so people wouldn't be like, I don't know, but Fartsky.
Oh my God.
You know we would pick it.
I gotta admit, that does sound kind of amazing.
Our standards for MPC names are super low.
Yeah, those are the kind of names we make up.
Like, yeah, don't take that from us.
Well, our listeners are cleverer and classier than us,
so they wouldn't try and go for that.
That's what we're here for.
But if they did, it's okay.
But that low-hanging fruit is the most delicious.
Exactly.
So ripe and tasty.
It's good, yeah.
I mean, if you're contributing at that adventurer level,
then absolutely, we will take whatever NPC name,
within reason, that you want to give us.
So now that we've hooked you on our Patreon,
I know that was a great sell.
We are sales people.
It's true.
By trade.
Yeah, we are trying to hit our first goal,
which is getting $50 a month.
And when we do reach that goal,
we'll be giving away a Dumbgeons and Dragons starter set
to a lucky patron.
So we wanna give back to you
if you feel that we are worthy
of your contribution every month.
We would greatly appreciate anything
and everything that you do for us.
So thank you in advance.
Including just passing it along to friend, word of mouth.
That's right.
If you can't contribute, word of mouth is the best.
Well, enough of this.
Shall we D&D?
Let's do it.
We shall.
You opened the door to this back room
that was attempting to be guarded
by these various zombies previously.
And you enter into this room
and there are two large spires.
In the center of those spires
is a piece of the Axe of Mirabar armor
and surrounding them are three floating jars
with brains inside.
And they have attacked your minds as you entered the door
and you took a lot of damage when you walked in,
psychically.
Let's start by rolling for initiative.
Fucking roll the shit out of this.
One.
I got a one.
One is high, right?
One is real good.
Yeah.
I got 11.
22.
Starting off the order is New Lara.
Okay.
I'm nervous to be first
because I think things are gonna kill me
when I try and kill them.
This is my fear.
So maybe what I will do,
how far is this stuff from us?
Oh, close.
Like five feet.
Yeah, they're kind of just swirling
around the room right now.
But yeah, they're varying degrees of distance from you.
But it's not a huge room.
Rather than use my sword,
I just am a little concerned
about immediate contact with these things.
They did just hurt my brain pretty bad.
Maybe I will take one of my daggers
and throw it.
Just to see what happens to the weapon.
So that is a 17.
And let's say like blue floating brain.
Yes, each of the brains are very clearly
a different color to you as your character sees them.
You throw your dagger
and just before it connects with the brain,
it casts shield.
It is deflected by a magical shield spell.
Oh good, more of these.
So it is a spell that it is casting.
Okay, good.
So it didn't like explode anything
or do anything like that.
So in that case,
then I am going to use my best attack,
which is of course my sword flame tongue.
So let's try that.
See if that is better.
That is not better because that is a 17.
You swing and you swing true,
but it is deflected by this invisible shield barrier.
Can Donnie on his turn,
is the armor floating in the middle
or sitting on the ground in the middle?
It is on like a pedestal in the middle
between these spires.
And did the spires go floor to ceiling
or are they like platforms?
They're like curved columns.
So like a half moon-esque feature,
kind of like a statue of sorts.
I see.
I don't want Donnie to get that close to them.
Could Donnie on his turn,
he won't be able to do this
because he's very weak, bless his heart,
but maybe try and move the armor off the platform,
like dislodge it somehow.
He can certainly try.
Like fly into it basically.
And I guess would that be a strength check?
He's not good at that,
but yeah, that's a 10.
But he tried.
Tried to move it.
He flies into the middle of this action
and one of the other brains,
you can see it kind of focusing its energy
on the piece of armor.
And it as well appears to get this invisible field
brought up to it.
And Donnie is deflected off.
Me doesn't take any damage,
but he is deflected away from the armor.
Great.
Now it is the blue brain's turn.
Ruh-roh.
The one that you, Nularaaa, went for.
And it's going to mind thrust.
Dirty.
Yeah.
Yikes.
Makes me uncomfortable.
It's going to mind thrust you, Nularaaa.
So you have to succeed on an intelligent saving throw.
That and blow your rape whistle.
Jesus.
Yeah, no kidding.
Yeesh.
Okay, intelligent saving throw.
Tom's back.
All right, sorry about that.
There's mind-thrusting going on, Tom.
Yeah, there's a brain is mind-thrusting me
and I rolled a 15.
You don't take any damage,
but it's going to mind thrust on Thea as well.
So you must make an intelligent saving throw.
Oh yeah.
Okay, well that, well, it's still not that good.
So it's a 13.
You do not save.
3d6 psychic damage.
Oh, Christ.
It's a low roll though.
You only take seven, seven damage.
That's about as good as you could have hoped for.
And then this brain floats
to the left corner in the room there.
And now it is the gray brain's turn.
And this one is the one that cast the shield spell
onto the barrier.
And it is going to attempt to mind slave
Flint.
So Flint, you must succeed on a wisdom saving throw.
Excellent.
Wisdom is my worst one.
Oh damn, 17.
You feel this brain trying to break in and control you,
but you save and it doesn't have any effect on you.
Now it is Flint's turn.
Payback time.
All right, blue has a protective shield on him.
Gray does not.
The shield spell lasts until the end of their next turn.
But he cast the shield spell on the armor, no?
The gray one did, yes.
All right.
I'm going to go kick the shit out of the gray one then.
Do it.
In theory, I'm going to kick the shit out of him.
That is a 25.
25 will hit.
Excellent.
17 damage on the first attack.
And we'll go for attack number two.
Unless it's dead.
Is it dead, Russ?
They're just squishy brains.
Well, they're in the things, though.
Oh, are they in jars?
They're in jars.
They're not just floating squishy brains.
Well, that's where I keep all my brains.
In jars.
It's true.
It's a good place for them.
Yeah, but I'm really hipster about it.
I use mace in jars.
Solid.
No, it is not dead.
So sorry, that was 17 damage?
Yeah.
Write it down.
Yeah, I just had to make sure I had the hit points,
right?
Go ahead.
All right, I will go for attack number two.
And that is a 22 that time.
22 will hit, yeah.
God bless those plus seven bonuses.
That's a 27 damage.
Oh yeah.
You strike this thing twice
and it rocks and spins and moves back into the room,
but it is still floating
and it may have taken like a bit of damage
on its outer shell, perhaps a crack in its glass.
Now it's the green brain's turn
and it focuses its attention on you, Flint.
I kind of figured it would.
Yeah.
Also, I don't want Amy to take any more damage,
so I'm gonna try and get them all on me.
Thanks, man.
I don't wanna die today.
So what I'm here for as the role of Dwarven Shield.
A sickening green energy comes out of this brain
and towards you, Flint.
And it creates a ray of sickness attack.
That's an 18.
Is this like a physical attack or?
It's a ranged spell attack, yes.
Okay, does AC work the same against spells
as it does against physical attacks?
Sure does.
Okay, I just don't know.
No one's ever nuke me with spells before.
If it hits you,
you make a constitution saving throw
against this damage though.
So 18 would hit.
Yeah, so you make a con save.
Okay.
That is plus 416.
So you save, so you take full damage,
but you're not poisoned.
Oh, great.
Yeah. Yay.
I'm also resilient to poison
being a Dwarf.
That would be half damage then.
So you take. Yeah.
You take four poison damage
with your Dwarven resiliency.
Sweet.
And then it is Thea's turn.
Oh, is it?
Oh really?
I'm gonna evoke Moonbeam to see how this happens
cause I can like whip it around
as we found out that other time.
I need to concentrate it on just one creature
and I think I'm gonna go for the gray one.
Yes, Amy.
Yeah, cause it's already kind of damaged.
I evoke Moonbeam.
Shoo, shoo, shoo, shoo, shoo.
That's what Moonbeam sounds like.
The official Moonbeam sound effects are just fantastic.
Thank you.
High budget.
Constitution saving throw.
And brains and jars get advantage on saves
against magical effects and spells.
But both the rules are terrible.
So you hit anyway.
So 13.
Not good.
Not good, okay.
So you take two D10 radiant damage.
11.
It almost looks like the fluid in the jar
begins to boil and there's a visible crack
that appears on the outside of this jar
that the grayish brain is inside.
Yeah.
And we are back to the top of the order,
which is New Lara.
All three of you here allow rumble
as these zombies on the other side of the main entrance
and kind of looks like it's bending
as the zombies behind are trying to push their way
into this room.
I have a feeling like our two guys over there are dead.
All right, we gotta fix this ASAP, guys.
Yeah, no kidding.
Is the door behind us closed?
Are you saying they're entering the boardroom door
where we were before?
Yeah, the main door.
So it was barred when Torgar and Osric left,
but the door that you are in is open.
You can see that,
but yeah, the door to get into the main room
and you are in this little side room.
Okay, well, maybe step one,
I'll turn around and close the door behind me.
Solid.
I was not born in a barn.
I might've been, but regardless,
it's not much defense, but at least it's something.
So I closed the door.
Door closed.
Now I'm going to try again to get this blue dude.
That does not work because that is 13.
Let me try again.
That one's better.
That's a 28.
Whoa.
Yeah, that connects solid to this blue brain.
So he gets 24 damage.
Oh yeah.
These jars have like ornamental design work to them
and you knock some of it clean off of this jar
as it cracks a little bit as well.
And you move this floating jar back in the room.
It appears that they're floating together now.
Okay, Donnie's going to try
and push that armor off again.
I don't know if that's going to do anything,
but it's not like he can attack a jar.
He's not very, you know.
So why not?
Why not let him try that?
Yeah, it does not work.
Did you use both of your attacks?
Yeah, one of them failed and I only rolled a 13.
Oh, right, right.
Donnie got a like seven or something.
So I don't think that worked.
No, no, same kind of thing.
The green brain this time senses Donnie
and focuses its energy on the shield as well.
And Donnie is again deflected away from it.
It's the blue brain's turn now.
And it's going to try to cast Crown of Madness
on New Laura.
Yay.
You must make a wisdom saving throw there, New Laura.
Okey dokey.
That is a 12.
That does not save.
New Laura, you feel control being taken from you.
And Flint and Thea, you look over to her
and you see a twisted Crown of Jagged Iron
appear on top of her head.
And madness begins to glow in her eyes.
Good thing she already had her turn.
On your turn, it will tell you to attack someone.
You can't hurt yourself,
but you will be attacking someone that it chooses.
And you do that before you make a move.
And then at the end of your turn,
you can try to make the save again.
Okay.
Well, good thing I'm just hanging out
in the corner of the room by myself.
Everyone just kind of takes a few steps away from New Laura.
Exactly.
The gray brain floats around the room and to Thea here.
Thea, it is going to cast Hold Person on you.
You must succeed on a wisdom saving throw as well.
20.
You succeed.
So you feel it trying to paralyze your body.
I'm like, not today, motherfucker.
Exactly.
And you are-
I was kind of secretly hoping Amy would fail the check
and then Russ would have to pipe in
like Thompson twins hold me down underneath.
Next time, next time.
You save that and now it is Flynn's turn.
I'm going to focus all of my energy on this blue brain
and try and destroy it bigly.
Sure.
Okay, first attack roll.
That is a 16 and seven, 23.
23 will hit, yes.
Excellent.
19 damage.
It is sustaining more cracks in the glass
but it is still floating there.
Oh, there's more of that coming its way though.
I figured, I figured.
So that is a 18.
Come on, 18.
18 deflects.
Boo.
Same kind of thing as when New Laura
threw her daggers.
You swing and you are striking true
but as you get a little bit of ways,
it's deflected by the same kind of magical shield.
Okay.
And it is Green Brain's turn.
Oh, not yet, it isn't.
I'm going to take my action surge
which is one of my special skills.
22, much better.
22 will break the barrier, yes.
19.
You strike through and you feel it cut through
this invisible barrier and it cracks the glass
and it begins actually leaking fluid from it
and it sends it spinning wildly.
I'm going to make a save
to see if he can hold the concentration
and the thorns that are on New Laura's head
shrivel up and disappear.
Yeah.
Yes.
New Laura, you have control back.
It is still floating.
It's losing some fluid
but you are no longer controlled by that brain.
Now it's the Green Brain's turn
and it's going to cast Mind Thrust on Flint.
Flint, you have to make a saving throw
of the wisdom variety.
Oh, my super strongest one, here it goes.
That is a six.
So you are going to take 3d6 psychic damage
off this first Mind Thrust.
First Mind Thrust.
Yeah, I was like what?
Seven, nine.
Well, they each get two Mind Thrusts or a spell.
Okay.
And the second Mind Thrust will be directed at you as well
so make another...
Sorry, that was an intelligence save, not a wisdom save.
Oh, well, it would have been seven,
so it wouldn't have made much of a difference.
So yeah, an intelligence save on this next one here.
Okay.
14.
14 will save.
So you do not take the psychic damage on the second one.
Thea, your turn.
You just had this gray brain try to hold you
and control you.
You see the thorns appear
and madness glow in Nularaa's eyes
and then disappear as Flint attacks this blue brain
but then crumples under the strain
put on his mind from the green brain.
I am going to...
I still have my moon beam.
When it says I can use an action to move my moon beam.
That is your attack action.
That is my attack action, okay.
Because it can move at 60 feet,
I am going to swing it to the right
to hit the gray dude
and then I'm gonna whip it up to hit the blue dude
because altogether that is less than 60.
Sure.
So a con save.
Yes, a constitution saving throw from both those dudes.
Gray dude is a five.
The blue dude is a 17.
The 17 will save so he'll take only half damage.
Do I roll two separate damages for them?
One singular damage.
10 for the Bruin guy
and then five for the other guy.
The gray takes this damage
and you see kind of the splintering
of these cracks being put into its jar
and the blue, its jar erupts
and the brain falls to the floor with a splat.
And I go somebody curve stomp that thing.
You see it kind of pulse a little bit
and then it stops.
I still want someone to curve stomp.
We shoot it twice in the head
to make sure that it's dead.
Yeah, for sure.
After you shoot it twice in the head,
it is truly dead, truly dead.
Guys, I killed something.
Nicely done.
C-claps for herself.
Laura, you hear your communicator fuzz in
and Salazar's like,
Hey, you guys there?
Yeah, we're here.
So we just dropped some armor off
with those soldiers out there.
You guys okay?
Been better, little busy.
We're killing some brains.
It's a whole thing.
New communicator, who dis?
There's a horde of horrible zombie creatures
basically right outside the door of the room we're in.
So things are not excellent right now.
However, I think we found the piece of enchanted armor.
Oh, that's good.
All right, well, I'll let you get to it.
Just so you know, they're suiting up right now
and should be heading in to try and help you out
with the hordes,
if nothing else gets taken care of before then.
All right, well, double quick time.
Thanks, buddy.
Okay, bye.
You also hear the door outside.
You hear like wood splintering
as the zombies are trying to break through
that front door to that room.
Are they mostly the armored soldiers
or are they like the fucked up mismatched?
When you looked out the front door
and you put the chain lock on,
the majority of them look to be all kind of mismatched
and like they had been being worked on
for quite a while now.
And now it's your turn.
Okay, then I'm going to attack a brain.
Otherwise I was gonna try and attack the armor.
But if they're not the soldiers zombies,
like we need to deal with this armor issue,
but you know, they're not the ones
immediately trying to kill us, I don't think.
So yeah, exactly.
Gray brain going to,
I'm gonna carve out his amygdala and step on it.
Nice.
Awesome.
That's a 26.
26 will hit.
Okay, that is 16 damage.
More cracks come into the jar.
And again, you see some of the fluid
beginning to leak from some of those edges.
Not a lot, but some coming through.
Great.
Let's see if we can't make that splat on the ground.
That is a 18.
18 deflects off of its shield spell.
Balls is what I say to that.
Of course.
Since there's some cracks in it now,
I think Donnie can kind of try
and get in there a little bit
rather than just attacking smooth glass.
I think he has like a barb on the end of his tail
that he uses when he stings.
So I don't know, let's give it a shot.
See if he can crack open that glass.
Nope, that's a 17.
17 also will deflect off of the invisible shield.
And now it is the gray brain's turn.
It's going to cast Mind Slave on Thea.
It can try.
Oh, you can cast a wisdom saving throw.
28.
All right, it does not cast.
It appears to be losing more fluid than it thought.
And you are not under its slavy spell.
That's what I thought.
Flint, your turn.
I have a plus eight wisdom saving throw.
That is amazing.
Am I right in assuming that these brains
are floating in like Barbasol?
Absolutely.
Okay, because that's what's happening in my head.
Are there a few like combs and like scissors in there too?
So I guess I should try and kill the gray brain.
Yes, no, maybe so.
Yeah, because I bet you could kill it in,
like if you make contact, it'll be dead.
Excellent, let's go with a real Salazar on this one
and steal the kill.
That's a 23.
23 will hit.
I kind of imagined Salazar piping in
through the communicator going, I heard that.
So that's 21 damage.
Nice.
So you run over from the other side
of the room there, take a giant leaping swing
and carve through this glass that explodes its fluid
over Thea and new Lara.
And the brain itself explodes as well.
So you've got, you killed it,
but you covered everybody in brain guts.
Just a real mess around here.
Sorry, peeps.
Yeah.
Can I like hear if the crazy mob outside
is like still coming after us?
Is there any noise that they're making?
It's just this constant banging against the door
and wood splintering as the door is bowing
and cracking inwards.
Okay, so they're still real thirsty.
Yeah.
Okay, I'm gonna try like knocking this armor
off of the pedestal,
see if maybe that might help alleviate problems.
Sure.
Do it.
Okay, that is a 24.
24, yeah, you'll hit it.
Okay.
Now, am I just trying to like do damage to this
or what do I wanna do with this?
Does anyone have any suggestions?
Not really.
Like I guess, I guess destroy it.
Like I don't, as much as you can destroy armor,
like I was thinking the brains somehow were,
I don't know, making, but they're not, right?
Like they're just putting protection on it.
They weren't enchanting it, I don't think.
I kind of figured that like, yeah,
the three of them were like enchanting it together
and maybe once we killed one or two, that might stop.
Yeah, me too, but so far that has not happened.
So I think they're just protecting it.
I'll just try and do as much damage as possible
and maybe knock it off of its pedestal.
Can really cut it down a peg, am I right?
Yeah, totally.
19 damage.
You strike this armor and it throws it across the room
and bounces off the wall and lands near one of the spires.
And as you do this, the spires,
they have like writings carved into them
and they begin to glow.
And you hear a louder crash coming from the other room
as the zombies begin to pour into the room.
But it's no longer on that pedestal.
Great.
We did it guys.
You successfully moved it from one place to another.
So wait, are these pedestal things
that we can be like beating the crap out of?
Now that I see that there are like carvings in them
that may be a magical variety,
we might want to do that perhaps.
Maybe?
Maybe.
So it's the green brain's turn.
Are you sure?
I feel like I haven't had a turn in a long time.
You're at the end.
You should roll better if you want turns.
You did roll a one on initiative.
Technically it was a two
because I have plus one initiative bonus.
But you rolled a one.
Yeah, I did.
Flint, make a wisdom save.
All right.
Are you sure it's wisdom and not intelligence?
This time it is wisdom.
Okay, just wanted to double check.
Yep.
That is a 14.
You feel like you want to follow
the directions of this brain.
Okey dokey.
You have been mindslaved by the green brain
and it is Thea's turn.
Okay.
I'm going to move my moon beam over.
There we go.
Right on top of the green brain.
Great.
Constitution save.
She needs to make a,
it needs to make a constitution saving throw.
Oof, four.
Yeah, no, that's not gonna do it.
Yeah.
So, he takes five damage.
Is that enough to break his concentration
on whatever he's going with Flint?
That was my aim.
That was my goal.
Nope.
Damn.
Sorry buddy.
Back to new Lara now.
And you now hear the groans
and the zombies screams.
Whereas before they weren't,
they weren't like mindless zombies.
Now they just, it sounds like they are more,
more mindless than what they were before.
But you hear those coming in into the room now
as this door has been broken down.
Fuck.
I don't know what to do.
Hey, what happens with that moon beam?
Like, can I attack that brain or is it on it?
Like, what's the story?
Is it still like stuck in a moon beam?
There.
No, sorry.
I didn't need to drop it on it.
Oh, okay.
I swept it over it.
Sorry.
I was just mad.
Fair enough.
It's free to fight.
Okay.
I'm going to attack the brain.
That is a 20.
20 will hit, yes.
Is that a question?
Okay.
It was a question if it was going to hit or not
because it's got dumb deflection going.
13 damage.
Does that break its concentration?
Hold on.
If you don't ask, he doesn't roll for it.
I'm learning this.
This is good.
Doesn't break his concentration.
He's got the worst side on you guys.
Okay.
Ain't nobody going to break his stride.
Nobody going to hold him down.
He's got to keep on moving.
Okay.
You want to take another swing there?
Yeah, I do.
I'm just so torn because I want to do something
with the pillars because like a million zombies
is worse than one brain and one Flint,
but Flint's my dude so I don't want to have to fight him.
So it's a 21.
21 will hit, yep.
12 damage.
Okay.
And concentration.
Flint, you feel your control come back to you.
Yay.
Nice.
Thank goodness.
Okay, I guess Donnie's going to try for this jar
because I don't know what else he could do.
I don't know.
Donnie's got claws.
Maybe he tries to like slash through
some of that glowing writing on that spire.
Good idea.
That does not work, but he's tried.
He just got a manicure.
So he's a little worried about his nails.
He only rolled a six.
Although to be fair,
we haven't done any rolls against those pillars yet.
So maybe a six will hit.
Yeah, true.
It's true.
Me being like, I want to hit this wall.
So he goes up and like scratches at it,
but it's stone so it doesn't really do much of anything.
Oh, but the actions you just did were great.
Like a T-Rex attacking a wall.
Oh, I love it.
Flint, you feel the control come back to your body
and you kind of take a little step
as you see Donnie T-Rex attacking this spire
and Yular attacking the green brain
with Thea's moonbeam still in the room
and the moaning of these zombies
on the other side of the door getting louder and louder
as you can picture in your mind
that there are a lot of them coming in.
I'm going to move in between this pillar
and close to the armor
if I need to make a switch in tactics here.
Yep.
I'm going to swing my axe as hard
as I fucking can at this pillar.
Sure.
The swearing was for emphasis.
Of course.
That is a 24.
24, yeah, you'll hit it.
All right.
Big damage, 20.
Nice.
You strike this spire on the far side there
and it fractures some of the stone
and the glowing in the ruins that are inscribed in it
begins to fade on that side.
It's still bright on the other side,
but it begins to fade.
I'm close enough to get to the other side of it, no?
Yep.
I should be clear.
They're still glowing.
It's just not as bright.
Oh, they're still glowing.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, I'll just remain on that side then
and try and get them to stop glowing.
Shooters.
So it was a 25 on the attack roll.
That will hit, yep.
I would hope so, 16.
You strike in the same spot
and it splinters all the way up,
but seems like it's being held together
as just there's a very dim light
being emitted from the inscriptions on this spire.
Bullshit.
Please leave that extremely long pregnant pause.
Please don't edit that out.
No, yeah, that's fine.
That's good.
Damn it, this is stressful.
These zombies screaming in the next room.
Guys, guys, I have a trick up my sleeve.
I'm very excited about it.
It's not your turn.
Oh, Jesus.
Amy, wait your fucking turn.
It's gonna have to fucking wait, all right?
Okay, fine.
So the green brain is going to-
Murder Thea.
Give your mind thrust on Flint and new Lara there.
Ooh, a double mind thrust.
So you guys have to make a wisdom save.
Okay, it's okay.
No, this one's intelligence, isn't it?
This one's, oh yeah, this one's intelligence.
It's intelligence.
It's intelligence save.
12.
12 as well.
Both of you take full damage.
So on Flint, 11, 14 psychic damage.
Go.
Splitting heads.
It was much worse than the first time.
Yeah, well, roll better.
New Lara, you take seven psychic damage.
Amy, I'm gonna need you to start rolling
Russ's damage rolls for us.
Right?
But that's okay,
because this one doesn't control our brains.
It just gives us damage, and that's fine.
That's true.
I wouldn't want to fight both of you guys.
That would suck a lot.
Because now we can focus on what I think is important,
which is stopping the murderous ward outside.
Oh, and that too.
All right, well, to help with all of this,
I'm going to conjure two minor elementals.
About damn time.
Okay.
They are going to be like earth rock elementals.
Tell me what the rating is for two of them.
Two elemental challenge rating, one or lower.
If you cast things that are one or lower,
you have access to dust methods or mud methods.
What, like, what are they?
Can I look at their stats and their skills?
Sorry, what elemental can I have
at a challenge rating of two?
Gargoyle.
Oh, fuck yeah.
Think maybe one that's really powerful
might be more beneficial than two.
Methods are small, small things.
Two that are little.
So let's go for a gargoyle.
He has a multi-attack bite and claws.
Okay, he needs to be rolled into the initiative roll.
At a nine.
Look at me playing by the rules.
He will go after Flint.
You cast this spell.
Energy kind of pours out into the room and swirls,
and there's a window in this room,
and it bursts open as one of the statues
that you've seen outside of the building
flies into the room,
and you now have this stone gargoyle ready to attack.
Nice.
Hey there, I'm your dungeon master, Russ More.
Thank you for joining us and continuing on this journey
for episode 19 of Dumbgeons and Dragons
titled Battle of the Brains.
As we mentioned already, this episode is early,
and it's for good reason.
Today is the launch day of our Patreon page.
We're very excited and hope that you'll be too.
We are aiming to expand our community,
and in turn, have you more involved with the show and us
as we create more amazing content for you.
I'll link everything in the description,
but our Patreon page is Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
It's easy to sign up
and become a patron for Dumbgeons and Dragons,
and from as little as $1 per month,
you'll have access to all of our Patreon only content,
which will include another show beginning this month.
This new show will be DMed by Tom Laird,
AKA Flint Firebeard,
and we will be giving you a taste of it
with the first episode in two weeks on this channel.
But from then on, it'll be a Patreon only endeavor.
So if you want to hear more,
please check out Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
And this is the first of many games or shows
we're trying to put together,
and we want to hear what you want to hear.
We plan to try out new RPG systems
in hopes that we can create new and interesting stories
in different settings and give you a chance
to hear new game styles and mechanics
that will maybe give you ideas for your own games,
or it might give you a feel for another system
that you've been meaning to try,
but just weren't sure on.
We do have higher tiers, a $5 and a $10 tier,
with more opportunities to be involved with the show,
including show dedications or being named an NPC
or providing questions for a future Q&A episode.
Our hope is that we build a fun
and inclusive community with Dumbgeons and Dragons
that is able to grow and become a huge part
of many people's lives, including yours.
If you can't donate, we totally understand.
But what you can do to help us
is continue spreading the word about Dumbgeons and Dragons
in your everyday life and on social media.
Please click through to our Patreon page,
Patreon.com slash dumbdragoncast.
And if you can and you want to be a part
of the dumb dragon community, we would love to have you.
Our next episode is that special Patreon only preview episode,
which will have a title
by the time it comes out on August 16th, I promise.
Then the next regular episode
will be available August 30th.
Let's get back to the brain brawl
and see if the adventurers have the smarts
to outwit the brains and the horde.
And the horde, don't forget those guys.
Have a great couple of weeks.
Talk to you soon.
Guys, I just got a tiny glimpse of like the side
of Preston's computer and what's going on here.
You can see it on your computer.
Can I?
Oh, if you just scroll down on the map,
it's a full horde of zombies coming at us.
Oh shit, those are scary.
I had nightmares about zombies last night.
Well, it's not my intent to line that up, but you know.
It was really just a prequel of sorts.
Lara, it is your turn as the groaning
sounds like it's getting closer to the door
where you guys are in.
Fuck some shit up.
God, by what you mean.
Hit a stone pillar.
That's exactly what I mean.
Beat the shit out of that inanimate object.
Yep, I'm gonna, I'm gonna do my very, very best.
That is a 21.
On the stone pillar, yeah, 21 will hit her.
Great, 12 damage.
Same kind of thing that Flint saw.
You crack the stone that's making this statue
and the writings begin to fade.
When they fade this time,
it kind of sounds like the zombies themselves,
their groaning fades and then comes back a little bit.
Okay, let me do that again, but better.
Gonna hit that crit 20.
I didn't, but 23.
Yep.
Good enough.
19 damage.
Same kind of thing you saw with Flint's
on his second strike.
It cracks further up.
The writing fades out as well,
but it appears that something is still holding
these statues together.
And same thing happens again.
The groans fade a little bit, but then come back
as you hear footsteps coming closer to the door.
Okay, well, I guess Donny's gonna try
and hit that brain because he won't have any luck
against the stone.
I don't think, or the brain,
because that's an eight.
Poor Donny.
He's not doing so good this time.
So he's just kind of flying around this brain here.
He's kind of freaking out with all those
zombies out there. Yeah, no doubt.
He's having a hard time.
Can't wait till the gargoyle gets to go.
Flint, it's your turn.
And after you hear Nylar striking this other spire,
you hear from out in the courtyard
the cry of the remaining members of the acts of Mirabar
as they engage in battle with the zombies
that are still outside there.
Nice.
But they have arrived on the scene from what you can hear
and they are battling from the other side
of the zombie horde.
And it is your turn.
Okay, now with the pillars, they're still standing,
but they seem less functional than they did before.
Is that correct?
Yeah, the runes, where they were glowing brightly,
they are, the writings are fading.
Okay, I'm going to take another big swing
at the pillar that's in front of me
and try and knock it down.
He came in like a wrecking ball.
That's exactly correct.
So that's a 21.
21 will hit it, yeah.
I mean, don't get me wrong.
I prefer party in the USA,
but wrecking ball works for the themes.
Of course, yes.
The imagery.
All right, oh, it's a one,
but I get to reroll that damage.
Score, 10 and 12 is 22 and four is 26.
Ooh, baby.
This spire crumbles.
It's not being held together by anything anymore
and it falls to the ground in a dusty,
small pebbly shape.
It kind of just disintegrates,
but you still hear the same kind of thing.
The zombies get super quiet,
but then pick back up a little bit.
Okay, I'm going to head on over to the other pillar
and try and knock this one down as well.
That's a 19.
19 is deflected off of the-
Fuck!
I mean, okay.
Off of the shield that appears
to be holding this rune together.
With that strike, you hear what sounds like Torgar
yelling a battle cry,
for Mirabar!
And then there's this explosion
as it sounds like the floor on this level
has crumbled inward and down to the floor below.
And a lot of the sound from the zombies
feels like it has moved somewhere else.
But there are still zombies on the other side of the-
Don't worry, guys, there's still zombies there.
Yeah, don't worry.
Gargoyle.
Okay, the Gargoyle-
Come on, Gargoyle.
It's going to attack the stone pillar
because it seems very important.
So first it's going to bite at it.
22.
22 will bite, yeah.
Go, Gargoyle!
For seven damage.
The pillar crumbles a little bit more,
but it's still standing
and the runes glow a little less brightly,
but still bright.
He's going to do it again, only with his claws.
Okay.
17.
17 will not break through the barrier that is there.
Man.
Greenbrain's turn.
Damn Greenbrain.
Damn Greenbraaaain.
Oh, he's got a theme song?
Yeah, he does now.
He's the last standing brain,
so you got to go out with the glory.
Flint, make a wisdom saving throw.
He's going to try and mindslave you.
Damn it.
Oh, shit!
17.
Okay, you saved.
Oh, he's so disappointed.
Well, I mean, wisdom's my worst one,
but that was a good roll.
Yeah, you're up, Thea.
Hey!
Okay, so I don't really have anything
to hit this pillar with.
What about your Cure Wounds spell?
Do you still have that going on?
I can't do it.
Oh, you already used it?
Yeah, it was a fifth spell slot
and I only have one.
I'm going to Thunderwave the Greenbrain.
What's the range and stuff on your Thunderwave?
I'm going to go over here, 15 feet.
So this would reach him, right?
Yep.
Okay.
So I think you have to make a saving throw
of the Constitution variety.
It's its favorite, seven.
That didn't work.
2d8 Thunder Damage.
On a failed save.
Yeah.
Good.
And it's pushed 10 feet away from you.
Yes, 11.
The wave of force comes out from you
and knocks this Greenbrain into the wall behind you.
Roll a d6.
One!
All right, and it takes an extra one damage.
Ha ha ha!
As is theist style.
You get bonus points for being so happy about it though.
Ha ha ha!
But it appears this one is a little bit,
it's more firmly built
and no cracks have appeared in the glass yet.
Wow, this is good craftsmanship right here.
I know, right?
Well, we didn't even have a crack
in the glass of this one.
No, no, this one.
Guys, once that pillar comes down.
You guys left this one right alone.
Yeah, it was pretty much perfect.
Back to the top of the order
and you hear from outside the door,
it sounds like some of the soldiers
have continued to fight their way up the stairs
and are battling their way through the horde of zombies.
But they are now knocking on the door
and sound like they're right outside.
Jesus.
No, you just moved a whole army of zombies at once.
I know, God.
It just all appeared on my screen.
Like 50 zombies.
So my turn now.
This is like a really cool
thriller dance going on out there.
Yeah, it's awesome.
I don't like it at all.
Ha ha ha!
I don't approve!
No, it's very stressful.
Okay, my turn, yeah?
Yes.
Okay, great.
I'm gonna hit that pillar again.
That is 27.
27 will strike it, yeah.
Okay, 17 damage.
Damn!
You strike this pillar and it,
the same way as the other one, crumbles into dust.
And the sound coming from the other side
of the room stops.
You don't hear any groaning.
And then there's a pause
that seems like it lasts a long time,
but then you hear bodies falling to the floor.
A wave of them.
It's still your turn.
Okay.
Okay, then I am going to,
I guess, attack that green brain.
Yeah.
16.
Probably not gonna hit.
16, no.
Well, hold on.
Yeah, 16 will hit it.
Oh, good.
That means he's out of protective juice.
16 damage.
A crack begins to form in this brain's jar
as you strike it with your sword.
Okay, Donnie's gonna try and get in there a little bit.
Oh my God, Donnie.
That's a six.
I don't think Donnie's- Donnie.
He hasn't rolled higher than like an eight,
I don't think.
One time this time.
Poor guy.
Donnie yells from the side.
He's like, you guys are doing great.
Rah, rah.
You got it.
Way to go.
And Flint, you're up.
All right.
Spurred on by Donnie's excellent cheerleading,
I go take a running start at this green brain
and wind up for a big old swing, the 21.
21 will strike true.
20.
The cracks begin to splinter out
from this green brain's jar
as you knock it across the room
and into the wall, roll a D6.
Oh my God, I haven't had to roll a D6 in a long time.
Three.
And it takes three extra damage,
but it's still floating in the air.
Is it too far away from me or can I make it over there?
You've moved about 10 feet,
so you could probably still make it.
Then the onslaught continues.
And that is a 14, which is probably not gonna do it,
but let's hope that shield is really, really, really down.
14 will hit.
All right.
Yeah.
25.
Yeah, it is.
Wowzers.
I guess when you're a brain in a jar,
you're not that strong.
Oh, shit.
What?
Without the magic, yeah.
The cracks begin to splinter,
and like you've seen before,
the fluid inside begins to ooze out.
And now it is Gargoyle's turn.
All right.
He is going to fly over here
because he can fly 60 feet.
Sweet.
Because I think that's bigger.
Yeah, you're good, you're good.
He's going to first bite at it.
Oh, 12?
12 does not break.
Ooh, he's gonna claw at it.
Oh.
Ah.
Critical miss.
So in this, he flies across,
and maybe you lost some of your,
that's a critical miss.
It's five.
It's a critical miss.
God damn it.
He flies across and kind of bashes into the wall
on his first attempt and misses entirely
as the green brain is nimbly dodging
out of the way of your clumsy, clumsy Gargoyle.
All nimbly bimbly.
Nimbly bimbly.
Oh, nimbly bimbly.
And it's the green brain's turn,
and in a final act is going to cast
Mind Thrust on Flint and Thea.
Ring it.
Wisdom.
Mind Thrust is intelligence.
That was an eight for me,
so I'm taking damage.
You're taking damage.
14.
14 saves, but Flint.
Sorry, I can't count.
It's 15.
Still saves.
Turns out, actually, 15 doesn't save.
Oh, God, but 14 did.
14 was good.
15 is not.
Flint, you are gonna take eight psychic damage
as you feel your brain swell.
Okay.
That eight damage literally would have been
half the amount of points I have.
Oh, no.
So now it's your turn, Thea.
I'm gonna tell my Gargoyle to,
like, just take a knee for a second.
I'm just gonna throw a little Produce Flame.
So, two D, eight.
Seven, and a six, that's 13.
The fluid inside of the jar begins to boil
as you cast Produce Flame onto this jar,
and it erupts outward,
and the fluid just covers Flint.
Payback.
I had it coming.
I had all that splatter earlier.
As the brain sizzles and falls to the ground
and stops throbbing, it is dead.
Wow, I probably should have lit one on fire earlier.
He did liquid in a sealed jar.
Of course that would have exploded it.
God, stupid.
All the brains in the room,
jars have exploded and are dead.
The spires are all crumbled to the ground,
and it sounds like silence on the other side of the door.
Guys, what should we do with this armor?
Can we look out the window that the Gargoyle came in
and see, like, is the Ax of Mirabar out there
just, like, fucking up zombies,
or if the zombies are all just, like,
laying down and the Ax of Mirabar are just, like, huh.
Sure, yeah, it's a little higher up,
but Donnie flies up there,
and he kind of flies out and looks around a little bit,
and he comes back in and he's like,
Garg, well, guys, it looks like all the zombies
are lying down there,
and the Ax of Mirabar looks a little confused,
but nobody's fighting.
Seems okay.
Neat.
And this is where they live now.
God, I guess we open the door
to walk out over the zombies.
She says confidently.
Wow, it seems like a bad idea,
but there is no exit from this room,
so either we have a nap in here with the rotting brains
or we exit through the zombie shop.
Let's grab the cursed armor,
because we don't want this to just happen again.
True.
We should probably destroy this somehow.
But Flint, if you wanna grab that,
because you're all strong and stuff.
Oh, sure, leave it up to the strong guy.
I'm close to death here.
I get on top of my gargoyle.
I put a cloak around the armor before I touch it,
but then I pick it up.
Sure, yeah, you pick it up,
and it just feels like regular armor.
Okay, I open the door.
You see a horde of zombies crumpled and laying flat
on the ground, none of them moving, no noise being made.
Just a sea of undead, dead guys.
Gross, is there a big hole in the floor?
Like when we heard that explosion,
was that like, did it take out part of this level?
You look beyond the main door of the room,
and it looks like the hallway
has caved into the floor below.
Okay, well, this is gross as shit,
because these are all like pieced together creatures, right?
Yep.
Great.
Okay, well, I guess I would like to get out of here.
Friends?
I second that.
Okay. Yup.
So let's get around these hordes of rot monsters
and get to, I guess, the stairs if we can.
Like those would have been on the other side of that door.
I'm not sure what our egress point is here
with a big hole in the ground.
Is there a muster point we could be meeting at?
Yeah, look for the glowing signs.
Where do we go?
You make your way out of the room
and you step over top of the bodies,
and you're trying to be careful,
but of course, there's gonna be some squishing.
Ew.
There's gonna be some gross.
You kind of step as far to the side as you can
so you can walk down to the hall,
and you look down into the caved-in hallway,
and you see Torgar lying motionless
at the bottom of this hole.
No. Aw.
Cause he blowed the place up to kill all those zombies.
I get, I'm still on the back of my gargoyle.
I get my gargoyle to fly me down there
and see if he's still alive.
Sure.
You fly down, it's about a 15-foot drop,
and you go up to check on him,
and he appears to still be breathing.
Can I give him a healing kit?
It's shallow and faint, but he is unconscious.
Will that help him?
Yep.
I have 16 healing kits.
Well, healing kits would bring him back.
You need to give him a potion or a spell.
Oh, shit.
I don't have, ah, ah.
I toss you down a healing potion.
Aw.
So I give it to him.
Oh, wait, I have a cure wounds.
Do you still have spell slots available there?
I do, I have two spell slots available for cure wounds.
Okay.
That works better, then.
Wanna walk me through. I don't know if it does.
Roll play through what you see and what you do?
I'm sure.
I go down and I see poor tour guard lying there,
and I touch him with my hand,
and he gets 15 points back.
You cast this on him,
and some of the energy comes back into his body,
and his eyes flutter open as he looks up at you,
and he says, still not a huge fan of you, but thank you.
I send my gargoyle up to get, ah, Nularaaa at least.
I'm not sure how heavy you are, Flint.
You're small though.
I'm stout.
I am stout.
The gargoyle is a medium creature, so I don't know.
You guys could probably,
you guys could probably jump down.
Oh, there you go.
me down somehow. Okay, we're making our way down then. Does Torgar need, like, do we need
to carry him? Thea, do we need to carry you? Are you still on your gargoyle? Like, are
you cool? I'm alright, I'm on my gargoyle. I'll take a long rest. Torgar appears to
be quite badly beaten up, but you help him to his feet and he's still able to
walk from the building. You guys head out through the hall and out the front door
of the castle you're in, and there's just a sea of these undead creatures that have
all collapsed as the remaining members of the Ax of Mirabar look like they're
kind of like, well, shit, now we've got to clean this up. But Torgar, you guys
get out into the daylight and Torgar says, well, I don't know why this was
here, but you guys are, you guys are good, you guys are good fighters, and without you
guys, I mean, we would have all been turned, and who knows what would have
happened after that. We've got a lot of cleaning up to do, but I want to,
for the Ax of Mirabar, commit us to help you when you need it. We'll have
some rebuilding to do, but if you ever need anything, you can call on us.
Thanks.
Sounds like a good plan.
Says, I need a nap and to clean up some gross, gross stuff.
Yeah, we're all covered in brain goo, so right behind you.
We need a drink.
Yeah, we need a bath and a drink maybe at the same time.
Says, so you know where to find me, so I'm gonna go home and then figure
out what to do with this, and he kind of takes himself from your hold and
straightens himself up and begins to walk off and give directions and
orders to the remaining members of the Ax of Mirabar.
Wasn't there a river or something?
There is a river. Yeah, the River of Marar.
I don't even care about a bed.
Like, I want to get clean and go to sleep.
Like, I am happy to camp out.
We've done it many times before because I feel like everything in this town is
just like covered with rot zombies now.
To the river.
Just like the old days, guys, we'll camp out.
You decide to head out of the city and down to the River Marar to find a place
to set up camp and get cleaned up before moving on.
You leave the walls of the stronghold and you see Osric, pretty badly beaten,
covered in drying zombie matter, and he is working with many members of the
Ax of Mirabar who are tossing zombie parts onto carts to be carried away.
Somewhere. Not sure yet.
As you make your way further through the streets and closer to the edge of
town, you see more members of the Ax of Mirabar coming out of cellars that
look reminiscent of bunkers with civilians who are squint-eyed and
climbing out into the daylight.
Among those civilians, you catch a glimpse of Bahran and Sasha and many
of the other members of Little Rock.
They see you and recognize from the brain goo all over you that you have been
part of saving yet another city and Bahran gives a nod and helps some of
the children along the street.
You make your way beyond the wall and down to the river.
And for a city that is covered in mayhem, it surprisingly seems peaceful
by the side of the river.
There are no bodies.
The birds are chirping and a gentle breeze is blowing through.
You clean up, lie down, and all of you drift off to sleep.
A few hours later, you wake up naturally, a little more rested than
before, and ready to head off on the next part of your adventure.
Where do you go?
I think we have to go back and see what's her name there, Makkath,
in Luskin because we're going to go try and find out about Bort and
getting him sorted out, correct?
Yeah.
Oh, hey.
And, you know, big, big bad dragon thing that happened?
We also should try and tell Salazar that we're alive.
Oh, yeah.
So I pull out the fantasy walkie talkie and we remember how to use it, right?
We just press the button and say, Salazar, are you there?
There's a bit of a break, but then it comes back in.
He says, yeah, yeah, what's going on?
Well, the good news is the zombies are all dead.
The bad news is Primsbane, we didn't get him.
You get away?
Yeah, he opened a portal and escaped.
And this whole town just like covered with rotten, disgusting zombies now.
So like of the homemade variety, arms, legs, different creatures.
Oh, that's pretty shitty.
I hate portals.
OK, we will send a cleanup crew to help the people out there.
Are you guys OK?
You've made it out?
Doing all right?
We're fine.
We'll be fine.
All right, I had every faith that you guys were going to handle it.
Just fine.
Good.
Well, all right, I'm glad to hear things are going all right.
If you need anything, you just give me a holler.
Okie dokie, over and out.
Well, I say we probably go visit Macoth first and see what we can do about Bort.
Who's been eerily quiet?
We came to an understanding, if you remember.
See if the Arcane Brotherhood wants to help us out, right?
So we'll go back and see Macoth.
Are you guys taking the road or are you taking the river?
I guess, is it downriver from where we are?
Yep.
Let's take the river.
River sounds nice.
You begin down the river and you find an abandoned riverboat not far from where you set up camp.
You climb aboard and you get your bearings.
You manage to get it floating on the river back towards Luskin.
As you travel down the river through the open plains, what was lush and green as
you cast away from Mirabar slowly turns dead and barren.
Large swaths of the land burnt to the ground.
You recall the last time you passed through these lands with the town members of Little Rock,
three plus weeks ago, that it was not this way at all.
Certain areas have been torched.
Others look like the life energy was sapped from the ground itself.
Takes you about a day of travel to get about three quarters of the way to Luskin.
You see ahead a large lush forest that now stands out like a sore thumb in the land of devastation.
At the edge of the forest you see a bridge that looks to be blocking the river
and on that bridge stands a single knoll.
As your boat drifts forward, the knoll calls out to you.
You're going to pay a toll to get by.
Boys, we got company.
And out from the bushes step three more knolls, two with spears, one with a flaming torch.
They walk into the middle of the bridge and all are staring at you.
As you hear a thunderous crash, as something takes what you can only assume is an enormous
lumbering step through the surrounding trees.
Elsewhere you see a torch lit dungeon.
Rats scurrying from the light.
There is a man hanging from the wall suspended by chains clamped around his arms.
You can't see his face yet.
A thick wooden door opens and in walks Thelonious Primsbane,
dressed in seemingly royal robes and he slowly enters the room,
his footsteps barely making a sound.
He walks over to the man suspended on the wall and lifts his head.
You can now see that this man is Leonin Glorygem of the Iron Fist of the Dawn.
Thelonious chuckles.
You'll be glad to know your friends didn't even ask about you.
It doesn't look like they are coming for you anytime soon.
They may have stopped me this time, but once I make you into the true warrior you can be
and raise an army in your image, I will be unstoppable.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
So there's stuff in it for what?
I think it's going to be a starter set.
That is that what I said?
It sounded like a starter set to a life.
He's going to swing into the house.
I like the Dumbgeons and Dragons starter set.
I think Amy is fucking ruthless.
It's going to be a good day.
Good day.
I have a headache.
I don't like it when Russ has to like plan things out
because I have a feeling that bad things are coming.
He's thinking so much.
I feel like he's very unprepared right now.
There's a lot of typing happening.
They're looking through books.
He's flipping pages.
Let me see the player's handbook.
Yes.
We need some sort of super montage of Russ doing research in order to kill us in D&D.
Yep.
He's in a dingy journalism office.
He's got papers everywhere.
There's probably some sort of cork board on the back
with a map and all these pictures connecting with yarn.
He's learning the Dewey Decimal system
so he can know how to find things in the library.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.