previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Grug, do you know where the Lonely Whip is?
We'll have to look around. Maybe something will jog my memory.
You enter the Lonely Whip. It smells like drunk.
One man does stand out to you though.
A possible knight of the Order of the Gauntlet.
Hey friend, whatcha drinking?
I'm sorry, I have to be going.
I try to stop him.
He manages to slide you off.
Fine, we're just gonna follow you then.
Alright, mom, my ride's leaving. I gotta go.
Grug, you coming?
Oh yeah, yep.
You need to stop following me.
And he pulls his greatsword and runs at Thea.
Donny stings him and he utters the single word, succubus.
Alright, so we gotta kill this thing dead.
You crash in the door.
Demon! Demon!
Face me!
I think we better go in as well.
Everybody in their mind hears a voice.
Your efforts have been thwarted time and time again by my helpers.
You see a winged, beautiful creature.
And I say, listen here, bitch.
I cast Sunbeam.
God damn it!
And then I'm gonna cast Lightning Bolt.
Her wings are fried and she drops to the ground,
but she begins to phase out.
I raise up my hand in a prohibitive manner and I say,
Halt!
And it doesn't work and so I just get like a little bit sad.
And just kind of stare at my feet.
We know your plans.
Did we kill the thing?
Yeah, what happened out here?
She ran scared.
Oh, she's got some plans against you.
It's good you're making enemies.
It means you're doing something right.
I think.
Rug steps back up to the stage and plays you a ditty on the way out as we fade out.
Don't you go.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We are D&D 5th Edition Actual Play Podcast
and I'm your dungeon master Russ More
and with me today is Tom Laird.
Oh, hey, that's me.
Surprise second billing today.
Usually it's Amy, but glad to be here guys.
I play Flint Firebeard.
Well, you are about to chew something.
So I threw it to you.
It's true. It was great timing on your part.
Yep.
And Carla Johnson.
That is me.
I play Nularaaaa Moonbrook.
And Amy More.
I can't believe I was replaced by Tom.
Yeah.
I play Thea Amastasia.
Hello, everybody.
Hello.
No, Amy's all despondent now.
I just don't feel as loved as I usually am.
I mix it up every now and again.
You can't be second all the time.
Sometimes I can be first.
Oh, now we're getting to the heart of the matter.
Now we're getting to the heart.
You can DM the second episode.
I don't want to.
Give me your notes that I won't be able to read.
And no, thank you.
Yeah, Russ, if you had like clear printing,
maybe it would be possible for someone else.
But oh, boy, that chicken's ratchet.
He's like, I want to make sure that no one can take over for me.
Well, it's not even just that.
You know, it's the glance across the table at the book
and see what's coming up.
You just want to avoid all of that, if possible.
Are you calling me a cheater?
I sounded like he was calling you a cheater.
I didn't say it was an intentional glance.
I merely said it was a glance.
Oh, I'm an accidental cheater.
Oh, I see how it is.
Yeah.
So with that note, we're on Patreon.
Russ is going to need money for a divorce lawyer.
Yeah, Russ is definitely going to need to buy me something pretty.
Yeah.
What's that level that we should set that at?
Russ and Amy get a divorce.
Oh, boy.
A certain level.
But we can now.
So that's the point, right?
We can afford it.
OK, then.
It's got a dark profile.
Yeah, yeah.
This episode is dedicated to one of our lucky patrons,
because that's what you get when you're a patron,
is you get an episode dedicated to you.
And this one about divorce talk goes to our good patron,
Nathan Donahue.
Nathan.
We'll try and make it a bit more upbeat from now on.
For sure.
And Nathan, I just want you to know it's not your fault.
It's not your fault.
Everyone loves you very much.
And we won't stop loving you.
There's nothing you could have done.
Yeah.
So we're going to move right along from that.
Patreon, Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast,
if you want to go check it out for yourself.
We have rejigged the tiers there a little bit.
So we've got some new things going on that you can go
check out and get some great rewards, including Tom's one
shot.
That was pretty awesome.
That just finished up last month.
Timing of everything.
Yep.
And the new one that starts right now probably or soon
hereafter.
Dates.
Dates are good.
I didn't look at a calendar beforehand.
Also, there's 11 episodes of my quote unquote one shot.
So yeah, we can't call it a one shot.
Play the tape back, Russ.
Play it back.
Oh, I know.
I know exactly what I said.
Not a one shot.
An 11 shot.
Yeah, Tom's Ark is what the word I was looking for.
Yes, it was super fun.
Hopefully, if you do sign up, you enjoy the hell out of it.
You will, I'm saying.
I'm saying you will enjoy the hell out of it.
Carla's landed down.
You will enjoy it.
Yeah.
So go check that out.
We've got a new one starting up.
Oh, fuck.
I just looked at the calendar.
We've got a new one.
It's already started.
We're playing fake core.
We're an RPG podcast over there.
Not just a Dumbgeons and Dragons podcast.
Doing new crazy things.
So go check that out.
We know stuff.
We know all the things.
And everybody is great and awesome.
Yes.
Now we're getting to the love part of the podcast.
Right?
Fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
Yeah.
Tom didn't talk over me this time.
That was good.
It's got to keep you guessing.
It made me laugh a lot when I listened to the episode
where I did do that.
You guys have just finished partying hard
with your good friend, Grug.
That was awesome.
And you wake up in your respective rooms.
What are you doing there?
Let's start with new Laura.
Well, big day today for me and for Donnie
because I think things are about to get starting rolling
big adventure-wise, big dragon fighting-wise,
even more than they already have been.
Sure.
So Donnie is going to put on his Caller
of Evolution, which means he is no longer
going to be a pseudo dragon.
He is going to be a gold dragon Wormling,
which means he is a straight-up badass.
You're going to need a bigger backpack.
Yeah, he definitely will not be backpack-sized anymore.
He's very powerful and can do lots of cool things
wonderful to be announced.
But yeah, I think this morning before we go,
kind of talk to the council and get things going,
we'll eat some breakfast and I'll put that Caller on him
and he'll have his new flashy form
for the rest of the adventure.
So Donnie, this is it.
Are you ready?
This is going to change a lot.
Not who you are, you know, deep down,
but certainly appearance-wise and let's say strength-wise.
Are you ready?
No, you know, I've been feeling like I've been just
like a big dragon in a little dragon shell here.
So really, I think this is where we need to be.
So yeah, hook me up.
Hold on.
I'm not going to blow the roof off this place, am I?
I don't think so.
I think you'll be OK.
You're going to have some new,
let's say, breath-focused skills.
So maybe try and keep that under control.
Well, I make no guarantees, but you know how it is.
Sometimes you just have to use your breath.
That is the saying.
OK, are you ready?
Let's do this.
Let her rip.
OK, so I come over to it and he's so little.
He's just like the size of like a cat right now.
And I put on the collar and he gets like big, like not
dragon big, but like medium sized creature big,
which is like way bigger than he was, right?
Like that's like human size.
He's like 10 times the size he was or something.
It's pretty dramatic.
So yeah, you put the collar on
and like a magical energy swirls around him
and he begins increasing in size
and a golden shimmer comes from this energy.
And he, yeah, grows to about the size of a human.
And he's standing there and he says,
Holy shit, you got a mirror or something?
I can see my beautiful self.
I guess is there like a mirror in the?
Sure. Yeah, there's a mirror there.
Sure.
Or some, yeah.
Seems like Nularaaa is not like so into that,
but I'm sure there's like mirror comes like standard issue
in one of these kind of bunk kind of rooms.
You know, sure.
There's a thing.
So yeah, I guess I point towards the mirror
and he like smooth, I was going to say waddles over,
but that's insulting.
He smoothly walks over like the cool beautiful dude he is.
If you could put some like tuba music in the background
as he waddles for us.
Yeah, you got it.
Yeah, he glides over and is like, you know what?
I'm a damn fine good.
I mean, I was good looking before as far as pseudo dragons
go, but who doggy look out Lady Dragons.
Donnie's on the town.
Flint, what are you doing as you wake up in your,
in your, you're probably not super hungover.
You're a dwarf, but you know,
you're you're groggy from the night before.
Got a pretty hearty constitution.
I bounce back quick.
Yeah, I take a look in the mirror
and look at the blue dragon scales
that are getting a little bit bigger on the old chest.
Yeah, you walk over and you look,
you don't even really need a mirror or whatever you do.
You see that they've, they haven't grown much higher.
They haven't grown much higher towards your neck,
but they're beginning to spread down to your side.
Yeah, which is nice.
They haven't grown up because I like to wear a deep V
on occasion, so it's real good
that they haven't been creeping up there yet.
You hear Bort in your mind and he's like,
yeah, I know I've been noticing you've been trying
to get those deep V's, so I've been trying
to hold it back as much as I can from that area.
I appreciate that a lot.
Yeah, but yeah, you see it's kind of grown around
and it's starting to move around your right side,
the rib cage there.
And you even notice a little bit beginning to go kind
of into your arm, like armpit
into your right bicep there, Bort says.
So we haven't told everybody yet.
I know we've only, you know, not been wearing underwear
once, but I feel like the old difficulty level
on that, keeping that one in the bag is wearing thin,
my friend.
Yeah, I kind of figured
when I saw more of the scales that that was going
to be like, dude, do you know how long like I have
until we kind of like, till this gets worse?
Again, not entirely sure how quickly the transformation,
some it's been very quick.
You appear to have a much higher will
to fight it than others.
So I'd put us at a couple months tops
for a complete transformation wherein I am you
and you are me at this point.
I sure hope that my friends wrote down everything
I need to to fix this because I can't remember it.
I'm sure if you sure if you asked your your dungeon
master nice enough, he would probably reiterate.
Okay, I'll keep that in mind.
Sounds good.
Do you do anything else?
Maybe what do you what do you do preparing?
Because you're going to meet the council next.
I would like to did I order some room service
because that seems like something I would have done.
Sure.
Yeah.
Excellent.
What's what's what's the in known for?
What's his specialty?
Their specialty is eggs eggs eggs.
Okay, baconator Benedict.
Oh dear this I'm going to need all the details
on this baconator eggs baconator Benedict eggs
bake eggs bacon.
Maybe not baconator eggs.
Mega bacon is it because it's trademarked by Wendy's.
We can't use it.
Eggs mega bacon addict.
Oh dear.
This sounds deadly.
Yeah, so it's got your it's got your your standard standards,
you know, maybe it's a scone.
We got going on the bottom there.
Nice scone layer of bacon crosshatched naturally a perfectly
poached egg to your liking soft medium or firm medium
all the way.
There you go.
And then topped with the house specialty hollandaise
and a sprinkle of chive.
Oh, it's a delightful twist.
Isn't it isn't it?
And as I power through this whatever you said,
it was I can't remember the name now because I'm fixated
on the other word.
This trademarked eggs baconator baconator mega bacon addict.
I look in the mirror and I say well,
if the scales won't kill me this sure will and I pound
it on back here here save one of those for me
when we switch we swap sees will do bud.
So Thea your your next stop is likely the Council.
Everybody's just kind of getting ready for the day.
What is Thea do?
See wakes up and rolls over and all fluffy next to her
is her big owl guacamole at some drunken point last
night.
She called guacamole out and they snuggle buddied it up.
No, yeah, she woke up in a fluff of white feathers
and she looks over beside the side of the bed
and there are empty mugs of ale on her side and like a
whole lot of dead mice and a couple of dead rabbits
on the side of guacamole's bed and she kind of like
makes a face but scratches guacamole's belly and lets
out a little owl trill or hoot or whatever happy
owls make kind of like that and Thea kind of rolls over
but guacamole is like super smart and kind of looks
out and sees that the Sun is rising and kind of
nudges Thea and I'm like she's like there's five
more minutes.
I get nudged out of the bed and start to get
dressed for the day.
You get dressed and all up and ready and do you
transform guacamole back or is she staying around?
She's going to walk around behind me for a little
while.
Giant owls can fit through doors.
Can they?
Sure.
Yeah, absolutely they can and you head down the
stairs and you're out front of the building and
you see Nulara and Flint are standing outside
and behind Nulara is a I mean not giant but
you would expect to see Donnie so therefore a
giant gold dragon Wormling standing behind her.
Thea kind of skips up with guacamole following
close behind.
Who's your handsome buddy?
It's me.
Donnie?
Yeah, you didn't recognize the eyes.
I look close into his eyes and yes, that is
you Donnie.
What?
Oh, you put your fancy collar on because
I remember because I was there when he got it.
Yeah, I was going to be like,
where did you get that?
No, that's amazing.
Does he still maintain his like telepathic-ness?
He does I assume just because that's who he
is, but he also now can speak draconic,
which I believe you also speak.
Oh, I speak a little draconic.
He says, no draconic doesn't talk like that.
Yeah, Russ, geez, get it together.
Amy speaks it, but I don't want to right now.
And Flint is just walking around like in awe
looking at Donnie like over from every angle
and just like looking back at Nulara and then
back at Donnie and back at Nulara.
He's just blown away by this.
Guacamole hops up to Donnie.
Are they similar in size now?
Guacamole is probably still bigger.
She gives him a nuzzle anyway.
Sure.
Like she knew.
What do you do?
I think we need to go and alert the council
about this fucking messed up succubus bitch
as well as what we think might be happening
with those.
She might be connected to those suicide murder
suicides.
I'm not sure.
You're fairly certain that she is the cause
of the murder.
Well, we should go and tell someone of authority
about that and maybe they can do something.
And we haven't talked to them like since we
talked to the Dragons, right?
This is true.
Yeah.
The last time you went there, it was before
the Dragons and before the Misty Forest.
So that was the last kind of set out and do
point that you would have talked to any of them.
You all head to the council.
You head right to the council chambers.
Do you go try and check in with Leosin?
Where do you go?
I don't know.
It might seem like a professional courtesy
to go check in with him.
You walk by Leosin's chambers.
The door is open and you poke your head in there.
And he's seated at his desk looking down,
scrawling some notes into a big ledger
that he has there.
He doesn't notice you kind of step up there.
Can we do like a real cool guy knock on the door?
Yeah.
How does it sound?
I love that that's your cool guy knock.
Yeah, that's right.
Yep.
That is the coolest guy knock.
Right.
He looks up.
He has kind of a, well, he has a tired
look on his face.
Like he's been dealing with a lot of stuff
perhaps, but he smiles a little bit when he
sees you and he says, good to see you, my friends.
It's been a while since your last visit.
A few weeks, a couple weeks.
I don't even know.
So much has happened.
You've dealt with the Misty Forest and the Dragon Council?
Yes.
Yep.
We checked both those off our list.
It's a good time.
And you have a large dragon and owl behind you?
Yes?
Yes.
Yep.
Okay.
This is just Donnie.
Not hallucinating.
Oh.
This is just Donnie.
Really?
New and improved.
Yeah, it's just me, bud.
Don't worry about it.
Okay.
Well, if you're not worried about it,
I'm not worried about it.
It's okay.
Everybody is actually in the council right now.
I don't know where to start with the news
that we have going on.
The Cult of the Dragon has been expanding rapidly.
Everyone is hesitant to move forward until you return.
So thankfully, you've returned today
and hopefully can light some fires under their butts,
so to speak.
I love lighting fire.
I knew you do.
That's why I used that one.
It's for you.
You know me so well, yes.
I can walk you down there if you'd like
or if you have any questions for me prior,
please, please, please ask.
You get enough sleep, buddy?
No.
When the Cult of the Dragon is trying to take over the world,
it makes it kind of difficult to get a good night's rest.
You should really work on that.
It's important.
You know, you take care of you so you can take care of others.
Of course.
I will take that into consideration tonight.
Thank you.
Is there anyone that's going to give us
any pushback on the council these days?
The last time you were here, everyone
seemed to have their own opinion.
This time, I feel like you will be more in the driver's
seat.
You have not heard us speak publicly for a while, then.
They will have information for you
as to what has been going on
and possibly where to send you next,
but I think they're more concerned
with the reinforcements from the Dragon Council,
if that has gone well, and what of the Misty Forest.
All right, let's drop some news bombs on these peeps.
Let's go.
He leads you down the hallway that you've
walked down a few times.
And normally, the doors are closed
and you hear like a rumble of argument and chaos
behind these doors, at least the last time you came.
This time, the doors are open a crack
and it seems quiet.
It seems almost silent.
You hear a few stirs of chairs and you
enter and beyond the doors, you
see the council all seemingly silent in thought,
kind of looking off into different corners
and not entirely all there, but Leosin
makes a little rap on the door.
Well, this is the story.
Does a cool guy knock like Flint does.
Yeah.
Everyone, as if jarred from whatever stupor
they were in, look up and you
see a bit of relief wash over their face
as you enter the room.
Leosin makes the announcement that you have all returned
and have news from the previous missions
that you were sent on and says,
I will leave you to it.
If you need anything from me before you leave,
please swing on by.
And Lady Laryl Silverhand ushers you to sit
at some empty chairs at the table there
and she says, dear adventurers,
it is good to see you back.
What can you tell us of your journeys?
We went to the Misty Forest and we found Narenvain.
Is King Melandric there?
Yes, King Melandric is there
and he sits up and he says, yes, you found my son?
Oh yeah, I don't know if you want to call him that anymore.
That bastard's riding around on a green dragon
destroying elven villages.
You see a rage well up inside.
He was angry the last time with just
about everybody who was in the room.
But this time you see just this silent,
seething anger and his pale compLexion
grows a bright fiery red and he says,
so he's with the cult of the dragon?
Yes.
I mean, to be a hundred percent honest with you,
I'm not sure if he's with the cult or not,
but he's definitely with a dragon named Cuth
and they're laying some shit down on people.
Oh, I have a journal.
Go for it.
Okay, I pull out of my regular bag,
not of holding, but it does hold things.
My bag of hold things.
Oh, yeah.
And I walk over to King Melandric
and I place the journal in front of him
and I say, do not take our word for it.
See for yourself.
Read for yourself.
Sure.
Take a look at this.
Check this out.
You see him hold his hand on the book
and then skim past a few pages
and he, as you look,
you see some of the pages that you have read
where he's mentioned that in fact,
the dragon mask that he had is at the well of the dragons
and that the cult of the dragon steps towards
becoming the power that it needs to be
or the pieces are being put into place
and the red in his face begins to fade
to more of an ashen gray
and he just looks sick.
I tentatively and then firmly lay a hand on his shoulder
and I say, I'm sorry.
It is not your fault.
Thank you though.
My son disappeared.
Let's be honest.
He was exiled a long time ago.
He didn't disappear.
Yeah, we kind of figured.
But this and you see him flip past more pages
talking about King Melandric
and how he's thought less upon by Naren Vane
and how he's a poor old man.
You see different phrases skim by
and how he's going to be taught a lesson
and he shakes his head and slams the book shut
and he says, I could not have seen this coming
and I mean, there were signs that he was not
all we expected of him.
But we hoped, hoped for more.
Hey there.
I'm your Dungeon Master, Russ More.
Thank you so much for joining us for episode 45
of Dumbgeons and Dragons titled
The Perception of the Guild.
If you haven't checked out our Patreon community recently
I invite you to go give it a look today
as we've added a ton of new ongoing content
for our patrons, switched up some of the tiers
and added new goals to work towards as a community.
A big congratulations to our patron, Nathan Donahue
who won our second goal giveaway
which was two D&D 5e books of Nathan's choosing
which had been shipped directly to him
all the way in Australia.
Now Nathan chose to keep it a surprise
as to what we were sending him
but we'll make sure he posts them online
when they arrive so everyone can participate in the fun.
Let's just say they'll add a whole ton of new stuff
to Nathan's games
and they are two of my favorite books right now for planning.
So if you can and you want to directly support the show
just visit Patreon.com slash dumb dragon cast
and you can see all the tiers and rewards
and we really hope to see you over there.
If you can't support us on Patreon, we totally understand
and definitely don't want anyone to feel left out.
We get it.
If you like what we're doing
and you want to support us in other ways
the best way to do that is to share a link to the show
and talk about us on social media.
We're on Facebook, Twitter and Instagram
which is where you can link your friends, family
or random internet folks
that you meet and chat with every day.
Ordemouth is really one of the greatest ways
to get the show out to the masses.
So thank you for doing that.
Speaking of which all of our social media links
can be found at dumbdragons.com.
So go check out the website and join follow
or like where you can today.
And thanks to Sirenscape
for some of the amazing atmosphere and music.
Make sure you check them out at sirenscape.com
to bring your games to life.
Links for everything mentioned today
can be found in the description below.
The next episode will be out July 25th.
It's time to get back to the council session though
and figure out what is happening
and where the adventures could be off to next.
Have a great week.
We'll talk soon.
Lady Laral Silverhand,
she pipes up and she says,
I'm sorry you have ridded the misty forest of Kuth
and Nerenvane?
Well, we drove them out of Kuth's lair.
We're not sure where they are now.
They were too strong for us to defeat
even with the help of Delaine and Laskat.
They were too powerful for us.
Yes, Delaine has been seen back in the city.
He has not yet returned to the council.
We weren't sure why,
but that could have something to do with it.
Perhaps he himself is on the hunt.
I don't know.
I guess the more pressing matter,
the Dragon Council.
What of your meeting with the council
of the metallic dragons?
Do you want the short answer or the long answer?
Well, I guess will they help us?
They will,
but they've made demands
that will need to be met before they will help.
And if I may say, they're not unreasonable demands.
What are their demands?
And you see some of the other members
kind of stirring in their seats a little bit.
Reparations, for the most part.
People of our kind have been not kind to them.
Our history is terrible,
but the elven history specifically
and what we have done to the dragon kind
is inexcusable.
However, they are willing to help us
if a formal apology is given from you,
King Melandric.
From me, for what?
For what she just said.
Listen to her.
Jesus Christ, right?
The Drakorg mythal,
all dragons made agitated and turned to beasts.
That was the gold dragon pro-tanther
that is looking for this apology.
And if we give this apology,
they will help us.
The gold dragons will help us.
Just the gold.
This is the demand from the gold dragons.
And I think an apology
for the help that they can give us
is a very, very small price to pay.
You're right.
We pressed our luck long enough
against the cult of the dragon
and we need all the help we can get.
I will give them their apology.
I will make arrangements and do so.
Thank you.
You look around the room
and this is the fullest the room has ever been.
There are a couple new faces in the room as well.
You look to the right of Lord Dagglet,
Never Ember and you see a female tiefling
sitting quietly to his right
who you remember seeing
at the very first council session you were ever at.
And she was very much very similar
sitting quietly to herself.
You also see the ambassador from Mithril Hall,
Ambassador Conrad Braunenville,
sitting at the table
and he hasn't been to any council sessions
prior to this one.
Also in this room, you see another new face,
an older man dressed in very luxurious robes.
Delaine is not there,
but Remilia Haven Tree of the Harpers is there.
Anthaar Frum is there.
And then the rest of the Lord's Alliance is also there.
King Melandric, Sir Istival
and everybody else who you already know,
Lady Leral Silverhand and that's all.
Is that dwarf that's there,
by incredible dwarven coincidence,
happen to be the one that Flint knows from Mithril Hall?
So that'd be amazing.
I do believe so.
I mean, yeah.
Yeah, that's the one.
He is the ambassador.
Good old Kenneth Branagh.
Kenneth Branagh?
I love that guy.
He's good in everything.
He's very good.
Flint turns toward Conrad Braunenville
and he says,
the Silver Dragons agreed to help us
if we're able to get back something of theirs.
And he's not really kind of looking at you directly,
but turns when nobody else responds
and you mean us.
Yeah, Braunenville, I'm talking to you.
Keep up, over here.
Over here, bud, over here.
All right, all right.
Yep, yep, okay.
What do we got?
We got gold.
We got...
Oh, it's not quite anything like that.
The Silver Dragon, oh, to really a Karnos.
Well, turns out we didn't treat her niece so well.
We kind of killed her and made her into a suit of armor
and they're not very happy about that,
but they're willing to help us
and let some bygones be bygones
if we're able to return the armor to them.
Yeah, we made a suit of armor out of a dragon
and they got a problem with that.
Look, I mean, we only killed dragons
if they were mucking with our stuff.
I don't think they're too concerned
about why it happened, just that it did happen,
but they're willing to forgive provided we return the armor.
And you see kind of every other person in the room
look to Braunenville with a look of like,
just shut up and do it.
And he kind of, he takes the hint
and he's like, all right, I'll, yeah,
we got to return the armor and say we're sorry.
Okay, and then we're good.
That's it, we're good.
Otorillia Karno said we'll be good after that.
All right.
Yeah, yeah, I can make that happen.
Silver dragon armor.
Yeah, not going to be happy to see that one go,
but okay, I get it, I get it.
There were of course three other dragons at the council.
The good news is one has made no further demands of us.
That's-
So good news first.
Much easier to deal with.
Good news first.
Couple things though that are still being looked for
and this is more perhaps to everyone,
not specifically to one race,
but the brass dragon, the Luthora,
they'd like the masks returned.
When the battle is done and we've defeated the cult,
they want those dragon masks back.
There's a bit of silence over the whole room as you say that
and Lady Silverhand,
she speaks up first and she says we need to win first
before we can deal with who is to deal with the masks.
If we are successful then there is something,
there's room to bargain with them
for perhaps protection from these masks ever again.
I don't really think it was negotiable.
I don't think it was negotiable
nor was it made as a threat.
They don't want the masks back to harm us.
They could harm us whenever they want.
They want the masks back because they belong to dragons
and we've taken them.
Of course, I see no issue in working with them
to make sure they're kept safe
and it could even be in their hands.
So yes, we will make that concession
so long as we receive the protection
of the metallic dragons
which we desperately need at this point.
And our final demand we've been asked to return to you
with comes from the copper dragon, Tazmakala,
who wants our promise that this will be the only time
we call upon them.
They will fight with us for one war, but only one war.
They don't want to start a series of never-ending conflicts.
This is it.
They will fight.
They will help us defeat the cult and then that's it.
Well, honestly, I hope it never gets to a point
where we need to call on them.
So yes, we will deal with this one instance
and that will be that.
We will go our separate ways.
Flint shoots a look at Nularaaaa and he's kind of like,
hey, I think we're fucking doing this.
And you look around the room and you kind of see
some people are less happy about the arrangements
that have been made, but nobody seems to be jumping up
to say, hey, we shouldn't fucking do this.
Everybody seems to be in agreement
that what needs to happen are these things
to make sure that they have the dragon,
the metallic dragons on their side.
You at this point seemingly have sold them
on the metallic dragons demands, so to speak,
for lack of a better term.
Perfect.
Lady Silverhand with that speaks up and says,
we will make sure that arrangements are made
to return the items that they are in need of
and to make sure all things have been met.
And have you, in your travels,
have you seen much resistance from the cults?
Have you seen or heard tales of what we've been hearing?
Like they've been expanding is what we've been hearing
and the amount of people showing up in Waterdeep
and in Baldur's Gate and even farther north
up into Neverwinter.
It doesn't sound like it's looking good.
Well, we just got back to town last night
and it seems like shit's pretty bad here in town.
Also, we did hear from a bard about some local
resistance cells that are cropping up here and there.
So that's at least somewhat promising.
She says, yes, yes, yes.
And she reaches into her to a sash
and pulls out a piece of parchment
and lays it on the table and on the table
is a symbol of a sword and an axe
crossed with the eyes of an owl over top.
And she says, is this what you speak of?
Yeah, yeah, that's the symbol we were shown.
This is many people's, from what I gather,
many people's symbol of hope now.
And it would be, it would take a blind person
not to see it, but you three are that symbol.
How does that rest with you?
Oh, well, I feel good about it.
I do. I mean, were we qualified
when we took this job?
No.
That is an understatement and an app.
Are we qualified now?
Still no.
No.
But this war isn't going to be won by a select few.
It has to be won with everyone coming together.
And if they need a symbol in order to do that,
well then, fuck yeah.
I'm into being part of that symbol.
And you all are of this belief and stance?
I think Thea's right.
Symbols are powerful and important.
It doesn't matter that we are perhaps not the heroes
that people think we are.
If it motivates them to help and to fight,
then that's enough.
And Flint clasps Thea on the shoulder and he says,
yeah, she pretty much nailed it.
I feel that way too.
Guacamole kind of wanders over
and looks at the piece of paper
and sees the owl eye staring back at her
and looks at me and looks at the paper
and looks at me and just pet her.
In her head, she's like,
I'm the one saving the world.
What are you doing?
She's like, I don't know why my eyes are on here.
You never let me out.
With that, the doors to the council chambers burst open
and followed by two guards,
a young squire come rushing in
and he's waving a piece of paper
and he's very out of breath.
And he says, I come with news
of stopping the Cult of the Dragon.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin MacLeod
of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
Don't lick, don't lick, don't lick.
Russ, control yourself.
It's not me, it's the surgery dog.
I will put a clone on you.
Remember what Bort sounds like?
He's probably just some sort of old man.
The default Russ voice.
You see the council all seated around the large table
and they are all snoring.
You heard the dog there.
That's so loud.
Well, let's start at the beginning, I guess, which is...
So we went to Russ and Amy's to play D&D the first time.
It was years ago now.
That was what, like three to four years?
It's a while ago.
Yeah.
Mistakes were made and now we're here.
Paisley, stop crying.
Jeepers.
What's your problem?
Jeepers?
Jeepers, creepers.
I took her hump toy away.
No, Russ.
I don't like to edit out humping.
That's got to go with the bloopers at the end.
Right?
You got to see this.
So many different ways to say it.
Reading rainbow.
They will come for you.
You cut that out.
I will cut that out.
That's true, they came for Jordy LaForge and he used to be the host of that show.
Yeah, so...
Yeah, fair enough.
Oh, no, screwed your name up.
Oh, oh my god, I can't say it.
Say it one more time, Russ.
Oh, you just got to say it once.
Dumbgeons & Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.