Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
from it you see a bloodstone that bounces off the wall and towards the exit and you are in a room of
even more mayhem and chaos okay what's next guys as you begin to examine the room again the
shadows start slowly rotating till they shrink into the gnomon we can put all the gems on the
sundial you reach at the exact same time and your precision is accurate and they all fall
through and disappear podcast over bye guys well really you don't think there's a portal
that they just went through try to i stand on the gnomon thea disappears flint crawls in
and everybody falls harmlessly back into the sundial room where the shadows are pointed at
every single exit the curving path you follow suddenly twists to reveal a proper maze you
hear the pounding of hooves is a massive stone gorgon i really hope that we never figure out
dnd me too i like the way we do it i like the way we do it too welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons
we are dnd fifth edition actual play podcast and i'm your dungeon master Russ More and with me
today is Amy More i have a pink fuzzy robe on and i play thea amastasia and also sporting
nightwear attire maybe carla johnson i am not sporting nightwear attire but i did
literally say to amy when we got on this call you're wearing the robe i missed it so much
the robe was like one of our original players when we started playing around the table
also i play new lara moonbrook and tom laird and i am wearing my queens of the stone age
concert tee from when i saw them back in january and i play flint Firebeard russ what
are you wearing i am wearing an avengers infinity war thanos t-shirt it's a little
too intimidating i meant to say something like pretty hard is aggressive oh he's yeah he's he's
good like yeah i don't like it no she doesn't like it i wear it go change your shirt russ
it's upsetting carla and i've had numerous people say i am offended by that shirt
as i walk through the door okay i mean that's and he doesn't care i don't care he is a real
troublemaker that's me that's me um yeah welcome everybody uh this is the podcast
and we're gonna jump right in to the podcast but first a message from us
about the podcast we love you re the podcast we notice that you've been listening and we
appreciate you oh we do appreciate you that's true yeah definitely it's like a little psa
yeah i mean it's just nice to throw it back just a little bit yeah you know also you look great
today yeah oh you really do real good okay now pause for response good good yeah yeah um where
i was kind of going with this is we're on Patreon wow wow that is yeah that's whoo i don't
know how i was gonna get there it's a 90 degree turn yeah and when you're on Patreon
you get a random episode dedicated to you and today this episode is dedicated to
katharina sindelar thanks katharina sorry if i pronounce your name wrong yeah katharina you're
awesome you rock also if it's katharina we apologize oh 100 we apologize 100 but there's
a th in there so i feel pretty confident maybe katharina could have gone could have gone
either way yeah it's a cool name it's very melodic i'm deeply into it Patreon.com slash
dumb dragon cast go check it out uh if you're interested in supporting us uh just a little bit
more but i mean if you just got to listen that's totally cool too fuck it let's play dnd
you're still stuck in a maze yeah we are boy how are we so happy about that oh yeah
we're still in there just accepted it you know where we live now this is our life it's
guys it can't be i need to find guac moldy you're right and there are people wondering about her
oh there's a lot of people wondering about guac but i'm very confident that we are gonna
hashtag find guac that's right so you have currently find yourself in perhaps another
maze after you went down a pathway and you ended up in what appears to be a more different
type of maze perhaps even a bit more real that's the queen's english by the way more
mazy sort of style more mazy maze yeah like maybe it's a corn maze maybe it's maybe that's
whimsical right maybe just on the other side we hear like there'll be a pumpkin patch pony riding
and there's yeah people picking pumpkins sure to make pumpkin spice lattes out of
which are now available as of yesterday starbucks get on board uh sponsor this
podcast as this recording is released oh three weeks ago the pumpkin spice
it's more seasonally appropriate for us to be talking about such autumnal things when this
episode actually comes out so that's true yeah yeah way to go ask screw you starbucks whoa we
want them on board ross unless you want to sponsor this podcast unless then we're into it
is this like when you were gonna badmouth google the other night come on ross get it
together come on all these all these could be potential sponsors of ours because i'm sure
starbucks sponsors they're itching to get in the podcast game mediocre dnd
and starbucks are looking for us if you are give me a call five five five
that's my number there's the thing that people need to understand there's like a far fewer
people in canada so our numbers are only three that's true yeah that's very true
brusco five five five and it's all rotary too so oh yeah yep yeah our phone is on the wall
in the kitchen as we speak there are cell phones but they're the 80s zack morris brick
cell phones exactly we really just use them to throw at each other when we're angry but
that doesn't ever happen because this is canada let's face it very genteel
so we're in a maze so yeah the path you follow suddenly twist to reveal a proper
maze cut out of the surrounding hedges moments later the pounding of hooves rings out
and a gorgon charges out of the greenery towards you
roll for initiative does it smell like gorgonzola nice thanks
ah i'm here all day i got a 20 uh 23 i think seven sorry 27 amy that's very good
right no it was just a seven isn't gorgon from trolls no not trolls sorry smurfs
that's gargamel that is gargamel isn't that isn't a gorgon like medusa in her cronies
aren't they gorgons i believe so in this case yeah i'm talking real world greek mythology here
russ bowl yeah stone bowl a stone yes that does sound yes well that's just confusing when we're
talking about myths they can't they can't just take a name of a thing and make it the name
of another thing that's true that's not allowed i mean i guess it is wizards of the coast
way to be confusing so no new law you're first i'm gonna go first is that what you're saying
that's what i said yeah new law new lara you are up first how far is uh old mr gorgon from us
the gorgon has just come out of the greenery okay and he is now 25 feet charging
towards you and your friends who are standing in the middle of a maze there is an opening
to your right as you look at the gorgon and an opening behind you and to your left well i'm just
gonna try and stab it i know it's really big and muscular and looks like it's got some kind
of armor on it but i'm pretty irritated and would like to get out of this maze so
whether by success or death i care not okay so you're rushing forward charging at the gorgon
yep all right roll it up
all right well that was only a 14 so that probably didn't do anything
oh nope it's okay i'll try again okay well that was a 13 so that probably didn't do anything
either i'm just gonna like yeah i'm gonna scooch a little sashay a little scooch have you seen
that gif of um and it was also in the show of homer simpson just like into the head into the
head just gonna do one of those moves sure i get that um so yeah you charge forward 25 feet
swinging um and uh i mean it's it's we'll say it's glancing off of its horns but you
don't connect solid and sidestep off allowing it to continue charging forward to your friends
okay well donnie's gonna try he's gonna first try to recharge the old breath weapon yep didn't
work so he is probably going to sure he's gonna try and bite this charging bull because why
wouldn't he why would me you guys he's worried about um guac too they're best friends you
know uh that is a 16 uh 16 will not hit okay well he's gonna try and recharge his breath weapon
again and it didn't work again so he's gonna try and bite again and he doesn't because he got a
10 i'm gonna swap out my dice donnie leaps and flies just above not too high because he's
worried about the guac syndrome and hovers above the bull that's charging towards you
and takes a couple bites at its back but misses and the gorgon continues forward i feel like he
lies above it and just is like that and just licks down the gorgon's back
and just as he's about to reach the group lets forth a giant green plume that goes
30 feet out in front of it encompassing flint thea thaddeus and Flamikinskins who all have to make
a constitution saving throw yes you have to make the constitution saving throw everyone
has questions about poison it's not poison i know that's why you were confirming they had
to do it right i crit failed oh that is not great amy uh flint got a 19 thaddeus got an 18
i rolled with a different dice for Flamikinskins it's an 18 for her i know i just swapped all my dice
three of you are fine and you just you just this cloud comes up and over you thea however
we'll get to that in a second the bull as it releases this gas continues charging forward
moving to gore flint as he is the first one in the way or with a 21 to hit oh yeah so that's
15 piercing damage and you must make a strength saving throw or be knocked prone as it is in a
trampling charge okay so i'm gonna take 12 hit points because i can lower these things by three
due to my heavy armor master skill strength throw that's a 19 plus four so 23
you are not knocked prone suck it gorgon and then as you are gored and kind of knocked to the
side the the cloud settles and you see a stone figure and thea is what's called petrified
oh no just like a basilisk does so you can at the end of your next turn you can make another
saving throw and on a success you are no longer petrified on a failure the target is petrified
until freed by a greater restoration spell or other magic next up in rotation Flamikinskins
russ is banging out the uh big guns as far as side effects for us fucking failing
saving throws these days true i mean things things get real if i be hurt if i'm petrified
you have resistance against a lot of stuff if you're petrified nice um so Flamikinskins as
right into the right into the gorgons face Flamikinskins hurls a bubble of acid
and it must make a dexterity saving throw which it does not succeed on and that is a
high roll so that is six twelve seventeen acid damage against this gorgon's face
oh i've mixed up Flamikinskins and flint two fls in that list so flint you go now
okay so being as it kind of knocked flint off to the side i'm guessing i'm
just to the side of it as opposed to in front of it yes so it has a charge like five feet
past you okay uh i'm gonna go alongside it and kind of swing my axe in an uppercut fashion right
where like its front legs meets its upper body just to like just to get in that joint yeah for
sure and that is a 25 that will hit come on big money 13 damage on that one and i'll
continue attacking it in the same spot that's a 21 no 22 sorry it's another 13
we're consistent on the damage front and a 20 but not critical uh yes okay
and that's 12 more damage with like down and up swipings you're working into the joint and
you see like cracks begin to form on the front shoulder and creeping down the back of this
gorgon as it is thaddeus's turn all right everybody make a perception check as well as
as flint is deciding can i perceive anything i didn't think i could uh thaddeus got a
23 and flint critically failed carla got uh oh sorry carla's not there new laura got a 23 as
carla's not here man flint's too focused on defeating this is gorgon but the 23s as the
dust is settling you notice a diamond kind of in the middle of where it shot its blast of
petrified breath which he would currently be standing right over top of so the gorgon is
currently standing right over top of a diamond so the gorgon is standing over the diamond like
as if the diamond is in the floor uh like it's just a diamond that has is placed on the ground
it's not inset in anything okay oh i thought thaddeus had mage hand and i was like does
he have one of those hand spells right where he can grab things i thought that would be very
handy but i'm not seeing here at all handy yeah uh thaddeus is going to touch the stone
statue of thea and cast resistance on it so she has uh an extra d4 to a number
rolled on a saving throw of its choice ah thanks okay i'll need it may i roll two d20s
because i think if i if i add them together i could maybe get it's possible oh and thaddeus
kind of gets out of the way as well so he can go like back into his right as far as where the
gorgon is or back into the left uh he will go to the left to the left back into the left
so kind of just in that doorway there so he runs back and down and just out of sight
or just you know peering around the corner at the action happening thea you get to make a
saving throw yeah i do do it do you remember what kind of saving through it is what i don't
care i rolled a 19 is it constitution it was a constitution okay so 21 so and you can add a d4
to it if you want do it did my 21 i'm pretty sure my 21 made it up to you yeah the effect
effect ends so you the stone begins to fall away from your skin but that is the end of your turn
you should be doing this like when you have like luna's face masks on it gets on crack
you're making all those faces back to the top and that's new lara okay well i'm going to try
again that's a 27 so you're rushing back towards the gorgon to attack stab it in the
butt nice while i'm behind it so realistically i'm gonna stab it in the butt yeah or how about
doesn't have horns this sounds better i'm gonna stab it like in the rear flank oh sure how about
how about that well you do have all that animal handling stuff so just a fancy way to say butt
stab so that's 18 damage okay i'm gonna stab it in the butt again i'm gonna stab it in the
other side of its butt uh no maybe i'm not 16 does not hit 16 is not a butt stab okay not
a butt stab it's a it's a glance off it's it's a spank stony hide okay you just spanked it
donnie's gonna try and recharge didn't work so he's gonna try and bite that is a 23
yeah uh for six damage recharge attempt recharge fail bite attempt 25
uh and seven damage where is beginning to show and the cracks are beginning to spread throughout
this gorgon as it is its turn and it rears up and stomps to the ground and releases another
petrifying breath which spreads out and encompasses everybody except thaddeus yeah thaddeus
everybody's got to make a constitution saving throw again i'm glad i didn't use that d4
15 i'm using a d4 i got a 20 flay mccain's got a 19 flink got a 20 donnie did donnie roll
donnie got a 12 uh so as the cloud comes up you hear a thud like a stone hitting the ground
as donnie falls to the ground from the brief small height that he was up and he too is
petrified it's not as bad as it looks donnie the gorgon jumps through the greenery in front
and comes back out from the other end down by on the other side of thea
and begins charging back towards you but does not make it as far since it was charging past
thaddeus does he have an opportunity attack yeah yeah yeah i'll give you an opportunity
attack yeah all right he's gonna swing his war hammer at this bad boy and that is a 22
yeah and nine damage his hit stops him in his tracks and he turns and looks
at him and now it is truly flint's turn all right uh how far out from flint is this bad
boy now 30 feet flint is going to grab his dwarven thrower and throw that bad boy at this
fucking gorgon yeah ranged weapon and that is a 17 17 will not hit okay he's going to do the
same thing again so you throw your hammer and recall it back to you instantly that's right
only to whip it again that's right and this is a nat 20 yeah it is we haven't had a nat 20
in a long time it feels like a while yeah so that's 17 plus five is 22 damage tell me how
your hammer destroys this gorgon uh well after it missed on the first flyby it noticed a little
weak spot where we've been hitting the gorgon repeatedly and there's cracks showing so
as uh flint let it fly again it strikes true and shatters the gorgon into a million pieces
yeah it does thea shakes off the rest of the rock and goes whoo dust herself off good job team
uh yeah so your hammer strikes true and the gorgon explodes and crumbles and begins to mist
up into the air and you have seemingly defeated the gorgon he just i don't like the sound of
that seemingly you have defeated the gorgon yay i don't know what you're talking about i didn't
say seemingly when the gorgons destroyed does donnie magically become unpetrified negative
okay uh guys can somebody do help me out here uh that is that is is gonna cast uh that same
spell again that resistance spell um so should he just should i just roll so it would be
that is his turn flaming kins there's like i can't fucking do shit thea no sorry uh and
then it's back to you and donnie so yeah we'd say you'd have to make a constitution
saving throw at the end of his turn uh that is a 17 you can add a d4 to that if needed
and a d4 because why the heck not that is a 21 you see the stone begin to retreat from donnie
as he stands up he's like well that was a shitty experience yeah but we went through
together donnie yeah high five over here all right with my hand claw which clearly i have
yeah that's weird right didn't we decide that it was like weird baby hands yeah and also you
have a pretty bitching hat so right well not anymore now it's just tiny oh yeah well that
makes it even more bitching that's adorable it's adorable new lara you told me that it was
adorable is it not adorable no it's no donnie it's adorable you look amazing oh i'm gonna have
a compLex no i gotta hang out with you all the time i wouldn't want you to look like an idiot
shit all right where are we we're in a maze donnie i think the stone is at the same place we've been
forever yeah somebody ought to uh pick up that diamond you look back to the diamond and it is
gone motherfucker well how about thea turns to her right and says how about we go this way you
guys do you do you go as a group do you split up what are you doing well traditionally
we love splitting the party so oh we never split up yeah you kind of follow each other around
throughout this throughout this maze about a minute passes as you're trying to find some
sort of exit and you seem to be just kind of looping around not really getting anywhere
and you hear the beating of hooves and charging out from in front of you thea
the gorgon returns
releasing his breath directly down towards you so thea and flint need to make a constitution
saving throw i get stuck and i don't get to fight this gorgon again that's an 18
oh yeah that's an 18 without any added fun so you're fine but you get a gore attack there
thea for a 19 so that's gonna be 20 piercing damage oh yeah and you must make a strength
saving throw as you were thrown about 13 and you were knocked prone and as a bonus action
the gorgon stomps on you with his hooves holy shit for a 17 that will hit me for another
15 bludgeoning damage oh my god damn so he is currently on top of you and will continue
in initiative order so i guess we'll go back to the top there new lara you and donnie are up
did he drop a diamond when he released his breath weapon yes you see down in the mist
a crystallizing diamond form as he is stomping on your friend okay i hope my friend starts
crawling towards that she's really tough she'll be fine in spirit yeah she's tough in spirit her
body is weak and brittle she's very willowy and slender uh okay i am going to uh you know try
and stab stab the guy that is a 20 19 damage yeah i'm gonna do it again because i got 22
it's 22 damage uh donnie's gonna try and recharge hey it worked guys guys it worked
worked so he uh is going to well god can he even do that where is everybody here
thea is directly underneath the gorgon but like she's up a little she's all flat on the ground
oh i'm so flat on the ground so prone i'm trying to be very like unassuming and
yeah so maybe he'll stop stomping on me if i pretend i'm not there like sinking into the
grass um i think that now that donnie has recharged he's not gonna shoot fire when
he is right there seems like a bad idea so he'll he'll he'll do a he'll do a bite move
which is a 19 okay for seven damage and then he will do that again uh but that is only a 14
so that's probably a big old nothing 14 doesn't hit so donnie leaps almost on top of and begins
biting at the gorgon as it begins attempting to buck him off and flint what's the what's the
deal with this diamond russ is it directly below the gorgon what's what's the situation
here yeah it looks like it formed like it started its its breath kind of as it came out
of the the greenery so it's kind of just behind where the gorgon is right now and since the
gorgon is all like distracted from stomping on thea would i be able to make some sort of
acrobatic like run and jump uh kind of off to the side and maybe go grab this diamond
if you roll for it well i suppose i could roll for it this is d and d after all hey nat 20 again
oh my goodness the sweetest of flips occur yeah so i do like some parkour moves using like the
hedge the side of the hedge and like run up the hedge kind of crouching tiger style
and uh jump in behind and grab this diamond okay as you pick up the diamond thea and flint
make a perception roll thea at disadvantage because you've got a gorgon stomping on top of you
as a 16 for flint 14 i rolled a 15 and a 14 plus an eight oh right plus eight 22 you've
been adding your modifiers yes i have just not right now so flint as you pick this up
uh you and thea hear greenery like moving um and you see down the corridor behind you
a doorway open up about 30 feet down the next aisle that you were right beside there
do i alert everyone can everyone else see this is it just something that we can see what's
happening here it's just that something that you two have seen uh everybody else is kind
of out of eye shot of where they would be able to see it i do should we like attack
this thing or like disengage and run for it what's what's the group consensus here
run flint but you're kind of trapped under this army crawl my way out it'll be okay
uh i don't want to abandon everyone carla any thoughts it's in the moment man
time's ticking turn's gonna be over in five four three uh i'm gonna attack the gorgon okay
stab it in the butt you're behind it right i am behind it gonna pull a real carla butt
stab here yep no carla's not there it's new lara yeah but it was carla who wanted to do the
uh that's a 25 on the first attack yes sir uh so that's 14 damage okay i'll give a second
attack uh and that's a 21 on the second attack yes sir oh that's only 10 damage
swiping your axe into its butt uh you begin to
create new butt cracks as it becomes uh thea's turn oh god is this does this thing have me
pinned with its big no you're not fucking you're not pinned you are prone though all right
while i'm prone can i cast a spell well i'm in a wild shape sure yeah i'm in a wild
shape into a winter wolf look at me with all my hit points i yell guys a door yes winter wolves
can speak common we've already been over it it's just been so long since she wild shaped these
are for the it has been it has been and you know for any new listeners sure so yes they do
speak basic common and i say guys a door and i disengage Flamikins kens yells a window it's
not a window from the window to the wall yeah yeah it's from yeah finish finish the lure
dress seems like it would be a song Flamikins kens would be that's true yeah yeah facebook.com
slash dumb dragon cast group i don't know what the fuck it is go put that song in there now
oh yeah oh and the beyonce to the left oh yeah yeah got a couple in this one uh so i
i yell to them that there's a door and i i want to disengage and dash to the door okay you are
i'm gonna dnd disengage and dash that's right so how far are you going well i can move 50 feet
okay i'm gonna go right to the fucking door okay and just wait because guys i'm like
i'm hurting real bad i want nothing to do with any more fighting that's fine um
now with this bullshit right ah
Flamikins kens comes around the corner and she's like what's going on oh shit and then Flamikins
kens casts dimension door what's that she teleports herself from her current location
to another spot within range and she arrives at exactly the spot desired so she's going to
dimension door herself right oh that's the girl oh excuse me she sends the girl on a one
why Flamikins kens why uh Flamikins kens dimension doors right over to the door and then it's
thaddeus's turn he starts like big time like what the where's what she comes in like almost
at a run hey i like snarl like these squares on your map are roughly 10 by 10 exactly 10
by 10 i think if that is like hugs the fucking uh the shrub wall and dashes over there he can
just zip right on over to that door like you guys have been walking around the maze so you
kind of have a feeling that um where thea and Flamikins kens is he could get to from the
other side it's just based on your travels through so he could dash and get to thea without
even passing the gorgon okay he will do that then yeah so wait maybe he should like yeah no
he'll do that that's fine yeah so thaddeus uh turns and heads back down a pathway that you
guys have kind of researched and heads back to the group over there and then it is the gorgon's
turn boom he likes you go home and as the gorgon kind of sees all the commotion of everybody
running away and moving uh flint you look down in your hand and the diamond begins to disappear
and as the diamond disappears so does the door son of a bitch and the gorgon releases another
breath out in your direction flint and down and banks around the corner
to where uh Flamikins kens thea and thaddeus are and you all need to make a constitution saving throw
it probably doesn't hit thaddeus but that is just out of range for all these things
yeah he's lucky it's pretty good uh that's a 17 for flint oh Flamikins kens doesn't do well
either so Flamikins kens and thea are now petrified and flint you see at the base of
where the gorgon is about 10 feet away a new diamond forming in place and just for good
measure the gorgon charges you with of course yeah oh it doesn't do well though that's a 14
oh hooray yeah uh new laura you're up so whereabouts is that diamond
it is about 10 feet in front of the gorgon so on the opposite side of where you are currently
located it turned and faced towards flint and the rest of the group so i have to stab it in
the butt again wow is it always behind so i'm not like i'm not really into butt stabbing all
of a sudden just as always facing away from me or maybe i always have been i mean everybody's
got secret character motivations right this is like an m night shamAlydin level twist here
yeah it's my twist butt stabs uh okay so let's go for the old butt stab that is a 25
yeah that's a solid butt stab and that is eight that is 24 damage whoa that is almost
the most i could get i'm gonna do it again i'm not gonna do it again that was a 12
well like you needed to you just nailed you just gave more damage in that one roll than i have
since we started recording this episode because it would zero i've given zero to
okay how far okay is it is our map positions right now accurate uh as far as i've been
trying to keep up with them so yeah they should be fairly accurate have you determined
in canon that breath weapons go through shrubberies because i feel like you have
didn't that just happen with the gorgon well it went through like the doorway in front of it
and banked around like it hit the wall and kept going well i noticed that it's bleeding but
it's kind of sticking behind that oh well that's because i can't put it anywhere else
like it just where the thing that's okay i think donnie's gonna sure its butt is hanging
no it's fine i mean it's a it's a fire weapon so fire can go through trees trust me as we have
all learned in british columbia oh yeah like light this shit up yeah fire fire can go through
trees so he is going to do his fire weapon which means ye old gorgon needs to uh do a
deck save and this is not going to be good it's going to be amazing it's going to be a seven
it's going to be seven does that save it's it's it doesn't see it coming it just goes
straight up its butthole oh jeez jesus oh boy did donnie put his lips to it like how is his
oh my god why with the visual no the butthole it's too far russe did you hear how many dice
a lot of dice anytime i get a lot of dice it's 22 damage so canonically he's blown this fire
up his butthole and cooks him from the inside out and bursts in a cloud of stony dust vapor
and as he does those watching the diamond it does the same thing and dissolves into the
ground so we're going to go through and make some saving throws at this point uh it would be
flint's turn next if there's anything you want to do flint uh i go and cheer real loud
for thea's saving throw that she's going to make all right make a constitution saving throw
the uh
oh not 20 whoa i have to whisper to my dice right against a fall away and you are back the same
Flamikinskins however did not fare so well and as the stone falls away you're kind of just
watching Flamikinskins hoping the same happens but nothing does happen
hey there i'm your dungeon master russ more thanks for joining us for episode 53 of
Dumbgeons and Dragons it's all about that butt as mentioned off the top if you enjoy what we do
and can support us in a monetary for perks and rewards fashion visit us on Patreon where
we have many different tiers and rewards to give you access to amazing bonus content
patrons have access to tons of cool stuff like monthly bonus episodes character sheets
naming of NPCs and much much more right now patrons can go on and fill out a survey to let
us know what they currently like and would like to see more of in the Patreon community so we can
help mold it and make it the best that we can for the people who are taking advantage of it
so if you're a patron go fill that out and if you sign up to be a new patron you can fill
that out too check out all the details at Patreon.com dumb dragon cast another way you
can support the show is to share a link to your favorite episode or just the show in general to
social media talk about us to your friends and family or write a review on apple podcast
stitcher or wherever else you can rate or review podcasts every little bit helps get us out in
front of all those people who hopefully will love the show as much as you and we do and
thanks to sirenscape for some of the amazing atmosphere in this episode make sure you check
them out at sirenscape.com to bring your games to life links for everything mentioned
today can be found in the description and the next episode will be out wednesday september 19th
when maybe just maybe the adventures will be able to get out of this darn maze maybe i make
no promises but maybe but let's jump back into the action and see if they can figure out
this diamond riddle diamonds can be pricey though so you know it might be tough have
a great week we'll talk soon that is kind of gives the old like chin like thinks about it
for a second he says i might uh rust does the voice for this guy but he sounds like an old man
says i might have something for this and he digs around in his spell component pouch
and he opens up a couple different containers and he can't quite find what he's looking for
and finally he finds a container with the ruby dust in it and he puts a little bit in his palm
and just blows the the ruby dust over the the statue form of flamikins and says
heal thyself he's casting greater restoration uh the ruby dust sprinkles down over top of
flamikins and she she was like standing with her face and like a weird kind of motif seems
pretty normal for her and as the stone falls away she's like okay we're back are we out yet
uh nope not yet guys we gotta we gotta game plan this it seems like we only have a limited
time with the open exit and the diamond so uh i think next time we gotta have people like
make a break for the exit right away and then we gotta get lucky with some some some
acrobatic type of stuff and get that diamond and go agreed how's everybody feeling
i've been better but i'm okay you're still a wolf form right i am perfect that's good because
that will be more uh acrobatic than i assume everybody's gone over to where the stone stone
features were thereabouts oh yeah if everyone was yeah like as you guys are game planning
you begin to hear the sound of hooves again so this is your time so if you're doing anything
in particular okay you guys as soon as you see the diamond one of us will grab it once that
stone door opens up and makes itself known we just need to high tail it there get it high
tail it there i swish my tail i i mean agreed i think whoever grabs it run to the door and
try to open the door maybe the door will stay open once it's open as you finish discussing this out
of the greenery right behind flint you hear the charging hooves of the gorgon as he runs towards
and blasts its petrifying breath out and down towards flint thaddeus and thea god i had to be
in the fucking corner please nobody puts baby in the corner 11 uh thaddeus got a 16 and flint
got a 15 and i say not again mother and then as i turn to stone thea turns to stone again
and flint and thaddeus are fine except for the charging trample that flint receives
uh that's a natural 20 35 piercing damage and you must make a strength saving throw
so that's 32 damage let me just subtract three from that small victories oh boy okay that's a
lot of uh that's a lot of damage and a strength throw you bet that is a 15 that doesn't make it
you are knocked that makes no and as a bonus action it tries to trample you with its hooves
wait a minute wait a minute wait one goddamn minute waiting waiting i am going to use my
indomitable skill and re-roll a saving throw that i fail
17 that makes it so you are not prone yay and it doesn't trample you with its hooves
even better yeah that doesn't feel good doesn't feel good it did not look fun when you were
doing it so no uh new lara you were up did it drop a diamond did it drop it you were around
the corner presently so unless you move around the corner you may not be able to see if only
someone else who could see asked regardless right do you remember the plan i am going to
i was busy saving things i know you were rolling around and like not getting stomped on it was
amazing i assume i couldn't see i'm gonna come around the corner though and uh you know i guess
try and stab it in the front this time which seems seems crazy but well maybe it'll work
maybe it'll work uh it's a 25 that will hit so you push your way through
and uh make it in front not on the hedges but you're like yeah you're beside flint not
standing on top of it in the front and the back yeah so that is 24 damage okay i'm going
to try and stab it again but i failed because i rolled a nine that will not hit okay donnie's
gonna try and recharge didn't work he wasn't gonna use it anyway because all of his friends
are in the way this time but he's gonna try to bite he he fails he's gonna try again
and he probably succeeds because as a 24 yeah 11 damage
oh hey now do i see a diamond you sure do right at uh like pretty much right at your feet within
five feet of where you are great i'm super gonna grab it you grab it and right behind you in the
same spot that it was before right behind where you the main group of you is pretty much where
i'm frozen yeah no donnie you know oh there's a lot of people in here i know we're all up
there clustered yeah you're there you're there you're there there's a gorgon here sure you're in
that vicinity but right where thea is okay the hedges move away and an exit forms flint should
i go try and open the door guys you're it's it's an open oh no you're not like it's an
open we've been over this i'm sorry oh it's not right beside me yeah i'm like right beside
you can i just hand it to you i mean i guess can i because i can i just can i just steal it from
her hand yeah yeah absolutely i feel like we should all go at once but i will go all right
i'm gonna i'm gonna disengage i don't even think i've been fighting this thing i'm gonna
disengage yeah well you're within range so yeah i'm gonna book it over to that opening with
my diamond in my hand oh sure he's stealing the diamond so you're gonna stand like right
in the entryway like it's open like essentially it's just another pathway down a maze yeah
essentially i'm going to stand in the way as if there was a door there that might try to close
and i'm at the supermarket and it's not going to be able to close because i'm in the sensor
i like it uh anything else you're doing before we go to the next person uh i tell everyone
to get the fuck over here see how does that sound like a character and whatnot tom uh it's
really i'm just running and grumbling so it's like and then i'm over at the door
and we've been with him long enough to know you guys got the gist of it clearly get the
fuck out of here um thea your turn 19 so the stone falls away from you and that's the end of
your turn yeah um but you are right beside the the entrance that's not gonna turn
yeah she does it's her turn next oh Flamikins kins um hurl something just vomit
did she just oh she literally just hurls does she have a nervous tummy when she fights
rough night guys rough night uh that's gonna be five feet away from me so i'm just gonna
go stand with you flint and see what happens okay can you can you drag thea over here with
you i pull her does she what her hair she moves but she growls oh yeah she's a wolf
fatius's turn yeah he's just gonna back away and go for the fucking door while the pathway
that's open yeah so he backs away and continues to go for the door everybody is standing
roughly in the doorway as it becomes the gorgon's turn and where before as it readied its
petrifying breath the old diamond would disappear flint you look at it now standing within this
newly created maze exit the diamond remains present but the gorgon still gets a turn and
tries to gore uh new lara why did i roll your dice fuck oh it was bad guys it was a 15
15 to hit okay doesn't hit and then it's new lara's turn i can use well i probably don't even
need to use this can i just like run away yep you can disengage and run okay that's what i am
going to do donnie's gonna come with me all right so both of you uh disengage and run
towards the group that is standing in the exit um and as you continue down the path you turn
and see that the gorgon stops at the passageway that is created and kind of steps back and tips
his hat because he was wearing a hat that we didn't say um exhales a giant green plume
and turns and exits into the hedges beside it and you guys run back down this maze that
is created and after a short while you enter back into the sundial room where the shadows
are pointed still at a through h i see why sundials are no longer in favor
music in today's episode was by Kavin mcleod of incompetech.filmmusic.io i mean sorry about
your cat but um it's kind of dark and angry yeah no i wish you hadn't said that i didn't like
it at all i think you should probably cut that part out someone's gonna be like how did you
know my cat died and then we don't need dead cat stuff happening well maybe it's something
more innocent like they had to switch the cat from wet food to dry food and they're and
we're just sorry about it yeah because the cat's not happy yeah however however they're probably
happy because wet cat food smells disgusting oh yeah it does not smell good confirmed doesn't
smell good not just not just you doing them over and over and over again just kind of like
kind of how we do this joke over and over and over again yeah i know apologies it's been a
while we'll brainstorm better jokes no we won't we won't brainstorm better not a chance
let's stumble upon one and then hold on to it forever forever correct gorgon charges out
charges charges charges right at you if i die this round doesn't mean i don't have to play
the rest of this game you won't die Dumbgeons and dragons is a dumb dragons production