previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
Shoot it at whatever you're shooting it at.
Sorry.
Dragon.
When you use it, it adds an extra 60, 10 piercing damage.
Whoa!
Wowzer.
What?
You hear from all around you a voice say,
it looks like the humans have brought me dinner.
We want to dispatch of this dragon as quickly as possible
so I should try and hit him with my magic arrow, right?
Totally.
Do we want to like save that
and really surprise him with it?
Well, sure.
She shoots it off and it deflects off of the scales.
What?
I'm trying to save some of my magic for later.
And I piss myself.
Friends, it's been nice knowing you.
Yeah, it's been good.
Same here, I think we may have all just died.
I can't wait till I get to DM a campaign
and murder Russ immediately.
Have you been whispering like-
Oh, sweet nothings.
Sweet nothings in his ear.
Like really break him down, just, you know.
Like, yeah, psychologically torment that fucking dragon.
A crit 20, a match 20.
What?
Oh my God.
I told you I believed in you.
Amy, you're amazing.
Wow.
Thanks for believing in me, you guys.
Can I just say that I am invisible
and all I have done this whole time
is stand up and get knocked down.
I'll call you chumbalumpa.
He has recharged his breath weapon.
19.
Constitution is plus one, so that is an eight.
Record scratch, freeze frame.
Yeah, that's me.
You might be wondering how I got here.
Thea, you take 31.
Oh no.
Points of damage.
New Lara, I think you're gonna shatter.
I think so too.
New Lara, so you take 60 damage.
Oh my God.
It looks like he's attempting to make an escape.
All right, well, since I'm next to New Lara,
I will try and stabilize New Lara.
So that is 16.
So she is also stabilized.
Part of me wants to continue after the dragons.
I feel like if we let him go now,
we're gonna lose the trail.
What you see in the cavern is a chute
that descends down into the ocean,
frigid waters of the ocean.
There's a spell I can light the ocean on fire.
Is there a spell you could light the ocean on fire?
Yes. No.
No.
Well, hello, how are you today?
That's great.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons,
a D&D fifth edition actual play podcast.
I'm your dungeon master and co-host Russ More.
Not with me today are Carla Johnson,
who plays New Lara Moonbrook,
Tom Laird, who plays Flint Firebeard,
and my wife Amy More, who plays Thea Amastasia.
Together, we are creating a world and a story
for you to come along with.
Take part in and enjoy for what it is,
a dive into a fictional universe
where adventure, intrigue, and excitement
all come together and make a sweet, sweet, delicious
Hot Pocket-style narrative podcast.
Too much?
Well, let's get to the reason
we're breaking format a bit today.
It starts with some good news and some bad news.
The good news is you probably noticed
you have two new episodes in your download queue from us.
Woo-hoo!
The bad news is the reason for those two episodes.
This episode, episode seven,
now titled The Lost Dice Game,
was lost to the tech gremlins
that decided to jack with some audio,
making it unrecognizable as conversation.
And I couldn't put you through that.
It just didn't sound very good at all.
So here's what we're gonna do instead.
I'm gonna give you a rundown
of the major plot points that were missed
in this episode.
And then we're gonna move right along to the next one.
So let's get started.
Fortunately, this was a bit of a decompressed period
for our adventurers.
Flint, Thea, and Nularaaa
lugged their treasures back on board the frost skimmer
and set sail towards Luskin
to return Makoth the Crimson
and all the stolen wares to the Arcane Brotherhood
in hopes of signing them on board
to battle against the Cult of the Dragons.
To begin, the adventurers take a long rest
to regain much-needed HP, hit dice, and spell slots
that were lost in their battle with Aruthatar.
When they finish that, though,
we resolve some of the special items
that they used plot points for
at the end of the dragon battle episode
that they found when they were digging out treasure.
Thea is now in possession
of two functional Arrows of Dragonslaying,
where the dragon being attacked
must make a DC 17 Constitution saving throw
or take an extra 6d10 piercing damage,
half of that on a success.
Flint has two wonderfully magical
ice fragmentation grenades
that have a 60-foot range and a 20-foot blast radius.
Each creature within that radius
must make a DC 15 Dex saving throw,
taking 5d6 piercing damage
plus 2d4 cold damage on a fail,
half on a success.
Nularaaa spent some of her time
after her rest with Makoth the Crimson
to learn a new spell from one of the spell books
found within the Arcane Brotherhood stuff.
She learned a spell called Boomerang Quiver.
It's a second-level transmutation
with a casting time of one bonus action
requiring verbal and somatic or gesturing components
and will last through concentration up to one hour.
When Nularaaa casts this spell on a quiver,
any Arrows removed from that quiver
that do not find their target
return to the quiver by the beginning of the next turn.
During this training montage
that Nularaaa had with Makoth,
Makoth mentions that she senses
Nularaaa has exceptional skill
in more ways than she knows,
to which Nularaaa said,
"'Well, thank you.'"
And that's where it was left.
After looking at their goodies,
Flint, Thea, and Nularaaa head down to the galley
where there are some of the shipmates
playing a dice game.
And I'll let you know,
the technical difficulties might have saved you
from having to listen to me
try to describe a dice game over Skype
and everyone just not do well at it.
Long story short, they lost some money
and went to have some grog.
Flint challenged a half-orc named Baran
to an arm wrestle and beat him handily many times.
Needless to say, Baran was quite embarrassed
but used this opportunity to approach Flint
and ask for assistance with what he describes
as a cult problem in his hometown of Little Rock.
Baran tells Flint that he and his sister Sasha
escaped Little Rock and describes wearers of purple
having come into his town
and terrorizing the people in Little Rock
for seemingly no other reason than to cause havoc.
Flint tells Baran that he will have to discuss
with Thea and Nularaaa,
but this is likely something
that they'll be able to help out with.
Nularaaa is approached again by Makoth in the galley
and taken aside.
Makoth warns Nularaaa that Luskin is a very prejudicial
and racially charged city.
And while Thea and Flint will likely be able to pass
about the docks of Luskin with little issue,
they might not be as welcomed in the city.
Makoth suggests that Nularaaa enters Luskin with her alone
to return the stolen goods and sway the leaders
of the Arcane Brotherhood to their cause.
Thea, Flint and Nularaaa all come together
to discuss Baran and Sasha's problems
as well as Makoth's concerns
about Thea and Flint entering Luskin
to meet with the Arcane Brotherhood.
After much debate about splitting the party,
they decide to tell Makoth
that she must do what she can to convince the Brotherhood
to fight against the Cult of the Dragon
while the three of them go off to Little Rock
and help the people there.
When they return, they will meet with Makoth
and any other representatives of the Arcane Brotherhood
and discuss options further if needed.
Once they arrive in Luskin,
the three send Makoth through the gates of Luskin
and head off with Baran and Sasha
after renting a carriage of horses.
Little Rock is located approximately halfway
between Luskin and Mirabar
and they expect to arrive within one to two days.
On the road, the adventurers come across a band of dwarves
who appear to have taken a wear of purple
with the Cult of Dragons prisoner.
After some negotiation and payment to the dwarves,
they question this woman
who they find out is named Chila Flagsteel.
They learn that she got a little too greedy
while leading a group of cultists
that was terrorizing the dwarves.
Some super tough negotiations and banter happens
and the adventurers learn of a lead from Chila.
They learn that one of the worm-speakers,
Nerenvain, has gone missing from the cult
and is heard to have fortified a stronghold
in the Misty Forest.
He may even be trying to defect from the Cult of the Dragon,
but who's to say either way
until you talk to someone, right?
As the adventurers go to hand Chila back over,
the dwarves are struck by a large boulder
and the adventurers turn to see four ogres
charging towards them.
The dwarves turn tail and run,
but the adventurers charge to fight the ogres.
That's the end of the episode.
Quite a lot covered there.
Thanks for listening through this one.
There is another episode right away
so you can have the full adventure experience
with all four of us,
but there was just too much that was touched on
to just avoid it altogether.
You can keep those reviews coming in.
We love hearing what you think about the show.
It really does mean a whole lot to us
when you tell us what you think.
You can head over to iTunes
and leave your review and rating.
The ratings are great,
but the reviews along with them
help a little bit more, I think,
because it tells someone who's cruising around
looking for a podcast to listen to
that this one may be worth their time.
You can also tell your friends, family,
or your next door neighbor to visit DumbDragons.com.
All of our social media and email links are listed there
as well as the latest episodes.
On Twitter, we are at DumbDragonCast.
You can use the DumbDragonCast hashtag
so we can track you down
and find out who's talking to or about us.
That's the one we're most active on right now.
Mostly me, but Tom, Carla, and Amy
are all on Twitter figuring it out
and make appearances on there too.
On Facebook, we're at Facebook.com slash DumbDragonCast.
We obviously keep both of those up to date
with the latest episode details
and posting some other cool D&D RPG related stuff
that you may find interesting.
You can also send us an email
to DumbDragonPodcast at gmail.com.
And that's all for your Russ the DM centric episode.
Episode eight is out right now.
There is definitely some cool stuff coming up,
so don't delay, click away.
Yeah, I heard it.
It's terrible.
Yeah.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin MacLeod
of Ncompetech.Filmmusic.io.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a DumbDragon's production.