previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
You were being rushed by four ogres.
The dwarves that you were dealing with,
they have turned tail and fled.
So you are now under the possession of the cultists.
So we have to fight and babysit at the same time.
She left like steel, yes.
Donnie, make sure you look at that prisoner.
Yeah, she shackled up, but I'll go over there.
Yeah, Donnie's got his watchful eyes on her.
Second roll, critical fail, critical fail.
Yeah, I like the delay.
Donnie does take a bite or a sting at him,
trying to stop him and paralyze him, but it doesn't work.
And he still manages to get to Cheela
and he breaks her neck.
And she doesn't seem to put up a fight at this.
Saves you having to tie her up
and throw her in a river, yeah.
It was a lot of fun.
We're gonna keep going a little rock
and save B.A. Baracus.
Wait, did you say B.A. Baracus?
Yeah.
Nice.
And Baran and the older lady
are having a bit of a discussion.
They brought with them something evil.
I don't think they knew they had it
among them when they came,
but I do believe they've left it here.
Yeah, we wanna pick a good location
where we can keep an eye on things,
like we're gonna trap it.
And then you hear a woman scream
and it sounds like it's coming
from the direction of Baran's house.
There doesn't appear to be anything in the room
except you see a green haze or mist
and she's screaming over and over.
It's gone.
I don't know what it was,
but I think I heard it and it's big.
Last time you guys burst into Baran and Sasha's house
after you set your trap in the town square.
Which did not work.
Which clearly did not work.
But I get to jump like a badass off a roof onto an owl.
Yeah, you did.
Can you really call that a fail?
Oh no, it was a win all around.
So you burst in and you see Sasha screaming.
She's covered in blood.
She has some minor cuts.
You look at her and you don't really think
that it's all of her blood specifically.
You see there's a smashed window to the right
in the room where she's sitting.
Is it smashed in or smashed out?
It is smashed in into the room.
You can see from the front door,
there's a straight shot to the back door.
The back door is also open.
So you notice a kind of a mist in the room
where Sasha is that seems out of place,
but you can't figure out exactly what it is.
But there's a mist in the room.
Guys, there's a mist in the room.
Does it seem like it's magical?
I'm gonna say yes.
Spooky.
Just because I just feel it.
I just feel it in my bowels.
I don't like the sound of this mist.
No, I'm not into magic mists at all.
You wanna turn off your phone there, Hollywood?
Sorry.
God.
You guys said sass her, right?
That's exactly what we said.
I was gonna just say, did you guys ever see,
and then I couldn't even remember what the movie was
so that Tom and I were bugging you guys to go see.
Rogue One.
Did you ever go see Rogue One?
No, we haven't seen any movies in theaters.
Oh my God.
You guys are the worst.
It's almost out on VHS, isn't it?
Betamax, yeah.
Oh, good, good.
That's funny.
I have arcana.
Can I, can I like?
You have arcana?
Arcana.
Arcana would be more dog-like.
Well, I have that too.
Can I make an arcana chat?
Sure.
I know of any magical or historical properties
having to do with like, creatures that it's a,
it's a, it's a.
Fuck.
We all know what you're trying to say.
I'm trying to figure out my modifier.
It's a plus five.
I got 16.
You can detect that there are some magical properties
to it.
I knew it, I knew it in my bones.
But you haven't come across this spell in particular
in your, in your magical enlightenment period.
Can I tell if, like, do I have like a little
Rolodex of mystical, like, creatures that create
this kind of mist in their wake?
Like, maybe.
Like, his look on his face is like, mm.
No.
It's not some kind of smoke bomb that fantasy Batman
throws down before he leaves the room?
No, no, not a smoke bomb.
Well, I'm thinking more of like, ectoplasm left behind.
Okay, okay.
So, no.
Also a hard no.
While we've been checking out this mist,
I assume, uh, Baron has run to Sasha's side
and is seeing if she's okay,
since we're all just standing here
jagging around talking about the mist.
She's bleeding.
Yes, Baron rushed immediately to Sasha's side
to try and calm her down as she was screaming
and yelling.
Good, good.
And they are discussing what happened.
And she tells him that two beasts in dark cloaks
came in, they had long claws and bright white eyes.
And when they came in, she felt that she could not move.
She was enthralled or something?
Like paralyzed?
She says, it felt like I had control of my body
but I just couldn't, like I was in my body
but I just couldn't move.
I don't know what, if they were doing something to me
or if I was just so frightened.
Where'd the blood come from?
Is she bleeding?
You examine her a little bit
and she does have some cuts on her.
Looks like they could be some from the glass
of the window.
There are a couple, a bit larger cuts
which looks like they could be from some sort of claw
or knife or something like that.
But there's a little bit of blood elsewhere in the room
but you don't see anything major
where a lot of the blood could have come from.
Could you walk us through the events of what happened?
She says, yeah, well, I was waiting here
for Bahrain to come back
and there was a loud explosion beside me
as the window burst in.
I was hit by some of the glass
and in came these two creatures.
And as I said, I couldn't move to run away.
And then they started to attack me
but you guys quickly came after I screamed
and they heard you running up.
And then I think they left through the back.
Well, it looks like we saved the day again.
End of adventure.
Well, I guess if they just left
we should probably high tail it after them.
Yeah, probably.
I quickly like go down
and like take like a little sample of the blood
like a CSI elf, like an ECSI.
Sue put it into your test tube and.
I love that you just said that
cause that's what I was just thinking.
Like I want to say to her, tell us everything
even if it doesn't seem important.
And it's like, I'm not a cop.
Like I'm not.
Even the most minor detail.
Yeah, like I don't know any of the creatures
in this universe,
except for the ones we have explicitly already seen
and I probably forget some of them.
But still for like the sake of character interaction,
exactly.
I like it.
So you take a sample of blood.
I do for.
What do you put your blood in?
I have, well, considering I am a magical druid
I have my satchel, my bag, right?
That can carry many things.
No, not this bag, not yet.
But my bag, my regular bag
has a lot of different little glass jars
and containers in order to gather the things
that I need to create my spells.
Cause there are some spells that need to ship.
All right, good.
And of course I have empty ones
because I need to collect shit.
I'm just looking for you guys to justify things
every now and again.
I justify the shit out of that.
Russ, you just got served.
That's good.
You just got served.
That's right.
I mean, if I didn't have an answer whipped up for that
I'd be like, I get a cup from the kitchen
and put it in there.
It would be a bit of a power move
to chase an enemy,
go into the fight and be like, what's this?
Oh, this is a glass of your blood.
It'd be pretty intimidating.
I would have to think so.
I would be intimidated.
Well, I'd be very freaked out.
Amy left should be right back, I assume.
We could try and take guacamole without her.
They're taking guacamole.
Without me?
Yeah.
Oh fuck.
Can I come too?
Yeah, guacamole doesn't go for it.
What is your problem?
I'm hungry.
That's my problem.
So you got the noisiest snack in the house?
I can't open the bag.
This is like when someone is at the movie theater
trying to quietly open their bag
instead of just ripping it open.
Did you not want to get a bowl?
Oh shit.
We'll wait.
No, don't get in louder things.
She picked up a mouse pad wrapped in a plastic bag
and was like, I'll use this.
So good.
She really took that sass note to heart.
Yeah, yeah.
I think both of the Moors did.
You're good now.
Oh, another bag.
Amy's fully work this episode is amazing.
Hi.
Oh, stellar.
This is her collecting the blood in a Ziploc bag.
There are no snacks.
She's making all these noises.
That's what I was just gonna say, little do we know.
She's not even getting snacks.
She's making this all up
just for the amazing theater that she's creating.
So Thea, can we take guacamole
to chase the blind werewolves?
For sure.
Well, they have white eyes.
It's not necessarily that they're blind.
Well, we don't even know if they're covered in hair.
I know, I was just picturing them like cataracty.
Well, like goats.
Yeah, like kind of milky.
Like big freaky eyes.
You're looking, Russ is staring at me.
Like I've got a walnut in my hand
and he's just staring me down.
Like how much fucking noise are you gonna make with that?
They can more work for us.
Okay, what are you guys doing?
We are hopping on the back of my giant owl
and we're gonna soar and like,
I don't know, get a bird's eye view.
See if we can.
Sure, you guys say you're gonna go out the back
and see if you can't track down whatever creature it is
and Baron is going to take Sasha back to the house
where everybody had set up camp.
It is still the middle of the night.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, I have a question.
Are they gonna be safe walking?
I don't know.
Sasha, how did you manage to cut the beast
if you couldn't move when they were near you?
Didn't the beast probably get cut going through the window?
Seemed like a lot of blood for a window.
She says, I don't think,
I don't know if I cut the beast.
Oh, okay.
Just assumed with the amount of blood
there was probably some sort of struggle.
It could have cut itself somewhere,
somewhere else.
Seems suspicious.
Let's get on the owl.
Okay, two, three, Lee.
I can never tell if Russ just isn't ready
for the question or if that's how he's actually
reacting as the NPC.
That's why he's so, yes, exactly.
I never know if the character is being wily
and we need to interrogate them more
or if Russ is like, it doesn't fucking matter,
let's move on.
Why are you asking about this?
His face gives nothing away either.
He just has this dickish smile on his face.
I was thinking at least when we played in the same room,
sometimes he could be like dudes.
Just with his body language, he could say dudes.
Just a total slump of my body.
Yes, exactly.
The defeat in his eyes as we focus
on something completely irrelevant.
All right, well, let's hop on this owl.
Okay, we run out the back door
and I whistle for guacamole and she swoops down.
Sure.
You hop onto her, you see footsteps leave the house
and their house backs onto the little ways onto the forest
and they run straight for the forest.
Through the forest.
With your owl or without your owl?
How thick is this forest?
If we were flying above the trees,
would we be able to see down?
It's fairly thick in most parts.
Of course it is.
On foot we go.
Well, that was a bitching ride on guacamole.
He's still around for like three days, right?
Guacamole is a girl, but yes.
Oh yeah, sorry.
Yeah, that's okay.
So into the dark woods we go.
Fly up on guacamole,
but you see that it is quite thick in most areas
and you determine that you probably won't be able
to see something walking around.
I instruct guacamole to go,
to still fly above the forest and like circle around
because the owl has amazing eyesight.
So there's a good chance that if something happens,
I tell her to like do a loud owl cry.
Sure.
Or she can be there to snag us up
if we get into trouble.
Exactly.
I love it.
You go off on foot into the forest.
Do you want to make a?
I don't care what it is.
Yeah.
I rolled a 14.
Now tell me what it was and I'll add my bonus.
Is it nature?
Cause I'm proficient in that.
I was going to say probably nature, yeah.
Perfect.
That is 18 for me.
19 if we're going with survival.
20.
Okay, so you quite easily follow the footprints
for quite a while.
I take it you guys are probably moving fairly quickly.
Mm-hmm.
We're trying to catch them.
You get a good distance into the forest
and it's quite thick and dark there
and the footprints seem to disappear.
And as you kind of stop and you're looking around
trying to find where they went or what happened to them,
you hear a small cry for help coming up
from further into the woods
and you hear small footsteps
running in roughly your direction.
Can I see?
I think you guys can both see in the dark, can't you?
I have dark vision.
Yeah.
Within 60 feet.
So can I see this person?
Is this person like within 60 feet in front of us?
You don't see them directly.
There's a fair number of trees and stuff.
Oh, okay, right.
Yeah.
But you don't see them directly
in your field of vision at this moment.
You can more or less tell
which direction they're coming from
and it's the direction that you were traveling in.
And they are coming towards us?
Yep, roughly in the direction that you guys are,
you hear them coming towards you.
I say we call out and ask if they need help
or who they are.
Mm-hmm.
Do that in your character voice.
Someone has to join me.
Come on, you guys.
I'll work on it for next time.
Hello.
Who's out there?
It's me, Lent.
I'm over here.
And you guys can pick up pretty closely
the direction that it's coming from
and it sounds like a child's voice.
We run.
So you run in the direction you think it is
and you eventually come to a small boy
and he looks like he's in some tattered clothes
and it looks like he has been running for quite a while.
He's a little bit out of breath
and he finds you and he looks a little uncertain
because obviously he doesn't know who you are.
But he says, can you help, help me?
Is he a human boy?
Yes.
Of course we can help you.
What's chasing you?
The, I don't know what it is,
but it took me from my house
and took me to this place and there's lots of bones
and it's not good.
It's okay.
Thea has an affinity for children
and she crouches down and hugs the little boy.
So thank you.
I, it's back in the woods there.
I don't want to go back for fear that he'll get me.
Fair enough.
Can Guacamole take him back?
We'd have to go all the way out of the woods, I think.
I don't know if Guacamole can like
burst down through the tree.
Can he burst down through the trees?
He can just climb up the tree, can't he?
Well, yeah, I mean, you could find
a bit of a clearing patch, yeah.
What's your name, little boy?
Oh wait, Lent, right?
Lent.
Lent or Lent?
Lent, L-E-N-T.
I gave up cider for you.
Okay, so we go in, we find a clearing
and maybe Guacamole can take Lent back to the village?
Yeah, yeah, so you find a clearing,
Guacamole comes down and he looks a little scared
of your giant owl.
She's really nice.
Wait, did he tell us where this lair was in detail?
Or what the creature looked like
just to make sure there's not
a other creature we're after?
He didn't yet because he didn't ask, but.
Well, sorry.
He said there's this cave that he has been keeping me
in and other people from my village.
And it's further back into the woods
the way I was running.
I didn't know which way to go once I got out
so I pretty much just kept running.
I don't know what direction specifically I took.
The creature that I saw, he was big, he was really big
and he was always kind of hunched over
and had a robe or a cloak on, something like that.
And he had scary eyes, scary eyes.
Was there only one of them or was there two?
There was only one that I saw.
I don't know if there are more.
What is he doing with all the people?
Eating them.
Well, you're safe now.
So just hop on up on the owl
and Guacamole will take you home.
Okay.
I instruct Guacamole to come back after she's done dropping.
Sure.
So he hops on and holds on to.
The saddle.
The saddle, obviously.
I couldn't remember if there was a saddle or not.
Yep.
Hops on and holds onto the saddle
and Guacamole takes off and you hear a little
as he's going up into the air and then flies away.
To the cave.
I assume like, I know he's a little kid
but he also was running for his life.
So he probably left sort of like a thrashed out trail
from the cave, right?
Oh, I would imagine so.
I think someone out running something
is not really caring about whether or not
they're breaking twigs.
Exactly.
I'm a master tracker.
So I think we should just probably be able
to go to the cave or at least follow the path
that he ran away from the cave in.
So we head in that direction.
Yeah, so you guys go back to where you met him
and you are quite easily able to follow his footprints
because obviously he's not trying to cover anything up
and you make it to a very dark cave
that's carved into the side of a large hill
that's back in these forests.
Okay, guys, what's the plan?
Rush in like foolish maniacs, like normal.
Ooh, tempting.
Or our other plan where you turn into a small creature
and go suss things out.
What do you guys feel in tonight?
We do only have two plans, don't we?
We basically do those two things.
We also, I guess, could send Donnie in there
because he can also see in the dark.
Oh yeah, let's send Donnie.
So Donnie's gonna fly in sneakily, he's very small,
and see what he can see
and then send us some telepathic messages back.
Sure, so you send Donnie in there
and he's in there for a few minutes
before you start getting any word from him
and you start seeing images of,
it's very, there is no light in there.
Everything's very, very dark and dank,
but you see images of piles of bones.
There are a couple people in makeshift cages
that look like they're in similar garb
to the people from the city you were in, Little Rock,
but you don't see any creature
that you think you're looking for anyways.
So you see a couple humans in cages
and lots of bones, both human and animal bones as well.
Can Donnie fly down and look at the cages
and see how they are fastened?
Yeah, they're very tightly tied with thin rope.
Thicker than twine, but thinner than rope
and it just looks like it's very well knotted.
So as the people inside can't easily get out.
Can Donnie try and chew through it?
Yeah, yeah, he could probably chew through it.
Cause if the creature's not there,
we should try and get these people out.
Yep, do you want him to chew through it now?
Sure.
He chews through it and the people inside
look like they were kind of asleep,
but not that halfway between sleep stage
and they hear their doors open, but they aren't,
they look a little concerned about leaving the cages.
Can Donnie give them some kind of vision
of, well, maybe Little Rock,
where we just were or something
so that they understand where we're coming from?
He manages to explain through some images and stuff
that you guys are from Little Rock
and they were sent here to try and help
and that the path looks clear to the cave door.
And it looks like they are getting up and leaving.
Yay.
So they slowly make their way out of the cave
and you meet them at the cave entrance
and they say, who are you?
Are you here to help us?
Yes, we are.
We're here to get you out.
That's good.
We might go quickly before it comes back,
before they come back.
They?
Yes, yes.
How many are there?
Two that we've seen.
Should we send the people home?
Via owl.
And go and get in the cages and jump them?
You don't think they might notice
that they used to have two people
and now they have three people and a pseudo dragon?
Is there only two people?
I thought there was like a group of people.
There are two people, a man and a woman.
Do they look okay?
Are they okay like health-wise?
Yeah, they look more or less like the kid,
a little beaten up, clothes tattered,
but more or less they look okay at this point.
What are your names?
The man says, my name's Landon and this is Umara.
We're from Little Rock.
You are?
We are the.
I was hoping someone knew to fill that in.
That'd be very organic.
We are the.
Oh, I was waiting.
Tom, I thought you were gonna come up
with something really weird.
I got nothing.
We are the.
Thea, Nularaaaa and Flint, okay.
We're trying to come up with a clever name for our team.
It'll happen, it'll happen, it'll happen.
We already got little Lent home.
Lent, Lent died a while ago.
Oh, this isn't good, guys.
God, come on.
Russ, you think they can't be the bad guys?
Always with this shit.
No, you know what, I fucking knew it.
I contact Guacamole.
If you fucking killed my owl.
How long's your range on Guacamole?
We, it's telepathic.
Yeah, but there's a specific range.
There is no range.
There is a range.
I can't believe you pulled the like,
there hasn't been a Lent here in 60 years.
You know, I almost said earlier
that if this is another like witch situation
like we had in that goddamn forest before,
I was gonna lose my mind.
Russ as a DM wants us to not trust anyone.
That then makes us feel so guilty
if someone is not a bad person
and we don't trust them.
Yeah, if I was like, and I fucking murder the kid.
Exactly.
He would have been like,
well, turns out it wasn't the kid after all.
Turns out you murdered an innocent child.
I reach out.
Guacamole, yeah, you do your telepathic thing
with Guacamole,
and Guacamole is already on the way back to you.
So she's dropped off the kid.
Okay, how close is she?
Is it better to just get her to come
and pick up these people
and then drop them back off in the city of Mayhem?
Guacamole should probably just pick us up.
Yeah, it sounds like we just sent the big bad
back to the city on winged owl.
So maybe we should take that same route back.
Yeah, I think we should, I think we might.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Sure.
Kid's creepy ass.
Oh Russ, you've done it again.
Oh man.
Okay, so we can get on Guacamole's back,
but I'm sorry,
you two are gonna have to be carried via claw.
Okay.
You'll be fine.
They'd be less scared.
Sounded a lot more menacing than it actually is.
It's actually delightful.
There's no time to lose people, come on.
But like it's totally fine guys,
don't worry about it, you're totally safe.
They say, okay, we could be on board for that.
We run to the clearing that we were at before.
Yep.
And Guacamole meets you there
and everybody gets on board.
Pretty sure we're pushing the limits
of what your owl can carry at this point.
But you know what though,
Guacamole is just gonna have to push through.
It's fine.
It's an emergency.
She just doesn't fly as fast.
Little adrenaline.
Little adrenaline pumps through and away you go.
What if these people are the bad people now?
Like what if Russ is pulling a double switch on us?
Cause there's two of them.
And now I can't trust anything.
Okay, so now that we're in the air and we're flying,
Guacamole has them in her claws.
Perfect.
Let's interrogate them.
Can we roll some sort of check at least
to see if we can figure anything out
before we interrogate them?
I detect magic.
I do detect magic on them, right?
If they're shapeshifters.
I should have done that.
I thought about doing that on the kid.
Oh, I thought about so much stuff with that damn kid.
We were all trying to be nice this time.
Damn it.
Maybe we should be the untrusting three.
The too trusting three.
Our DM has ruined us.
Exactly.
I rolled a perception check,
but I didn't perceive very much.
So nevermind.
Yeah, they look like people.
Solid perception.
I swear to God, I used detect magic in the last.
I thought so too.
Oh, I do.
I have it because it's on my heart.
You do have detect magic.
Well, you had it before.
Yes, I certainly did.
Long story short,
you don't detect magic on either of these.
I just wanted to make sure you could do it.
See?
See why we don't trust you.
Kidding.
Okay, maybe we should ask these people
if they've ever seen these evil things
like shapeshifters.
Absolutely.
Whenever they've come into the cave,
it's usually,
they're usually rather big.
I've never seen them change form,
but that doesn't mean they can't.
It just means we've never seen them do that.
It's very philosophical of you.
Shouldn't you be yelling this all
because you're in an owl claw high above the trees.
I've never seen them do anything like that before.
Thank you.
I feel so safe.
I'm very relaxed in this giant owl claw.
While you interrogate me.
She has a gentle caress.
And you guys come up to the edge of the city
where you want Guacamole to set you down.
Yes, edge of the city.
I instruct Guacamole to take us
to where he or she dropped off Lent
or the Lent imposter.
Yeah, and she takes you to the house
that was the barricade point for the people you met.
Oh, shit.
There's gonna be a fucking massacre in there, you guys.
We've really messed this one up.
And drops you at the front door.
And you go in and everything seems to be okay.
Everybody kind of looks to you expectantly,
but you don't see the boy.
Where's the boy?
What boy?
Oh, fuck.
The old lady says, what are you talking about?
Also, also a muppet.
Okay, so we messed up a little bit.
What do you mean?
We met a boy named Lent
and we sent him back to town.
But then these two,
gesturing of course to land in Enumara.
They wave.
They said Lent's dead.
The old lady says,
Lent was one of the first boys to go missing
of our people.
So yeah, we assume he's been dead for quite a while.
Well, we saw him in the forest
and I hugged him and everything
and he seemed really weird.
Now that's, that's not good.
No, no.
So we've just unleashed a Lent looking thing
into the city.
Our apologies.
Did anything happen here while we were gone?
Sasha and Baron showed up
and we saw your owl swoop by.
But when we went and kind of looked out,
it flew off and we didn't see anybody.
Oh, okay guys.
It was just a ghost.
Don't worry about it.
Oh, perfect.
Yeah, but I hugged it.
You can't hug ghosts.
Who says what you can and can't do
to ghosts in this world?
I suppose.
Is everybody from town in this stronghold?
Yes, yes.
Everybody that's left is here.
There are about 10 or 15 people within this main room.
And then she says there's some more people
in the bedrooms upstairs,
a couple of people in the kitchen.
But yeah, everybody is now in this house
that is left in the town.
Well, that's good news.
The bad news is it's a shapeshifter,
so could be any of us.
Oh goodness.
Or maybe it's not.
Maybe Thea just hugged a ghost.
I don't know.
Maybe I did.
I like that option better.
Maybe Thea should run another archana chair.
I'd do that.
From this room, you can see upstairs that go upstairs.
Helpful.
There's the kitchen.
Hey, those stairs could go downstairs.
Could have.
Could go downstairs.
Yeah.
But they go upstairs.
Okay.
Not big on basements here apparently.
So the stairs that go upstairs,
there is a feeling of some sort of magic
coming up or down the stairs there.
I, am I like a snake?
Am I like, there's like just a hint, guys.
Just a hint of magic happening.
Well, you get like a glow off of it, right?
So.
Let's follow the yellow brick glow.
So you go upstairs
and there is more of the mist
that you saw in the room with Sasha.
And it's coming out of one of the bedrooms
and you can hear inside singing.
Oh, I kicked that door down.
That's right.
I'm just, I'm making an executive decision.
I'm gonna use that.
No time for singing.
I want to Jean-Claude Van Damme that door down.
You kick in the door and you very clearly startle.
There are a man and a woman and her daughter in there
and the daughter was singing.
And they kind of jump up and huddle together
in the corner.
Is there more mist in the room?
Yeah.
Is there like a glow?
Is it coming particularly from a place?
Yeah, there is.
Sorry.
Like I'm like a bloodhound on the glow trail.
Yeah, there is.
This room has quite a lot of the mist.
No one else can see this mist.
Are you asking somebody that?
Yeah.
Well, yeah.
Like everybody can see the mist.
And they don't find,
they're just hanging out in the mist room.
Like they're hot boxing in the mist room.
What are you doing in this misty room?
Fuck, I don't know.
What do you say after you kick a door in?
Hey, what's going on here?
Mist be gone.
We were just having some quiet time with our family.
What in the creepiest of all of the rooms?
What do you mean creepy?
I can barely see a foot in front of my face.
Okay, it's not that much of a mist.
It's not like a fog.
It's a wall of mist.
I'm imagining it to be like,
I open the door and-
John Carpenter's The Fog.
There's like-
Yes.
It's a light misty aura about the room.
Do you not notice the light misty aura about this room?
Well, yeah.
It's been happening since-
Since when?
For quite a while.
How long has it been like this?
Figured it was like a fog thing.
How long?
Well, since people started going missing.
This room in particular?
Not this room specifically, just-
How when to this room?
Within the room, like tonight.
I thought it was just like a cold,
cold mist form. How many minutes?
A lot of-
Are we talking like an hour?
Well, like a few.
It started a little while ago.
I turn back toward them.
Probably since we accidentally dropped off the lens.
Seems to line up.
Also, who doesn't notice that there's a mist
that comes to town at the same time
as people start disappearing?
I glare at these family that we just kicked in their door.
I have no remorse.
I trust no one now.
The-
I have a little girl.
The man kind of adjusts his glasses
with his middle finger, as you say that.
Pushing it up on the bridge of his nose
and says, well, I guess we didn't put two
and two together.
That mist might mean not good things.
Well, there's some things specifically not good
about what's going on in this room.
How have any of you been separated in the last two hours?
I'm talking bathroom breaks.
Did you implement the buddy system or not?
Well, yeah, I mean, we've used the bathroom.
That was your first mistake.
All three of you or just one of you.
My wife went.
My daughter went.
In what order?
My wife and then my daughter.
And when your wife went, were you with the daughter?
Yes.
The whole time.
You didn't even go get a snack.
There's not much snacks here.
There's not many snacks here.
Sorry, we're not as intuitive
and intelligent for your likings.
There is something wrong here.
She call you the hoity-toity.
I'm making a scene now.
Thea was a scribe.
She's very particular about language, it's fine.
As you are having this argument,
the mist seems to be swirling around you,
specifically Thea.
Oh God, I've anchored the mist, you guys.
Just blow really hard.
Yeah, I just kind of kick and blow at it.
You don't feel like it's doing anything to you,
but it is swirling around you
as you are interrogating this family.
Okay, there's something mystical about this family,
you guys.
I would detect magic,
but I have a feeling like it's just.
But you're surrounded by a glowing mist,
so you feel like it might be redundant.
There might be plenty of magic already going on.
Can she feel it?
Sorry, Russ, I think you might've just said that.
Can she?
Yeah, it's not hurting me.
Nothing is happening, it's just.
She doesn't, she feels like the breeze of it
moving around a bit,
but it doesn't feel like there's any sort of substance
to it.
Okay, which one of you is doing this?
Fess up.
They all look to each other.
No, shaking your head isn't gonna do anything, fess up.
I think we're not doing anything to you.
The husband and wife are shaking their heads
and the little girl is just looking down.
Great, I'm glad now we automatically suspect children.
Another guilty child.
Oh my God, this is the worst.
I switched tactics.
I switched tactics and I'm like,
listen, listen, I'm sorry.
We had an awful experience.
We found little Lent, but it wasn't him.
It was somebody in his body
or pretending to look like him.
And we're just trying to make sure
that the house is secure.
As you're doing this,
the little girl starts to sing again.
Oh my God.
What's she singing?
She sings.
Lock the door, blow out the light.
The hungry Oni haunts the night.
Hide and tremble.
Oh my God.
It'll want to be fun.
I'm gonna have nightmares now.
Yeah, so.
The Oni wants to have some fun.
Oh gross.
I turned to her parents and I'm like,
that's a lovely ditty, you teacher.
Like dudes, this ain't normal.
Hey there, long time no see.
It's me, your dungeon master Russ More.
And this is episode nine of Dumbgeons and Dragons.
This one titled A Hunter in Little Rock part one.
This is the episode where I think it's really
becoming evident how little trust in me
as the DM the players have.
And you know what?
That's okay by me.
What's a little fear of children among friends?
They can be scary.
I know, I have one.
We didn't do any comments or feedback in the last episode
so we have a few today that I would like to get to.
So let's kick that off right now.
Tackle Maniac 777 from the US says,
great D&D podcast.
If you're a fan of Dumbgeons and Dragons,
then this is the podcast for you.
Russ and co do a great job
and every episode is filled with tons of fun and laughs.
Highly recommended to anyone into D&D.
Disco Sist from Great Britain says,
awesome, love listening to your adventures.
Nerds with Words from the US says,
great D&D podcast.
I absolutely love playing D&D
and I love listening to you guys play.
Very creative gameplay.
Super highly recommended.
All super kind words.
So thank you from the bottom of our hearts
to everyone listening and leaving reviews
on iTunes for us.
It really truly helps out a lot.
So if you have a little bit of time,
please go ahead and do that.
If you don't use iTunes
and you've got something on your mind,
you can send us a note to DumbDragonPodcast at gmail.com
and we'll read them the same way we do the iTunes reviews.
Any and all we get certainly help out a boatload.
But there is another way you can help us
and that's by referring our podcast
to your friends and family.
You can just send them over to DumbDragons.com.
All of our social media and email links
are listed there.
On Twitter, we are at DumbDragonCast.
You can use the DumbDragonCast hashtag
so we can track you down
and find out if you're talking at us.
On Facebook, we're at Facebook.com slash DumbDragonCast.
Twitter is certainly the place to get the quickest response
as I am on that account quite frequently
throughout the day.
And you can also send us an email like I mentioned
to DumbDragonPodcast at gmail.com.
We do certainly read every review
and mention on Facebook and Twitter.
So please keep sending those in
and they will likely get read on the show.
That's enough for me though.
Let's jump right back in.
Episode 10 will be available April 12th
and that will be the continuation
of this Hunter in Little Rock side quest.
You have a most wonderful couple of weeks
because you know what?
You deserve it.
And I can't wait to talk to you again.
Back to the episode.
Let's find out how many more trust bridges I can burn
before this one's over.
We'll see you later.
They kind of looked at us and said,
well, that's a children's lullaby that, you know,
we tell kids to scare them into listening
to their parents.
I was, the only is going to come and get them.
The only is not real.
Anything horrible when they say, the only is not real.
And then the only burst through the closet.
No, the little girl stands up and begins to shift shape.
Ah, the fuck.
Yeah, she does.
And she grows into a large.
Oh, I'm going to get to see a picture.
I'm not going to show you the picture.
It's an audio medium.
You used to show pictures.
This was more fun in Canada.
You see a giant or ogre looking creature
with dark blue skin, very dark hair.
It has a set of ivory horns protruding from its forehead.
The eyes are dark, but the pupils are strikingly white.
And it has very sharp razor teeth
and claws that are jet black.
Do we scare you guys?
Well, let's fucking kill them.
Before we roll for initiative,
you make a charisma saving throw.
A charisma saving throw?
Well, that was shitty.
Nine.
I'm not very charismatic today.
You feel like you don't want to hurt this thing.
Ah, shit.
Roll for initiative.
I have a three.
I rolled a 20.
Nice.
15.
No, I hate it when I wasted on initiative.
What a waste.
I know.
God damn it.
I mean, good for you, but.
I know, but then I get a fucking one on my attack roll.
That's okay.
Well, yeah.
No, Laura, you're up first.
Perfect.
I pull out flame tongue.
I whisper Mui Caliente, and then I roll an amazing.
Oh, 19.
That will do because I get,
I don't even remember anymore,
but to plus something amazing.
It's like nine or something stupid like that.
I think it is nine.
Why can't I remember how to play this game?
Yep, plus nine.
It really hasn't been that long.
You know, but I feel like we haven't had a fight in a while.
Only almost two years.
And we're fighting children, so.
I know.
Not fighting a child anymore.
So that is a 28.
By the way, Rusty,
these parents just like freak the fuck out
when this thing transforms.
The parents, yeah, the parents lose their shit.
And they are working their way towards the door.
They're still in the room,
but they're not quite frozen in fear,
but they're just kind of scooching along,
screaming and not having a great time
that their kid just turned into this giant monster.
Scream, scooching.
Scream, scooching, yep.
Classic.
Sorry, it was wisdom saving throw.
So you had.
I didn't do a wisdom saving throw.
I know.
So.
That gives me an 11.
You still feel friendly towards this creature.
Friendly, like I'm not gonna be able
to participate in the battle.
We'll see once it gets to your turn.
So sorry, yeah, Noir, you're hit.
Eight damage.
It was a 28, which I assume hit.
Yeah, 28.
Okay, so eight damage.
Second attack.
Not so good.
14.
14 is not a hit.
Okay, Donnie's gonna go for it
because he's real pissed off at this fake out.
And he got a 20 just with bonuses.
Cool, yep.
Donnie.
And Russ, it's up to you if I do this,
but I actually was reading my notes today
and I've been giving Donnie his normal damage,
which is one D four plus two,
but he's also supposed to get a plus three
for something to do with one of my level ups
that I had forgotten about.
Oh yeah, sure, absolutely.
Okay, so that is five damage from Donnie
and then it needs to do a constitution saving throw.
That is a 15.
Yeah, that's fine, that's fine then.
Oh, Flint.
Oh, I'm gonna bring the pain.
I am not impressed with this whatsoever.
So the first one is a 21.
21 is good, yeah.
Six and 11 is 17 and four, so 21 damage.
And second one is a 18.
18 is still good, yeah.
All right, perfect.
Six again.
10 this time, so plus four is 20.
Okay, and it is his turn.
Donnie's, at the start of their turn,
regain 10 hit points,
as long as they have at least one remaining.
Good lord.
So he will do that.
Is there some way I can learn that skill?
It's called regeneration, you figure that out.
All right, I'll work on it.
You can work on it.
He pulls from his cloak a long glaive,
which is a long spear type rod
with two blades on either end.
And he swings at Flint and he gets two attacks.
So first one is a 13.
Second one is a 19.
I think the 19 hits.
The 19 definitely hits, yeah.
That sounded like a lot of dice.
There's only two dice.
16 slashing damage.
Ow.
He moves himself towards the window in the room.
It's Thea's turn.
And you, Thea, you see your friends hitting the Oni
and you are drawn to stop them from doing that.
Okay.
So you are going to attack one of them.
You are going to try and attack.
Okay.
I'll roll for it just to keep it random.
You are going to attack New Lara.
Okay, sorry, New Lara.
But I get to choose what I attack her with.
Yep.
Okay, so New Lara, this is good.
This is fine.
It's gonna be okay.
Okay.
So I'm going to use hold person
and that is going to be my, okay.
So it doesn't actually cause any damage, but it doesn't.
Why do you have 2D8 fire damage associated to it?
I don't know.
Oh, because I, no, I.
It's not just damage when it's convenient.
Let me look.
Essentially, it just stops you from moving.
But then again, oh wait, do you want that
or do you want to be hurt?
I'm just gonna have to.
Just like hit me with some shitty weapon.
Okay.
I have full hit points.
Don't move me or anything, but.
Okay, no, I wouldn't do that.
I'm gonna use like, oh, I'm gonna use my slingshot.
I'm gonna throw a rock at you.
Perfect.
I mean, I guess not perfect, but.
Roll for your attack.
It's one of those healing rocks.
Four, does a four hit you?
It does not.
Plus two, how about a six?
Even still.
Okay, nevermind.
Perfect.
So I whip it at you and I go just kidding.
The end of your turn, you can save
against the charm that you have over you.
Fuck.
You are still charmed by the Oni
and it's new Lara's turn.
And you guys just see the end aim for new Lara
and now it's new Lara's turn.
You don't know that she is charmed.
Even though she's threw a rock at me?
So I know something's up.
You know something's up,
but you don't know that she has been charmed.
Right.
Player knowledge, character knowledge.
Okay.
Flint, I think that miss did something to her.
She's throwing rocks at me.
That's super weird.
And then, and then I attack the Oni with a 24.
Yep.
And 16 damage on that attack, second attack.
21 and that is seven, 11, 13 damage.
Then Donnie gets in on the action.
He rolls a 20, well he doesn't roll a 20,
and he gets four plus three is seven damage.
And then constitution saving throw for that big bad.
17.
Yeah, that'll, that'll do it.
Flint, you're up.
I'd like to get in the way
in between the window and this Oni
because it seemed like it was making its way over there.
Sure, yeah.
It is currently between you and the window at this point
but there's about five to 10 feet
between it and the window.
All right, well I hustle
and do some sort of awesome powerslide
to get into its way.
Rewind a little bit here.
So you, if you go through his reach, his zone,
there is a chance for an opportunity attack from him.
Okay, that's fine.
So you go to move past him
and get between him and the window
and he tries to reach at you with his claw,
which might not be good.
13.
He doesn't do any damage.
It's like a swipe at me but didn't hit.
Exactly.
So you are now between him and the window.
Excellent.
Cause it's go time.
So 23 on that roll.
Yeah, 23 is good.
Four.
And six, 10 and four is 14.
And second attack.
That's 21 but not critical.
Six, seven, 13 and four, 17.
It's his turn and with that hit,
he's looking noticeable damage to him.
So he's looking a little bloodied there.
And he, when you ran past him,
he kind of turned and followed you
and he looks like he is charging you.
So that'll be 19.
That hits.
He runs into you and is trying to push you
seemingly with him through the window.
So I'll give you a strength saving throw.
To see if you can block him
from pushing both of you out the window.
Strike, don't fail me now.
So that is a 17.
And he rolled a 16.
He runs into you for,
you take four damage off of his hit
but you stop him from vacating the room.
Excellent.
His second attack, he's going to claw at you.
And that is a 25.
Whoa, that definitely hits.
You take eight slashing damage from his claws.
And now it is Thea's turn.
So he's blocking Flint.
So you're going to try and attack Nularaaaa again.
Soaring Nularaaaa.
13 plus.
Yeah, your sling is plus four.
My sling is plus four?
Yeah.
Really?
I'm proficient in slinging.
Apparently.
Does a 17 hit you?
17 does hit me because that matches my AC
and we said that is a hit now, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, and it's a one D three.
One D four plus three.
Five damage.
I'm sorry Nularaaaa.
We're cool.
I can roll for, to break this bubble.
And now you can roll to save, yeah.
Fuh, uh, uh, uh.
Is this a wisdom?
Is wisdom.
So that's seven plus four.
And you have advantage.
Is 11, and which is plus two.
An advantage.
Your wisdom saving throw is seven.
So you got 14 plus two.
So you shake whatever charm he had on you.
And you know that anything you have been doing since then
was because he put the charm on you.
And now it's Nularaaaa's turn.
We'll hug it out later, girl.
Is he facing Flint?
Like, is he facing towards the window?
I think they're in the middle of a man hug right now.
Are they not?
Yeah, they're more or less grappled.
Yeah, to a point, yeah.
Like man hug better, but.
Yeah, so his back is to you and, uh, Thea.
Does that give her advantage?
Whoa.
Stab him in the back.
I'm just worried about Flint now if they're like
locked in a manly embrace.
Nah, you go for it, girl.
I rolled a 17, so that's 28.
Um, where are his feet?
On the floor.
I'd like to chop off one of his legs.
Ah, I'd like to chop off one of his legs.
Or at least like below the knee, something.
Sure, yeah.
Kick slash an Achilles tendon.
Yeah, yeah, you could try that.
So that's 16 damage on that one.
Yeah, you take a good chunk out of his leg there.
So he kind of crumples a little bit under that hit.
Great, I'm going for the other one now.
Kind of reaches off and pulls his hand away from Flint.
So that was a 25.
Okay.
Is he, he's still upright though.
Yeah?
Yeah, he kind of, fall into one knee there
with that last hit.
Okay, so that is seven plus four plus three
is 14.
I'm just gonna try and just stab him right through
with my 14 damage.
Did I say what my roll was?
Did I black out there?
That was a 25.
Yeah, I did.
I was sure you hit him,
but what weapon are you using, your flame sword?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay, so 14 damage.
So you go through the body?
Yeah, just through the body.
Cause he's gonna be dropped away from Flint a bit, right?
Yeah, your sword is now through him.
Yeah, yeah, we could say that.
Okay.
Johnny rolled a 16, does that get him?
Yeah, 16 hits.
Okay, so Johnny gets seven damage.
Even with that new plus three?
Yeah, he only gets to roll one D4 plus five.
So seven damage and then constitution saving throw.
15.
Yeah, it's fine, he's fine.
Johnny did sting someone that one time.
Yes, I remember.
That one time and it was glorious.
It's great, it's so good.
We go to Flint.
How's this thing looking?
It's not looking good.
He's got a sword through his chest.
A flaming sword at that.
A flaming sword through, yeah, the chest shoulder region.
It's got a big chunk taken out of its leg.
It's pulled off of the embrace that it had you in.
It was a sweet embrace.
Oh, he really was.
Yeah, you felt like he just meant good things.
No, you don't buy it?
All right, well, I guess I'm gonna go
for the old killing blow then.
Okay.
So that's a 16,
which I think you said for Carla, hit.
Yep. Perfect.
Six, and six is 12 and four is 16.
Okay, still alive.
Didn't sound like it, kill them.
No.
It keeps getting that stupid plus 10 back, so.
Oh, natch 20.
Not gonna get out of that one.
This doesn't seem like it's gonna go well for this guy.
No, no, probably not.
All right, I've got a ton of things to roll.
Four, six is 10, so 14 on the first one.
11, and four is 15, so 19 on the second one.
33.
Yeah, so you, what are you, what were you doing?
Cause he's dead, go for it.
Well, I was taking a vicious swing
at his head slash neck area.
Yeah, you do that and it comes off,
like when a pool ball hops off the table, it's gone.
And as you do that, the mist that's still in the room
begins to churn a little bit more
and looks like it's reforming as the little girl
that it changed from.
So there is, the little girl is now in the room
with you and the mist is gone.
She has every urge to murder her.
She looks quite scared.
What's your name?
My name is Betha, Betha.
Hi Betha, where were you?
I felt like I was in the room,
but I tried to tell somebody,
but I couldn't, everything I was doing and saying,
I just, no one was listening.
It's okay, sweetie, it's because you were missed.
Well, I'm glad to hear you missed me.
Yeah, okay.
So I'm pretty sure she's just a regular human child.
Okay, human child, let's take you down to your parents.
Did you just call her human child?
I did.
Yeah, let's take her down to her parents
and yeah, not that they really noticed anything wrong
with her before,
because there is still one of these creatures, right?
There was two of them, wasn't there?
That's what everyone had told us.
But maybe we can take her to her-
Thea just came to a realization.
What's that?
If the mist was the girl, where else did we see mist?
Oh, come on, God, at Baran's place,
his sister is another one of those stupid Onis.
Oh no.
Oh man.
I'm trying to redress his facial expression.
I know, but I think, but you must be right, right?
Wasn't that-
There's only one way to find out.
Yeah, let's take her downstairs and find Sasha.
You go down the stairs
and everybody's kind of piled in down at the bottom.
Listening in.
Listening in a little bit.
And Beth runs back to her parents,
the two people that were in the room they had left,
and everybody's there except Sasha and Baran.
Naturally?
They are sitting over in the main living area.
There is still that mist about.
Of course there is.
And Sasha pulls from behind her,
and it seems to grow in her hand another glaive.
And she swings at Baran,
and he takes a big hit to his neck,
and he is down on the ground bleeding.
And she begins to take form of another Oni.
Sweet.
Still gonna die just as hard.
Oh yeah.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin MacLeod of Incompetech.Filmmusic.io.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a Dumb Dragons production.