Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
You, my fine green friend, may call me Grug.
Have you not heard the rumors?
No.
Well, I hate to inform you that a council or their aides are dying.
We're going to go to the morgue to look at a dead body because we're really good at that.
Let's invite Grug too, guys.
To the morgue!
Let's go.
Nularaaaia, you're taking a look at the second body and you see marks around his neck.
I'm going to speak with that one.
I cast Speak With Dead.
Why did you die?
She compelled me to do what I did, though.
What did she look like?
Long red hair, eyes as black as night, and she wears red silk robes.
How did you come across this woman?
At a tavern in the field ward.
The place is the Lonely Whip.
Grug, do you know where the Lonely Whip is?
We'll have to look around.
Maybe something will jog my memory.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
We are D&D 5th Edition Actual Play Podcast, and I am your Dungeon Master, Russ More.
And not with me today at this very moment are Amy More, Carla Johnson, and Tom Laird, and Spence Joe.
We split this into two episodes, so I'm just doing the intro real quick here.
They will be joining me very shortly.
I hope you didn't turn it off, like under the assumption that I was going to do a full episode by myself.
We'll save that for the Grants' full episode that I know I keep talking about.
I'm just kind of stringing you along until I get it finalized.
Yes, joining me for the second part of this episode will be Amy, Tom, Carla, and Spence Joe,
who we are so grateful could join us and play both of these episodes with us.
So that was fantastic.
All right, guys, fuck it.
Let's play D&D.
You kind of wander the streets and there are there are a bunch of people kind of doing the same things,
but some look at different states of drunkenness as you go by.
It's nighttime now.
Yeah, we're like in the we're in the club zone then.
Is the field like a like a tavern district or something?
It's got some it's got some good good taverns over there.
OK, well, why don't we just ask someone?
It's mostly just massage parlors.
Ask someone.
Hey, who do I see?
You see a very stumbly dwarf looks like an older man.
Oh, it's an old man.
He looks like a young spry man.
And he's he's stumbling towards you has a tankard in his hand that he's he's drinking back from.
Hey, hey there.
Hey, we're looking for the lonely whip.
You tell me where that is.
The lonely whip.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's down down down over.
Down and over.
Six.
See it crouches down and takes a small step to the left.
Am I there?
I like to mess with drunk people.
Yeah, she's there.
You guys, you go down the street.
Whoa.
And cuts over and cuts yourself over a few blocks.
All right, thanks.
Have a good night.
It's a lonely place, though.
The lonely whip mumbles to himself as he walks off.
They're going to they're going to be so sad there.
God, Jesus, your young man sounds old.
He's a dwarf.
He's got a rough voice.
Maybe this is like some sort of like bar rescue operation that we're running.
Yeah.
Is that why it's so sad?
It's just such a pathetic.
I mean, let's go find out.
So we walk down a few blocks and over and we follow this wonderful drink and directions.
And you like it was perfect directions.
You make it just outside the lonely whip.
And it it looks like a pretty rundown, slummy kind of place from the exterior.
Anyways, you go in.
Yeah, I think so.
Thea pushes the door open or pulls.
I have trouble.
You enter and it's it's.
It smells like drunk.
There's alcohol and beer and stuff poured all over the floor.
It's like sticky as you walk in.
I can smell exactly what you're describing.
It's 19 year old Carla has been to this place.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
There are only a handful of people in there at most.
There's one woman tending the bar who does doesn't fit the description that you were that you were given by the corpse.
And then there are five other men, kind of a couple sleeping at the tables they're at.
One man does stand out to you, though.
You recognize him by what he's wearing as a possible knight of the Order of the Gauntlet, which is one of the yeah.
Well, I'm just for all right.
You're telling a story.
And the people listening, the Order of the Gauntlet are one of the main council members of the Council of Waterdeep.
He's sitting alone at a table in the back with his back to you or kind of shoulder to you because you can see the insignia of the Order of the Gauntlet and his fineries that he's wearing right now to look hammered.
He doesn't.
Okay.
He's has a drink, but he doesn't look like he as far gone as the other guys in this building.
Are there any other drinks on the table?
Like, is this is this friend in the bathroom or see by himself?
Sure, no.
He only has the one drink at the table there and appears to be sitting by himself.
Okay, let's go talk to him.
Mm hmm.
And walk up.
Who has a badge?
Whose badge is handy?
I've got mine.
It's attached to me.
I walk up to him.
Is he at the bar?
Is he at a table?
He's at a table.
But his back is to us.
Yeah, he doesn't.
He doesn't directly see you coming.
I like really like smooth like slide into his seat beside him and say, Hey, friend, what you drinking?
You startle him and he jumped.
Oh, Jesus.
Sorry.
Who are you?
I pointed my badge.
Oh, those were the honorary things they gave to those adventurers.
Uh huh.
Yeah.
Right.
Okay.
Can I help you?
What's doing here all alone?
I come and sit down too.
Because you don't want to leave him alone at the end.
Well, no, I just like we're all just like standing there awkwardly.
We would come sit down, right?
Yeah, I think so.
Flammikins is sidled up to the bar and she's like, I'm here with the adventurers, the decimators of dragons.
And the bartender looks at her and shakes her head.
Like, okay.
Flammikins puts a goal down on the table.
I just want to drink.
She's hoping to milk this for all it's worth.
Like, how many free drinks can I get out of this?
All she wanted to do was get drunk and now we're taking her on some murder mystery adventure.
So get that girl a drink.
What are Grug and Flint doing?
Should we grab a different table and just kind of eavesdrop?
Yes, let us drop the eaves.
Do you guys say this real loudly right beside the table?
We'll be like two tables away.
Well, Grug's not very smart.
So probably he said that.
He's got like a booming, you know, singer's voice.
So sorry.
Your question.
What are you doing here?
What are you drinking?
Just the wholesale.
Is it any good?
Yeah.
I'm building rapport.
It's really good.
Thanks.
Good work.
Why are you here?
I don't know him.
What are you doing here all alone?
It's just a tough, tough day.
I just thought I'd come grab a drink.
And that's what I'm doing.
Do you frequent this bar often?
Oh, I'm sorry, Nularaaa.
I'm manhandling the conversation.
That's the word I was looking for.
Yeah, it was.
It's exactly the word Thea was looking for.
Thea, she manhandles the conversation.
You manhandle it.
Flint just shouts that from across the bar.
It looks like you work for the Order of the Gauntlet.
Am I seeing that right?
Yeah.
I just came from a rotation and didn't change my regalia.
Can't you get the free drinks?
I mean, no.
I pay for my drinks.
Good.
Honorable man.
See any hot redheads in here lately?
He kind of gives you like a no.
He's lying.
It's probably good for you.
I don't know.
I cast Zone of Truth.
I don't have to.
You don't have Zone of Truth?
Grug might.
You know what?
I didn't pick it.
Does he say it like, no, I wish?
Or does he say it like weird and suspicious?
Like, why are you asking me that?
Make a perception check.
Oh, I will also perceive.
Oh, I perceive anything.
I'm going to go talk to the barkeep.
I rolled a 20.
I didn't roll a 20, but a 20.
Yeah, he looks like he's being a little cagey.
And we'll resolve that after you're the barkeep.
She sees you walking up and says, what can I get you?
I say, hello, miss.
Has it always been your lifelong dream to run such a depressing establishment?
He's got zero charisma.
Which is weird for a performer, you'd think.
She looks a little taken aback by that statement, but she says it was not my intent to run a place where people come to drink away their sorrows
and not have fun while doing it.
It was my father's dream, and I merely inherited it.
It's a terrible dream to have.
Oh, I guess I asked.
Well, I happen to be a bard who is very knowledgeable of all things fun related.
Would you like to have a fun time at this depressing otherwise place?
I mean, yeah, we would love if you would.
Are you offering to play a song?
I just can't stay here with so many people so sad.
So, yes, I'd like to play them some music.
I would love that. Yes, please do.
I will. All right.
I'll just play in the background here, these little notes while you continue your conversation.
Yes, he does. The knight does look a little cagey to your question.
It seemed like you had kind of a reaction there to our question about the redhead.
Do you want to want to expand on that?
He looks like he's beginning to say something and then stops.
And it says, I'm sorry, I have to be going.
Can I try and intimidate him?
Yeah, sure. You can try.
We can't let him leave.
He's going to go murder, suicide.
That is an 18.
I don't know if you know who we are, but we need to know what's going on.
Can you tell me anything about this woman?
He again looks like he's going to say something and then stops, almost like he's got a pain on his face.
Blank twice if she is compelling you right now.
I don't know what you're asking me. I have to be going.
Hey, do you have any thoughts of murder or suicide?
He looks at you and there's no twang. There's no, no, no.
Why would I have thoughts of murder or suicide?
Sometimes for like medication, it's a side effect.
I just, you know, there's something horrible going on and I think you've been compelled.
There's kind of just a blank look on his face and he goes a bit gaunt and ghostly white, like the blood is draining from his face.
Not like somebody's sucking the blood from his face, but just like he's coming to a realization.
But he doesn't say anything and he tries to push past you.
I try to stop him.
Worst case, we just follow him. So it's fine. You can stop him.
Well, while this is happening, the people that were slumped over sleeping at the tables begin to wake up
and are kind of drawn to the music that's filling the room.
Fuck!
He doesn't push you, so to speak, like he doesn't shove you, but he manages to slide you off and stands up.
I pinch his hiney.
And slaps it away.
I'm just trying to get him to stay. Fine, we're just going to follow you then.
He kind of, with some form of robotic-ness, begins walking towards the door.
Dammit, he's going to go murder or suicide someone.
Well, we have to follow him. There's something going on.
Flameykins! Get that beer to go, girl! And we start following him.
And as you walk by Flameykins, she's telling the bartender a story and she's like,
And that's when I met these fine folks as I was saving their ass from a dragon.
The bartender's just smiling and nodding. Yeah.
And she's like, All right, mom, my ride's leaving. I got to go.
Grug, you coming?
Oh, yeah, yep. I put my guitar away and follow.
The bartender calls to Grug and she throws him a gold piece.
He's like, Grug's got one gold piece.
Come back any time!
Okay, so we follow the knight.
Yeah, you get out into the street and you're, are you saying anything to him or are you just following him?
Just following him. I'm screaming obscenities.
I'm just following him.
You get about, you get about a block away and he stops and turns around and he says,
You need to stop following me.
No, you need to get yourself to someone who can help you with this magic shit that's been cast on you.
Where's Grancis? Not Grancis.
Damn it. Where's Grancis?
I'm going to cast a spell magic on him.
Oh, yeah, do that.
That's what I'm going to do.
So what does that entail? Let's see here.
So any spell of third level or lower on the target ends.
For each spell of fourth level or higher, I make an ability check.
Yeah.
And the DC equals 10 plus the level of this spell that's cast on him.
Yeah, yeah, you're going to need to make a spell check or a saving throw or whatever it is.
It's a charisma, straight charisma, which actually isn't that good.
Oh, five.
Can you cast it again?
I mean, I mean, I got one left.
So he puts his hand on his sword that he has on his belt and says, You need to stop following me.
I'm sorry we can't do that. You're going to hurt yourself or someone else.
He draws his sword. Roll for initiative.
I'm waiting to hear that. Saved what? Numbers.
What is happening, Amy?
Eighteen.
I was going to yell seventeen, but then I knew I had an initiative bonus, but then I couldn't remember if it was a one or a two.
Twenty five.
Jesus Christ.
Fourteen for me.
Plus eight.
Carla's first always.
He gets first action and he pulls his great sword and runs at Thea and swings.
Oh, he can try.
It's only a seventeen.
Yep.
Four slashing damage.
And then it is Nularaaa's turn.
God, we're having this problem again where I don't want to kill this person.
No, no, remember, we can just aim to incapacitate.
So if we get him down to zero hit points, he just passes out.
He doesn't die.
Okay, great.
So, you know, hit him, hit him hard.
Violent, Thea's coming back.
I pull out Flametongue and say Buoy Caliente and fucking roast this guy that has done nothing wrong.
Perfect.
He will do something wrong.
I don't want to hurt them, but I'm going to pull out my most fucking huge weapon to do it.
I'm either stopping him or I'm not.
So that is a sixteen.
Sixteen does not hit.
Okay, then I'll take another swing.
That is a twenty.
Twenty will hit.
Okay.
Sixteen damage.
Okay, go Donnie.
Donnie's going to try and sting him.
So that is a sixteen, which obviously doesn't hit.
But he gets a second attack now and that is an eighteen.
Eighteen will hit.
Okay.
So he gets five damage and he has to do a con save, I think, for eleven.
Okay, so two things happen on this.
Okay.
Donnie stings him.
Everybody make a perception check.
Sixteen.
Eight.
Lots.
Twenty-seven.
Sure.
All of the perception.
You see something come back to him and he utters the single word succubus.
And then he's unconscious from Donnie's sting.
Donnie, my man.
One shot.
So we're dealing with a succubus.
Okay.
Well, now we know what we're dealing with, so that's a positive.
Still don't know how we're going to find a succubus.
Anybody have a find succubus spell, Thea?
Anything?
No, but I mean, they're like...
Succubuses are fiends.
Do you not have something about fiends, Carla?
Or is that something different?
I don't think I have something about fiends.
They are not one of my favorite enemies, if that is what you are asking.
That is what I was asking.
Okay.
That being said, I could...
Yes.
I like what you're saying.
You're not saying anything, but I know you are, actually.
I am going to...
If we find out where the succubus lives, I think I have a spell that can...
Is it called kill succubus?
No, it's called find the path.
Maybe we can go back to the bar and ask if anyone knows of a succubus that lives nearby.
Maybe we could interrogate this guy.
Maybe we should tie him up and wake him up.
Throw him in a river.
Classic.
Classic idea.
Well, the best way to dispose of a body really is to eat it.
Oh, God.
Just goes back to nature after that, right?
He is stung until he takes damage or he is shaken awake.
So, I mean, in theory we could restrain him.
Sure.
Yeah.
You know, there's four of us and one of him.
So even if he wakes up while we're tying him up, it's fine.
Sure.
Flynn could just sit on him.
That's true.
And then...
So you're just tying him up with some rope?
Yeah.
Okay.
And then who's shaking him awake?
I slap him in the face.
Okay, so you slap him in the face.
He startles awake.
He appears to be more lucid now than the stone-faced man you were talking to.
So sorry.
That hurt.
Where can we find this succubus?
I was supposed to meet her tonight, but she hadn't shown up before you.
She also has a place where I've met her not too far from here.
How are you feeling?
Are you still...
Do you feel less under her control?
You're talking to us now, so...
I can normally, like, all through our conversation, I could hear her in my head
talking to me and telling me what to do and say.
And I don't get that now.
She's aware of us.
Where does she live?
He gives you pretty good directions to a place in the same district
and not too far from where you are.
Should we bring him with us?
I don't think I should go near her.
If she's had her control over me once before, I don't want that again.
I'm really...
Yeah, she'll use them against us.
Yeah, that's true.
I'm also really worried that you're going to hurt someone.
If you could just go and lock yourself up in, like, the prison or something,
that'd be wonderful.
Just until we get this whole succubus thing taken care of.
Okay.
Yeah.
Can you untie me?
Partially.
Like, maybe the feet, sure.
Okay.
So I can walk.
That would be good.
Yeah.
And then I'll head right to the guards.
To the guards.
And tell them that you've been compelled.
Yep.
And that this is for everyone's safety.
Yes.
Don't stop on the way.
Can't stop won't stop.
So yeah, we untie his feet and prop him up.
Yeah.
And he heads off towards the nearest guard post, which is in the vicinity.
Okay.
Let's go find a succubus.
Yep.
You follow the directions and it takes you, I don't know,
it takes you 15 or 20 minutes to get to the place.
What do you guys know about succubi?
Sweet F.A.
Do you have lore or anything?
Arcana?
Yeah.
What about Arcana?
No?
History?
Yeah.
History.
Maybe religion would be, they're demonic, right?
Yeah.
I'd say either, either history or religion,
depending on whatever anybody thinks.
I'm switching.
I'm switching dice.
25 to my history check.
Flint, you know that succubus and incubus,
the male versions of them, inhabit the lower plains
and are dark winged fiends that can be used to service
devils and demons and all sorts of evil, no good doers.
Sweet.
They're slutty bitches too, aren't they?
Legend speaks of them and says that they are corruptors.
So they appear in an ethereal form first when they find a target.
So they latch onto someone who they know is of weak mind
and they appear to them in this ethereal form
and kind of like in a dreamlike state.
And they cast charm on them
and they get them to do their bidding, whatever that might be.
Okay.
And when they're done with them,
what they usually do is they have what's called a draining kiss.
So they basically suck the life out of their target.
The fact that these murder suicides have been
breaking that knowledge of succubus,
you know something different might be going on,
but that's what you know about them.
When they are confronted, they usually aren't alone.
They're usually sent up from these lower planes
with something else or someone else.
Sweet.
And when they do have this bond with whatever their target is,
you've heard that they can maintain that bond,
whether they're on this plane or their own plane.
So it doesn't matter where they are.
Whereas most charm things,
they have to be on the same plane within a certain range,
succubus can maintain it always.
Are succubus fey?
No.
What?
Really?
Are they elemental?
They are fiends.
Oh, they're fiends.
Fuck.
Yeah.
All right.
So we got to kill this thing dead.
What?
So let's go check her place and see if she's there.
What is this place that he's given us directions to?
It is a dark rundown,
looks like nobody lives there kind of house.
It's got torn up curtains.
There doesn't appear to be any light on the interior.
It has a single entrance.
There are several windows along the top floor and the main floor.
There is a door around the rear as well.
Shall two of us go around and sort of go in from both entrances?
Or do you want to just bang down the front door?
Splitting up probably sounds like a good idea.
I mean, it's not like we're how big is the house?
It's not like we're really splitting the party, right?
We're just like slaggy.
It is.
It's a small.
Well, it's not a huge house.
But yeah, so.
Okay.
Yeah, it's not not like going in one side of a dungeon versus the other side of the dungeon.
Exactly.
It's a it's just a standard house.
Yeah.
I bet she's just a standard succubus.
Just a standard.
Probably.
Okay.
You guys want to all stick together?
That would be fine, too.
But I think we should go through the back.
I will go with with this big guy.
Which big guy?
Well, there's only yeah.
I mean, I'm rather short.
Tom's small of stature, but huge and buff.
Big personality.
Okay.
No, that's what I was going to suggest is that, yeah, Thea should go with someone strong.
All right.
Let's let's go check out that back door.
Who's entering the back door first?
I will.
Is it?
Oh, I try it.
I try it to see if it's unlocked.
It is unlocked.
All right.
Then I go in first.
Yes.
Are you going in stealthy like?
Are you going in?
Not much point.
Loot out.
Let's let's try it.
No, there's no joke happening here.
So your roles are my roles today.
I don't think maybe we should have gone together.
You I don't know how bad it was, but you crash in the door.
It's a six.
Okay.
Yeah, you're not quiet.
Do we hear that from the front?
I mean, probably.
They made it in.
I sling my loot.
I'm like.
Demon!
Face me.
I think we better go in as well.
So we'll come in the front too.
Grug goes in and Grug, you see what looks to be like a kitchen area, and it quickly
disappears from your sight and you are suddenly in total darkness.
Flint and Nularaaaa and Flamikinskins, what are you doing up front?
Is the door unlocked?
It is unlocked.
Okay.
Then I think we just go in.
Flint, what do you think?
Yeah, that sounds like a good idea.
Okay.
You go in and you see there's a set of stairs that goes directly upstairs.
There's a living area and then a hallway that shoots straight to the back, which
looks very dark at this point.
Use the banana ball.
Both of you make a perception check as you walk into.
14.
26.
Flamikinskins got a seven.
Nularaaaa, you see out of the corner of your eye zip past like a flash of white in the
living area that draws your attention in there.
Guys, did you see that?
That flash that just went in that direction.
I didn't see anything.
I was looking at the lovely architecture of this here house.
A weird observation.
Nope, nope.
Must have missed it.
Okay.
Well, flashing light that way.
Our friends that way.
Which way do you want to go?
Well, if you saw something, we should probably follow it.
Okay.
Let's go this way then.
Hey, Thea and Grug, what are you doing?
We're in the dark.
You're in the dark.
I'm gonna aside.
I haven't entered yet.
Grug, you are in the dark.
Thea, you have not entered yet.
Do I see just a dark...
I'm assuming we walked into the kitchen.
Is that?
Yeah, that's the kitchen area.
I put on my helm and I cast light on the two horns on top of it.
And therefore, I have a 20 foot radius, maybe?
Now, looking in, do I see just a dark room?
Yeah.
It was pretty dark when you saw him go in, but as you step to the door, you can't see him or anything else.
Oh, even with my dark vision?
Nothing.
No.
Okay.
Does that help at all or is this some kind of freaky magic, freaky darkness?
No, yeah, no, yeah, because yeah, it's magical light.
Yeah, you can see, but Thea, you still cannot see him.
Okay.
So you don't see any...
Sorry, Grug, you don't see any figures or anything like that.
It just illuminates the room and it looks shadowy.
It's not as bright as you would think that it would be when you normally cast this spell.
I yell in, Grug, you okay, buddy?
All good so far, but there's some freaky stuff happening here.
I produce flame.
Does that help me as I walk in?
No.
No, my magic fire doesn't help me? Okay.
Stay there.
I take a look around, I wander around the room and I sort of take a better look at the corners.
Are there doors or anything?
There's one hallway heading straight back and then there's one door to your left as you walk into the room.
A hallway heading straight back in the direction of the other...
Sorry, in the direction of the front of the house.
Okay.
Hey, I think I'm going to check this door before you come in here. How's that sound?
Sure, stay safe, buddy.
That's why I open the door.
Nelara, Flint, and Flamingons, you've wandered into to follow this blur.
So you're walking into the living area and you see a single door off to the left and an open window off to the right of the room.
Okay, and no sign of whatever this thing was?
No, no sign of any sort of creature or anything else.
And as you walk further into this room, the door to the left opens and Grug steps through.
But as he steps through, a wave of darkness follows over top of him and encompasses you.
Can I see the kitchen now?
Yeah, some of the kitchen. Are you walking into the kitchen?
As I see the kitchen start to brighten, I follow that.
As you guys get closer to Grug, you're able to see a little bit as well.
And behind Grug, you see a glint of what looks to be a scimitar-like weapon.
And the shadowy face of a hideous fiend with downturned horns, spikes protruding out of its head,
scaly dreadlocks and a lizard-like body with massive wings and a hideous snarl with teeth ready to sink into the back of Grug's skull.
Oh my.
Nice. Okay.
Oh shit.
Roll for initiative.
I'm using my rainbow dice, you guys. My other dice had been balling with me.
18, 19, 19.
Oh, rainbow dice.
Rainbow dice.
Wow.
I just kicked my puppy in the face.
Oh, sorry Paisley.
Sorry puppy, I got so excited.
15.
24 for me.
I got an 11.
So the thing is up first. This creature, like a blur, rushes in and strikes at Grug, who doesn't see him coming, for a 22, no criticals or anything.
Hit.
And as he goes by, he strikes at Flamikinskins and Flint as well, but misses on those two, so he hits Grug for eight slashing damage across your back.
Wow.
After he makes those moves, he moves to a corner of the room that is outside of Grug's light, and he seemingly disappears from your sight.
Nularaaaia, you're up next.
So I pull out Flametongue and say Mui Caliente, and as I get, like, approach the direction he was, like, is that helping with light at all?
No, your flaming sword doesn't seem to have any extra effect on the darkness in the room.
Okay, what if I say banana?
Yeah, there you go.
The ball glowing orb jumps up and illuminates the room so that it is like there is no darkness around you.
Yes, banana ball.
Looks like daylight.
Okay, so I can see the creature?
Nope.
Is he there, like, haha.
He's not there.
Damn.
No, he doesn't appear to be in the room.
Last you saw him, he quickly moved towards the front of the house, which there are stairs and a hallway that cuts down back to the kitchen.
Stairs going upstairs or down to a basement?
Upstairs.
Going upstairs?
Then I guess I will go upstairs.
You get to the top of the stairs and at the end of a hallway that leads back down to a front room on the second level, you see staring back at you what looks to be one of these hideous white fiends, its gaping maw curling into an evil smile as if beckoning for you to come to it.
Okay, great.
Okay, then I am going to cast Hunter's Mark on it.
That's a bonus action.
It is mystically marked as my quarry, and then I'm going to try and hit it non-mystically with my flaming sword.
Visible only to you, a wave of energy envelops the creature as you prepare your attack.
That is a 24.
24 will hit it.
Great.
It's fun.
Comforting?
Yeah, no kidding.
I also need you to split up your fire and your slashing damage there.
Okay, so it's piercing, it's three piercing damage, and it is seven, nine fire damage.
You strike with flametongue into this creature and it looks like you didn't do anything to it.
I bet fire helps it.
What a dick.
Okay, then for my second attack, because I'm so fast apparently, I'm going to put that sword away and pull out my other sword.
Can I do that?
I've never had more than one good weapon.
Sure, yeah.
Okay, then I'm going to try and use Dragon Slayer.
Okay.
That's an 18 to attack.
18 will hit, yeah.
Okay, so that is nine, 11 damage, oh, plus an extra D6 because of Hunter's Mark, 11, so that's 14 damage.
14 slashing or piercing?
Piercing.
So you strike into it and it doesn't appear, you hit it pretty hard, but it still doesn't feel like it did the damage that you thought it did, and it strikes out and bites at you for a 16.
Okay, that doesn't hit.
Donnie rolled a 20.
Donnie bringing it.
Way to go, Donnie.
Three piercing damage.
Okay.
Which is not much, but he was stinging, so I guess it also has to do a con save.
Nothing happens to him.
Okay, he's going to sting it again.
That does not work because that is a nine.
Okay.
Thea, you can see into the room, I assume you left the glowing ball in the room downstairs, or did it follow you?
I don't know, does it follow me?
It just illuminates and you have to move it, so unless you held it and moved it, otherwise it just stays stationary.
I guess I didn't ask that, did the darkness that was gone?
As soon as you went upstairs, yeah, we'll say you left it, as soon as you went upstairs the darkness left.
I feel like the darkness is attached to Greg.
I feel like that's a fair assumption.
Then yeah, for sure it stayed.
So it's your turn, Thea.
Okay, well, I obviously hear a scuffle going on because I feel like I'm in the door of the kitchen in the back of the house.
Yeah, you step into the kitchen and you go to go follow behind Grug, but you're caught by the glare of the black demon creature.
Good, okay, I cast Fairy Fire on it.
First time with this one, I want to see what happens.
Luckily, because we are in a completely separate room, right?
Yeah, you're in the kitchen area and Grug is in the living area now and everybody else, so you're alone.
So would you face 20 feet away from me?
So it's just me and the...
Yeah.
Okay, cool, because I think I found out why I didn't think this was a good spell is because everyone is affected by the attack rolls.
Right.
If you fail the con save.
You need to make a deck save.
That's a 19.
Well, that I guess it saves.
Sorry.
That's okay.
That's it.
Do you stand still?
Like, oops, that didn't work.
Is it blocking my way?
Well, there's the door to go follow in behind Grug or there is the way to the front of the house where it's standing.
I run to Grug.
Hello.
I'm not going to run toward.
There's a fucking black demon.
There's a scary black demon.
What's going on over here?
It's Grug's turn.
So you're in a room with Flint, Flammie, Kins, and Thea now.
I cast Dispel Magic on myself.
Sure.
Great idea.
That's a good idea.
If we're correct in our thinking that this...
Seems like it's following you.
Let's try it.
Any effect?
Outside the light that is being illuminated, the darkness that you were seeing disappears.
Right on.
For my bonus action, I give Thea Bardic Inspiration.
Thank you, sir.
So you get to roll a D10 and add it to any ability, attack, or saving throw.
You also can add it to your damage or your AC as a reaction.
Oh, that's fun.
That is good.
Nice.
Thank you, actually.
Anything else you want to do?
You're good?
I suppose I'll move back toward the black demon and see if I can still see him.
Yeah, you step around the corner and it is coming towards you.
So you're now like...
Can I put myself in the doorway between Thea and the demon?
So that if he's attacking, he's just hitting me.
Sure.
Bag of hit points.
Thanks, buddy.
You're going to start calling Flint bag of hit points.
I like it.
It's pretty accurate.
It's super accurate.
Yeah, absolutely.
So Flamikinskins is up and she's like, I'm going to go upstairs and see if Nularaaaa needs a hand.
And she runs quickly.
Not quickly because she's a goblin, so she's a little bit behind.
She can't quite make it all the way, but she's got spells, so that's fine.
And she sees the white beast creature that you see and she's like, holy fuck, that's ugly, too.
Right?
I think you guys are just talking.
Right? Hideous. My God.
And then it loses five hit points because its feelings are real hard and its confidence is shaken.
It's got disadvantage for confidence rolls.
She is going to make a ranged attack and throw a chaos bolt at this creature, which she's going to try and do.
I feel like Nularaaaa is going to get hit right now.
Well, I mean, no.
It is a chaos bolt.
So we're going to roll that and that's an 18, which will hit because that was hitting.
So you hurl an undulating, warbling mass of chaotic energy at one creature in range.
I did that.
And then I roll 2d8 plus 1d6, which is 13.
And I choose one of the d8s.
I'll choose that one.
And it shoots out thunder damage.
So it shoots out 13 thunder damage at this creature and it is knocked back.
Jump back.
And lets out a just a hideous shriek that kind of hurts your ears.
It's a noise that you have never heard before.
And then it is Flint's turn.
OK.
Which are they both within range of me or just the downstairs one?
If you were to dash, you could probably make it upstairs.
That's what Flammikins had to do.
Otherwise, the black one is within range for your full three attacks.
OK.
We'll go for the black one.
Yeah.
Grug's in the way.
So you'd have to I would say that you would like kind of slide under his legs, either
slide under his legs or like barrel through knocking your knees.
The demon thing.
Well, yeah, I'll kind of I'll kind of slide under him and pop up on my feet and
get to swing in this axe.
OK.
How does Grug feel about that?
So that's a 17 for the first one.
Excited.
17 will hit.
All right.
Now, do you need to know anything particular about damage I'm doing, Russ?
I need to know types of damage everybody is dealing.
Slashing.
And I do have like a plus three magical damage on this thing as well.
So I just need to know if you want like anything separated.
Well, your axe is like all magic, though, isn't it?
I'm assuming so, but I'm not 100 percent.
Yeah, OK.
Your axe is magic.
OK.
So.
All right.
Well, then I'll just roll what I need to roll it.
So six plus seven.
So 13 damage on the first attack.
OK.
So, yeah, you slide under and strike into its back.
It's got massive wings that you cleave into.
And one of them is damaged quite a lot.
Sweet.
Let's go for slides under its legs.
Or did you pop up between it and Grog?
No, I like I like power slid all the way past.
All right.
Right through everybody.
OK.
Very exciting.
Yeah.
So I'll go for a second attack.
So that's a 26.
I think that's good.
No, surprisingly 26 doesn't hit.
Once you go too far, it cancels out.
Yeah.
Oh, that's fun.
So that's full damage.
So that's 17.
Yeah.
And we'll go for one more because I got that third attack now.
Oh, that's not so good.
But it's a 15.
15 hits.
Oh.
I like this plus 11 to hit.
That's fun.
Damn.
That's great.
So that is 14 damage.
After sliding through Grog and the creature's legs,
you pop up and begin slashing and hacking into this creature's back,
its wing beginning to separate at the joint,
and you see major gashes going into its skin as it lets out a horrendous shriek.
It's the white beast thing's fiend thing's turn.
Great.
And it is going to...
Well, I mean, Nularaaaa is the only one in...
In range.
Oh, why is there Flammikens?
She wasn't really in range.
Flammikens, she couldn't quite make it directly to...
Right.
It's going to make two attacks, one with its longsword and one with its claws.
It desperately misses with its longsword, and the claw attack is a 13.
So it's like...
So it slashes at me and then misses, and then as it's flailing, tries to scratch me.
I like it because it missed both times, so good.
I'm glad it is ugly and looked a fool.
I laugh at it.
As soon as it misses with its second attack there, everybody in their mind hears a voice.
Hey there, it's me again, your Dungeon Master Russ More.
Thank you so much for joining us for this episode 44 of Dumbgeons and Dragons, titled
A Friend in the Night, Part 2.
We're always happy to see and chat with Spencer and we're going to hear from him
in a brief moment about where you can find more from him on the internet.
I wanted to mention also that we've had some pretty awesome things happening over on our
Patreon page since the last episode, like making our second Patreon goal.
Truly amazing!
With that, we did a big giveaway for any two D&D books and we added some new fun
content that Patrons will be able to print, use, and take with them to your own
gaming tables.
So if you want to support the show directly, just visit Patreon.com slash DumbDragonCast
and you can see all the tiers and rewards.
We really hope to see you over there.
Another amazing way to support us though, if you can't join us on Patreon, is to
share a link to the show or an episode on social media.
Word of mouth is really one of the easiest ways to support any podcast or show
or anything that you listen to or like.
And it can go a long way to get the word out about those things that you like.
And speaking of which, all of our social media links can be found at
DumbDragons.com.
So go check out the website and join, follow, or like where you can today.
Well, this is the part where we say thank you, Spencer, for joining us.
Thank you so much, Spencer.
The music was so great and the spells were not too shabby either.
Yeah, awesome work.
Yeah, thank you very much for having me.
That was a lot of fun.
I've never done, well, I've never done a D&D podcast before and I've never done
D&D over Skype before.
There's a lot of firsts tonight.
Yeah, so a couple of firsts.
So thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Awesome.
Well, I can see, I can see Grug making another appearance at some point down the
road.
You know, he's always around or he's at least never far off.
There we go.
One of those, one of those shadow types.
Yeah, I like it.
Let, I'll let you let everybody know where they can find you on the
interwebs.
If you want to direct them towards anything or sell anything or do
anything.
Yeah, sure.
You could, you could look up Spencer Joe, J-O, in Google and find my
music.
And then from there you might be able to find some.
I run out like a D&D Instagram.
Not very well and a D&D Twitter, but I don't do those very well either.
But I do.
I think I may at one point get into podcasting myself.
So who knows?
Keep an eye out.
There we go.
Yeah, I like it.
All things done.
Yeah.
We'll put all the links to find Spencer down in the description below as
well.
And thank you again.
We really appreciate you being here.
Yeah, that was awesome.
Thanks, Spencer.
So good.
Thanks, folks.
One final thing.
Just big thanks to Sirenscape for some of the amazing atmosphere and
music.
Make sure you check them out at sirenscape.com to bring your games
to life.
Links for everything mentioned today can be found in the
description.
The next episode will be out July 18th.
Have a great week.
We'll talk soon.
And it is a lovely lady's voice.
What does it sound like, Rob?
It sounds like a lovely lady that's not going to sound like me.
But she says, your efforts have been thwarted time and time again
by my helpers.
And let me tell you, it's not going to end here.
And downstairs, we're going to have a party.
It's not going to end here.
And downstairs, you see through the front door a winged,
beautiful creature.
She's lovely looking.
I wish there was something that I could get you to roll to just...
Make a horny roll.
Make a horny roll downstairs.
Make a supermodel roll.
Everyone downstairs.
Thea rolled a 19.
She's super horny.
Super horny.
She probably has a plus seven.
I have horns on my helmet.
This is true.
Glowing horns.
Right.
Glowing horny.
Out the front window, you see this beautiful creature with huge
wings and a long tail.
And she is hovering in front of the house outside.
And we're back to the top.
And it's the black creature's turn.
And he is going to swing two scimitar attacks at Grug.
One bite.
He's going to turn around at Flint.
So Grug, 23.
Hit.
And a 13.
Okay, one hit.
Okay, and Flint on yours.
That is a 25.
Oh yeah.
Damn.
So the scimitar attack on Grug is six slashing damage.
The ensuing bite on Flint is 11 piercing damage plus seven acid
damage.
So how much was the piercing you said?
11.
I get to subtract that by three because of my heavy armor
mastery.
It then takes a bonus action.
And disappears into a shadow.
How am I going to resolve that?
Yeah.
No, I can't do that because you're right in range.
All right.
It just stays there because he's done.
What was his horniness role?
Maybe he's also very captivated by this new creature.
I mean, he's used to it.
He was pretty horny, but not quite as horny.
He's old after a while.
Yeah.
Okay.
Then obviously I don't know about this.
I don't know anything that's going on downstairs.
Only anybody downstairs.
You've heard the voice, but you haven't seen the creature.
Okay.
Then I am going to attack the one that I was attacking.
So that is 23.
23 will hit.
And that is 22 damage.
Whoa.
Mammal.
That is awesome.
Well, because Hunter's Mark too, right?
So I got an extra D6 on there.
You got a Hunter's Mark everything.
Okay.
Yeah.
You're mine.
You're my quarry.
You slice into it in a huge gouge right across its chest.
It's spewing black blood like fluid.
Fluids.
Ickr.
That's what it is.
Good.
Yep.
Ickr is icky.
Got another swing.
I sure do.
Uh, I sure do.
It's an 11.
Huh?
Nope.
Okay.
Well, Donnie's gonna pick up my slack.
Maybe.
Oh, he totally is.
Donnie rolled a 22.
Donnie is on fire today.
I know.
He is doing really well.
Even without the Cholera.
I'm just giving him a lot of confidence, I think.
Yeah.
Like, he knows he's got that in his back pocket if he needs it.
Yeah, exactly.
So that is three damage and then a con save.
Oh, but yeah.
The con save doesn't do anything.
Doesn't do anything.
But damage.
Okay.
The damage he takes.
Yep.
Okay.
The thing strikes out and bites at, you are one, two, three.
Donnie is four, five, six.
Strikes out and bites Donnie.
For a 22.
Not damage.
Okay.
22 to hit.
Yep.
Donnie never gets hit.
Donnie's gonna take seven piercing damage.
Okay.
And two cold damage.
Urr.
Poor Donnie is chilly.
He's got a bite taken out of him.
And then his second attack.
Next attack is a 21 and four damage on that one.
Okay.
And again, this thing strikes out.
And this time, bites at new Lara for a 12.
So that doesn't work.
Okay.
Thea.
So in front of me I've got.
Rug.
Thing.
Black creature.
Flint.
And then.
Succubus, you assume, out front.
Out front.
Oh, okay.
I'm going out the front door.
Yeah.
You get her.
I'm gonna get her.
So you make it out front there.
And I say, listen here, bitch.
She just laughs at you.
Get out of my head.
Okay.
I'm going to cast.
I cast.
Sunbeam.
Sure.
So a beam of brilliant light flashes out from my hand in a five foot wide angle.
Okay.
I cast.
Sunbeam.
Sure.
So a beam of brilliant light flashes out from my hand in a five foot wide.
Wait, hold on.
How close?
Here's a better question.
How close is she?
Sir.
Yeah.
Because you said she was in the air.
She was like hovering, flying outside the front window.
So she's probably like 20 feet from you at this point.
Okay.
Fine.
That's good.
Because this is 60 feet.
Okay.
The creature must make a constitution saving throw.
14.
Oh, she failed.
Yay.
Don't forget your Arctic inspiration.
Thank you.
I feel like she, because I can put that on damage, right?
Yeah.
No, you can't.
I'm not supposed to really say that am I?
No, you know why?
We table talk all the time.
We need help.
We need all the help we need.
Edit it out.
It's okay.
Yeah.
That's a D10.
Plus whatever else you do.
On a failed save, a creature takes 6d8 radiant damage.
And is blinded until my next turn.
Okay.
Yeah.
Fuck you, bitch.
Radiant damage.
That's right.
I was like fire.
No, no, no.
Bledging, I mean, sure.
I could hit her with the oath bow.
You know what's going to hurt her?
Yeah.
It's going to be radiant damage.
And a lot of it.
I like it.
All right.
What are you rolling?
I'm rolling.
6d8.
Yep.
Here's two more.
It says 19, so that's 26.
Oh, my D10 rolled a one.
Aw.
Well, it's something.
27 radiant damage.
She is blinded until her next turn.
Motherfucker.
Motherfucking awesome.
Thank you, mid.
Okay.
God damn it.
Fuck.
In her beautiful woman's voice.
However that's going to sound.
Should I outsource that?
Yeah.
Okay.
Blinded.
That's right.
Yeah.
Well, I got it.
Are you done?
Yes.
I can only ever do one thing.
Yeah, but it was a good thing.
Grug.
I know, right?
Grug, your turn.
All right.
I'm going to, I think Flint's probably got this demon.
Sure.
So I'm going to turn and move away from it, which probably provokes an attack of opportunity,
but I'm going to attack that succubus.
Well, it already turned around to attack me, so you could probably get by it.
Right, we're sort of flanking it.
Yeah, you're still engaged, so it will attack.
Okay.
No worries.
Which is a...
I got them hit points.
20, 23.
Big old bag of hit points.
23.
It strikes out with its scimitar, which hits, which is going to be a 1d6 plus
3 slashing, which is going to be 5 slashing damage.
Now I'm going to move to be around near Thea.
I use my bonus action to give her bardic inspiration again.
Thanks, buddy.
And then I'm going to cast lightning bolt at the blinded succubus.
Yeah.
Okay, with advantage because it's blinded.
Exactly, so dexterity saving throw.
So with disadvantage.
Yeah.
So that is going to be, sorry, dexterity.
Right.
That's a 5.
Awesome.
Perfect.
Beautiful.
I'm casting it as a one level up because I'm out of third level spells, so it's
a fourth level spell.
Sure.
So it does 96.
Damn.
Yeah, it does.
Fuck yeah, grug.
Our lightning damage.
Yeah.
Okay.
Whoa.
Holy shit.
That was so many.
It was.
There's a few sixes here.
39 damage.
Oh my God.
Damn.
Did you murder her?
No, because she takes half lightning damage.
Damn.
Damn it.
Still real good though.
It's still a lot of damage.
So yeah, your lightning bolt's front and her wings are fried and she drops
to the ground, but she's still alive, screaming in pain.
Thea's so happy.
She's close enough to kick.
I just run up and I kick her in the shin real fast.
You're good, grug.
So Flamikins Kinn's turn.
She is going to, I'm just going to say she's going to do the same thing.
Make a ranged attack and a chaos bolt towards the creature.
Yeah.
I'm just going to say she's going to do the same thing, make a ranged attack
and a chaos bolt towards the creature.
Which is going to be a 20, not critical, 16.
And that will be force damage.
What do we do for force damage?
Oh yeah, bud.
Is it space force damage?
Yeah.
So this creature is knocked back into the room as Flamikins Kinn's yells
and lets force this force chaos bolt and the windows burst from behind
and sprinkle down onto the grass that you see down in front there, grug and Thea.
And it is knocked to the ground.
It is prone.
Sweet.
And then it is Flint's turn.
All right.
Is it like a straight shot out the door?
Like, can I, do I have eyes on the succubus from where I am?
You do.
You're still engaged in combat with the black one though.
Yeah, yeah.
No, I was just curious.
No, no.
He just winds up murdering it real fast.
It's like around the corner maybe.
Sorry.
Yeah.
You can see Thea and grug kind of out front of the house,
but the succubus is more off to the side.
Okay.
Kicking some crazy succubus ass.
Flint's like, I've got three attacks.
I'm going to finish this one and then go.
Yeah, exactly.
The rules go to the roundhouse everybody.
I love it.
I got a fun throwing camera that will return to me automatically.
So.
Oh yeah.
All right.
Sweet.
I'll, yeah.
I'll take another chop at this big dude that's right in front of me.
That is a 15.
15 will hit.
All right.
I'm going to go back at the wings again because I damaged the one before.
So I'm going to go back there.
Sure.
So that is a 12 on that one.
Okay.
So yeah, you, you, you cleave one of its wings off and it lets forth a shrill scream as the wing falls to the ground.
Excellent.
That's another 15.
So.
Okay.
Should be good.
Yeah.
Oh, not super great.
10 damage on that one.
We're just, I'm just hacking into like the same spot.
Yeah.
No.
You're like, you've cleaved off its wing and now you're cleaving into the winged wing wound that is now opened.
Oh yeah.
And it drops to its knees and still it turns around and looks at you kind of with puppy dog eyes.
Ugly motherfucking puppy dog eyes.
Perfect.
Cause I really wanted to hit it in the neck.
So that's great that it turned towards me.
So that is a 19, but not critical.
Yeah.
Big damage.
Oh, there we go.
That is 16 damage.
It turns and looks at you and whimpers as you do what to it?
I have a family.
As I, as I lift my ax up, I just look at it with like no emotion.
Like this puppy dog routine is not working on me.
And I just like, I step into it.
Like I step forward and just bring the ax down and just, oh, it's, it's carnage.
It's not, it's not pretty.
That's what happens.
Yep.
It's not pretty.
As just before it connects with its face, it lets forth this, this another angered shrill scream.
It dropped the puppy dog thing when you didn't stop.
Yeah.
And it like was like reaching for you.
So it, it's momentum plus your momentum split this thing's head in two.
I knew you got, you had it.
Right?
Yep.
I have the choice of having three attacks that all have a pretty good chance to land.
Great ax work.
Thank you.
I'll slowly start strolling towards the front door.
I feel real good about yourself right now.
Covered in gore.
Upstairs, tuning back in, the thingamabob or dooder.
Yep.
It stands up and jumps, like fly jumps towards new Lara and takes a bite at you.
And a, and a sword swing.
It's probably not going to be good.
Fuck.
Keep rolling.
Twelve and a sixteen.
Nope.
Remember we were so mean though about, about what it looked like.
That's true.
So it's confidence is really suffering.
And it just had to jump up from the ground.
Yep.
Can I get to hit it now?
Can I hit it?
I really want to hit it.
Yeah, go for it.
Okay.
That is a 26.
Yeah.
Barely though.
Got real tough.
Nine plus six is 15, 21 damage.
It jumps forward and swings and bites at you and catches your sword in its, in its, what does it, what do you do?
Okay.
I was like, it catches my sword.
I see what you did.
Yeah.
I mean, probably in its face.
It was just like jumping and trying to bite me.
Right?
Yep.
So I've got, yeah, I've got dragon slayer up and yeah, just right, right into the
ugly, ugly face.
I like it.
Yeah.
Okay.
That happens.
And it is, it is split in twain and then it is the succubus's turn and she's like,
she can't, she can't see, she can't really move, but she begins to phase out.
Counterspell.
Oh no, bitch.
Basically what I'm picturing is like in Kill Bill when Darryl Hannah gets her eye ripped
out.
That's the succubus right now.
Hold on, hold on.
Grug has a counterspell.
Yeah.
It sounds like Grug's going to do something cool.
Oh shit.
This is a reaction.
Do it.
So I am attempting to interrupt a creature in the process of casting a spell.
If they're casting a spell of third level or lower, the spell fails.
And if it's casting a spell of fourth or higher, I need to make the ability.
This is like the same as the spell magic.
Only it's the reaction, I guess.
So I got to make an ability check.
DC is the same.
I like like all this tricky counter magic shit that you've got.
I know.
Grug's got some good shit.
Bards are cool.
Yeah, you're going to need to make a check.
All right.
So I'm making a charisma check.
Big money, big money, big money.
12.
Can I give you your die of inspiration?
Just return this.
You can have that back.
It's for you.
No.
We can't do it.
I got a 12.
Yeah.
Which I imagine didn't work.
Valiant effort.
Needed a 17 on that one.
Oh boy.
That's a lofty roll.
Damn.
So no, you see Grug as she begins to phase out.
What does Grug try and what does he do as he's doing this?
I raise up my hand in a prohibitive manner and I say, Halt!
And it doesn't work.
And so I just get like a little bit sad and just kind of stare at my feet.
I pat him on the shoulder.
I'm like, it's all right.
Sorry.
I wanted it to work.
It was good.
But you shall not pass.
She finishes phasing out and you in your mind here.
We know your plans.
We know where you will be next and we know how to stop you.
And then it's gone.
Well, we don't even know our plans.
So that seems unlikely.
Is the second bit still blind since she never took her next turn?
Yeah, that's true.
Well, she just stayed blind.
Like it never got back to Amy.
I mean, she's going back to like Fiendville.
So I'm sure.
Fiendville.
Population 200.
Very close to Vaudeville.
198 now.
Right, right, right.
Yeah.
Yeah, you did.
So I really wanted to murder her more.
Yeah.
Flammikins and Nularaaaa are upstairs and I assume you run downstairs as you finish
your battle and you guys reconvene out front.
And Flammikins is like, what?
What happened out here?
It's like it's daylight.
How's that?
How's that sunbeam working for you?
I blinded a succubus.
Oh, fuck.
Yeah, I got this cool sunbeam because we heard her upstairs, right?
We just didn't see her.
Yeah.
Because she was telepathically communicating.
Right.
From planes beyond.
What do you do?
I guess I turn off my sunbeam.
It's a lay like.
Hey, so was that it?
Like, are we, did we kill the thing or get rid of the thing?
Yeah, what happened out here?
We heard a voice, the succubus, I assume.
You guys kill her?
Kill her real good?
I tried to stop her escaping, but was not successful.
She ran scared.
We heard her a bunch, fried her wings, blinded her, but.
Oh, she's got some plans against you.
It's good.
You're making enemies.
It means you're doing something right.
It's going to really add to our songs, right?
Something about a succubus.
Are you going to sing about this, Grug?
Maybe we go back to the bar and have a drink and just relax a little bit and Grug will play us a tune.
Yeah, I think what we need to do is talk to the council, which is what we need to do.
We got a meeting tomorrow.
Exactly.
Yeah, exactly.
So we have a little more to report.
So tonight we celebrate.
Yeah.
Remember poor Flamikins Kins wanted to get fucked up.
She only had like one tiny drink.
I'm trying to get drunk.
Back to the lonely whip.
I think Flamikins Kins might have a bit of a problem.
Not back to the lonely whip.
But it was so like rocking in there.
Yawning portal, yawning portal.
Alright, let's go to the yawning portal.
Let's go back to the yawning portal.
Yeah, they got a good basement there.
Have you been down there?
I want to go check it out sometime.
I've been meeting too.
Well, let's do a side adventure.
Grug and Flamikins Kins go into the yawning portal.
Yeah, do it.
Sounds like a viable spinoff.
I mean, yes.
So you guys head back to the yawning portal and get set up with drinks from Dernan who's still working.
He's still just working away.
I like that Grug just peaced out while he was performing.
I got to go.
This is the usual thing for Grug.
He comes and goes as he pleases and plays his tunes and people love it.
But Grug steps back up to the stage and plays you a ditty on the way out as we fade out.
I recently composed this one.
And I said, no, oh, don't you go down to the house of the succubus.
You might get struck by lightning or a sunbeam and those demons might kill you.
And I said, no, don't you go to the house of the succubus.
No, don't you go, don't you go, don't you go.
We clap.
So good.
Music in today's episode was by Kavin McLeod of incompetech.filmmusic.io.
One man does stand out to you, though, and he is dressed in a bathing suit.
He's dressed in just a banana hammock bikini.
That would stand out.
Awesome.
My wife.
I can see his whip.
I didn't get my turn.
Don't worry.
You'll be fine.
That means you're going to get a turn.
Anyone ever seen Lost Girl?
Nope.
All right.
The TV show all about a succubus.
That's where that's where all my succubus information comes from.
Keep it handy.
All right.
Let's let's go check out that back door.
So you are heading all the way upstairs.
Sure.
I don't know if there's five thousand of them.
No, but otherwise, there are five thousand.
It's a very tall house.
Well, it's just kind of like the really scary demon in the child thing or the child that was the demon thing.
That darkness was attached to you, Flint.
We've been here.
Sure.
Yeah.
We had to make you leave the house.
We were like, get out.
You're dark and stuff.
So he nasty.
If you could if you could hold it a little closer so I could see what it's resistant to.
No, not going to happen.
All right.
Six, eight plus eleven.
Oh, God.
Maths hard.
Basic simple math is very difficult.
They were high level characters.
So the math is.
Yeah, it gets so much harder.
Lots of ones and threes.
It's also just because I'm using a different weapon.
I'm so used to it with flame tongue.
But so this is blinded by the light.
Hmm.
It's kind of a kind of a funny like weak weapon for these like terrifying creatures.
The cemetery.
Yeah.
And it takes out its sling.
Do you want your characters to say goodbye or do you want to just fade out there?
I think we do a fade out because I think I think we like.
Yeah, we were clapping.
We're raising glasses.
High five.
Finally gets drunk.
Yeah.
Classic high five.
Well, you party through the night.
And and yeah, your friend, Grug, is is off to off to find more tales the next morning.
Yeah, that sounds right.
Yeah.
He takes his one gold.
You got paid more handsomely at the at the.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production.