Previously on Dumbgeons and Dragons.
And this blue orb appears and you are back and you look to Mirabar and you see plumes of smoke coming up from the city.
Thea sits down on the ground and pulls out a joint.
Yeah, guys, this is a lot. What the hell is going on?
I look at Flynn's face and I throw him a joint.
This is much needed.
Out of Flynn's mouth, Bort begins to scream.
He said I wanted to come back. I did not want to come here with you.
But if the choice was that or die, isn't this a better choice?
Bort is gone and Flint is back.
Flint, where did you go? What did that feel like? What's going on, buddy? Tell me.
It does not feel good when that happens, I will tell you that much.
And as you look to the east over the top of another large hill,
you see the remaining soldiers of the Axe of Mirabar marching towards Mirabar.
Guys, they haven't made it there yet.
Crimsbane probably isn't controlling them yet.
As you fly more towards the army, they see you and they yell up to you.
If you don't want to be shot from the sky, you should probably come down now.
What's your name, sir?
I am Commander Hammerstryker and I am the commander of the Axe of Mirabar.
Hammerstryker? Yeah.
Where do you think Crimsbane is?
The most fortified location in the city is likely where you were when you were in the break.
Thea, you are searching rooms and you hear a startled yell.
And as you become visible to Osric, he swings down at you with his axe.
Where have you guys been?
Around.
Hey guys, he's in here.
How long have we been gone?
Uh, you guys have been gone for three weeks.
What?
That was unexpected.
Yeah.
Okay.
All of you hear a static charge and you hear what you think is Salazar.
Tibby, where are you?
We just got your signal back.
Ah, you stupid man.
Welcome to Dumbgeons and Dragons.
This is a fifth edition D&D actual play podcast.
I'm your Dungeon Master, Russ More, and with me today is Amy More, who plays Thea Amastasia.
Hey there.
And Carla Johnson playing New Laura Moonbrook.
Hello.
And Flint Firebeard, who was played by Tom Laird.
Yes.
Sorry to interrupt.
I like I like the switch because now that means I have a friend in real life who's a dwarf.
And that sounds amazing.
Hooray!
Everybody wins.
How are you guys?
Good.
Doing well.
Eloquent as always.
Excellent.
This is good.
Good banter we've got going on here.
We wasted it all before we started.
We're really vibing on the banter right now.
It's pretty.
I always feel like Russ's innocent questions are like a trap for us if we say the wrong thing.
How are you guys doing?
Good.
Roll a D20.
Yeah, see?
And then maybe we're not so good.
There's something about not even I was going to say the format, but it's not because we were just chatting before we started recording,
but something about like the second we say we're playing that we absolutely forget how human communication works.
Like we cannot talk to NPCs.
We can't even talk to each other, our actual friends in real life.
It's a weird thing.
The story checks out completely.
Sounds about right.
It's an interesting barrier you guys have put up there.
I mean, there's a real fourth wall thing going on.
But yeah, as long as you commit to the awkward, awkward interaction, it's good.
Yeah, my life has just been a series of awkward interactions.
This is just a recorded, awkward interaction.
Well, good.
Let's if all the awkward banter is done for now, we can we can jump right on in.
So we left off last time and you had figured out, Nularaa, that you appear to have a communicator that was left in your your arrow quiver.
And it appears to be Salazar speaking on the other end.
We're going to take a quick step back from there.
We're rewinding just a little bit.
So, Flint, you guys have just found Osric and everybody's talking amongst themselves.
But you yourself have been kind of quiet and concentrating, trying to fight Bort for control of your body since you returned from Enan.
But in this moment, your mind is quiet and you find yourself being able to relax for the first time since entering, really, the library of the dead.
You seem to ignore the conversations around you.
You hear them, but you're not really paying attention to them.
You're reveling in the silence now upon you when you hear Bort in your mind very quietly say,
So I think we might have got off on the wrong foot.
Well, we were kind of thrust together without anyone's consent.
Yeah, yeah, that happened.
And I feel like I've been treating you a little little poorly.
I mean, I've been screaming like a child in here.
I've noticed.
Yeah, and I had a moment of contemplation when I thought maybe maybe we could help each other.
I like the sound of this.
I recognize that I was angry and I've never been known to take things calmly before.
I mean, Ralph, Ralph had been working with me on that up until I had my head chopped off, obviously.
And I want to I want to help not hinder anymore and hopefully find a way to separate us
and get me another body.
I mean, I know you guys said you would help with that.
I just feel like I wasn't really receptive to that.
So instead, I just tried to, you know, annoy you until I took over your body.
I'm sorry.
It was what you thought was right.
It's OK.
We do know some fancy magic types in a different town.
We just haven't had a chance to go there yet.
So when we do, hopefully they'll have some sort of solution to our problem.
That sounds good.
So what I'm going to do is, you know, just kind of hang out in here and, you know,
offer my two cents if I if I if I have it, if you think that's cool.
Definitely.
That's good.
And you know what?
I think that I'm able to channel and just as he's saying this,
you hear the communicator catch in and it kind of cuts him off mid-sentence.
Right before the communicator going to Thea now.
I'm sorry.
Is this was this Flint like mumbling to himself
or is he having a conversation in his head?
He's having a conversation in his mind.
OK.
So you guys see him be like, oh, yeah, he's he's kind of just,
you know, stoically standing there kind of deep, deep in thought or zoned
as you guys appear him.
Thea, you got the Book of the Druids and you read through it.
And it made you think differently about how being a druid should work.
You've been thinking about this book since you got back.
And this has kind of been going through your mind
throughout the last last couple days, couple days for you.
And to this point, you've kind of used your druid ship
as more of a way to benefit yourself and make yourself money
in terms of selling your your wares, your weed products to to certain people.
And you've been a little bit almost hesitant to truly commit
to true druid ship to this point.
You've used your learned skills to help your business grow, so to speak.
But that seems to be mostly all it's been to you.
More of an enhancement of your nature.
Maybe your family growing up kind of held you back
or maybe on your path to understand your nature.
You were lost on your desire to make profits of your skills.
Maybe a little bit.
Whatever the reason, after having read the Book of the Druids,
which you acquired from the Library of the Dead on Eden,
something inside of you suddenly clicks in this kind of same moment
as Flint is having this internal conversation.
And you get it.
All of your skills and connections to nature itself become clear to you.
Your connection to your skills seems more focused now.
And your spells seem like second nature now.
And you feel inside of you, your wild shape churning and begging for freedom.
Every animal you have ever seen begins flooding to your mind all at once.
You see bears and eagles and tigers all trying to help you enhance your abilities.
You look down at your equipment and you suddenly feel a distaste,
a severe distaste for the metal things you have.
You drop your spear, you drop your daggers,
and you look down at your new armor and where...
New armor!
Where before you overlooked its metal build,
it doesn't repulse you quite the same as your spear and your other weapons did.
You analyze it a little more closely.
And you feel a magical aura coming off of it.
You can't quite tell what the enchantment or the aura is,
but you feel like it's not truly metal.
It just appears metal.
So it, to you, you don't feel the need to get rid of it.
Oh good, I just got it.
It's a lot of hassle to get that armor.
It was.
I know.
So to everybody else watching you, Thea, they just see you drop your metal weaponry.
Druids kind of maintain their use of scimitars,
but your daggers you drop, your spear you drop.
And then both you, Thea, and new Lara,
in this moment, just before the communicator clicks in,
you pause and you feel waves of energy from the world course through all at once.
And what moments ago felt calm is now suddenly darker
and seems like an energy is tainted or evil.
And these people you are fighting, the Cult of the Dragon,
you sense that they have just moved a step closer to their goal.
You can't sense exactly how close they are
or what they have just done, but something in the very essence of nature itself,
something evil is coming and is closer.
And then the communicator kicks in.
Tibby, Tibby!
Oh, where are you?
New Lara, you search through your quiver and you find
a small kind of cogwork communicator
that appears kind of the same build and make as what Tibby is made of.
And the sound is coming out of that.
Do you want to roll, just roll a d20 for me?
Uh, that is a three.
Nice!
So I throw it in the river.
What is this?
This is evil.
Did you tie it up first?
Yes, important question.
Thank you, Flint.
Use your intelligence modifier there.
Well, that's a one, so that's a four.
So it really made a difference.
So you look at this device and you don't have an idea of how to potentially make it work.
Guys, I can't figure out how this works.
Can one of you?
Do one of you?
I don't know.
I miss Tibby.
How do we work this?
Meanwhile, the communicator says,
Tibby, where the hell have you been?
Answer me!
Is that?
Is that Salazar?
It sounds like Salazar and I'm holding this thing and like just fumbling it in my hands.
Like I don't know how to...
Salazar!
Just holding it, yelling at it.
I don't know how it works.
I rolled an 11.
Thea, you come over and you look at it and there is a button on the side.
Does it say on?
No, there just appears to be a button or a switch that...
Like a walkie talkie.
You are able to depress and it, the static that's coming through, it stops.
Hey, try this.
Hello?
I let the button go.
From the device, he says,
Is that?
Is that Thea?
I press the button again.
Who's asking?
This is really quite a good conversation, obviously.
This is Salazar.
Where's Tibby and where have you guys been?
Uh, you know, that's like a super long story.
Guys?
We like transported to some different place and now Flint has another dude in his head
and everything is totally crazy.
Also, we were gone for three weeks and now Tibby's gone too
and an evil army is taking over a town.
So where are you at?
Oh, ask him what he's wearing.
Says...
She ignores me.
No, I'm not asking that.
Well, you're the one holding it.
I assumed you just said that while you were still holding it.
Oh, I thought you were holding it and I was just pressing the button.
No, I don't know.
That was my understanding.
I was just jumping in.
I like that better.
You are holding it and Thea just pushing, just pushing the button.
That's what I imagined.
He says,
What do you mean Tibby's gone?
I'm back at the guild.
Three...
Yeah, I guess that timeline lines up.
You guys have been kind of disappeared for a little more than three weeks
as we lost you before we sent Tibby to try and find you.
Okay, army taking over.
You guys just kind of make danger up as you go, don't you?
It just kind of follows you around.
I think this one literally like this danger
just jumped out at us in the middle of the street.
Like I don't think this one was our fault.
Interesting.
Okay.
Yeah, I know it doesn't sound right to me either.
We probably did find it.
Hey, what just happened?
Did something just happen?
I felt something.
Well, I don't know what you're talking about.
What do you mean something just happened?
So I'm like looking at Flint and Thea
because I just felt this crazy wash of power or whatever happened.
So I'm looking at them like,
guys, did you just feel that like something has changed?
I didn't feel anything.
Yes, I felt it too.
Something is definitely happening.
Well, we've been tracking the cult a little bit.
They're doing some pretty bad stuff around.
We haven't been able to track down
where exactly they've been kind of collecting yet.
But pretty much entirety of Faerun is falling apart,
whether it's the cult or it's just rogue groups
popping up in cities and claiming them for themselves.
They've taken the cult as kind of a call to action
to just allow evil to run rampant.
Okay.
Well, that sounds really bad.
Yeah, it's not good.
We're here in Mirabar.
Half of the army has been enchanted.
Somehow through their armor by an evil wizard.
Any tips on some kind of disarming?
You're a smart guy.
Got any tips and tricks?
Disarming, enchanted armor.
I mean, it sounds like something magical.
I can get the wizards on it over here
and just see if they can't figure something out.
But we might need more information as to
who's doing the spell and how they're doing it
in order to shut it down.
It's an elf wizard named Primsbane.
The name sounds familiar.
I feel like he's been someone who's been trying
to track us down for quite a while now.
He found us and he thinks that we can lead him
to this big powerful energy source.
Yeah, don't do that.
But we don't really know what it is
and why he's referring.
So I'm pretty sure he's just referring to us
as the guild.
Okay, don't come home.
Yeah, don't come home yet.
Feel safe.
So have they turned the entire Axe of Mirabar?
Because that would be bad.
Well, like half?
Half of the army is outside of town.
We've warned them not to come into town
because as soon as they do,
something activates in their armor
and they become like zombies or automatons or something.
They can't control themselves anymore.
So they know that,
at least the ones that aren't already turned,
but there's still a lot of them.
Yeah, definitely.
If you're sure it's in the armor,
it's going to take us a little while,
but we might be able to arrange to get new armor sent
to at least some of the other members of the Axe of Mirabar
if they're holding formation
so that maybe they can come in and help you.
So yeah, if you're certain that that's what it is,
we can have that sent.
Like I said, it'll take a bit,
but that's something as opposed to nothing right now.
Okay, I look at Thea and Flint like, right?
Am I remembering right?
We know for sure it's the armor.
Yeah, no, it is for sure the armor.
Their armor has some crazy mixture of alloys and metals
that is specific to them
and they're the only ones that got affected by this.
Yes, Alizar, anything you can do to help
because there's a lot of them.
We can't fight them with three of us.
Although I think the better thing to do
is to focus on fixing the enchantment
if we can break the spell somehow.
By murdering Primsby.
Yeah, we don't wanna like,
A, we can't fight a thousand army members
and B, we don't wanna kill all those people.
So if there's a way that we can save them
and you can get the wizards working on some sort of fix,
I think that's our best option.
Absolutely, I will do that.
If you figure out anything more that can help us do that,
let me know, but I'll get them started
on researching Thelonious
and kind of some of his schools of magic
and what he might be able to acquire for himself
and how he might be doing this
and get you guys some armor
for the other members of the army
and hopefully they can come in
and at least try and wrangle or subdue
some of the other,
some of these zombified ones that you're talking about.
You've got the communicator now,
so you should be able to just dial us back up.
Great.
Also, Tibby, I think went home?
Yeah, Tibby went home.
Went to a place that looked like the place
where she was from.
Tibby went home?
Tibby's home was destroyed.
Uh, we came back, different portals.
I don't know.
It sure looked like she went home.
She went somewhere different than us.
Well, that's interesting.
We had found some portal magic,
which we obviously used to try and get you out,
but yeah, Tibby's world was more or less destroyed,
which is why Tibby was working with us.
So maybe, huh.
Could Tibby have gone back to a different timeline before?
Well, you said you guys were gone for three weeks,
but did it seem like three weeks that you guys were gone?
No.
No, it was one day.
I have a feeling like you guys jumped forward in time
and Tibby might have gone a long ways back in time.
Well, hopefully, did he say he'd come back if he could?
Yeah, I, yeah.
I think that's exactly what he said.
Wanted to learn more about the portals.
Okay.
Well, yeah, hopefully, hopefully we can figure out more.
We've got some more research and stuff to do on portals.
And now, I guess, time jump.
Oh, busy day.
Okay, I'm going to go get started on all of this stuff here.
You guys.
Maybe Doc Brown will be around to help.
Tibby, Tibby, we got to go back.
It's your kids, Tibby.
It's your kids.
Can we please have an NPC soon that is Christopher Lloyd
because that sounds amazing.
That would be really good.
I'll make a note of it.
Guys, he's legit writing that down.
Okay, see you on the flippy flops, Alizar.
Yeah, good talking to you.
We'll talk to you soon.
I miss you.
He snuck it in right as he was hanging out.
I love it.
So guys, feel like the world's coming to an end.
Not really any help from the guild on this one right away.
Thoughts?
What should we do?
Let's find and murder that evil dark elf bastard.
Yeah, that sounds like a plan.
I like it.
Let's do that.
And we do that.
End of episode.
Excellent.
We win.
Good work, guys.
We did it.
Nice.
Hammer striker says, well, yeah, are we going in through the tunnels or do we want to?
Because we said that, or Osric said that they've got a whole bunch of people
outside the front door.
And yeah, I think the tunnels would probably be the best idea.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure we settled on the tunnels.
Yeah, at least the most funneled if there are, you know,
if there is somebody coming for us anyways.
Funneled tunnels?
Funneled tunnels.
Let's head to the funnel tunnels.
We're going to put the fun in funnel tunnel.
Is that anything like funnel cake?
Because that is delicious.
That sounds great.
OK, so that was a no on the funnel cake?
No, no funnel cake.
No funnel cake.
OK, all right.
It's disappointing.
Osric says, sorry, mate, the funnel cake place, it went first.
The zombie guys, they hit it really hard.
That's how it always happens.
I know, I know.
I went there first, too, and it was just a mess.
Flour, eggs, powdered sugar everywhere.
Come on, list more ingredients.
Baking soda, I'm sure.
Maybe some magic powder to make it taste so good.
Cinnamon, Ross, it's cinnamon.
No, he calls cinnamon magic powder at home, too.
It's kind of a weird thing to happen.
You don't tell me what I'm saying, cinnamon.
It's a real sticking point.
It is about dusk now, falling on the city.
We got to head to these tunnels, you guys.
I say no waiting.
Yeah, I agree.
Only murder.
Well, there's your episode title.
No waiting, only murder.
I was going to go with funnel tunnels.
He did write it in quotation marks.
I'll see how the episode pieces together.
Because we're all rested up, right?
Everybody should have full everything.
Tunnels, let's do it.
Let's go to them.
Guys, I'm going to show you some amazing shit after.
Just wait, just wait, just wait.
That sounds awesome.
I feel something.
After this immediate problem that needs to be solved,
we should probably figure out why it felt like,
I don't know, all the energy in the world
shifted a little bit eviler.
That seems like that should be on the to-do list.
So that was real weird and real bad.
But right now, we got a wizard to murder.
And murder him we shall.
And we skip gleefully towards the tunnel
and our task of murder.
Whistling a nice murdering tune.
Exactly.
You head out of the safe house there
and you go out into the street
and you're kind of sticking to the shadows
and the sides of the street.
And Torgar and Osric lead you back to the door
that leads down into the tunnels.
And now you're back down in there.
And the tunnels in this area are about 10 feet wide.
So enough for two people to walk side by side.
And about five, five and a half to,
you know, five and three quarter feet tall.
I crouch.
So anybody who needs to crouch is probably crouching.
And they're all very dry and stone built.
But when you get down into this first set of tunnels,
you hear somewhere very faint within the tunnels.
A very reverberated thud.
Very consistent as you're walking in here.
They're very muted at first.
And you begin walking through the tunnels
and checking corners as you go.
And you are walking for about 10 minutes or so.
You're on the north side of the city.
And as you're walking, this thudding gets a little louder.
And Torgar tells you,
we're going to have to go take the tunnels under the river
to the other side of the city where we think Thelonious is.
Shouldn't be a problem, but that's where we're going.
And he takes you and stops you around a corner,
tells you to hold back as around the corner,
he says and whispers,
looks like there's some zombie soldiers around the corner here.
I don't think they saw me,
but it looks like there's about four of them.
And that's kind of the way we need to go.
How do you feel about incapacitating them
in order to get through?
Well, if we can, we should probably try.
I've dealt with some undead stuff before
and usually you can't quite incapacitate them,
but we will do our best.
If it has to happen that we have to kill them,
then that's what we have to do.
Those are the words I was looking for.
Well, we get sneak attack anyway, right?
We're still invisible for five more minutes or something.
Yeah.
So you guys get sneak attack.
So you guys kind of all attack at once
because you are concealed and hidden
and they don't know you're there.
So the sneak attack,
you just tell me what you three each want to do.
There are four zombie soldier guys
and we'll say that you three
kind of take the lead on this quick attack here first.
All right.
I'm going to run behind one of them,
get on my hands and knees
and then New Laura is going to shove them over me.
So we're just going to play pranks on them for a little bit?
All right.
Yeah.
Either way, if that's what you want to do.
I mean, one of you has got to get
in front of them somehow though.
So that's going to be interesting.
Well, also, because we can't see each other.
So how will I know when he's in position?
Well, you guys can see each other.
Because you all have the same spell on you.
Imagine like the cone of silence
and everyone inside the cone can hear each other.
I think we're like in a cone of invisibility
where everyone inside your invisible bubble
can see each other.
And I mean, we've been kind of treating it
as invisibility, but I read the spell again.
It's not really an invisible spell.
It's more like a super buff to your stealth spell.
So you're like in the shadow.
We've been treating it like an invisibility spell.
So I'll keep doing that more or less,
but you guys can still see each other.
Yeah, we just have like super stealth and death.
Yeah, it makes you super sneaky and shadowy.
People can't follow our footprints or whatever.
Exactly.
OK.
Basically, we're all wearing Kavoth's shade cloak.
Yes.
Exactly.
All right, so we'll say that the Pass Without a Trace
will kind of wear off after the sneak attack.
So tell me what you want to do
and then we'll roll attacks.
How many?
There's four.
There are four of them.
I aim my Produce Flame at one of them.
OK.
So we're attacking, right?
We're like, well, yeah, you're just going to
because all three of your attacks
are going to kind of happen at the same time
to get sneak attack to get a sneak round.
OK, that's what I'll be doing.
I'm going to, as best I can, get behind
one of these zombo types
and just try and beat them in the back of the head
with my handle of my axe.
So not the blade.
So I'm not trying to kill them.
I'm just trying to take them down.
OK.
All right.
And you, Laura?
This is also my plan.
I'm just going to hit one in the head
with the butt of flametongue to try to incapacitate them
and then maybe tie them up or something.
Sure.
Hoping those flames can take out a couple,
but I imagine they can because
I don't have like an incapacitate kind of spell.
You got to you got to damage them somehow
to incapacitate them, right?
Truth.
So roll attacks for everybody there.
You're just producing flame.
So what's the what's the
And we have advantage on these, correct?
Yes.
So you roll two d20s and take the better.
Five feet.
22.
So that's a 23.
What's your what's your normal damage on your sword
and your axe?
Normally two d12 plus four.
OK.
So roll a one d10
just because you're using the butt of it.
And then New Laura.
Part of my damage is fire.
So I'll take that out.
So two d6 plus two.
Just do one d6.
I add six damage, Russ.
OK.
Five and then seven if I'm adding that plus or whatever.
Sure.
Yeah.
Flint and New Laura, you sneak up behind them handily with Pass Without a Trace still on.
And you hit both of these zombified dwarf soldiers, the base of the skull,
and knock two of them prone.
And Thea, you quickly produce flame on the backs of these other two
and they take the damage.
But turn around and seem more or less unfazed by it.
But swing towards you both.
Roll for initiative.
Oh, nat 20.
Why did I waste it?
Because it's an initiative roll.
That's what we always do.
That's the only time we get 20s, I think.
Plus your modifier.
21.
Seven for me.
14.
OK.
So Thea, you're up first.
Of course I am.
Thea decides to do that one more time.
So I'm going to produce flame and try to hit those two again.
Sure.
Four.
So Flint and Nularaaa, you have now kind of ducked down and out of the way of Thea's flame,
which she erupts again from her hand.
And these zombies take another four damage.
Now it is their turn.
Two of them are knocked prone.
They are going to stand up and swing towards Flint and Nularaaa, who are closest to them.
The one swinging at you, Flint, doesn't do very well.
That's a five.
He's swinging with his hammer.
Excellent.
And that's a critical miss.
So the zombies both stand up and awkwardly and clumsily swing down.
And the one who critically misses on you, Nularaaa, actually trips himself up and he's prone again.
The two behind them, they walk forward and kind of step push past the other two.
One of them swings at Flint for a 19.
And the other one swings at Nularaaa for a seven.
So I think Flint hits there and he swings down at you, Flint, for one bludgeoning damage.
Whoa, guys.
There's the all eyes in the end to it.
Should we go?
Do we need to back out through the funnel tunnel?
Need to run away.
I don't think I'm going to be OK, but we'll try it.
Nularaaa, you're up next.
OK, well, the first guy I attacked is laying down and then another one attacked me.
Yes?
Yes.
OK, well, I'm going to attack him right back.
But again, I'm just trying to disarm him, not murder him, unless he keeps fucking with me.
That's a 25.
25 will hit.
What weapons do they have?
They are holding war hammers.
It's really more challenging when you're trying not to kill someone.
We're just going to say that you are trying to incapacitate them.
So once they hit zero, they will die.
We'll see what happens once they hit zero.
Unless you tell me that you are actively trying to chop one of their heads off,
we will say that you are trying to incapacitate.
OK, well, maybe I'll use my lance then because it is not sharp, right?
It's more of a bludgeoning instrument.
I don't know.
You had a lot of things skewered on there at one point.
I did.
There is some small piercing damage on it, like if you stab with it,
but the majority of it is not.
So I'm just going to try and bonk him upside the head.
The old classic bonk upside the head, which will get him.
Sorry, let me just find that die.
I don't use it that often.
Uh, 11 plus 3 is 14, damn it.
So that guy is knocked down to the ground and appears to be unconscious.
Flint, you have two zombies attempting or kind of piled in front of you there.
You see new Lara swing her lance and knock one down to the ground.
It appears unconscious.
And now it's your turn.
OK, yeah, I guess I'll try and incapacitate the one that's prone.
Let's say 14.
He's prone, so you get advantage.
14 doesn't hit, but yeah.
Oh, well, that's much better.
23.
23 will hit, yeah.
8 damage.
He is hit, but still looks conscious there.
All right, well, let's second attack.
That one's an 18.
18 will hit, yeah.
Excellent.
And 4 damage.
On the same one, he is still conscious.
So now it's Torgar and Osric's turn and they can't really seem to get by.
So they are just going to ready their actions.
And if something, if one of you was knocked down, they will be ready to go next.
Thea, your turn.
So Flint is swinging the butt of his axe down on the prone one.
He has two other zombies right in front of him who are able to attack,
and New Lara has taken one out.
OK, I move in a way so that Flint isn't blocking the two.
And I produce a thorn whip.
So I'm going to thorn whip one of them, I suppose,
which means I need to make a melee spell attack.
So I need to roll a d20, yes.
I don't use this very often.
Here we go.
15 plus, is there a plus 8?
Spell attack bonus, yeah.
All right, so 23.
23 will hit.
So this vine comes out and wraps itself.
And I can pull it 10 feet closer to me,
but I was thinking about pulling it to the side and like trying to pull them,
because this isn't a large area, is it?
Is the width?
About 10 feet wide.
So they are, yeah, they're in kind of the middle of the hallway.
So instead of pulling toward me,
I was going to whip them to the side against the wall.
Yeah, it'd still come towards you, but you can kind of angle it.
Angle it so that he whacks against the wall.
Is that any extra wall damage?
Thorn damage and wall damage.
You get 2d6 damage for 2d6 piercing damage.
I do?
Yeah.
Germans are well known for their wall fighting ability.
Of course, right?
Yeah, 2d6 piercing damage.
And yeah, you're ramming them into the wall, so give it another d4.
Six plus three is nine damage.
Nine damage.
So you wrap your vines around and they dig into its skin,
and you pull him into the wall with a huge thud,
and he takes all of that damage and is now past Flint and New Lara
and more directly in front of you.
Okay, which probably maybe means that Hammeh and Ostrich can get into this
action because he's closer to us.
Okay, cool.
That seemed like a good idea.
That worked out.
Torgar sees this and he is going to take his action.
His hammer has been covered.
I'm trying to say how you just haven't really seen it,
but he pulls the covering off of his hammer,
and it isn't like a standard war hammer.
It is a solid piece of like mined ore,
and he pulls that out and swings at the zombie that you,
Thea, have just pulled towards you and hits him.
That's a 16, and he gets two d8 plus two damage.
He incapacitates the zombie that you have pulled towards you,
and now it is the other two zombies' turn.
The prone one stands back up and swings at you,
Flint, for a 15.
Not good enough.
The other zombie swings at you,
Flint, and that's a 15.
So he misses as well.
So there are two zombies still active and now both standing.
Nularaaa, you see Thea pull one past you and Flint
and into a wall,
and then Torgar strike it down until it's unconscious,
and now it is your turn.
Both swing wildly at Flint,
but you get to take an action now.
Excellent.
I'm going to remember to take both attacks this time.
And Donnie's, too.
We skipped Donnie.
Oh, yeah.
It is.
Welcome back, or welcome to The Adventure
if this is your first episode.
This is episode 16 of Dumbgeons and Dragons,
titled No Waiting, Only Murder, a.k.a. The Funnel Tunnels.
If this is your first episode, welcome.
It certainly is a great time to jump on board,
but I would recommend catching up on the previous episodes
and we've made it easier for you in a couple different ways.
What you can do, one of two things.
You can go back to episode one and just start from the beginning.
There's 15, at least 15 hours of great content, great goofs.
Some of the first couple episodes, I'm not going to lie,
a little shaky, but if you push through, it gets much better.
Last week, though, we released a recap episode.
I know, we were thinking, right?
We want you to get on board right now.
So you can go listen to that recap episode.
Then you're at least caught up to where we are now.
And then you can go forward with us
and then you can choose to go back
and listen to those first 15 episodes,
which lots of great goofs,
lots of great adventure, highly recommend it.
How's the episode sitting with you?
Would love to hear your thoughts.
We're trying out some new things these last couple episodes
to bring some new depth to the adventurers.
And trust me, those new things carry right on through
to the end of this episode and beyond.
So make sure you listen right on through till the end.
We've seen a couple nice bits of feedback
and comments these last couple of weeks,
and I wanted to share with you.
On Twitter, at oldschoolcm tweeted,
from one DM to another DM,
sweet move with Lent in episode nine
of the Dumb Dragon cast.
The players are starting to get paranoid.
Hashtag D&D, hashtag evil DM.
That's what you want, right?
Have the players checking every door, window, corner,
and NPC for a potential trap?
I thought it was fun.
Thanks for pointing that one out at oldschoolcm.
We're really happy that you are continuing
this journey with us.
We've seen some wonderful growth of the show,
both on social media and in episode downloads.
We're happy and thankful that you are enjoying the show
and continuing on this journey with us.
That's all I've got for now.
The next episode in our adventure will be available
July 12th with episode 17.
So let's get right back into the funnel tunnels
for a little more murder.
We'll talk to you in a couple of weeks.
Have fun and make sure you get those entries in.
We are bad at this game.
So I'm going to do the lance obnoxious
swat upside the head.
I feel like this happened in a movie once
and it was very insulting.
They were actually doing a horse duel lance lancing
and instead of trying to actually hit him,
he just smacked him upside the head
to really prove how much better he was.
It's probably a night's tale.
I was just thinking that.
I was just going to say the one with Heath Ledger.
Yeah.
That's what I'm picturing.
So that's probably it.
That is a 26.
26 will hit, yeah.
So he gets a six damage.
And that one is now appears to be unconscious.
Perfect.
Then I'll swing around and try and hit the other.
And that is a no, 10, no, 11.
11 will not hit.
No.
Okay.
Then I guess Donnie will try and like give him
a little little chomp-a-roo,
which also will not work because that is a nine.
Okay.
So you swing and knock one unconscious
and miss with the other one entirely.
And Donnie, he's just finding trouble
amongst all these swinging hammers and sticks
to try and get a good dig in there.
Flint, your turn.
There is only one zombie who is left standing and active.
That is a 21.
21 will do it.
And seven damage.
He is knocked back a little bit but still standing.
Okay.
And that's a 16 for the second roll.
16 will hit, yep.
With nine damage.
And you knock him unconscious as well.
So all four zombies are now laid out on the ground
and they appear to be have just incapacitated
as opposed to kill.
Excellent.
Good job.
We did it.
We didn't do murders once, ever.
Once, for once.
I think this might be the first time
we haven't just murdered everything.
I think so too.
So we tie them up, I guess.
So it's four less to deal with at some other point.
Can we use that thorn whip to tie them up?
That seems more painful.
Seems kind of cruel but I'm not opposed.
Seems more incapacitating.
I don't know if you can
because it's an instantaneous thing that disappears after you use it.
Oh, I see.
It's illusionary.
In my mind, the vine actually shrivels up.
Yeah.
Oh, that's fun.
So yeah, let's just tie them up with some ropes.
Keep on going.
Yeah, you each tie up one of these zombies
and kind of pile them off to the side
and you continue on.
And as you keep going further into this tunnel system,
Torgar's leading you,
that thudding that you heard and continue to hear increases in volume
and it's getting louder and louder but still very consistent.
He tells you that you're coming close to
where you should be going underneath the river
and there's a final staircase that goes down
and the thudding is louder and louder and louder.
You step down off this final step
and there is a four to six inch layer of water.
It appears that this tunnel is starting to fill up
and you look ahead and down to the end of this tunnel
and you see six dwarven soldiers with their hammers
beating in the sides of this tunnel.
Water looks like it's streaming in from where they are impacting it.
Well, this seems like a suicide mission for them.
Yeah, no kidding.
Torgar and you guys follow down and you take a splash into the water
and they look over to you
and four of them begin charging towards you
while two of them continue to hammer on the wall.
Roll for initiative.
Looks like we're gonna have to stop that business.
Oh, I only got a five.
Nineteen?
Fifteen.
Good job, you guys.
My initiative bonus is plus three, so it's pretty good.
Nice.
Okay, so Torgar is first down and he's first to react
and he runs towards the four charging zombies
and swings his hammer at one of the ones in the front.
First one hits but doesn't hit squarely on the first one
and his second strike connects solidly with one of the other zombies
and it takes 15 bludgeoning damage
and it is knocked prone
and now it is Nularaaa.
You follow quickly behind Torgar and it is your turn.
Okay, I'll attack the next in the approaching group.
That is a six, no, 15.
Are you still using your lance?
Yeah.
15 will kind of glance off its armor.
The old lance glance.
Okay, I'm going to try that one more time
and that is a 23, so that one will probably work better.
Yep.
And that is 13 damage.
You give him a good hit and it stops him in his tracks
and the two zombies running behind them kind of barrel in
to the two that are now knocked down
and there's a bit of a pile of zombies
as they are trying to right themselves.
Flint, it's your turn.
So you have Nularaaa and Torgar in front of you
and then four zombies in a frantic pile
trying to stand back up right now.
Is there like that Benny Hill music playing in the background?
Always, always.
Okay, perfect.
Because that's what's running through my head
whenever we play this game.
Of course.
I'm going to run past Torgar and Nularaaa
and dive on in with a 14, so that's not going to do it.
Second attack.
Oh, that's much better, 19.
19 will do it, yep.
Excellent.
Oh, 10 damage.
You run through and past Nularaaa and Torgar
and you connect with one and kind of,
we'll say that you kind of do like a tuck and roll
over top of these scrambling zombies
and you are now on the other side of this pile of zombies.
And that one takes that damage
and it is two of the zombies who were first knocked down.
They stand back up.
First one swings towards Torgar
who doesn't roll well today who misses
and the second one swings toward Nularaaa
and that is a 15.
I think that misses as well.
Yeah, that misses.
I'm not trying to make this easy on you guys.
It's just working out that way.
That's better because we're trying not to kill them.
So it would be unfair if they were really trying to kill us.
Thea, you see the zombies knocked down
and Flint run and jump over them
and now he's on the other side and now it's your turn.
Okay, I am going to,
there's still two still beating on the walls, right?
Yeah.
Trying to get this whole shit to come down.
I am going to cast Conjure Animal.
I'm going to summon face spirits that take the form of beasts
and appear in the space directly in front of these two assholes
trying to cave the walls in.
Okay.
The beast that I choose is going to be a crocodile because it's...
It's within your challenge rating ability.
It's within my challenge rating ability of one half.
Okay.
Oh, I can choose a challenge rating of two.
Yeah, well just keep in mind that you've got space restrictions to consider.
Oh yeah, a crocodile would probably be good, you know,
because the water, I don't know.
So yeah, so I do that
and I'm and my crocodile,
can I fight with my crocodile immediately as I conjure him
or is that my action?
Hold on a second.
So you can summon four beasts at a challenge rating of one half.
I'm going to do, well, two of these beasts then.
I don't have to do four, do I?
I can do two crocodiles.
Yeah.
Good, because there are two guys there.
I'm going to scroll down.
The summoned creatures are friendly to us, but not to them.
Rule initiative for the summoned creatures as a group which has its own turn.
So it has to fall in line,
so it might not be able to go right away unless it falls.
Ten.
They would go next.
They would go next, cool.
So you have to give them a command.
Yes.
Otherwise, they just kind of stand there.
So I command, I say, hey, crocs, bite those assholes.
No, bite those guys.
They acknowledge your command and they go to attack the two that are hammering on the wall.
Yes.
So you roll attacks for your crocodiles.
Okay, they are going to use their bite because that's all they got.
Hold breath.
I don't think it's really going to happen.
So your first one hits.
Do you attack for your second one as well?
They fight as a group.
They still have to make an attack roll on each of them.
Okay, that one does not.
That's a seven.
So the first one is going to bite for 1d10 plus two.
So that's five.
Right in the ass.
So they're very literal when you say, bite those assholes.
That's what they're doing.
Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained.
So he's biting and holding.
That's my no.
Yeah, that's that's good.
I just need to.
There's something I had to get out of restraint.
I just need to know what the check is.
Guys, I'm so excited.
I'm using something new.
I know it's really fun, too.
And good choice because it just gives them the old chomp.
And then maybe he can't fight.
Yeah, maybe he can't fight now.
I like it also not breaking down the walls.
I mean, he's still that other guy.
And intimidating.
Yeah, like, boom, crocodiles out of nowhere.
I'd pee my pants.
Yep.
Agreed.
It has to make a strength check on its turn, but not right now.
So the crocodiles.
So Osric, he pulls out his crossbow and he goes to shoot one in the pile of mess there
and hits with an 18 and he will get eight piercing damage into one that's in the in
the pile in the middle there.
Two more in the center of the mess stand up and one that turns around and swings
towards Flint.
The other goes towards new Lara.
The one goes towards Flint is a nine.
So that's not going to be good.
And also a nine from your I'm just not going to play.
You guys just tell me when you kill them.
Okay, incapacitate them.
That's right.
Being good.
Yeah.
So the two hammering on the wall.
It's their turn now.
The one who is grappled by the crocodile can certainly try to escape the grapple.
I just imagine grape apple.
The word grapples.
We've been ruined.
Is there no, you can't see what you need to get.
No.
Okay.
I rolled a 13.
Just trying to play for fighting over the book.
Piercing damage is grappled until the grapple ends is already restrained.
And the crocodile can't buy it.
So we can't obviously like he's got a mouthful already.
You can't attack someone different.
So he's just going to hold him.
Okay.
Well, he's going to try and get it, but not.
And he's going to swing with disadvantage because he is grappled,
but he's going to swing, which is a nine versus his AC.
Nine versus my crocodile's AC.
Yeah.
12.
So that doesn't hit.
The other one continues to hammer on the wall and ignores the other crocodile there.
And as he continues to hammer, you hear an audible crack and crumble.
And it appears like more water begins to come into this tunnel.
Goodness gracious.
And to Torgar.
That's me again.
All right.
Let's just see if I can mess with this one too.
Torgar.
He swings at, he sees these crocodiles appear and he's like, holy shit, that's cool.
That's the appropriate response.
And he swings his hammer single-handed at the two zombies in front of him,
but seems a little bit thrown off by the, by the holy shit.
That's cool.
Crocodiles and misses with bows.
And New Lara, it is your turn.
You also see two spirit crocodiles, which is the first time you've seen
Thea do something like this appear down at the end of this tunnel.
I would just like to say Thea has been able to do this for a very long time and never has.
They don't need to know that.
Yeah, that's, yeah, that's fine.
I'll assume you learned it in your book.
That's right.
Books are important.
So I yell, sweet shit, Thea, dope spell.
Is there one now in front of me?
Two are laying down.
All four are standing up, but there are four in front of you.
One is engaged in combat with Flint directly.
The other three are more aimed towards you and Torgar.
Okay.
Well, I'll just attack the one closest to me, I suppose.
It's a 23.
23 will hit.
That is 14 damage.
That one is now appears to be unconscious.
Perfect.
I will attack a different one.
That is a 28.
And 12 damage.
And that one is also unconscious.
Donnie's going to try and bite one.
Yep.
That's a 19.
Donnie.
19 will be good.
So that is a four damage.
And then he needs to do a constitution saving throw.
Poison does not affect zombies.
So nothing happens there, but he does take the four damage.
Okay.
He is still standing.
So Flint, you have one zombie directly in front of you swinging its hammer at you.
It is your turn.
Anyone else imagining Russ though, every time he says still standing,
like these zombies are singing in their head like,
I'm still standing better than I ever did.
That's better than if they're watching that Jim Belushi sitcom.
So that's true.
That's true.
I think the song would be a great fight montage song.
I'm into it.
Oh, totally.
Yeah.
I was going to get those rights.
I was going to say we can't afford Elton John style rights, but I like the idea.
I'll call him up.
Play it on a recorder.
That's right.
Wait a minute.
That's just hot cross buns.
Every time.
Are there still the guys hammering into the wall?
Yes, sir.
Am I close enough to run over there?
You are.
There are two, two crocodiles between you and them though.
But they're not going to hurt you.
But they're friendly to me, right?
Whether you as Flint know that or not is uncertain.
Can I ask Thea if they're friendly or not?
Yeah.
Hey Thea, are those crocs of yours going to hurt me if I go over there?
No, no, man.
They're like puppies, scaly puppies.
You go, you go.
All right.
I'm going to run over there and try and take one of them down, I guess.
You are running away from the zombie that's in front of you?
Yes.
He will get an opportunity to attack me.
That is fine.
So we're going to do that here first.
He's not going to do anything.
I don't know why it even matters.
It's 13.
Keep going.
Run.
So confident that you were going to botch the roll that it was totally fine.
Get rid of these fucking dice.
He actually changed his dice right now.
He's like, this one's broken.
This one's broken.
That's so good.
All right.
So yeah, I'm going to attack the one that did get bit by the croc because he was a little
more hurt and see if I can take him down.
Sure.
All right.
That's an 18.
18 will do it.
And nine damage on that first attack.
It is grappled by this crocodile and you hit it and it is still alive.
Okay.
Well, I mean, I'm just trying to not try to kill him.
It is still able to take an action.
Okay, perfect.
That is a critical on a 19.
Because I get twice as many chances to hit criticals as everyone else.
All right.
So damage wise, this shouldn't be too bad because I'm still using like the blunt side
of my axe.
So that's six and another six.
So 12 damage.
It is unconscious now as well.
And we go to the first two zombies that had charged.
There's only one of those left up.
And he swings towards, it doesn't even really matter who he swings towards.
It's going to miss.
I'm going to swing towards new Lara.
Oh, that's a 21.
What?
Yep.
That'll hit.
Not critical.
And you take-
Quick, Amy.
Change the dice backwards.
Not looking.
You take-
It's red versus black.
I think he'd notice.
Yeah.
You take six bludgeoning damage off of that zombie soldier.
And then it is Thea.
Your turn.
Okay.
Well, guys, this allows me to have two actions.
I've always wanted two actions.
This is all you've ever wanted.
I love it.
It's all I've ever wanted.
And one time you're crocodile.
So it's just more exciting than just a roll roll.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I guess there is, there is.
So what you see, water's rising.
There are two zombies who are unconscious in the center,
engaged in combat with new Lara and Torgar.
There are two still standing there.
One is in the mouth of one of your crocodiles.
It is unconscious.
The other is still hammering on the wall with the crocodile
and now Flint over there.
I am going to get out my oath bow.
I'm going to say swift death to those who have wronged me.
You have to pick one of them.
I'm picking the one that is hammering on the wall
because I feel like this guy can just kill us all.
Yeah.
So I'm going to shoot my oath bow.
This is why I don't use weapons.
Four plus two, six.
So your oath bow shot just goes wide.
Whatever.
I've got two crocodiles.
I command the one crocodile to let go of the guy that he's biting
and for both of them to focus their attention on
the one that is pounding on the wall.
Sure.
So damn, damn, damn it.
That's a seven for one of them.
Matt misses.
Oh, a nat 20 for the other one.
The other one is the one that has not previously bit somebody.
So he gets a turn now.
So he is going to bite the derriere of this one
because his back is to him.
And he's going to do the death roll
because he's a crocodile and crocodiles do that.
Can I get him to do that?
Yeah.
It's not going to give him any more damage,
but can it rip him off his feet?
You'd get damage from the bite because he's biting him.
Yeah.
But I mean, can he also rip him down into the water and spin?
He'd be restrained and then prone.
Well, I mean, he'd be restrained, but yeah.
Cool.
Sure.
One D10 plus two.
Times two.
What?
Because you got a critical.
That's nine, 10, 11 times two?
Or do I roll twice?
You roll again.
Oh, yeah.
You don't get your plus again, but yeah, you get another dice.
Cool.
That's 17.
17.
He's like barrel rolling this guy.
So he is...
Flint, in front of you, you see one of these crocodiles
just snatch this zombie soldier
and then just begin rolling with him.
And it looks like quite a violent roll.
Nobody looks happy about it, except the crocodile.
Crocodile looks pretty stoked.
Whee!
Ostrich shoots his crossbow into one of the ones
that is in front of New Lara and Torgar.
And he gets a 19, which is going to be eight piercing damage.
And that one is unconscious.
So there is now only one in front of New Lara and Torgar.
And now it is that one's turn.
And he is going to swing at Torgar for 21, not critical.
And Torgar is going to take one damage.
Single damage.
A toe-stubbing worth of damage, if you will.
Is that what Flint has, too?
And Torgar's damage.
His toe's achy.
He's got an achy toe.
Zombie, who is now in a death roll.
I'm just going to roll and see if we can...
Strength check?
Yeah, roll a strength check for your crocodile.
Nat 20.
Even my...
Damn!
Yeah.
You got the good dice tonight.
Yeah, you got 22.
22.
So I got a 20.
You have a Nat 20.
This is my third one.
It's amazing.
He is flailing against this crocodile.
This crocodile is hammering him.
Kind of the role of this, though, is giving some more shake to the wall.
And you see some more crumbling coming out of the wall.
Yeah, I'll stop.
It's not the crocodile's turn.
It doesn't matter.
I can give verbal commands.
It's not your turn either.
What?
It's not your turn.
It has to be my turn.
It says no action required by you.
From the start to the end is six seconds.
Oh, all right.
Yeah.
Go so fast.
I know.
And now it's Torgar's turn.
There's one zombie left between him and new Lara there.
And that is a 20, not critical.
11 damage.
So that zombie takes a big hit, but is still up.
And new Lara, your turn.
I have a question.
If one of the people in the campaign, our friends, were to ask me to ask the crocodile
to stop, would I be able to let them stop?
No, because it's still not your turn.
No, I know.
But like when Flint asked me, hey, are these crocodiles cool?
And I said, yeah, they're like puppies.
Would it not be, would that not set a precedent that I can speak?
You still have to give.
Well, yeah, you're engaged in quick conversation with.
I'm just trying to find the loop.
No, no, you can't, you can't stop your goddamn things.
Fine.
Lara, it's your turn.
Keep looking.
I think you're on the trail.
Follow the money, Amy.
So I'm going to attack that last one.
That is a 17.
17 will hit, yeah.
Nine.
Nine is enough to incapacitate that zombie.
Nice.
So there's just the one in the death roll with the crocodile still active, we'll say.
Okay.
You don't know how you're going to.
Yeah, like I'm probably not going to.
Even though it won't hurt me, it might accidentally still seems like a bad idea.
Also, we got to get out of here because that wall cracked, right?
Do you want to start just start running?
I don't know.
What do you guys think?
Like, I guess we haven't heard any updates on how that cracked wall went.
It will be very ironic if this battle took three times longer than normal because
we were using not our best weapons to try not to kill these things.
And now it just floods and they all die.
Truth.
Yeah, that would be really stupid.
I say we run.
Yeah.
Because what's one non-incapacitated soldier out of like hundreds that we still are yet to fight?
Yeah, let's, let's.
How high is the water at this point?
About knee height.
Knee height.
Okay.
So you're, you would be slowed unless you have some sort of.
Crocodile to ride on?
I don't know.
Crocodile to ride on.
But yes, you would be slowed in terms of making distance.
I mean, I can walk on water.
Yes, you can.
I forgot that too.
Yeah.
Girl, walk on water.
We can water walk for one hour.
I think up to 10 willing creatures.
There you go.
Oh damn.
So we just walk as though on solid ground.
Let's walk our asses out of here.
In a now three foot tall.
Oh Jesus.
Oh, so we're bent like literally half seas at the waist.
Yeah.
Well, Flint's not.
Yeah, I'm just ducking slightly.
Neither is Torgar and Ostrich, right?
Flint, Torgar and Ostrich aren't.
That's true.
They're like hunched a bit.
I will.
I'll just lay down on top of one of my crocodiles and have them.
You can too.
We do have two crocodiles if you want to.
I love it.
That sounds amazing.
So you are casting water walk then as your second action?
Sure.
Walking on water.
Yeah, water walk, I believe.
You cast this and you guys just kind of go whoop.
Right to the top.
Nice sound effect.
I like that.
Yeah, that was good.
And then Flint, it's your turn.
I thought we were booking it out.
You're booking it.
Okay, so Flint, as everybody begins booking it, you hear in your brain space,
you hear Bort say, hey, I figured it out.
And then you feel a rumble, a burning charge.
We're making an attack roll.
16.
Do I have any modifiers?
Question.
No, we'll just do that for now.
You feel and now see.
So everybody's kind of behind you because you were closest to the exit stairs to get up.
Everybody else sees out of Flint's mouth come an electric lightning charge.
As he breathes lightning down this tunnel, Flint, roll 2d6.
Okay.
And also I turn around at everyone and wink at them.
Five and five is ten.
You're erupting lightning from your mouth and you turn and it strikes the wall and you turn
and the wall visibly cracks and water begins streaming in as you guys
run past this flood of water now coming into this tunnel.
The tunnel is flooding.
Water is coming up quickly and you guys are running out of this tunnel,
which is now kind of filling up the stairwell behind you and continuing to rise
as you look down and see if it's stopping or if it's not, it is not stopping.
It is continuing to rise music in today's episode was by Kavin McLeod
of Incompetech.Filmmusic.io just clicked a weird off thing.
Maybe.
Okay. Sorry.
That had nothing to do with anything.
Okay.
Or did it have something to do with everything?
I was going to say if you went to zero AC,
I think we would have left you outside the funnel tunnels.
Dumbgeons and Dragons is a dumb dragons production.